<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2742_nm.6415" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6415" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6415" rank="species">Mycobacterium wolinskyi</organism><reference id="rid.2742"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brown</surname><given-names>B.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Springer</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steingrube</surname><given-names>V.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wilson</surname><given-names>R.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pfyffer</surname><given-names>G.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garcia</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Menendez</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rodriguez-Salgado</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jost</surname><given-names>K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chiu</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Onyi</surname><given-names>G.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Böttger</surname><given-names>E.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wallace</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium wolinskyi sp. nov. and Mycobacterium goodii sp. nov., two new rapidly growing species related to Mycobacterium smegmatis and associated with human wound infections: a cooperative study from the International Working Group on Mycobacterial Taxonomy.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1493</fpage><lpage>1511</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-4-1493</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10555330</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycobacterium wolinskyi</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycobacterium wolinskyi</i> (wo.lins'ky.i. M.L. gen. n. <i>wolinskyi</i> of Wolinsky, named after Emanuel Wolinsky in honour of, and in recognition for, significant contributions to the study of the non-tuberculous mycobacteria)</s></p><p class="description"><s>A Gram-positive, acid- and alcohol-fast bacillus that produces visible growth in 2-4 d as smooth to mucoid, off-white- to cream-coloured colonies on Middlebrook 7H10 and trypticase soy agar.</s><s>No pigment is produced and growth occurs at 30, 35 and 45°C.</s><s>Isolates grow on MacConkey agar without crystal violet and in the presence of 5% NaCl, are negative for arylsulfatase activity at 3 d, and are positive for iron uptake and nitrate reductase.</s><s>They produce low-level semi-quantitative catalase activity that is stable at 68°C, pH 7.0.</s><s>As sole carbon sources, 100% of isolates utilize D-glucitol (D-sorbitol), i-<i>myo</i>-inositol, D-mannitol and L-rhamnose, 88% utilize D-galactose and D-trehalose, and 50-63% utilize L-arabinose, citrate and D-xylose.</s><s>The type strain is positive for galactose, arabinose, citrate, trehalose and xylose.</s><s>Isolates are susceptible to amikacin and sulfamethoxazole, intermediately susceptible to doxycycline and ciprofloxacin, variably susceptible to cefmetazole, cefoxitin, chloramphenicol and clarithromycin, and resistant to isoniazid, rifampin and tobramycin.</s><s>Mycolic acids and whole-cell fatty acids are typical of mycobacterial species.</s><s>By PRA, isolates exhibit a unique, distinctive set of band patterns with <i>Msp</i>I (135, 120, 110 and 75 bp bands), <i>Hha</i>I (185, 105 and 65 bp bands) and <i>Aci</i>I (125 and 90 bp major band pattern, and 135, 125 and 85 bp minor band pattern).</s><s>The proposed type strain, ATCC 700010<sup>T</sup> (MO739), was recovered from a post-surgical facial abscess in Switzerland and was originally identified as <i>M. smegmatis</i> (Pennekamp et al., 1997).</s><s>An additional reference strain, ATCC 700009 (MO238), was isolated from a sternal wound infection following open heart surgery in Texas.</s></p></content></protolog>