<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10083_nm.15030" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.15030" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.15030" rank="species">Jeotgalibacillus salarius</organism><reference id="rid.10083"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>S.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>T.-K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Jeotgalibacillus salarius sp. nov., isolated from a marine saltern, and reclassification of Marinibacillus marinus and Marinibacillus campisalis as Jeotgalibacillus marinus comb. nov. and Jeotgalibacillus campisalis comb. nov., respectively</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>15</fpage><lpage>20</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008318-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19643870</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Jeotgalibacillus salarius</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Jeotgalibacillus salarius</em> (sa.la′ri.us. L. masc. adj. <em>salarius</em> of salt).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-variable and rod-shaped (0.4–0.7×1.3–8.5 μm).</s><s>Cells longer than 10.0 μm occasionally occur.</s><s>Subterminal ellipsoidal endospores are observed in slightly swollen sporangia.</s><s>Motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Colonies on MA are circular to irregular, raised, glistening, smooth, light-yellow in colour and 2.0–3.0 mm in diameter after 2 days incubation at 30 °C.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature is 30 °C; growth occurs at 4 and 40 °C, but not at 45 °C.</s><s>The optimal pH for growth is between 7.0 and 8.0; growth occurs at pH 6.0, but not at pH 5.5.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs in the presence of 2 % (w/v) NaCl; growth occurs at 0–18 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Mg<sup>2+</sup> ions are required for growth.</s><s>Anaerobic growth does not occur on MA or on MA supplemented with nitrate.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Nitrate reduction is negative.</s><s>Aesculin and casein are hydrolysed and Tween 80 is weakly hydrolysed, but gelatin, starch, hypoxanthine, xanthine, tyrosine and urea are not.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, maltose, d-mannitol, melezitose, d-ribose, sucrose and trehalose and weakly produced from cellobiose, but not from l-arabinose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, d-mannose, melibiose, l-rhamnose, raffinose, d-sorbitol or d-xylose.</s><s>Esterase (C4) and esterase lipase (C8) are present, but alkaline phosphatase, lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are absent.</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin, carbenicillin, cephalothin, chloramphenicol, gentamicin, kanamycin, lincomycin, neomycin, novobiocin, oleandomycin, penicillin G, streptomycin and tetracycline, but not to polymyxin B.</s><s>The peptidoglycan type is A1<em>α</em> (l-Lys-direct).</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-7; a significant amount of MK-8 is also present.</s><s>Major fatty acids (&#x003E;10 % of total fatty acids) are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> alcohol, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 42.9 mol% (determined by HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, ASL-1<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13257<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 56751<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from sediment of a marine saltern located on the coast of the Yellow Sea, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>