<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6635_nm.4504" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4504" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4504" rank="species">Thermanaerovibrio velox</organism><reference id="rid.6635"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zavarzina</surname><given-names>D.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhilina</surname><given-names>T.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tourova</surname><given-names>T.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kuznetsov</surname><given-names>B.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kostrikina</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bonch-Osmolovskaya</surname><given-names>E.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thermanaerovibrio velox sp. nov., a new anaerobic, thermophilic, organotrophic bacterium that reduces elemental sulfur, and emended description of the genus Thermanaerovibrio.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1287</fpage><lpage>1295</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10843074</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thermanaerovibrio velox</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thermanaerovibrio velox</i> (ve'lox. L. adj. <i>velox</i> quick, fast, motile)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are curved rods, 0.5-0.7x2.5-5.0 μm in size, with wave-like movement by means of lateral flagella located on the concave side of the cell.</s><s>Colonies are small, white, irregular or round, 0.2 mm in diameter, and with an even edge.</s><s>The cell wall has a Gram-negative structure.</s><s>Non-spore-forming.</s><s>Multiplication occurs by binary fission.</s><s>Growth occurs in a temperature range from 45 to 70 °C, with an optimum between 60 and 65 °C, and in a pH range from 4.5 to 8.0, with an optimum at pH 7.3.</s><s>Ferments glucose, fructose, mannose, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, adonite, arginine, serine, peptone, yeast extract and Casamino acids.</s><s>When grown on glucose, produces acetate, lactate, H<sub>2</sub>, CO<sub>2</sub> and ethanol.</s><s>No growth occurs on galactose, ribose, sorbose, xylose, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, raffinose, sucrose, trehalose, acetate, ascorbate, butyrate, citrate, formate, glycolate, glutamate, lactate, malate, pyruvate, propionate, succinate, tartrate, L-dulcitol, L-inositol, ethanol, mannitol, methanol, propanol, L-sorbitol, betaine, lhistidine, glycerol, glycogen, DL-lysine, sarcosine, tryptone, choline, cellulose, chitin, starch or molecular hydrogen (in the absence of elemental sulfur).</s><s>Yeast extract (0.25 g l<sup>-1</sup>) and peptone (0.25 g l<sup>-1</sup>) stimulate organotrophic growth on glucose.</s><s>Yeast extract (0.1 g l<sup>-1</sup>) is required for lithotrophic growth with H<sub>2</sub> and S<sup>0</sup>.</s><s>Elemental sulfur is reduced to H<sub>2</sub>S during, and stimulates, organotrophic growth with glucose, peptone, yeast extract, trypticase and Casamino acids, or lithotrophic growth with molecular hydrogen.</s><s>Sulfate, thiosulfate, nitrate, Fe(III) and sulfite are not reduced and do not stimulate growth.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 54.6 mol%.</s><s>The organism was isolated from a thermophilic cyanobacterial mat from caldera Uzon, Kamchatka, Russia.</s><s>The type strain is Z-9701<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 12556<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>