<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10581_nm.17831" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17831" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.17831" rank="species">Ensifer numidicus</organism><reference id="rid.10581"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Merabet</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martens</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mahdhi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zakhia</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sy</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Le Roux</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Domergue</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coopman</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bekki</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mars</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Willems</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>de Lajudie</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Multilocus sequence analysis of root nodule isolates from Lotus arabicus (Senegal), Lotus creticus, Argyrolobium uniflorum and Medicago sativa (Tunisia) and description of Ensifer numidicus sp. nov. and Ensifer garamanticus sp. nov.</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>664</fpage><lpage>674</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.012088-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19656922</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Ensifer numidicus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Ensifer</em> <em>numidicus</em> (nu.mi′di.cus. L. masc. adj. <em>numidicus</em> pertaining to the country of Numidia, Numidian, the Roman denomination of the region in North Africa from which the majority of the organisms were isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Short, aerobic, Gram-negative, non-spore-forming rods.</s><s>Strains grow on yeast-mannitol medium, on which they form white slightly mucous colonies after 3 days at 28 °C.</s><s>At the molecular level, this species can be differentiated by phylogenetic analysis based on several housekeeping genes (<em>recA</em>, <em>glnA</em>, <em>gltA</em>, <em>thrC</em> and <em>atpD</em>) and 16S rRNA gene sequencing.</s><s>Its phylogenetic neighbours are <em>E. medicae, E. meliloti</em> and <em>E. arboris</em>.</s><s>Detailed phenotypic features for strains of the species are given in Supplementary Table S2.</s><s>Can be distinguished from <em>E. medicae</em>, <em>E. meliloti</em> and <em>E. arboris</em> by the differential use of a combination of growth substrates.</s><s>Does not grow on xylitol or dl-glycerate.</s><s>Results for other substrates were variable between members of this cluster (Cluster A).</s><s>In the API 100 gallery, about 28 substrates are used differently by strains ORS 1444, ORS 1410 and ORS 1407<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The type strain metabolizes only 13 substrates: dulcitol, d-lyxose, 1-<em>O</em>-methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, 3-<em>O</em>-methyl-d-glucopyranose, d-gluconate, l-histidine, succinate, fumarate, ethanolamine, dl-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate, l-aspartate, l-alanine and propionate.</s><s>Strains cannot be identified by biochemical and physiological characters alone.</s><s>Strains are able to nodulate <em>Argyrolobium uniflorum</em> (ORS 1444 and ORS 1407<sup>T</sup>) and <em>Lotus creticus</em> (ORS 1410).</s><s>The sequence of the nodulation gene <em>nodA</em> differs from those of other species of the genus <em>Ensifer</em> but is most closely related to those of the <em>E. meliloti</em> and <em>E. medicae</em> clade.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is ORS 1407<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 24690<sup>T</sup>=CIP 109850<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 62.8 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>A group of 13 <em>Sinorhizobium</em> sp. strains reported by Mahdhi <em>et al.</em> (2008), AB1, AB3, AB5, AB6, AB10, AM1, AM2, AM3, AS1, AS2, AS3, AS4, AS5, may be considered as belonging to <em>Ensifer numidicus</em> and are included as members of this species.</s><s>These strains were isolated independently from <em>Argyrolobium uniflorum</em> in South Tunisia.</s><s>The strains form a homogeneous group by PCR-RFLP of the 16S rRNA gene.</s><s>Three representative strains of this group STM 4034 (=AB1), STM 4036 (=AB3), STM 4039 (=AS1), share identical 16S rRNA gene sequences with strains of <em>E. numidicus</em> as isolated in this study.</s><s>The three latter strains form the most effective symbiosis with <em>Argyrolobium uniflorum</em> and strain STM 4036 is the most efficient.</s><s>The additional strains tolerate pH values of 6–9, 1–2 % (w/v) NaCl and grow at 40 °C, but not at 45 °C.</s><s>They are sensitive to (μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) ampicillin (100) and streptomycin (100), but resistant to kanamycin (100) and nalidixic acid (100).</s></p></content></protolog>