<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6844_nm.979" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.979" rank="genus">Anaplasma</organism><reference id="rid.6844"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dumler</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Barbet</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bekker</surname><given-names>C.P.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dasch</surname><given-names>G.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Palmer</surname><given-names>G.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ray</surname><given-names>S.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rikihisa</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rurangirwa</surname><given-names>F.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reorganization of genera in the families Rickettsiaceae and Anaplasmataceae in the order Rickettsiales: unification of some species of Ehrlichia with Anaplasma, Cowdria with Ehrlichia and Ehrlichia with Neorickettsia, descriptions of six new species combinations and designation of Ehrlichia equi and 'HGE agent' as subjective synonyms of Ehrlichia phagocytophila.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>2145</fpage><lpage>2165</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11760958</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Anaplasma</i> (Theiler 1910) Ristic and Kreier 1984</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>It is proposed that members of the <i>E. phagocytophila</i> group, including <i>E. phagocytophila</i>, <i>E. equi</i>, the HGE agent, as well as <i>E. bovis</i> and <i>E. platys</i>, should be united with the genus <i>Anaplasma</i>. This change requires emendation of the description of the genus <i>Anaplasma</i> (Ristic &#x0026; Kreier, 1984) by integrating it with some descriptions of the genera <i>Ehrlichia</i> and new data for <i>Anaplasma</i> and <i>Ehrlichia</i>, as follows. Gram-negative, small, often pleomorphic, coccoid to ellipsoidal organisms that reside within cytoplasmic vacuoles, either singly and more often in compact inclusions (morulae) present in mature or immature haematopoietic cells, particularly myeloid cells and neutrophils and including erythrocytes, in peripheral blood or in tissues, usually mononuclear phagocyte organs (spleen, liver, bone marrow) of mammalian hosts. By ultrastructure, two morphological forms are observed, including larger reticulate cells and smaller forms with condensed protoplasm called dense-core forms (Popov et al., 1998). Vectors, where known, are ticks. Organisms grow in tick vectors. Non-motile. Not cultivable in cell-free media or chicken embryos. Some species are cultivable in neutrophils, myelomonocytic cell lines, promyelocytic cell lines, erythrocytes and tick cell lines. Aetiological agents of diseases of dogs and other canids, humans and ruminants such as cattle, goats, sheep and llamas. Variably pathogenic or non-pathogenic infections in some ruminants such as cattle, goats, sheep and deer, horses and rodents. The estimated G+C content of the DNA varies between approximately 30 and 56 mol%. The type species is <i>Anaplasma marginale</i> (Theiler, 1910).</s></p></content></protolog>