<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7331_nm.6439" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6439" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6439" rank="species">Nocardia flavorosea</organism><reference id="rid.7331"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chun</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seong</surname><given-names>C.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>S.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hah</surname><given-names>Y.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardia flavorosea sp. nov.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>901</fpage><lpage>905</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-3-901</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9734044</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Nocardia flavorosea</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Nocardia flavorosea</i> (fla.vo.ro’se.a. L. adj. <i>flavus</i> yellow; L. fem. adj. <i>rosea</i> rose-coloured; M.L. adj. <i>flavorosea</i> yellow rose)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, catalase-positive, partially acid-alcohol-fast, non-motile actinomycetes which form an extensively branched substrate mycelium which fragments <i>in situ</i> into rod-shaped to coccoid elements.</s><s>The orange substrate mycelium carries white to pinkish aerial hyphae.</s><s>Colony elevation is convex to irregular and colony margins are filamentous.</s><s>Diffusible pigments are not formed.</s><s>Growth occurs between 25 and 50°C, but not at 10°C.</s><s>Starch is degraded but not adenine, casein, gelatin, tyrosine or xanthine.</s><s>Allantoin, hippuric acid and urea are not hydrolysed and nitrate reductase and phenylalanine deaminase are not produced.</s><s>Acid is formed from dulcitol but not from adonitol, L-arabinose, cellobiose, dextrin, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, meso-inositol, D-lactose, D-maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, D-melezitose, D-melibiose, raffinose, L-rhamnose, salicin, D-sorbitol, sucrose, D-trehalose, xylitol or D-xylose.</s><s>Propionate, pyruvate and succinate are used as sole carbon sources for energy and growth, but benzoate, citrate, gluconate, lactate, mucate and oxalate are not.</s><s>The organism is resistant to bacitracin and penicillin, but sensitive to gentamicin, streptomycin and tobramycin.</s><s>Antibiosis activity is evident against <i>E. coli</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The organism contains major amounts of mycolic acids with 50-56 carbon atoms and 2-4 double bonds (C<sub>50:3</sub>, C<sub>52:2</sub>, C<sub>52:3</sub>, C<sub>52:4</sub> and C<sub>56:3</sub>).</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are hexadecanoic (29% of total fatty acids), octadecenoic (23%), 10-methyloctadecanic (tuberculostearic, 17%) and hexadecenoic (9%) acids.</s><s>The remaining chemical properties of the organism were given earlier.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of strain JCM 3332<sup>T</sup> is 69 mol%, as determined by the thermal denaturation method.</s><s>The type strain is JCM 3332<sup>T</sup> ( =NRRL B-16176<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>This strain was isolated from soil collected in Yunnan Province, China.</s></p></content></protolog>