<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1420_nm.10226" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10226" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10226" rank="species">Paucisalibacillus globulus</organism><reference id="rid.1420"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nunes</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tiago</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pires</surname><given-names>A.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>da Costa</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Veríssimo</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paucisalibacillus globulus gen. nov., sp. nov., a Gram-positive bacterium isolated from potting soil.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1841</fpage><lpage>1845</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64261-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16902018</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paucisalibacillus globulus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paucisalibacillus globulus</em> [glo′bu.lus. L. n. <em>globulus</em> (nominative in apposition) a little ball, a globule, because the bacterium forms colonies that are similar to a little ball, a globule].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exhibits the following characteristics in addition to those described for the genus.</s><s>Cells are 0.5 μm in width by 3.0–7.0 μm in length.</s><s>Oval endospores are formed in a terminal non-swollen sporangium.</s><s>Heterotrophic.</s><s>Colonies are small, smooth, spherical and beige-coloured.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is about 37 °C and no growth occurs at 15 or 45 °C; the optimum pH is between 8.0 and 8.5 and no growth occurs at pH 6.0 or 9.5.</s><s>Grows in 0–8 % NaCl; optimal growth occurs in media containing 1 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Predominant fatty acids are anteiso-15 : 0, anteiso-17 : 0 and iso-15 : 0, which comprise over 90 % of the total fatty acids.</s><s>Hydrolyses casein, starch, DNA, arbutin, aesculin, hippurate, elastin, gelatin and Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80.</s><s>Xylan and urea are not hydrolysed.</s><s>DNase is detected.</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate.</s><s>Assimilates glucose, mannose, galactose, fructose, l-sorbose, d-xylose, sucrose, maltose, lactose, trehalose, l-rhamnose, raffinose, l-fucose, ribitol, xylitol, l-erythritol, mannitol, 2-oxoglutarate, lactate, malate, pyruvate, acetate, l-glutamate, glycine, serine and threonine.</s><s>Does not utilize arabinose, ribose, melezitose, cellobiose, melibiose, sorbitol, arabitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, glycerol, succinate, citrate, aspartate, alanine, asparagine, cysteine, phenylalanine, histidine, isoleucine, lysine, methionine, proline, glutamine, arginine, valine or ornithine.</s><s>Acid is produced from ribose, xylose, glucose, mannose, fructose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, sucrose, starch, glycogen, gentiobiose, turanose, tagatose and 5-ketogluconate, but not from the other substrates in the API 50CH test strips.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is B22<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 108857<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23148<sup>T</sup>), isolated from potting soil.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of strain B22<sup>T</sup> is 37.9 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>