<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7209_nm.4535" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4535" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4535" rank="species">Moorella glycerini</organism><reference id="rid.7209"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Slobodkin</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Reysenbach</surname><given-names>A.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mayer</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wiegel</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Isolation and characterization of the homoacetogenic thermophilic bacterium Moorella glycerini sp. nov.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>969</fpage><lpage>974</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-4-969</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9336894</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Moorella glycerini</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Moorella glycerini</i> (gly.ce.ri'ni. Gr. adj. <i>glykeros</i>, sweet; M.L. adj. <i>glycerini</i>, of glycerol, referring to the utilization of glycerol as a substrate)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Straight rods, 0.4 to 0.6 by 3.0 to 6.5 µm, that form round endospores that are 1.0 to 1.5 µm in diameter in large terminal swollen sporangia (diameter, 2.0 to 2.5 µm).</s><s>Cells stain gram positive.</s><s>Cells occur singly and exhibit slight tumbling motility.</s><s>Anaerobic and thermophilic.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 43 to 65°C, and the optimum temperature is 58°C.</s><s>The pH<sup>60C</sup> range for growth is 5.9 to 7.8, and the optimum pH<sup>60C</sup> is 6.3 to 6.5.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of NaCl concentrations of 0 to 2.0% (wt/vol).</s><s>Able to grow with glycerol as the only organic carbon source; however, yeast extract stimulates growth.</s><s>Utilizes glycerol, glucose, fructose, mannose, galactose, xylose, lactate, glycerate, pyruvate, and yeast extract.</s><s>In the presence of CO<sub>2</sub>, acetate is the only organic product of glycerol and carbohydrate fermentation.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub> production from glucose and glycerol is not observed.</s><s>Not able to grow chemolithotrophically at the expense of H<sub>2</sub>-CO<sub>2</sub>; however, suspensions of cells in the exponential growth phase consume H<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>No growth occurs with sucrose, cellobiose, arabinose, acetate, formate, methanol, ethanol, n-propanol, i-propanol, n-butanol, propionate, acetone, fumarate, succinate, ethylene glycol, 1,2- propanediol, 1,3-propanediol, phenol, benzoate, olive oil, and starch.</s><s>Reduces fumarate to succinate and thiosulfate to elemental sulfur, but does not reduce nitrate, MnO<sub>2</sub>, amorphous Fe(III) oxide, Fe(III) citrate, sulfate, sulfite, or precipitated or sublimed S<sub>0</sub>.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by ampicillin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, rifampin, and tetracycline at a concentration of 100 µg/ml but not by streptomycin.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 54.5 ± 0.4 mol% G + C (as determined by HPLC).</s><s>The habitat is a freshwater hot spring (Calcite Spring area) at Yellowstone National Park, Wyo.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is JW/AS-Y6, which has been deposited in the German Culture Collection as strain DSM 11254.</s></p></content></protolog>