<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4215_nm.7642" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7642" rank="genus">Modestobacter</organism><reference id="rid.4215"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mevs</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gallikowski</surname><given-names>C.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hirsch</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Modestobacter multiseptatus gen. nov., sp. nov., a budding actinomycete from soils of the Asgard Range (Transantarctic Mountains).</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>337</fpage><lpage>346</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10826821</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Modestobacter</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Modestobacter</i> (Mo.des.to.bac'ter. L. adj. modestus modest, humble; bacter the equivalent of Gr. neut. n. baktron a rod or staff;M.L. masc. n.. <i>Modestobacter</i> a rod with modest growth requirements)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive short rods or cocci with a tendency to remain aggregated.</s><s>Cells 1.0-2.8x1.0-3.0 μm, showing cross and longitudinal wall growth and multiplying by budding and swarmer formation.</s><s>Colonies are irregularly shaped, shiny, beige to pink.</s><s>Does not form spores.</s><s>Aerobic heterotroph, growing on oligotrophic medium PYGV or on DSMZ medium 65.</s><s>Growth occurs between 0-5°C and 20-28°C; a psychrophilic strain grows optimally at 11-13°C.</s><s>pH tolerance for survival lies between pH 3-4 and 11-12.</s><s>Positive for catalase, cytochrome oxidase and phosphatase.</s><s>Some strains show restriction endonuclease activity.</s><s>Carbon sources utilized for growth are: D-glucose, D-galactose, lactose, sucrose and mannitol.</s><s>Compounds not hydrolysed are: adenine, hypoxanthine, xanthine, hippurate, cellulose, chitin, dextrin, xylan, arbutin or casein.</s><s>All strains utilize peptone or yeast extract as nitrogen source and reduce nitrate aerobically or anaerobically.</s><s>Ammonia is not formed from arginine, peptone or yeast extract.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not formed from cystine or sulfate.</s><s>Sensitive to lysozyme.</s><s>Major fatty acids are n18:1, i16:0 and ai17:0.</s><s>Major respiratory quinones are MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>) and MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>) ; polar lipids of all isolates are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine and phosphatidylinositol.</s><s>The cell wall contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, glutamate, alanine and glycine as well as galactose, glucose and ribose.</s><s>The type species for the genus is <i>Modestobacter multiseptatus</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>