<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8311_nm.13505" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13505" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13505" rank="species">Paenibacillus castaneae</organism><reference id="rid.8311"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Valverde</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Peix</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rivas</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Veláquez</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Salazar</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Santa-Regina</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rodríguez-Barrueco</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Igual</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus castaneae sp. nov., isolated from the phyllosphere of Castanea sativa Miller.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2560</fpage><lpage>2564</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65663-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18984693</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus castaneae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus castaneae</em> (cas.ta.ne′ae. L. gen. n. <em>castaneae</em> of a chestnut tree).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells of the single isolate of this species (strain Ch-32<sup>T</sup>) are Gram-variable and motile by means of polar and subpolar flagella.</s><s>No chains are formed.</s><s>Ellipsoidal subterminal spores are formed in swollen sporangia.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient agar medium are yellow, round, smooth and convex with approximate diameters of 1–3 mm.</s><s>The only major quinone is MK-7.</s><s>The main fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Negative in tests for anaerobic growth.</s><s>Grows at pH 5.7; optimal pH is 7.</s><s>Grows in 2 % NaCl, but not in 5 % NaCl.</s><s>Optimal growth temperature is 30 °C; unable to grow at 40 °C.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Produces <em>β</em>-galactosidase, but not acetoin, indole, phenylalanine deaminase, urease, arginine dihydrolase, ornithine decarboxylase or lysine decarboxylase.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin, gelatin and cellulose, but not starch or casein.</s><s>In the API 20NE system, positive for assimilation of glucose, l-arabinose, mannose, mannitol, maltose and gluconate, but negative for that of <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, caprate, citrate, adipate, l-malate and phenylacetate.</s><s>Acid, but not gas, is produced from glucose.</s><s>In the API 50CH system, positive for acid production from l-arabinose, d-xylose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, galactose, d-glucose, mannose, l-rhamnose, mannitol, maltose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, raffinose, gentiobiose and turanose, but negative for acid production from glycerol, erythritol, d-ribose, l-xylose, adonitol, fructose, l-sorbose, inositol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, cellobiose, melezitose, glycogen, xylitol, l-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol and l-arabitol.</s><s>Acid production from salicin and lactose is weak.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is Ch-32<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 7279<sup>T</sup>=DSM 19417<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the phyllosphere of chestnut trees growing in the Sierra de Francia region, Salamanca province, Spain.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 46.0 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>