<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10545_nm.17777" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17777" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.17777" rank="species">Aeromonas tecta</organism><reference id="rid.10545"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Demarta</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Küpfer</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Riegel</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Harf-Monteil</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tonolla</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Peduzzi</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Monera</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Saavedra</surname><given-names>M. J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martínez-Murcia</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aeromonas tecta sp. nov., isolated from clinical and environmental sources</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>31</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>278</fpage><lpage>286</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2008.04.005</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Aeromonas tecta</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>A. tecta</em> (tec’ ta. L. fem. adj. <em>tecta</em>, hidden, concealed)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains display the typical characteristics of the genus <em>Aeromonas</em>: Gram-negative, straight, motile rods, cytochrome oxidase-positive, chemoorganotrophic with both oxidative and fermentative metabolisms, catalase-positive and resistance to vibriostatic agent 0/129 (150 μg).</s><s>A brown diffusible pigment is not produced.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 30 °C after 24 h on sheep-blood agar with the production of <em>β</em>-haemolysis.</s><s>Strains do not grow at 42 or 4 °C.</s><s>Acid and gas are produced from glucose.</s><s>Strains are unable to produce indole.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase-positive, ornithine decarboxylase-negative, and Voges–Proskauer are variable (type strain CECT7082<sup>T</sup> positive).</s><s>They can hydrolyze casein, lecithin, arginine-arginine, l-arginine, l-glutamate, l-leucine, l-proline, lysine-alanine, and <em>N</em>-acetyl-glucosaminide.</s><s>Lysine decarboxylase and hydrolysis of aesculin (type strain CECT7082<sup>T</sup> negative), bis-phosphate, glutaryl-glycine-arginine, glycine, glycine-proline, glucoside, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamate, and <em>γ</em>-l-glutamil are variable.</s><s>Strains do not hydrolyze l-tryptophan.</s><s>Acid is produced from arbutin, glycerol, dextrose, d-fructose, d-gluconate, and <em>N</em>-acetyl-glucosamine, but not from d-cellobiose, lactose, l-arabinose, <em>α</em>-methyl-d-glucoside, <em>β</em>-allose, d-melibiose, galacturonic acid, l-rhamnose, maltulose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-galactosamine, saccharose, and sorbitol.</s><s>Acid from salicin is generally produced, whereas acid from d-galactose is usually negative.</s><s>All strains are able to use caprate, d-glucose, d-galactose, glycerol, d-fructose, d-maltose, d-mannose, d-ribose, glycogen, l-histidine, l-proline, l-serine, arbutin, salicin, d-mannitol, d-trehalose, amidon (starch), gentiobiose, potassium gluconate, and <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid but not l-arabinose, d-arabinose, d-sorbitol, l-rhamnose, dl-lactate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, inositol, d-melibiose, d-saccharose, 2-ketogluconate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, 5-ketogluconate, itaconate, l-fucose, d-fucose, malonate, propionate, suberate, erythrol, d-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl-<em>β</em>
d-xylopyranoside, l-sorbitol, dulcitol, methyl-<em>α</em>
d-mannopyranoside, methyl-<em>α</em>
d-glucopyranoside, amygdalin, d-cellobiose, d-lactose, inulin, d-melezitose, d-raffinose, xylitol, d-turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-arabinol, l-arabitol, and valeric acid.</s><s>Growth on l-alanine, l-histidine, acetate, adonitol, citrate, malonate, tiglic acid, and l-xylose are variable.</s><s>Type strain CECT7082<sup>T</sup> is resistant to ampicillin (10 μg), amoxicillin (10 μg), amoxicillin/clavulanic acid (30 μg), ticarcillin (75 μg), ticarcillin/clavulanic acid (85 μg), cephalothin (30 μg), and erythromycin (15 μg), shows intermediate resistance to amikacin (30 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), tobramycin (10 μg) and kanamycin (30 μg), and is sensitive to piperacillin (100 μg), piperacillin/tazobactam (110 μg), cefoxitin (30 μg), cefotaxime (30 μg), cefoperazone (30 μg), ceftazidime (30 μg), ceftriaxone (30 μg), cefepime (30 μg), aztreonam (30 μg), imipenem (10 μg), ciprofloxacin (5 μg), norfloxacin (10 μg), trimethoprim-sulfamethoxazole (25 μg), tetracycline (30 μg), and chloramphenicol (30 μg).</s><s>The type strain is F518<sup>T</sup> (CECT7082<sup>T</sup>, DSM17300<sup>T</sup>, MDC91<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>