<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9465_nm.14605" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14605" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14605" rank="species">Fodinibacter luteus</organism><reference id="rid.9465"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Z.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.-X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>J.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>X.-X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wen</surname><given-names>M.-L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Peng</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>X.-L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Fodinibacter luteus gen. nov., sp. nov., an actinobacterium isolated from a salt mine</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2185</fpage><lpage>2190</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.006882-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19605729</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Fodinibacter luteus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Fodinibacter luteus</em> (lu′te.us. L. masc. adj. <em>luteus</em> orange–yellow, referring to the colony colour).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the morphological, chemotaxonomic and general characteristics described for the genus, cells are 0.3–0.6×0.7–2.2 μm.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–37 °C with an optimum at 28 °C.</s><s>Optimal growth at pH 6.5–7.5.</s><s>NaCl tolerance on GTM agar medium is 2.5 % (w/v).</s><s>Only very weak growth is observed on GTM agar without NaCl.</s><s>Anaerobic growth does not occur on GTM using the GasPak anaerobic system (BBL).</s><s>Acetate, d-galactose, d-glucose, maltose, melibiose and pyruvate are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources, sucrose and trehalose are utilized weakly and l-arabinose, benzoate, cellobiose, citrate, formate, d-fructose, l-glutamate, l-malate, d-mannose, salicin, succinate and d-xylose are not utilized.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, melezitose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, d-sorbitol or trehalose.</s><s>Aesculin, gelatin and Tweens 20, 40 and 80 are hydrolysed, but hypoxanthine, starch, tyrosine and xanthine are not.</s><s>With the API 20E kit (bioMérieux), arginine dihydrolase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase are present, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and urease are absent and H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite (API 20NE).</s><s>In assays with the API ZYM system (bioMérieux), tests positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase C4, esterase lipase C8, lipase C14, leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, cystine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, trypsin and <em>β</em>-galactosidase, but negative for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, fucosidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-galactosidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is YIM C003<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 21208<sup>T</sup> =CCTCC AA 208036<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a sample collected from the wall of a salt mine in Yunnan.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 72.0 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>