<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7120_nm.8058" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8058" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8058" rank="species">Prevotella nigrescens</organism><reference id="rid.7120"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shah</surname><given-names>H.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gharbia</surname><given-names>S.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Biochemical and chemical studies on strains designated Prevotella intermedia and proposal of a new pigmented species, Prevotella nigrescens sp. nov.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>542</fpage><lpage>546</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-42-4-542</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1390107</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Prevotella nigrescens</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Prevotella nigrescens</i> (ni.gres'cens. L. part. adj. <i>nigrescens</i>, becoming black, referring to the characteristic black colonies formed on blood agar plates)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Prevotella nigrescens</i> is a gram-negative, nonsporing, obligately anaerobic, rod-shaped organism.</s><s>Cells grown in broth cultures are 0.3 to 0.7 μm wide by 1 to 2 μm long; some cells may be ca. 6 to 10 μm long.</s><s>Surface colonies after 3 days on horse blood agar are 0.5 to 2 mm in diameter, circular, entire, low convex, smooth, and brown to black.</s><s>Pigmentation commonly occurs around the periphery of the colonies, while the center is cream to dark brown.</s><s>Most colonies exhibit bright red fluorescence under UV radiation (365 nm), particularly toward the less pigmented center of each colony.</s><s>Most strains are weakly hemolytic, but a few are alpha-hemolytic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major fermentation products from a glucose-containing broth are acetic, isobutyric, isovaleric, and succinic acids.</s><s>Dextrin, glucose, maltose, and sucrose are fermented by most strains, while the fermentation of fructose, glycogen, and inulin is variable.</s><s>Indole is produced.</s><s>Starch, but not esculin, is hydrolyzed.</s><s>Gelatin is digested.</s><s>The following commonly used test carbohydrates are not fermented: amygdalin, arabinose, cellobiose, inositol, lactose (two strains have been reported to ferment lactose), mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, trehalose, and xylose.</s><s>Of the constitutive enzymes tested by using the API ZYM system, acid and alkaline phosphatases, phosphoamidase, and p-glucosidase consistently give strong positive reactions.</s><s>Weak reactions occur for butyrate esterase and caprylate esterase lipase.</s><s>α-Fucosidase activity varies among strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Diaminopimelic acid is the only dibasic amino acid present in the peptidoglycan.</s><s>The major pigments produced are protoheme and protoporphyrin.</s><s>Malate and glutamate dehydrogenases are present.</s><s>Glucose-6-phosphate and 6-phosphogluconate dehydrogenases are absent.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acid is 12-methyltetradecanoic acid (anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub>).</s><s>The principal respiratory quinones are unsaturated menaquinones.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 40 to 44 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain ATCC 33563 (=NCTC 9336=VPI 8944=Lambe 729-74) (serogroup C).</s></p></content></protolog>