<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9108_nm.14302" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14302" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14302" rank="species">Mucilaginibacter daejeonensis</organism><reference id="rid.9108"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>An</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yin</surname><given-names>C.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>C.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mucilaginibacter daejeonensis sp. nov., isolated from dried rice straw.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1122</fpage><lpage>1125</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.003384-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19406804</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Mucilaginibacter daejeonensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mucilaginibacter daejeonensis</em> (dae.jeon.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>daejeonensis</em> referring to Daejeon, Korea, the geographical origin of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, facultatively aerobic, non-motile, non-spore-forming and rod-shaped, 0.6–0.8 μm in diameter and 1.3–1.6 μm long after 2 days on R2A agar.</s><s>Colonies are opaque, circular, convex and orange in colour after 2 days on R2A agar.</s><s>On R2A agar, grows at 15–37 °C, but not at 4 or 42 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 4.5–8.5 and with up to 3 % NaCl.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 30 °C, pH 7.0 and without NaCl.</s><s>Substrate utilization, enzyme production and other physiological characteristics are indicated in Table 1.</s><s>In addition to the properties listed in Table 1, l-arabinose and rhamnose are utilized as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Adipate, l-alanine, 4-hydroxybenzoate, caprate, l-fucose, glycogen, histidine, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, inositol, itaconate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, lactate, malonate, phenylacetate, l-proline, d-ribose, l-serine and suberate are not utilized as sole carbon sources.</s><s>In API 50 CH tests, acid is produced from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, aesculin ferric citrate, amygdalin, dl-arabinose, cellobiose, gentiobiose, lactose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-glucopyranoside, starch, sucrose and turanose, but acid is not produced from adonitol, dl-arabitol, arbutin, dulcitol, erythritol, dl-fucose, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, d-lyxose, d-mannitol, melezitose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-xyloside, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate, potassium 5-ketogluconate, raffinose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, salicin, d-tagatose, xylitol or l-xylose.</s><s>According to the API ZYM gallery, positive for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>α</em>-glucosaminidase, acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, cystine arylamidase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, leucine arylamidase and valine arylamidase activities, weakly positive for <em>α</em>-glucosidase and negative for chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-glucuronidase, lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-mannosidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and trypsin.</s><s>According to the API 20NE gallery, positive for arginine dihydrolase, urease, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, protease, <em>α</em>-galactosidase and glucose fermentation, but negative for nitrate reduction.</s><s>The predominant respiratory quinone is MK-7.</s><s>The major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH and summed feature 3 (iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 40.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain Jip 10<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12639<sup>T</sup> =LMG 23488<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from dried rice straw in a field in Daejeon city in South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>