<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2752_nm.9784" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9784" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3422" rank="species">Aggregatibacter aphrophilus</organism><reference id="rid.2752"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nørskov-Lauritsen</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kilian</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Actinobacillus actinomycetemcomitans, Haemophilus aphrophilus, Haemophilus paraphrophilus and Haemophilus segnis as Aggregatibacter actinomycetemcomitans gen. nov., comb. nov., Aggregatibacter aphrophilus comb. nov. and Aggregatibacter segnis comb. nov., and emended description of Aggregatibacter aphrophilus to include V factor-dependent and V factor-independent isolates.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2135</fpage><lpage>2146</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64207-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16957111</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Aggregatibacter aphrophilus</em> (Khairat 1940) comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Aggregatibacter aphrophilus</em> (aph.ro′phi.lus. Gr. n. <em>aphros</em> foam; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. adj. <em>aphrophilus</em> foam loving).</s></p><p class="nomenclature"><s>Basonym: <em>Haemophilus aphrophilus</em> Khairat 1940.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Short, regular rods, 0.5×1.5–1.7 μm, with occasional filamentous forms.</s><s>Colonies on chocolate agar incubated in air supplemented with 5–10 % extra CO<sub>2</sub> are high-convex, granular, yellowish and opaque and reach a diameter of 1.0–1.5 mm within 24 h.</s><s>When plates are incubated without extra CO<sub>2</sub>, the growth is characteristically stunted, with very small colonies interspersed with a few larger colonies.</s><s>Growth in broth is granular, with heavy sediment on the bottom of the tube and adhering colonies on the walls, which are difficult to remove.</s><s>The presence of haemin may enhance growth, but porphyrins are synthesized from <em>δ</em>-aminolaevulinic acid and X factor is not required.</s><s>Some isolates are capable of synthesizing NMN from nicotinamide and 5-phosphoribosyl pyrophosphate (formerly <em>Haemophilus aphrophilus</em>), while others lack a functional nicotinamide phosphoribosyltransferase and are dependent on V factor (formerly <em>Haemophilus paraphrophilus</em>).</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, fructose, lactose, maltose, mannose, sucrose and trehalose, whereas arabinose, cellobiose, mannitol, melibiose, melezitose, salicin, sorbose, sorbitol and xylose are not fermented.</s><s>Variable fermentation is observed with galactose and raffinose.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> is not decomposed; ONPG is hydrolysed.</s><s>Key tests for discrimination between V factor-dependent isolates of <em>Aggregatibacter aphrophilus</em> and strains of <em>H. parainfluenzae</em> biotype V (negative for indole, urease and ornithine decarboxylase) are fermentation of lactose and trehalose.</s></p><p class="description"><s><em>Aggregatibacter aphrophilus</em> is a member of the normal flora of the human oral cavity and pharynx.</s><s>May cause brain abscess and infective endocarditis and has been isolated from various other body sites including peritoneum, pleura, wound and bone.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 42 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is NCTC 5906<sup>T</sup>=ATCC 33389<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 3715<sup>T</sup>=CIP 70.73<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The GenBank accession number of the 16S rRNA gene sequence of the type strain is AY362906.</s></p></content></protolog>