<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5075_nm.7351" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7351" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7351" rank="species">Streptomyces yerevanensis</organism><reference id="rid.5075"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Alderson</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Elytrosporangium brasiliense Falcao de Morais et al., Elytrosporangium carpinense Falcao de Morais et al., Elytrosporangium spirale Falcao de Morais et al., Microellobosporia cinerea Cross et al., Microellobosporia flavea Cross et al., Microellobosporia grisea, Konev et al. Pridham and Microellobosporia violacea, Tsiganov et al. Pridham to the genus Streptomyces, with emended description of the species.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>8</volume><fpage>48</fpage><lpage>54</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptomyces yerevanensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces yerevanensis</i> (ye.re.van.en'sis. M.L. adj. pertaining to Yerevan, Armenia, USSR.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based upon data taken from several sources (Tsyganov et al., 1964; Becker et al., 1965; Zhukova and Tsyganov, 1966; Lechevalier and Lechevalier, 1970 b; Pridham, 1974; Williams et al., 1983; Alderson et al., 1985)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, mesophilic organisms with extensively branched substrate and aerial mycelium.</s><s>Short chains (2 to 8) of smooth surfaced spores borne on both the substrate and aerial mycelium.</s><s>The aerial spore mass is light mouse grey; the reverse colour is violet and the pigment is pH sensitive.</s><s>A violet diffusible pigment, which is also pH sensitive, is produced.</s><s>Does not form melanin pigments.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Adenine, aesculin, arbutin, casein, hypoxanthine, starch, testosterone and tyrosine are degraded but allantoin, chitin, elastin, guanine, lecithin, pectin, urea, xanthine and xylan are not.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Adonitol, L-arabinose, cellobiose, D-fructose, D-glucose, <i>meso</i>-inositol, inulin, D-lactose, mannitol, D-mannose, D-melibiose, D-melezitose, raffinose, L-rhamnose, salicin, sucrose and D-xylose are used as sale carbon sources bur D-galactose, maltose, trehalose and xylitol are not.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Grow on L-arginine, L-histidine, potassium nitrate, L-serine, L-threonine and L-valine, but not on DL-α-aminon- butyric acid, L-cysteine, L-hydroxyproline, L-methionine or L-phenylalanine, as sale nitrogen source.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth occurs at 10 and 37°C but not at 4 or 45°C.</s><s>Tolerant to phenol (0.1%, w/v) and sodium chloride (4%, w/v) but not to sodium azide (0.01 %, w/v).</s><s>Resistant to rifampicin but sensitive to sodium chloride (7%, w/v).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Do not show antimicrobial activity against <i>Aspergillus niger</i> LIV 131, <i>Bacillus subtilis</i> NClB 3610, <i>Candida albicans</i> CBS 562, <i>Escherichia coli</i> NCIB 9132, <i>Micrococcus luteus</i> NCIB 196,  <i>Pseudomonas fluorescens</i> NCJB 9046, <i>Saccharomyces cerevisiae</i> CBS 1171 or <i>Streptomyces murinus</i> ISP 5091.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The peptidoglycan contains LL-diaminopimelic acid as the major diamino acid.</s><s>The organism has a type II phospholipid pattern (Lechevalier er al., 1977) and contains major amounts of tetra-, hexa- and octahydrogenated menaquinones with nine isoprene units (Collins et al., 1984; Alderson et al., 1985).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The mole % G plus C content of the DNA falls within the range 68 to 70 (Tsyganov et al., 1966, 1970; Zhukova and Tsyganov, 1966; Yamaguichi, 1967).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Produces violacin, a pigmented antibiotic of the rhodomycin-cinerubin-mycetin type.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from soil, Armenia, USSR.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: DSM 43167 (= IFO 12517 KCC 3047=NCIB 9589).</s></p></content></protolog>