<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12682_nm.4991" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4991" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4991" rank="species">Bacillus thermoamylovorans</organism><reference id="rid.12682"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Coorevits</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dinsdale</surname><given-names>A.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Halket</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Scheldeman</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heyndrickx</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Van Landschoot</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus thermolactis sp. nov., isolated from dairy farms, and emended description of Bacillus thermoamylovorans</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1954</fpage><lpage>1961</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.024240-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20833876</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Bacillus thermoamylovorans</em></s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus thermoamylovorans</em> (ther.mo.a.my.lo.vo′rans. Gr. adj. <em>thermos</em> hot; Gr. n. <em>amulon</em> starch; L. part. adj. <em>vorans</em> devouring; N.L. part. adj. <em>thermoamylovorans</em> utilizing starch at high temperature).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Facultatively anaerobic, Gram-positive, rod-shaped cells (0.45–0.5×3–4 µm) that occur either singly or in short chains of two to four cells.</s><s>Usually non-motile but some strains are motile.</s><s>After 24 h of incubation at 50 °C on TSA, colonies are circular and cream-coloured, with smooth or irregular edges, and have diameters of 0.5–4 mm; colony surfaces range from smooth or glossy to slightly rough or matt.</s><s>Endospores are formed within 24 h of incubation at 50 °C on TSA containing 5 mg MnSO<sub>4</sub> l<sup>−1</sup>; they are ellipsoidal, lie subterminally, and occasionally swell the cells.</s><s>Growth does not occur at pH 5 but can occur between pH 6 and 9, with the optimum for growth being between pH 7 and 9.</s><s>Growth occurs at 50 °C, but does not occur at 40 or 60 °C.</s><s>Tolerates 2.5 % NaCl but does not tolerate 5 % NaCl (w/v).</s><s>Starch and aesculin are hydrolysed, but casein is not.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase production are positive.</s><s>In the API 20E strip, reactions for gelatin hydrolysis and nitrate reduction are positive.</s><s>Reactions for <em>ortho</em>-nitrophenyl-β-d-galactopyranosidase (ONPG) production and the Voges–Proskauer (acetoin production) test are variable but the latter, when positive, is weak.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, citrate utilization, hydrogen sulphide, indole, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase and urease reactions are negative.</s><s>Acid but no gas is produced from the following carbohydrates in the API 50 CHB gallery: amygdalin, arbutin, trehalose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-glucose, d-mannose, galactose, gentiobiose, glycerol (weak), glycogen, lactose, l-arabinose, maltose, melibiose, methyl d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, ribose, salicin, starch and sucrose.</s><s>Acid production is variable between strains for raffinose, melezitose, d-xylose and methyl d-mannoside.</s><s>Acid is not produced from 2-keto-d-gluconate, 5-keto-d-gluconate, adonitol, d-arabitol, d-fucose, turanose, d-arabinose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, dulcitol, erythritol, gluconate, inulin, l-arabitol, l-fucose, l-sorbose, l-xylose, mannitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, methyl xyloside, rhamnose, sorbitol or xylitol.</s><s>Major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Major polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>MK-7 is the predominant menaquinone and the peptidoglycan type is A1γ.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 37.0±0.2 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from Senegalese palm wine, milking equipment, straw and grass.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LMG 18084<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>In the variable reactions listed above, the type strain has cream-coloured colonies with slightly rough, matt surfaces and irregular edges.</s><s>It is positive for acid production from raffinose, melezitose, d-xylose and methyl d-mannoside although the reactions are very weak; and negative for Voges–Proskauer and ONPG.</s></p></content></protolog>