<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1449_nm.3748" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3748" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3748" rank="species">Byssovorax cruenta</organism><reference id="rid.1449"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Reichenbach</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lang</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Spröer</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Byssovorax cruenta gen. nov., sp. nov., nom. rev., a cellulose-degrading myxobacterium: rediscovery of 'Myxococcus cruentus' Thaxter 1897.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2357</fpage><lpage>2363</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63628-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17012562</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Byssovorax cruenta</em> sp. nov., nom. rev. (<em>ex</em> Thaxter 1897, 409) Reichenbach 2006</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Byssovorax cruenta</em> (cru.en′ta. L. fem. adj. <em>cruenta</em> blood-red).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following attributes in addition to the characteristics of the genus.</s><s>Vegetative cells are rather stout, 0.9–1.1×3.5–7.5 μm, phase dark.</s><s>Pseudoplasmodia are deeply blood-red, of very variable size: fan-like anterior ends are 200–2800 μm wide, tails are 2600–8000 μm long, often branched with several fans.</s><s>The migrating pseudoplasmodia deposit slime trails of a parchment-like texture.</s><s>After many transfers, true swarm colonies with veins may arise.</s><s>The pseudoplasmodia eventually contract into 350–500 μm wide, blood-red rings, 250–600 μm large knobs or cup-shaped structures, around 800 μm wide and 300 μm high.</s><s>Fruiting bodies are produced rarely and consist of large red sporangioles, 80–140 μm in diameter (between 70×90 and 160×190 μm), in flat, sheet-like sori, 200–600 μm in diameter (sometimes more than 1000 μm wide).</s><s>Myxospores resemble vegetative cells in shape, but are stouter, 1.5–1.7×3.3–5 μm, and optically refractile.</s><s>Crystalline cellulose (filter paper) is broken down completely.</s><s>The organism requires a carbohydrate for growth; suitable substrates are cellulose, maltose, l-arabinose, d-xylose, fructose and cellobiose, in order of decreasing suitability.</s><s>Glucose prevents all growth at the low concentration of 0.1 %, even in the presence of cellulose.</s><s>Good nitrogen sources are nitrate, ammonium, urea, Casitone (Difco), Casamino acids and glutamate; slightly elevated concentrations of the organic nitrogen source, namely 0.2 %, may become totally inhibitory.</s><s><em>N</em>-Acetylglucosamine seems to serve (mainly) as an excellent nitrogen source.</s><s>Chitin and starch are degraded, but only chitin allows growth and seems to be used as a carbon and nitrogen source.</s><s>Cellobiose at somewhat higher concentrations (0.2 %) blocks cellulose degradation, as does glucose.</s><s>The organism can be cultivated on yeast (VY/2) agar; the <em>β</em>-glucan of the bakers' yeast cell wall apparently supplies the required carbohydrate.</s><s>Better growth is obtained on filter paper placed on VY/2 agar.</s><s>Grows between 26 and 38 °C; optimum temperature around 30 °C; optimum pH about 7.2.</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 69.9 mol% (by HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, By c2<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 14553<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108850<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil with decaying plant material collected south of Holbrook, AZ, USA.</s><s>It appears to be a very rare organism, or at least to live in places that have only rarely been investigated.</s><s>So far, only two strains, obtained from the same sample, have been isolated in pure culture.</s></p></content></protolog>