<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7935_nm.13029" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13029" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6573" rank="species">Catelliglobosispora koreensis</organism><reference id="rid.7935"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ara</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bakir</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kudo</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Catellatospora koreensis Lee et al. 2000 as Catelliglobosispora koreensis gen. nov., comb. nov. and Catellatospora tsunoense Asano et al. 1989 as Hamadaea tsunoensis gen. nov., comb. nov., and emended description of the genus Catellatospora Asano and Kawamoto 1986 emend. Lee and Hah 2002.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1950</fpage><lpage>1960</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65548-0</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Catelliglobosispora koreensis</em> comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Catelliglobosispora koreensis</em> (ko.re.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>koreensis</em> of Korea, pertaining to soil from Korea from which the organism was isolated).</s></p><p class="nomenclature"><s>Basonym: <em>Catellatospora koreensis</em> Lee <em>et al.</em> 2000.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphological, chemotaxonomic and general characteristics are given above for the genus description.</s><s>The description is based on data taken from previous studies (Lee <em>et al.</em>, 2000) and our own studies.</s><s>Straight, relatively short chains of non-motile spores are borne directly on substrate mycelium.</s><s>Each spore is cylindrical and has a smooth surface.</s><s>Abundant globose bodies are observed on oatmeal agar and ISP medium 4.</s><s>Good growth occurs on ISP medium 3, ISP medium 4, glucose-asparagine agar, glucose-yeast extract agar, Hickey-Tresner agar, yeast extract-starch agar and Bennett agar.</s><s>Moderate growth occurs on yeast extract-malt extract agar, 1/5 yeast extract-starch agar, oatmeal-nitrate agar and poor growth occurs on glycerol-asparagine agar, nutrient agar, ISP medium 7, tap-water agar and sucrose-nitrate agar.</s><s>Melanin pigment production on ISP medium 7 is negative.</s><s>Abundant sporulation occurs on tap-water agar and sucrose-nitrate agar and moderate sporulation occurs on ISP medium 7.</s><s>In general, vegetative mycelia are cream to honey-gold in colour and aerial mycelia are not present.</s><s>Utilizes l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-glucose, d-galactose, d-mannose, maltose, d-fructose, d-xylose, d-lactose, sucrose, starch and raffinose as carbon sources.</s><s>Does not utilize d-arabinose, dextran, gluconate, inulin, melezitose, melibiose, glycerol, erythritol, d-ribose, l-rhamnose, salicin, l-sorbose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>meso</em>-inositol, 2-propanol, propanol, d-mannitol, sorbitol, d-xylitol, adonitol, dulcitol, butanol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, ethanol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside or trehalose.</s><s>Does not degrade adenine, hippurate, hypoxanthine, dl-tyrosine or xanthine.</s><s>Hydrolyses casein, gelatin and starch, but not DNA.</s><s>Grows on 0.001 % brilliant green and 0.0001 % crystal violet.</s><s>No growth in 3 % NaCl and 0.01 % lysozyme.</s><s>Susceptible to novobiocin (50 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), vancomycin (20 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), streptomycin (100 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) and tetracycline (10 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), and resistant to gentamicin (50 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) and neomycin (5 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>).</s><s>Predominant fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (44.5 %), iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (10.8 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 1</sub> (8.6 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (8.5 %), with minor amounts of anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (6.6 %), anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (3.7 %), iso-C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (3.0 %), 2-OH-C<sub>16 : 1</sub> (2.9 %), C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (2.6 %), iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (1.7 %), anteiso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> (1.5 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (1.2 %) and C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (1.2 %).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, LM 042<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 10976<sup>T</sup>=DSM 44566<sup>T</sup>=IMSNU 50729<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil from a gold-mine cave.</s></p></content></protolog>