<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.302_nm.7696" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7696" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7696" rank="species">Bifidobacterium inopinatum</organism><reference id="rid.302"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Crociani</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Biavati</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Alessandrini</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chiarini</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Scardovi</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bifidobacterium inopinatum sp. nov. and Bifidobacterium denticolens sp. nov., two new species isolated from human dental caries.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>564</fpage><lpage>571</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-2-564</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8934909</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bifidobacterium inopinatum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bifidobacterium inopinatum</i> (in.o. pin.a' tum. L. neut. adj. <i>inopinatum</i>, unexpected, referring to the very unusual morphology)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram positive and nonmotile, do not form spores, are very small and coccoid, and occur singly or in pairs; the cells are 0.3 to 0.6 μm long.</s><s>When strains in liquid cultures ferment sugars, such as lactose or raffinose, the cells become longer and more slender, while in the presence of maltose and starch, the cells are much longer and larger with swellings (length, 1.3 to 3.0 μm) (this occurs also on Mann-Rogosa-Sharpe medium and tomato juice agar).</s><s>The homogeneous sediment can be dispersed easily and is never in clumps.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on TPY agar are circular, soft, smooth, convex with unbroken edges, and cream to white.</s><s>There are two types of colonies, T colonies and O colonies.</s><s>The T colonies are made up of cells having a species-specific shape, and the O colonies are made up of longer, slightly irregular rods and rarely contain club-shaped cells.</s><s>When liquid cultures are incubated in air-CO<sub>2</sub> (1:10), the cells obtained from O and T colonies are much longer and more flexuous with wider ends and rare branches (length, 2.0 to 8.0 μm); these cells are very similar to the cells of typical bifidobacteria.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Anaerobic.</s><s>CO<sub>2</sub> enhances anaerobic growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 38.5 to 42°C, the minimum temperature is 27 to 30.5°C, and the maximum temperature is 44°C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 26.5 or 46°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimum initial pH is 6.9 to 7.4, growth is delayed at pH 4.9 or 8.0, and no growth occurs at pH 4.3 or 8.5.</s><s>D-Xylose, D-ribose, glucose, fructose, sucrose, maltose, dextrin, starch, amylose, and amylopectin are fermented.</s><s>L-Arabinose, D-glucosamine, L-rhamnose, mannose, α-D-galacturonate, D-fucose, L-fucose, D-galactosamine, trehalose, cellobiose, gluconate, lactate, xylan, polygalacturonate, alginate, arabinogalactan, pectin, laminarin, D-mannitol, D-glucitol, glycerol, hyaluronate, heparin, chondroitin sulfate, ovomucoid, bovine submaxillary mucin, porcine gastric mucin, gum arabic, gum ghatti, gum guar, gum locust bean, gum karaya, and gum tragacanth are not fermented.</s><s>Galactose is characteristically not fermented by this species.</s><s>Fermentation of melibiose, lactose, salicin, D-glucuronate, melezitose, raffinose, and inulin is variable.</s><s>Only 1 of 31 strains does not ferment dextran.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Produces acetylmethylcarbinol and hydrolyzes asparagine.</s><s>Nitrate reduction, indole, hydrogen sulfide, and catalase or pseudocatalase (hemin) production negative.</s><s>Gelatin is not liquefied; ammonia is not produced from urea or arginine.</s><s>Litmus milk is always acidified and coagulated, The fermentation products from glucose are L-(+) lactic acid and acetic acid at a molar ratio of 1:2.9.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA of this species is not related to the DNA of <i>B. denticolens</i> or the DNA of any other species of the genus <i>Bifidobacterium</i>.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 45±1 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Found in human dental caries.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain B3109 (= DSM 10107).</s></p></content></protolog>