<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4461_nm.6787" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6787" rank="genus">Lechevalieria</organism><reference id="rid.4461"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Labeda</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hatano</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tamura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Revival of the genus Lentzea and proposal for Lechevalieria gen. nov.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1045</fpage><lpage>1050</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11411672</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Lechevalieria</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Lechevalieria</i> (Le.che.val.i.er'i.a. N.L. fem. n. <i>Lechevalieria</i> of Lechevalier, named after the American microbiologists Hubert and Mary Lechevalier, who contributed substantially to the field of actinomycete biology during their careers at the Waksman Institute of Microbiology)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Branching vegetative mycelium (approx. 0.5 μm in diameter) is produced.</s><s>Very scant aerial mycelium is produced on some media.</s><s>Gram-positive.</s><s>Lysozyme-resistant.</s><s>Catalase-positive and aerobic.</s><s>The cell wall is of type III (<i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid).</s><s>The whole-cell sugar pattern consists of galactose, mannose and traces of rhamnose.</s><s>Possesses the type PII phospholipid pattern, with significant quantities of phosphatidyl-ethanolamine lacking hydroxylated fatty acids.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The fatty acid profile consists of saturated and monounsaturated iso and anteiso fatty acids.</s><s>Phylogenetically, the genus represents a line of descent in the <i>Actinosynnemataceae</i> adjacent to the genus <i>Saccharothrix</i> and close to the genera <i>Actinosynnema</i> and <i>Lentzea</i>.</s><s>The sequence of the 16S rRNA gene contains a genus-specific diagnostic nucleotide signature pattern, namely TT (844-845) andGGT(1107-1109).</s><s>The type species is <i>Lechevalieria aerocolonigenes</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>