<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4519_nm.6132" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6132" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6132" rank="species">Leifsonia aurea</organism><reference id="rid.4519"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Reddy</surname><given-names>G.S.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prakash</surname><given-names>J.S.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Srinivas</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsumoto</surname><given-names>G.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shivaji</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Leifsonia rubra sp. nov. and Leifsonia aurea sp. nov., psychrophiles from a pond in Antarctica.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>977</fpage><lpage>984</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02396-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12892114</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Leifsonia aurea</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Leifsonia aurea</em> (au′re.a. L. fem. adj. <em>aurea</em> golden, referring to the yellowish pigment that the bacterium produces).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are yellowish, circular, convex, smooth, butyrous, opaque, yellow-pigmented and 1–2 mm in diameter.</s><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-positive, curved, non-motile rods.</s><s>The pigment is insoluble in water but soluble in methanol and exhibits four characteristic peaks, at 390, 414, 438 and 468 nm.</s><s>Grows between 0 and 30 °C and between pH 6 and 11 and tolerates up to 3 % NaCl.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 22 °C, pH 7 and in the absence of salt.</s><s>Positive for catalase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase, gives a positive result in the Voges–Proskauer test and reduces nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Negative for oxidase, urease, lipase, gelatinase, phosphatase and indole, gives a negative result in the methyl red test, is negative for H<sub>2</sub>S production and does not hydrolyse aesculin or starch.</s><s>Does not produce acid from l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, lactose, d-maltose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, sucrose or d-xylose.</s><s>Does not grow on minimal medium containing l-arabinose, adonitol, ammonium acetate, d-cellobiose, cellulose, creatinine, dextran, dulcitol, glycogen, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, inositol, inulin, lactose, lactic acid, d-maltose, d-mannitol, d-melibiose, melezitol, myristic acid, polyethylene glycol, potassium hydrogen phthalate, d-raffinose, sodium citrate, sodium succinate, sorbitol, sucrose, d-xylose, l-alanine, l-glycine, l-glutamine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-serine, l-tyrosine or l-tryptophan.</s><s>Can grow on erythritol, d-fructose, d-glucose, d-galactose, glucosamine, glycerol, d-mannose, pyruvate, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sodium acetate, d-sorbose, trehalose, l-arginine, l-glutamic acid and l-phenylalanine as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Resistant to colistin, nitrofurantoin, cotrimoxazole, erythromycin, norfloxacin, lincomycin and chloramphenicol and sensitive to novobiocin, cefaperazone, cefazoline, penicillin, kanamycin, cefuroxime, amoxycillin, ciprofloxacin. tobramycin, roxithromycin, vancomycin, cephatoxime, streptomycin, amikacin, ampicillin, tetracycline and rifampicin.</s><s>The peptidoglycan contains dl-diaminobutyric acid as the diamino acid, along with glycine, glutamic acid and alanine, and the cell-wall sugars are galactose, glucose and ribose.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-11.</s><s>Fatty acid methyl esters are listed in Table 2.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 64 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain CMS 81y<sup>T</sup> (=MTCC 4657<sup>T</sup> =DSM 15303<sup>T</sup> =CIP 107785<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>