<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8805_nm.13093" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13093" rank="genus">Goodfellowiella</organism><reference id="rid.8805"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Labeda</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Euzéby</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of Goodfellowiella gen. nov. to replace the illegitimate genus name Goodfellowia Labeda and Kroppenstedt 2006.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1047</fpage><lpage>1048</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.2008/000299-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18398217</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Goodfellowiella</em> Labeda, Kroppenstedt, Euzéby and Tindall gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Goodfellowiella</em> (Good.fel.lo.wi.el′la. N.L. fem. dim. n. <em>Goodfellowiella</em> named for Michael Goodfellow, a microbiologist at the University of Newcastle, in recognition of his contributions to microbial systematics).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Previous illegitimate name: <em>Goodfellowia</em> Labeda and Kroppenstedt 2006.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Gram-positive, non-acid-fast, non-motile actinomycetes.</s><s>Branched substrate mycelium (approx. 0.5 μm in diameter) and, on some media, aerial mycelia are produced.</s><s>Ovoid conidia are produced by fragmentation of substrate mycelium.</s><s>Catalase-positive.</s><s>Contain <em>meso-</em>diaminopimelic acid as the diamino acid.</s><s>The whole-cell sugar pattern consists of galactose and ribose.</s><s>The phospholipid pattern consists of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylethanolamine containing hydroxylated fatty acids and traces of phosphatidylinositol and phosphatidylinositol mannosides.</s><s>The predominant menaquinones are MK-9(II,III-H<sub>4</sub>) and MK-10(H<sub>4</sub>) in almost equal portions (see Table 2 in Labeda &#x0026; Kroppenstedt, 2006 and Kroppenstedt <em>et al.</em>, 1990).</s><s>Have a fatty-acid profile rich in branched-chain (iso-hexadecanoic and anteiso-heptadecanoic fatty acids predominate) and saturated components including 10-methyl-branched heptadecanoic acid and 2-hydroxy anteiso heptadecanoic and 2-hydroxy hexadecanoic fatty acids (see Table 3 in Labeda &#x0026; Kroppenstedt, 2006 for details).</s><s>Phylogenetically nearest neighbour is the genus <em>Actinoalloteichus</em>.</s><s>The type species is <em>Goodfellowiella coeruleoviolacea</em> (Preobrazhenskaya and Terekhova 1987) Labeda, Kroppenstedt, Euzéby and Tindall.</s></p></content></protolog>