<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6383_nm.3699" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3699" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3699" rank="species">Cystobacter gracilis</organism><reference id="rid.6383"><citation citation-type="book"><authors><person-name><surname>Reichenbach</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><editors><person-name><surname>Garrity</surname><given-names>G.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Krieg</surname><given-names>N.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Staley</surname><given-names>J.T.</given-names></person-name></editors><article-title>Genus I. Cystobacter Schroeter 1886, 170AL.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>2, Part C</volume><edition>2</edition><fpage>1086</fpage><lpage>1096</lpage><source id="530">Bergey's Manual of Systematic Bacteriology</source><publisher-name>Springer</publisher-name><publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc><isbn>0387241450</isbn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Cystobacter gracilis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Cystobacter gracilis</i> (gra'ci.lis. L. adj. <i>gracilis</i> slim, slight)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Vegetative cells (Fig. BXII.δ.73) are rather short, delicate rods with tapering ends, 0.5–0.6x3–5 μm.</s><s>Swarm colonies with a thin, tough, locally delicate plicated slime sheet and fine radial veins, more or less red-brown and even violet, sometimes intensely so.</s><s>On peptone (CY-) agar the swarms spread only reluctantly and produce an intense, red-brown, diffusing pigment.</s><s>Fruiting bodies (Fig. BXII.δ.74) orange-brown to dark red-brown; sporangioles more or less spherical, 30–80 lm in diameter.</s><s>However, in cultures, degenerate fruiting bodies in the shape of short to moderately long, thin to somewhat broadened ridges and cushion-like, bulging masses are the rule.</s><s>Myxospores are short, relatively slender, sometimes comma-shaped rods with rounded ends to almost spherical, small, 0.8–1.4 x 1–3 μm, optically refractile.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Of the proteolytic–bacteriolytic nutritional type.</s><s>Does not attack chitin and cellulose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The outstanding characteristics of this species are the short, delicate vegetative cells and rather small myxospores.</s><s>Also typical is the thin but very tough slime sheet with very fine radial veins. <i>Cystobacter gracilis</i> probably represents a genus of its own in a complex of strains that may contain even more species.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Cystobacter gracilis</i> is found in the usual myxobacterial habitats; it is moderately common.</s><s>Strain Cb g1 was isolated in 1996 from a soil sample with decaying plant material collected in the same year near Beni-Suef, Egypt, by Dr.</s><s>Mohamed Khalil.</s><s>The origins of the reference strains are as follows: Cb g2 was isolated in 1996 from a similar sample collected in 1996 near Giza, Egypt; Cb g13 was isolated in 1997 from soil with rabbit dung collected in 1996 near Benson, Arizona, USA; Cb g30 was isolated in 1998 from rotting wood collected in 1998 in the Alsace, France.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The mol% G+C of the DNA is: not determined.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: Cb g1, DSM 14753, JCM 12625.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Additional Remarks: Reference strains include DSM 14771 (Cb g2), DSM 14754 (Cb g13), DSM 14755 (Cb g30).</s></p></content></protolog>