<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8583_nm.13359" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13359" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13359" rank="species">Halorhabdus tiamatea</organism><reference id="rid.8583"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Antunes</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Taborda</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huber</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moissl</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nobre</surname><given-names>M.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>da Costa</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halorhabdus tiamatea sp. nov., a non-pigmented, extremely halophilic archaeon from a deep-sea, hypersaline anoxic basin of the Red Sea, and emended description of the genus Halorhabdus.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>215</fpage><lpage>220</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65316-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18175711</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Halorhabdus tiamatea</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Halorhabdus tiamatea</em> (ti.a.ma.te′a. N.L. fem. adj. <em>tiamatea</em> belonging to, or related to, Tiamat, the ancient Mesopotamian goddess of ‘the primal abyss’ and salty water).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, pleomorphic cells ranging from rods to coccoid or irregular forms (0.5–1×1–8 μm).</s><s>Flagella are not observed.</s><s>Colonies on HBM agar are round, non-pigmented and 2–3 mm in diameter.</s><s>Extremely halophilic: growth occurs at NaCl concentrations between 10 and 30 % (w/v), with optimum growth occurring at approximately 27 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs with MgSO<sub>4</sub> . 7H<sub>2</sub>O at 0–25 % (w/v).</s><s>The temperature range for growth is between 15 and 55 °C (optimal temperature, 45 °C) and the pH range is between approximately 5.5 and 8.5 (optimal pH, 6.5–7.0).</s><s>Grows under anaerobic and microaerophilic conditions; shows extremely poor aerobic growth.</s><s>Produces acid from maltose and yeast extract.</s><s>Oxidase-negative and catalase-positive.</s><s>Methyl red test is positive and Voges–Proskauer test is negative.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate is produced.</s><s>Gelatin and aesculin are hydrolysed; starch is weakly hydrolysed.</s><s>Casein and Tween 80 are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Maltose and yeast extract are used for growth.</s><s>Glucose, xylose, fructose, galactose, and proline are weakly assimilated.</s><s>Amylose, l-arabinose, lactose, sucrose, sodium acetate, sodium citrate, sodium formate, sodium glucuronate, sodium lactate, sodium pyruvate, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, alanine, betaine, lysine, phenylalanine, serine, acetamide, ethanol, glycerol, methanol, sorbitol, glycogen and peptone are not utilized.</s><s><em>α</em>-Glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase are present.</s><s>Weak reactions also detected for <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>β</em>-glucuronidase.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are not detected.</s><s>Cells are resistant to ampicillin, cephalosporin C, chloramphenicol (25 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), erythromycin, neomycin, penicillin G and tetracycline, but susceptible to anisomycin, aphidicolin, bacitracin, chloramphenicol (50 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), novobiocin and rifamycin B.</s><s>The ether lipids are diphytanyl derivatives.</s><s>MK-8(VIII-H<sub>2</sub>) is the only respiratory lipoquinone present.</s><s>The major polar lipids present are phosphatidylglycerol, methylated phosphatidylglycerophosphate, triglycosyl diether, sulfated diglycosyl diether and an unknown component.</s><s>Phosphatidylglycerosulfate is absent.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 61.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SARL4B<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 18392<sup>T</sup>=JCM 14471<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the brine–sediment interface of the Shaban Deep in the Red Sea.</s></p></content></protolog>