<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5519_nm.9823" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9823" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9823" rank="species">Actinomadura hallensis</organism><reference id="rid.5519"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeong</surname><given-names>H.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinomadura hallensis sp. nov., a novel actinomycete isolated from Mt. Halla in Korea.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>259</fpage><lpage>264</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63943-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16403895</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Actinomadura hallensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Actinomadura hallensis</em> (hall.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>hallensis</em> of Mt. Halla, Jeju Island, Republic of Korea, the origin of the soil sample from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive.</s><s>Catalase-positive.</s><s>Urease-negative.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced.</s><s>Good growth on ISP 2, ISP 3 and ISP 4 media.</s><s>Forms a well-developed, non-fragmenting substrate mycelium that is blackish purple on ISP 2 medium, moderate brown on ISP 3 medium and greyish reddish purple on ISP 4 medium.</s><s>A dark-brown-coloured pigment is produced on ISP 2 medium.</s><s>On ISP 3 and ISP 4 media, a moderate amount of white aerial mycelia is formed, which matures into short spore chains in hooks or spirals.</s><s>The spore surface is warty.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 20–45 °C.</s><s>The optimum pH for growth is 7·0.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-glucose, glycerol, maltose, d-mannitol, salicin, sucrose, d-trehalose and d-xylose.</s><s>Decomposes casein, DNA, aesculin, gelatin and starch.</s><s>No acid is produced from adonitol, 2,3-butanediol, dulcitol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, d-galactose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-lactose, d-mannose, d-melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, 1,2-propanediol, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose or d-xylitol.</s><s>Does not decompose hypoxanthine, tyrosine, Tween 80 or xanthine.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 3 % NaCl.</s><s>Type III/B cell wall (<em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic is the diagnostic diamino acid and madurose is the characteristic sugar).</s><s>The acyl group of the muramic acid is of the acetyl type.</s><s>The predominant menaquinones are MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>8</sub>), with a minor amount of MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>Type PI phospholipid pattern (no diagnostic phospholipid).</s><s>Mycolic acids are absent.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are hexadecanoic acid (C<sub>16 : 0</sub>) and tuberculostearic acid (C<sub>18 : 0</sub>, 10-methyl).</s><s>Significant amounts of saturated, unsaturated and anteiso-branched fatty acids are also present.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA (determined by HPLC) is 67·5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is H647-1<sup>T</sup> (=IMSNU 50760<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 9992<sup>T</sup>=KCCM 42245<sup>T</sup>=NRRL B-24436<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a soil sample from Mt. Halla, Jeju Island, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>