<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.721_nm.7811" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7811" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7811" rank="species">Spirochaeta thermophila</organism><reference id="rid.721"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Aksenova</surname><given-names>H.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Janssen</surname><given-names>P.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zavarzin</surname><given-names>G.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Morgan</surname><given-names>H.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Spirochaeta thermophila sp. nov., an obligately anaerobic polysaccharolytic, extremely thermophilic bacterium.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>175</fpage><lpage>177</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Spirochaeta thennophila</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Spirochaeta thermophila</i> (ther.mo'phi.la. Gr. n. <i>therme</i>, heat; Gr. adj. <i>phila</i>, loving; M. L. adj. <i>thermophila</i>,heat-loving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Single helical cells are 0.2 to 0.25 by 16 to 50 µm.</s><s>Negative Gram stain reaction.</s><s>No lysis of the cells occurs in 3% KOH.</s><s>An outer sheath encloses a protoplasmic cylinder; two periplasmic flagella are present in a 1-2-1 arrangement and are subterminally anchored by an insertion disc.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic chemoorganotroph.</s><s>The temperature range for the type strain is 40 to 73°C (optimum, 66 to 68°C).</s><s>The pH range for the type strain is 5.9 to 7.7 (optimum, 7.5).</s><s>The NaCl concentration range for the type strain is 0.5 to 4.5% (optimum, 1.5%) (doubling time, 70 min).</s><s>The temperature, pH, and salinity parameters vary for different strains, reflecting the environmental conditions prevailing at the sites of isolation.</s><s>No reduction of fumarate, nitrate, oxygen, sulfate, or sulfur occurs.</s><s>Utilizes various mono-, di-, and polysaccharides but not sugar alcohols, organic acids, or amino acids.</s><s>Inhibited by penicillin, neomycin, erythromycin, tetracycline, polymyxin B, and novobiocin but resistant to rifampin and streptomycin.</s><s>The fermentation end products from glucose are acetate, carbon dioxide, hydrogen, and lactate.</s><s>Glucose is fermented via the Embden-Meyerhof-Parnas pathway, involving a pyrophosphate-dependent phosphofructokinase.</s><s>Ethanol and succinate are not produced.</s><s>Indole is not formed; urea is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Sulfide is not produced from cysteine, and esculin is hydrolyzed.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 52 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s><s>Type strain Z-1203 (= DSM 6578) was isolated from a marine hot spring near the beach on Shiashkotan Island, Soviet Far East, USSR.</s></p></content></protolog>