<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7456_nm.2110" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2110" rank="genus">Pfennigia</organism><reference id="rid.7456"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic note: transfer of Amoebobacter purpureus to the genus Pfennigia gen. nov., as Pfennigia purpurea comb. nov., on the basis of the illegitimate proposal to make Amoebobacter purpureus the type species of the genus Amoebobacter.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1307</fpage><lpage>1308</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pfennigia</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pfennigia</i> (Pfen.nig'ia. M.L. ending -<i>ia</i>; M.L. fem. n. <i>Pfennigia</i> named after Norbert Pfennig, in recognition of his contribution to the biology and taxonomy of anoxygenic phototrophic bacteria)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile and oval to spherical, 1.9-3.8 x 2.0-4.5 μm.</s><s>Large aggregates of cells (up to 40) may be formed.</s><s>Growth may be photolithotrophic under anoxic conditions in the light, or chemoautotrophic under micro-oxic conditions in the dark.</s><s>Electron donors used are sulphide, thiosulphate or elemental sulphur.</s><s>During the oxidation of sulphide or thiosulphate to sulphate globules of elemental sulphur appear inside the cells.</s><s>May not be capable of assimilatory sulphate reduction.</s><s>Intracellular photosynthetic membranes are of the vesicular type.</s><s>The major photosynthetic pigments are bacteriochlorophyll a and the carotenoid okenone.</s><s>The G + C content of the DNA is 63.4-64.1 mol% (buoyant density). 16s rDNA sequence analysis indicates that this genus is a member of the <i>Thiocapsa-Thiolamprovum</i> phyletic group within the γ-subclass of the <i>Proteobacteria</i>.</s><s>The type species of the genus <i>Pfennigia</i> is <i>Pfennigia purpurea</i> comb. nov.</s></p></content></protolog>