<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3634_nm.787" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.787" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.787" rank="species">Chlorobium phaeovibrioides</organism><reference id="rid.3634"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic taxonomy of the family Chlorobiaceae on the basis of 16S rRNA and fmo (Fenna-Matthews-Olson protein) gene sequences.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>941</fpage><lpage>951</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02403-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12892110</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Chlorobium phaeovibrioides</em></s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>The species description is as given by Pfennig &#x0026; Overmann (2001a), with the following modifications.</s><s>Cells are curved rods or vibrioid, 0·3–0·7 μm wide, non-motile and occur as single cells.</s><s>Colour of cell suspensions is green or brown, and photosynthetic pigments are BChl <em>d</em> (occasionally also BChl <em>c</em>) with chlorobactene as the major carotenoid in green strains, and BChl <em>e</em> with isorenieratene as the major carotenoid in brown strains.</s><s>Photoautotrophic growth occurs with sulfide and sulfur as photosynthetic electron donors; thiosulfate may be used by some strains.</s><s>In the presence of sulfide and bicarbonate, some simple organic compounds are photoassimilated.</s><s>Vitamin B<sub>12</sub> is required for growth.</s><s>Brackish water and marine bacteria that require at least 1 % NaCl.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 52–53·5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is DSM 269<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The GenBank/EMBL accession number for the 16S rDNA sequence of the type strain is Y08105.</s></p><p class="nomenclature"><s>This species is a representative of group 2, according to Alexander <em>et al.</em> (2002).</s><s>The type strain of <em>Chlorobium phaeovibrioides</em>, DSM 269<sup>T</sup>, forms a distinct phylogenetic lineage which allows its recognition as a separate species.</s><s>Almost-identical sequences of the 16S rRNA and <em>fmo</em> genes, salt requirement, similar fatty acid composition and DNA G+C contents of 52·0–53·5 mol% strongly support the inclusion of <em>Chlorobium phaeovibrioides</em> DSM 270, <em>Chlorobium vibrioforme</em> DSM 261 and <em>Chlorobium vibrioforme</em> subsp. <em>thiosulfatophilum</em> DSM 265 into this species.</s><s>Strain DSM 265, which was previously considered as the type strain of <em>Chlorobium vibrioforme</em> subsp. <em>thiosulfatophilum</em>, loses type strain status and the name becomes a synonym of <em>Chlorobium phaeovibrioides</em>.</s><s>Other strains of this subspecies must be assigned to different species (see below).</s><s>It is particularly striking that the four strains now classified as <em>Chlorobium phaeovibrioides</em> were previously assigned to four different species and subspecies.</s><s>Further studies are needed to prove the taxonomic status of <em>Chlorobium phaeovibrioides</em> UdG 6035, which is related to this species.</s></p></content></protolog>