<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2770_nm.1117" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1117" rank="genus">Rhodothalassium</organism><reference id="rid.2770"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Petri</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Süling</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of species of the spiral-shaped phototrophic purple non-sulfur bacteria of the alpha-Proteobacteria: description of the new genera Phaeospirillum gen. nov., Rhodovibrio gen. nov., Rhodothalassium gen. nov. and Roseospira gen. nov. as well as transfer of Rhodospirillum fulvum to Phaeospirillum fulvum comb. nov., of Rhodospirillum molischianum to Phaeospirillum molischianum comb. nov., of Rhodospirillum salinarum to Rhodovibrio salexigens.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>793</fpage><lpage>798</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-3-793</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9734033</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhodothalassium</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhodothalassium</i> (Rho. do. t ha. las'si. um. Gr . n. <i>rhodon</i> the rose; Gr. adj. <i>thalassios</i> belonging to the sea; M.L. neut. n. <i>Rhodothalassium</i> the rose belonging to the sea)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are vibrioid- to spiral-shaped, 0.5-1.0 μm wide, motile by means of polar flagella, multiply by binary fission and are Gram-negative.</s><s>They belong to the α-<i>Proteobacteria</i> and have a G + C content between 63 and 66 mol%.</s><s>In tracytoplasmic photosynthetic membranes are present as lamellar stacks.</s><s>Contain bacteriochlorophyll a and various carotenoids as photosynthetic pigments.</s><s>Contain ubiquinones and menaquinones Q-10 and MK-10 as major components.</s><s>Halophilic bacteria that require NaCl or sea salt for growth.</s><s>Have salt optima above sea water salinity and tolerate up to 20 % or more total salts.</s><s>Growth occurs preferably photo-organotrophically under anoxic conditions in the light, but is also possible under microoxic to oxic conditions in the dark.</s><s>Amino acids may be required as growth factors.</s><s>The type species is <i>Rhodothalassium salexigens</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>