<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4362_nm.1532" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1532" rank="genus">Angulomicrobium</organism><reference id="rid.4362"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vasil'eva</surname><given-names>L.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lafitskaia</surname><given-names>T.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Namsaraev</surname><given-names>B.B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Angulomicrobium tetraedrale, a new genus of budding bacteria with radial cell symmetry.</article-title><year>1979</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>1033</fpage><lpage>1039</lpage><source id="130">Mikrobiologiia</source><issn>0026-3656</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">530132</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Angulomicrobium</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Angulomicrobium</i> (<i>angularis</i>, from the Latin for angled, <i>micros</i> from the Greek for small, <i>bios</i>, from the Greek for life. <i>Angulomicrobium</i> is thus an angular microbe.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The genus <i>Angulomicrobium</i> includes unicellular, Gram-negative, budding, polygonal bacteria.</s><s>It is monotypic.</s><s>The description of the genus is the same as for the species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type species <i>Angulomicrobium tetraedrale</i> sp. nov ("mushroom-shaped bacterium," Whittenbury am Nicoll, 1971; "tetrahedron," Namsaraev and Zavarzin, 1972).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Tetraedralis is from the Greek for tetrahedral.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are Gram-negative, single or paired (1.1 x 1.5 μm; for strain 1109 - 0.95 x 1.2 μm).</s><s>They have radial symmetry, which is tetrahedral in the type strain, and flat in strain 1109.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells reproduce by budding, with the formation of a sessile bud at the apex of the tetrahedron (triangle).</s><s>Mother and daughter cells are identical in shape and size.</s><s>The intracytoplasmic membrane system is poorly developed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The colonies are white, circular, and slimy, with a pearly luster.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemoorganotrophs.</s><s>Carbohydrates, amino acids, organic acids, and alcohols are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources (see Table 1).</s><s>Sugars are broken down by the Entner-Doudoroff pathway and the type strain also has the enzymes of the fructose-diphosphate pathway.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain will grow on mineral medium with glucose as the sole carbon source.</s><s>Other strains require the addition of 0.02% yeast extract, which cannot be replaced by a mixture of vitamins of the B or by casamino acids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, catalase and oxidase positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Temperature range 15-35°C, optimal growth at 28-30°.</s><s>Optimal pH - 6.8-7.0.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Antibiotic sensitivity (μg/ml) of the type strain and strain 1109 as follows (respectively): penicillin G, 30 and 100; chloramphenicol-100 and 0.5; erythromycin - 10 and 30; actinomycin D - 5.0 and 8.0; polymyxin M - 50 and 10.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA composition of type strain: G+C 64.5 mol. % (68.2 mol. % according to other determinations.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from bog soils in the Moscow region.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain Z-2821 (All-Union Culture Collection B-1335) also strain 1109 (All-union Culture Collection of Sciences B-1336).</s><s>The cultures are maintained in the Soil Microbiology Section of the Microbiology Institute, Academy of Sciences of the USSR.</s></p></content></protolog>