<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5416_nm.3626" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3626" rank="genus">Desulfuromusa</organism><reference id="rid.5416"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Liesack</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Finster</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic Analysis of Five Strains of Gram-Negative, Obligately Anaerobic, Sulfur-Reducing Bacteria and Description of Desulfuromusa gen. nov., Including Desulfuromusa kysingii sp. nov., Desulfuromusa bakii sp. nov., and Desulfuromusa succinoxidans sp. nov.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>753</fpage><lpage>758</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-4-753</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Desulfuromusa</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Desulfuromusa</i> (De.sul.fu.ro.mu'sa. L. pref. <i>de</i>, from; L. n. <i>sulfur</i>, sulfur; M.L.n. <i>musa</i>, banana; M.L.f. n. <i>Desulfuromusa</i>, a banana-shaped bacterium that reduces sulfur)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are motile and slightly curved or rod shaped; they stain gram negative and are obligately anaerobic.</s><s>They do not form spores.</s><s>Elemental sulfur is used as an electron acceptor and is reduced to hydrogen sulfide.</s><s>No growth occurs when either sulfate, sulfite, thiosulfate, tetrathionate, trimethylammonium oxide, cystine, oxidized glutathione, N<sub>2</sub>O, or oxygen is added as an electron acceptor.</s><s>Growth occurs with fumarate or malate as the sole substrate.</s><s>Short-chain fatty acids, dicarboxylic acids, and amino acids are used as electron donors and are oxidized completely to CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Alcohols and sugars are not utilized.</s><s>Growth occurs with elemental sulfur; in liquid medium the bacteria are closely attached to elemental sulfur, which is used as an electron acceptor.</s><s>In agar medium the strains form whitish filamentous colonies.</s><s>Growth with fumarate as the sole substrate: the generation times with fumarate are generally shorter than the generation times with elemental sulfur.</s><s>In agar medium the peach-colored colonies are lens shaped and have entire edges.</s><s>Phylogenetically, the genus belongs to a lineage of the delta subclass of the <i>Proteobacteria</i> characterized by members of the genera <i>Desulfurumonas</i> and <i>Pelobacter</i>.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type species is 47 mol%.</s><s>The type species is <i>Desulfuromusa kysingii</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On the basis of DNA-DNA relatedness data and phenotypic characteristics, three different species of the genus <i>Desulfuromusa</i> are described below.</s></p></content></protolog>