<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2869_nm.2307" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2307" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2307" rank="subspecies">Francisella tularensis mediasiatica</organism><reference id="rid.2869"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Olsufjev</surname><given-names>N.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Meshcheryakova</surname><given-names>I.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Subspecific taxonomy of Francisella tularensis McCoy and Chapin 1912</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>872</fpage><lpage>874</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-4-872</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Francisella tularensis</i> subsp. <i>mediasiatica</i> (Aikimbaev) Olsufjev and Meshcheryakova 1982, 296, supsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Francisella tularensis</i> subsp. <i>mediasiatica</i> (med.i.as.i.at'i.ca. Gr. adj. <i>media</i> middle; Gr. adj. <i>asiatica</i> asian; Gr. M. L. adj. <i>mediasiatica</i> pertaining to mid-Asia)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>F . tularensis</i> subsp. <i>mediasiatica</i> was originally described by Aikimbaev (1) and was found in the middle Asian region of the USSR.</s><s>The morphology and principle characteristics of this subspecies are in accord with the species description (11).</s><s>This subspecies ferments glycerol and citrulline but shows weak fermentation of glucose and maltose, which is revealed by the Rodionova method (based on a determination of dehydrogenases).</s><s>This subspecies is highly susceptible to erythromycin and other macrolide antibiotics and to lincomycin.</s><s>Like the holarctic subspecies, it is moderately pathogenic for domestic rabbits and humans.</s><s>A study of fatty acid composition has revealed the lowest quantity of C<sub>14:0</sub> acid (4.2 to 4.5%) and, like the nearctic subspecies, the highest quantity of C<sub>14:0</sub> acid (12 to 16%), as determined by gas-liquid chromatography.</s><s>It is distributed only in central asian USSR (in the deltas and valleys of the Amu-Darya, Ili, and Tshu rivers).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Distribution of this causative agent of tularemia in nature is mediated mostly by <i>Lepus</i> and <i>Gerbillinae</i>. as well as by ticks.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain GIEM 543, was isolated from <i>Pallasiomys meridianus</i> Pall. by G.</s><s>M.</s><s>Kunitsa in 1965 in the Alma-Ata region, USSR.</s></p></content></protolog>