<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6159_nm.8349" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8349" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8349" rank="subspecies">Fusobacterium nucleatum animalis</organism><reference id="rid.6159"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gharbia</surname><given-names>S.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shah</surname><given-names>H.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Fusobacterium nucleatum subsp. fusiforme subsp. nov. and Fusobacterium nucleatum subsp. animalis subsp. nov. as additional subspecies whithin Fusobacterium nucleatum.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>296</fpage><lpage>298</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Fusobacterium nucleatum</i> subsp. <i>animalis</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Fusobacterium nucleatum</i> subsp. <i>animalis</i> (a.ni.ma'lis. L. n. <i>animal</i>, animal; <i>animalis</i>, of an animal)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Anaerobic.</s><s>Cells are nonmotile rods that occasionally form filaments which are up to 25 μm long.</s><s>Colonies on blood agar are round, smooth, glistening, convex, translucent white, and 1.0 to 2.0 μm in diameter.</s><s>Growth is markedly affected by the addition of Trypticase, protease peptone, and Bacto Casitone (Difco).</s><s>Few amino acids (mainly histidine, arginine, cysteine, and, to a lesser extent, glutamate) are utilized.</s><s>The terminal pH in a glucose liquid medium ranges between 6.8 and 7.0.</s><s>Both GDH and OGR are present and exhibit fast electrophoretic mobilities (3.2 and 3.8 cm, respectively).</s><s>Low levels of H<sub>2</sub>S are produced, and growth is not affected by the addition of 20% bile.</s><s>Strains are morphologically similar to <i>F. nucleatum</i> subsp. <i>polymorphum</i>, but the level of DNA-DNA homology between these two subspecies ranges between 60 and 67%.</s><s>All strains possess the constitutive enzymes leucine aminopeptidase and gamma-glutamyl aminopeptidase.</s><s>Serinevaline aminopeptidase and proline aminopeptidase are not produced.</s><s>Glycosidases are absent.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan contains <i>meso</i>-lanthionine as its diamino acid.</s><s>Possesses straight-chain monounsaturated, and hydroxylated long-chain fatty acids but not methylbranched acids.</s><s>Tetradecanoic acid (C<sub>14:0</sub>; ca. 24 to 30%) and hexadecanoic acid (C<sub>16:0</sub>; 20 to 26%) are the major nonhydroxylated acids.</s><s>The major hydroxylated fatty acids are 3-hydroxytetradecanoic acid (3OH-C<sub>14:0</sub>; ca. 12 to 18%) and 3-hydroxyhexadecanoic acid (3OH-C<sub>16:0</sub>; ca. 4 to 7%).</s><s>The DNA base composition is 26 to 28 mol% G+C, as determined by the thermal denaturation method.</s><s>The type strain is strain NCTC 12276.</s></p></content></protolog>