<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8301_nm.13683" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13683" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13683" rank="species">Acanthopleuribacter pedis</organism><reference id="rid.8301"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Fukunaga</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kurahashi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yanagi</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Harayama</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Acanthopleuribacter pedis gen. nov., sp. nov., a marine bacterium isolated from a chiton, and description of Acanthopleuribacteraceae fam. nov., Acanthopleuribacterales ord. nov., Holophagaceae fam. nov., Holophagales ord. nov. and Holophagae classis nov. in the phylum 'Acidobacteria'.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2597</fpage><lpage>2601</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65589-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18984699</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Acanthopleuribacter pedis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Acanthopleuribacter pedis</em> (pe′dis. L. gen. n. <em>pedis</em> of the foot, referring to the isolation of the type strain from the foot of a chiton).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the characteristics listed for the genus, the following are observed.</s><s>Cells are 0.7–1.0×2.4–4.7 μm and motile by peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Colonies on marine agar are circular, smooth and yellow in colour.</s><s>Grows on marine agar at 15–30 °C (optimally at 30 °C).</s><s>Grows at pH 5.0–9.0 (optimally at pH 7.0–8.0).</s><s>Growth is observed on R2A agar supplemented with 50–150 % ASW (optimally with 70–120 % ASW).</s><s>Catalase and oxidase activities are present.</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite are not reduced, acid is not produced from glucose and indole is not produced from tryptophan.</s><s><em>β</em>-Glucosidase and protease activities are present.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase and urease activities are not detected.</s><s>Growth by fermenting glucose under anaerobic conditions is not observed.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized for growth: <em>α</em>-d-glucose, l-alanine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, inosine, uridine and thymidine.</s><s>Activities in the API ZYM strip are detected for alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase.</s><s>Tests for esterase C4, ester lipase C8, cystine arylamidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase are weakly positive.</s><s>Activities of lipase C4, chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are not observed.</s><s>The quinone system of the type strain consists of MK-6 (57.8 %) and MK-7 (42.2 %).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, FYK2218<sup>T</sup> (=NBRC 101209<sup>T</sup> =KCTC 12899<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a chiton, <em>Acanthopleura japonica</em>, from the Boso peninsula, Japan.</s></p></content></protolog>