<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5862_nm.1823" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1823" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1823" rank="species">Polaromonas vacuolata</organism><reference id="rid.5862"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Irgens</surname><given-names>R.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gosink</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Staley</surname><given-names>J.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Polaromonas vacuolata gen. nov., sp. nov., a psychrophilic, marine, gas vacuolate bacterium from Antarctica.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>822</fpage><lpage>826</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-3-822</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8782696</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Polaromonas vacmlata</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Polaromonas vacuolata</i> (va.cu.o.la'ta. L. adj. <i>vacuus</i>, empty; N. L. part. adj. <i>vacuolata</i>, equipped with gas vacuoles)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells contain gas vesicles.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 4°C, and the growth temperature range is 0 to 12°C.</s><s>Colonies are snowy white, circular, and convex with smooth surfaces and entire edges.</s><s>The more gas vesicles within the cells, the whiter the colony.</s><s>Good growth occurs in media containing NaCl at concentrations ranging from 0 to 6.0%, but no growth occurs in the presence of 7.0% NaCl.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Tests for catalase, oxidase, urease, deaminase, and lipase are positive.</s><s>Amylase, protease (gelatin), tryptophanase (indole), nitrate reductase, cysteine desulfurase, and agarase tests are negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following carbon sources are utilized: acetate, lactate, malate, fumarate, pyruvate, propionate, citrate, succinate, oxaloacetate, butyrate, 2-oxoglutarate, glucose, glycerol, sorbitol, DL-alanine, DL-glutamate, DL-proline, DL-aspartate, and DL-asparagine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized: maltose, Dfructose, sucrose, lactose, D-xylose, D-ribose, formate, cellobiose, D-mannose, L-fucose, melibiose, melezitose, L-rhamnose, sorbose, trehalose, methanol, ethanol, erythritol, propanol, benzoate, malonate, DL-arginine, glycine, DL-serine, DL-isoleucine, DL-lysine, DL-histidine, DL-ornithine, DL-methionhe, DLvaline, DL-threonine, and DL-tryptophan.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The fatty acid composition is 75% 16:1 ω7c, 17% 16:0, and 8% 18:1 ω7c, 18:1 ω9t, or 18:1 ω12t.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Susceptible to novobiocin, tetracycline, neomycin, and kanamycin.</s><s>Resistant to bacitracin, streptomycin, and gentamicin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content is 52.0 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is <i>P. vacuolata</i> 34-P (= ATCC 51984).</s></p><p class="description"><s>It is likely that the other strains included in this study are members of the same species on the basis of the results of the phenotypic tests that were performed, including the whole-cell fatty acid analysis.</s><s>However, DNA-DNA hybridization tests were not conducted, and so this has not been verified.</s></p></content></protolog>