<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12100_nm.20090" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20090" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20090" rank="species">Vagococcus penaei</organism><reference id="rid.12100"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jaffrès</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prévost</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rossero</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Joffraud</surname><given-names>J.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dousset</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vagococcus penaei sp. nov., isolated from spoilage
microbiota of cooked shrimp (Penaeus vannamei)</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2159</fpage><lpage>2164</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.012872-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19897618</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Vagococcus penaei</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Vagococcus penaei</em> [pe.na′e.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>penaei</em> of <em>Penaeus</em>, a zoological genus name, pertaining to the spoilage microbiota of cooked shrimp (<em>Penaeus vannamei</em>), from which the type strain was isolated].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-stain-positive cocci, 0.5–1 μm in diameter, and occur singly, in pairs or in short chains, elongated in the direction of the chain.</s><s>Cells are non-motile and non-spore-forming, facultatively anaerobic and catalase- and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Colonies are small (up to 1 mm in diameter), smooth and white when grown on BHI agar at 30 °C.</s><s>No haemolysis or pigment on Columbia agar supplemented with 5 % defibrinated horse blood.</s><s>Lactic acid is produced from glucose fermentation, but gas is not produced.</s><s>Grows at 10 °C but not at 45 °C.</s><s>Does not grow with 6.5 % NaCl.</s><s>With API Rapid ID32S, acid is produced from maltose, melezitose, raffinose, d-ribose, sucrose, trehalose and <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, but not from l-arabinose, d-arabitol, lactose, d-mannitol, melibiose, d-sorbitol, d-tagatose, glycogen, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside or pullulan.</s><s>Produces acid phosphatase, arginine dihydrolase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), glycyl-tryptophan arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, but not <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>β</em>-mannosidase, alkaline phosphatase, lipase (C14), alanyl-phenylalanyl-proline arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, trypsin or urease.</s><s>Hippurate is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Acetoin is produced (Voges–Proskauer).</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan is type A4<em>α</em> l-Lys–d-Asp and the predominant cellular fatty acids are <em>cis</em>-9 octadecenoic acid and hexadecanoic acid.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 35.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CD276<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 24833<sup>T</sup> =CIP 109914<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the spoilage microbiota of cooked shrimp (<em>Penaeus vannamei</em>).</s></p></content></protolog>