<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12727_nm.22496" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22496" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22496" rank="species">Vibrio stylophorae</organism><reference id="rid.12727"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sheu</surname><given-names>S.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>S.-R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>C.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>J.-T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.-M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vibrio stylophorae sp. nov., isolated from the reef-building coral Stylophora pistillata</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2180</fpage><lpage>2185</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.026666-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20935089</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Vibrio stylophorae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Vibrio stylophorae</em> (sty.lo.pho′ra.e. N.L. gen. n. <em>stylophorae</em> of <em>Stylophora</em>, isolated from a coral belonging to the genus <em>Stylophora</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, slightly curved rod-shaped and non-motile.</s><s>After 48 h of incubation on MA at 30 °C, the mean cell size is 0.3–0.5 µm in diameter and 1.0–3.1 µm in length.</s><s>Colonies on MA are semi-transparent, round, smooth and convex with entire margins.</s><s>Colony size is approximately 0.5–0.8 mm in diameter after 72 h at 25 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–35 °C (optimum, 30 °C), at pH 6.0–9.0 (optimum, pH 7.0–8.0), and with 0.5–6.0 % NaCl (optimum, 2 %).</s><s>Positive for oxidase and catalase activities and hydrolysis of chitin and DNA.</s><s>Negative for lipase and urease activities and hydrolysis of starch, casein, alginate, lecithin, CM-cellulose and Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80.</s><s>In API 20NE tests, positive reactions for arginine dihydrolase activity, nitrate reduction, assimilation of glucose, mannitol and <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, and negative reactions for indole production, aesculin hydrolysis, gelatin hydrolysis, urease and β-galactosidase activities, and assimilation of arabinose, mannose, maltose, gluconate, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate and phenyl acetate.</s><s>In API 20E tests, positive reactions for acetoin production, and glucose, mannitol, xylose and sorbitol fermentation, and negative reactions for hydrogen sulfide production, indole production, citrate and malonate utilization, inositol, rhamnose, sucrose, lactose, arabinose, adonitol, raffinose and salicin fermentation, and lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, β-galactosidase, urease and tryptophan deaminase activities.</s><s>In the API ZYM kit, alkaline phosphatase, C8 esterase lipase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase activities are present, but C4 esterase, C14 lipase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase,α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon sources in the GN2 microplate: <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, cellobiose, d-fructose, α-d-glucose, d-mannitol, d-psicose, d-sorbitol, pyruvic acid methyl ester, α-ketobutyric acid, dl-lactic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>All other substrates in the GN2 microplate are not utilized.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 47.8 mol%.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω6<em>c</em>), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is KTW-12<sup>T</sup> ( = BCRC 80105<sup>T</sup>  = LMG 25357<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the reef-building coral <em>Stylophora pistillata</em>, collected off the coast of southern Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>