<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2612_nm.4042" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4042" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4042" rank="species">Clostridium thermopapyrolyticum</organism><reference id="rid.2612"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Méndez</surname><given-names>B.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pettinari</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ivanier</surname><given-names>S.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ramos</surname><given-names>C.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Siñeriz</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium thermopapyrolyticum sp. nov. a Cellulolytic Thermophile.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>281</fpage><lpage>283</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-41-2-281</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clostridium thermopapyrolyticum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clostridium thermopapyrolyticum</i> (ther.mo.pa.py.ro.ly'ti.cum. Gr. adj. <i>thermus</i>, hot; Gr. n. <i>papyros</i>, paper; Gr. adj. <i>lyticus</i>, dissolving; M.L. neut. adj. <i>thermopapyrolyticum</i> , a paper-degrading thermophile)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from sediment from a river bank in Buenos Aires, Argentina.</s></p><p class="description"><s>This microorganism can utilize filter paper as its sole carbohydrate source.</s><s>In liquid cultures, filter paper is degraded in 10 days.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on cellobiose or glucose agar medium after 48 h of incubation are 1.5 to 2 mm in diameter and are cream colored with entire edges.</s><s>After 8 days of incubation, colonies become pale brown and rough with lobed edges.</s><s>Cells from these colonies show subterminal spores when observed under an electron microscope (Fig. 1).</s></p><p class="description"><s>On cellulose agar medium, colonies reach 0.5 to 0.8 mm in diameter after 7 days of incubation.</s><s>No zone of clearing is detected, even on plates on which the agar has been turned over to facilitate direct contact of the microorganism with the cellulose.</s><s>To test for the presence of extracellular cellulolytic enzymes, the Congo red method (Fig. 2) was applied.</s><s>Fifty-three colonies were tested in this way, and all of them produced clear zones corresponding to hydrolyzed carboxymethyl cellulose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Under phase-contrast microscopy, cells appear as straight or slightly curved rods 4 to 7 μm in length and 0.5 to 0.6 μm in width.</s><s>Cells from young cultures are positive in Gram staining, but in the late stage of growth variations in Gram stain are often seen.</s><s>The cells are motile.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Electron-microscopic observations of ultrathin sections indicate a three-layer wall (Fig. 3) unlike the usual gram-positive mesophilic envelope.</s><s>However, lysozyme treatment (11) produces protoplastization and sensitivity to osmotic shock.</s><s>Thus, a peptidoglycan layer easily accessible to lysozyme surrounds the cells.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimum growth temperature, 59°C, was estimated from the generation time, which at this temperature is 60 min.</s><s>Growth occurs only between 45 and 66°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>This isolate grows on cellulose, cellobiose, arabinose, mannitol, xylose, lactose, maltose, fructose, starch, glucose, and galactose.</s><s>It does not grow on sucrose, melibiose, glycerol, sorbitol, raffinose, or inulin.</s><s>Acid is produced from all the carbohydrates tested that allow growth.</s><s>In the case of cellulose, acid production is weak, The type strain hydrolyzes esculin and forms curd in milk.</s><s>Cultures grown on gelatin medium did not solidify when chilled, showing gelatin hydrolysis.</s><s>This species does not reduce nitrate and does not produce indole.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The end products of glucose fermentation of the type strain after 48 h of incubation are as follows (in millimoles per 100 millimoles of glucose consumed): ethanol, 34; acetate, 48; butyrate, 38; lactate, 38; and butanol, 5.</s><s>Carbon</s></p><p class="description"><s>dioxide, hydrogen, and hydrogen sulfide are also produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 34 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is deposited in the South American Biotechnology and Applied Microbiology microbiological resource center culture collection as UBA 305.</s></p></content></protolog>