<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12574_nm.21828" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21828" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21828" rank="species">Paenibacillus phoenicis</organism><reference id="rid.12574"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Benardini</surname><given-names>J.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vaishampayan</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schwendner</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swanner</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fukui</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Osman</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Satomi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Venkateswaran</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus phoenicis sp. nov., isolated from the Phoenix Lander assembly facility and a subsurface molybdenum mine</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1338</fpage><lpage>1343</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.021428-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20584815</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus phoenicis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus phoenicis</em> (phoe′ni.cis. L. gen. n. <em>phoenicis</em> of phoenix, isolated from the surface of the clean room where the recently landed Mars Phoenix spacecraft was assembled).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Vegetative cells are rod-shaped with a diameter of 1 to 1.5 µm and a length of 4 to 6 µm, motile, Gram-positive, produce catalase and form endoendospores which are subterminal in position and have a diameter of 1 to 1.5 µm.</s><s>Colonies form after 72 h of growth on TSA at 32 °C, are beige, smooth, glistening, have a diameter of 4 mm, show no pigmentation and possess entire edges.</s><s>Grows at 32 °C on TSA (Difco), R2A (Difco) and TYG (5 g tryptone, 3 g yeast extract and 1 g glucose per litre).</s><s>Produces oval endospores in MSM medium which are resistant to UV radiation up to 500 J m<sup>−2</sup>.</s><s>Tests for urease, tryptophan deaminase and hydrolysis of gelatin are negative.</s><s>Assimilation of the following sole carbon sources is positive: glucose, mannitol, inositol, rhamnose, sorbitol, sucrose, melibiose, amygdalin, l-arabinose, d-arabinose, sucrose, l-arabinose, d-xylose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, arbutin, salicin, lactose (bovine), starch, aesculin ferric citrate, glycogen, gentiobiose and trehalose.</s><s>Acid was not produced from the following substrates: glycerol, erythritol, l-xylose, d-adonitol, dulcitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fructose, l-arabitol, potassium 2-ketogluconate, potassium 5-ketogluconate, l-sorbose, d-arabinose and l-rhamnose.</s><s>Positive for citrate utilization.</s><s>Growth occurs between 21 and 50 °C and at pH 7.0–9.0 (pH 10.0 for strain 3P02SA<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 37 °C and at pH 7.0.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 5 % NaCl.</s><s>Growth is inhibited at 65 °C and in the presence of 10 % NaCl.</s><s>The major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Major isoprenoid quinone is MK-7 menaquinone and the cell wall contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 51.9 to 52.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 3PO2SA<sup>T</sup> ( = NRRL B-59348<sup>T</sup>  = NBRC 106274<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from surfaces of the Payload Hazardous Servicing Facility (PHSF) located at the Kennedy Space Center where the Phoenix Lander was assembled.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain, 3PO2SA<sup>T</sup>, is 52.5 mol%.</s><s>The type strain, 3PO2SA<sup>T</sup>, differs from the other two strains, HM06-03 and HM06-05, by producing β-galactosidase and being positive for the Voges–Proskauer reaction but lacks production of lysine and ornithine decarboxylases.</s></p></content></protolog>