<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6191_nm.9092" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9092" rank="genus">Fluoribacter</organism><reference id="rid.6191"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Garrity</surname><given-names>G.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brown</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vickers</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Tatlockia and Fluoribacter: Two new genera of organisms resembling Legionella pneumophila.</article-title><year>1980</year><volume>30</volume><fpage>609</fpage><lpage>614</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-30-4-609</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Fluoribacter</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>(Flu.or.i.bac'ter, L.V. <i>fluor</i>, to flow, because of the fluorescence of this organism; M.L. masc. n. <i>bacter</i>, the masculine form of the Gr. neut. n. <i>bactrum</i>, a rod or staff; M.L. masc. n. <i>Fluoribacter</i>, fluorescent rod)</s></p><p class="description"><s>We believe that strains WIGA and MI- 15 belong to a new genus and species, for which we propose the names <i>Fluoribacter</i> and <i>F. bozemanae</i>, respectively. <i>F. bozemanae</i> is the type species of the genus, and strain WIGA (= ATTC 33217) is the type strain of the species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies of <i>Fluoribacter</i> fluoresce brightly when illuminated with longwave UV light.</s><s>When examined with a dissecting microscope, colonies of all three species have a clear, glistening to gelatinous surface with an opaque, ground-glass interior.</s><s>On BCYE agar containing 0.001% bromocresol purple and 0.001% bromothymol blue, Legionella colonies are white to pale green, <i>Fluoribacter</i> colonies are a brighter green, and <i>Tatlockia</i> colonies are blue-gray (Vickers, Brown, and Garkity, submitted for publication).</s><s>Although growth of these organisms is best on BCYE agar, adapted growth, although poor, may be occasionally obtained on a variety of nutritionally complex, charcoal-free media.</s><s>However, growth has not been observed on unsupplemented sheep blood agar.</s></p></content></protolog>