<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4050_nm.6349" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6349" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6349" rank="species">Mycobacterium frederiksbergense</organism><reference id="rid.4050"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Willumsen</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Karlson</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium frederiksbergense sp. nov., a novel polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbon-degrading Mycobacterium species.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1715</fpage><lpage>1722</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11594601</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycobacterium frederiksbergense</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycobacterium frederiksbergense</i> (fre.de.riks.ber.gen'se. N.L. gen. n. <i>frederiksbergense</i> of Frederiksberg, Denmark, referring to the place of isolation)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, acid-fast, non-spore-forming, nonmotile short rods, sometimes coccid without branching.</s><s>Smooth, scotochromogenic colonies, cadmium yellow in colour, appear after 5 d on TSB agar and Middlebrook agar.</s><s>Grows at 15-37 °C.</s><s>Shows a positive reaction for catalase and nitrate reduction but negative for urease.</s><s>Tween 80 is hydrolysed but no growth occurs on MacConkey agar.</s><s>D-Xylose, trehalose and mannitol are used as sole sources of carbon but glucitol (sorbitol) is not.</s><s>Able to utilize N-acetyl D-glucosamine, gluconate, D-glucosaminic acid, <i>i</i>-inositol, putrescine, L-rhamnose, succinate and 2-hydroxyvalerate, whereas acetamide, phenylacetic acid, L-alanine, D-arabitol, L-aspartate, benzoate, 4-aminobenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, citrate, glutarate, 2-oxoglutarate, L-leucine, L-proline, putrescine, quinate, D-ribose, sucrose, D-turanose and L-valine are not used.</s><s><i>p</i>-Nitrophenyl β-D-xyloside is hydrolysed but <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl phosphorylcholine and 2-deoxythymidine 5'-<i>p</i>-nitrophenyl phosphate show no change in colour.</s><s>Mineralizes the PAHs phenanthrene, fuoranthene and pyrene.</s><s>The fatty acid pattern from whole-cell methanolysates is composed of tetradecanoic acid (5%), palmitoleic acid (6%), <i>cis</i>-11-hexadecenoic acid (3%), palmitic acid (31%), oleic acid (35%), stearic acid (2%), tuberculostearic acid (1%) and eicosanoic acid (1%).</s><s>Significant amounts of the alcohols 2-octadecanol (11%) and eicosanol (2%) are also present.</s><s>TLC of mycolic acid methanolysates reveals α-mycolates, ketomycolates and xcarboxymycolates plus 2-eicosanol (wax-ester mycolates).</s><s>The mycolic acid HPLC elution profile is unique and can be used for differentiation from the closely related species <i>M. diernhoferi</i>, <i>M. neoaurum</i>, <i>M. hodleri</i> and from all other mycobacteria.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from the site of a former gas works at Frederiksberg, Denmark.</s><s>Strain FAn9<sup>T</sup> (¯=DSM 44346<sup>T</sup>=NRRL B-24126<sup>T</sup>) is the type strain.</s></p></content></protolog>