<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3379_nm.5192" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5192" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5192" rank="species">Planococcus kocurii</organism><reference id="rid.3379"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hao</surname><given-names>M.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Komagata</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A new species of Planococcus, P. kocurii isolated from fish, frozen foods, and fish curing brine.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>31</volume><fpage>441</fpage><lpage>455</lpage><source id="120">The Journal of General and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Gen Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-1260</issn><essn>1349-8037</essn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Planococcus kocurii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Planococcus kocurii</i> (ko.cu'ri.i M.L. gen. n. <i>kocurii</i> of Kocur; named for Miloslav Kocur, Czechoslovakian bacteriologist who revived the genus <i>Planococcus</i>.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are spherical, 1.0 to 1.2 μm in diameter, occurring singly, in pairs, tetrads and in clumps.</s><s>Motile.</s><s>The motile cells usually have one or two flagella.</s><s>Not spore-forming.</s><s>Gram positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on peptone yeast extract agar (PY) plate are circular, convex, smooth, and yellow orange pigmented.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>Metabolism respiratory.</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Catalase and DNase are positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following tests are negative: Oxidase, methyl red test, Voges-Proskauer reaction, indole production, hydrogen sulfide, nitrate reduction, phenylalanine deaminase, lysine and ornithine decarboxylases, arginine dihydrolase, hydrolysis of gelatin, Tween-80, and esculin, tyrosine clearing, hydrolysis of starch, and urease.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid but no gas is produced aerobically from D-glucose and glycerol in MOF medium of LEIFSON, but not from D-xylose, L-arabinose, L-rhamnose, D-mannose, sucrose, lactose, D-cellobiose, melibiose, maltose, trehalose, raffinose, starch, erythritol, adonitol, i-inositol, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, dulcitol and salicin.</s><s>Acetate, glyoxylate, glycolate, pyruvate, n-butyrate, fumarate, succinate, glutarate and hippurate are assimilated, but formate, propionate, oxalate, DL-lactate, malonate, L-malate, α-ketoglutarate, adipate, pimelate, urate, citrate and gluconate are not.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Optimum salinity for growth : 0 to 10% sodium chloride.</s><s>No growth at 15%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Optimum temperature for growth: 25 to 30°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Peptidoglycan in the cell wall: L-Lys-D-Glu type.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base composition is 40.0 mol % guanine plus cytosine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The menaquinones are MK-7 and MK-8 as major components, and MK-6 as a minor component.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major cellular fatty acid is <i>anteiso</i> C<sub>15:0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from skin of North Sea cod, <i>Gadus callarias</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is HK 701 (=AJ 3345=CCM 1849=IAM 12847=JCM 2569=NCMB 629).</s><s>This strain was isolated from the skin of the North Sea cod by Georgala in 1957 (41).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on the characteristics of the type strain, and variations within the species are shown in Tables 2 through 5, and in Fig. 2.</s><s>Strains HK 701, 702, 703, 704, and 705 were studied.</s></p></content></protolog>