<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1466_nm.5008" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5008" rank="genus">Amphibacillus</organism><reference id="rid.1466"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Niimura</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Koh</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yanagida</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>K.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Komagata</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kozaki</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Amphibacillus xylanus gen. nov., sp. nov., a facultatively anaerobic sporeforming xylan-digesting bacterium which lacks cytochrome, quinone, and catalase.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>297</fpage><lpage>301</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-3-297</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Amphibacillus</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Amphibacillus</i> (Am. phi. ba. cil' lus. Gr. pref. <i>amphi</i>, both sides or double; L. dim. n. <i>bacillus</i>, a small rod; M. L. masc. n. <i>Amphibacillus</i>, rod capable of both aerobic and anaerobic growth)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rods that are 0.3 to 0.5 μm in diameter and 0.9 to 1.9 μm long.</s><s>Gram positive in the very early stages of growth and loosely gram positive in stationary growth phase.</s><s>Heat resistant, oval endospores are formed, but the sporangia are rapidly lysed and the spores are liberated.</s><s>Spores are formed under both aerobic and anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Grows well both in well-aerated cultures and in aerobic cultures (E<sub>h</sub>,-370 mV; pH 10) when titanium(III) citrate is used as a reducing agent.</s><s>Does not grow in nutrient broth.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>Produces ethanol, acetic acid, and formic acid under anaerobic conditions and acetic acid under aerobic conditions from glucose (9).</s><s>Grows at pH values between 8.0 and 10.0 but not at pH 7.0.</s><s>Contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid in the cell wall, and the peptidoglycan structure is the direct-linkage type which corresponds to type A1γ of Schleifer and Kandler (11).</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso- and iso-branched and straight-chain acids.</s><s>Cytochromes, isoprenoid quinones, catalase, and oxidase are not detected.</s><s>The DNA base composition ranges from 36 to 38 mol% G+C.</s><s>Probably widely distributed in composts of manure with grass.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <i>Amphibacillus xylanus</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>