<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4365_nm.10661" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10661" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10661" rank="species">Citreimonas salinaria</organism><reference id="rid.4365"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>D.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>B.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Citreimonas salinaria gen. nov., sp. nov., a member of the Roseobacter clade isolated from a solar saltern.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2799</fpage><lpage>2803</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64373-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17158980</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Citreimonas salinaria</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Citreimonas salinaria</em> (sa.li.na′ri.a. L. fem. adj. <em>salinaria</em> of or belonging to a salt-works).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Shows the following properties in addition to those in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are non-motile and approximately 0.5–0.8 μm wide and 1.0–1.5 μm long.</s><s>On MA medium, colonies are circular with an entire margin, convex, opaque, shiny and beige in colour.</s><s>Grows at temperatures in the range 15–40 °C (optimum, 30–35 °C) and at pH 6–10.</s><s>Growth occurs at sea salts concentrations of 1–10 % (w/v).</s><s>No growth occurs without sea salts in the medium.</s><s>DNase, gelatinase, nitrate reductase, esterase, esterase lipase and leucine arylamidase activities are present and alkaline phosphatase and valine arylamidase activities are weakly present.</s><s>Amylase, indole production, acid production from glucose, arginine dihydrolase, urease, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, Tween 80 degradation, lipase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>Growth occurs on l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-glucose, d-mannose, sucrose, d-trehalose, d-xylose, acetone, acetate, Casamino acids, pyruvate, citrate, succinate, glycerol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, inulin, salicin, l-arginine, l-leucine, l-lysine, l-ornithine and l-proline.</s><s>No growth occurs on <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, acetamide, d-galactose, d-raffinose, d-ribose, l-rhamnose, polyethylene glycol, ascorbate, benzoate, formic acid, lactose, maleic acid, salicylate, tartrate, ethanol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, 2-propanol, d-mannitol, sorbitol, l-aspartate, l-asparagine, dl-cysteine, l-glutamate, glycine, glycogen, thiamine or urea.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 67.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CL-SP20<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 42116<sup>T</sup>=JCM 13036<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from hypersaline water from a solar saltern in Seosin, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>