<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4239_nm.4300" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4300" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4300" rank="species">Mogibacterium vescum</organism><reference id="rid.4239"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nakazawa</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sato</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Poco</surname><given-names>S.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hashimura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ikeda</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kalfas</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sundqvist</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoshino</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of Mogibacterium pumilum gen. nov., sp. nov. and Mogibacterium vescum gen. nov., sp. nov., and reclassification of Eubacterium timidum (Holdeman et al. 1980) as Mogibacterium timidum gen. nov., comb. nov.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>679</fpage><lpage>688</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10758875</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mogibacterium vescum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mogibacterium vescum</i> (ves'cum. L. adj. <i>vescum</i> weak, referring to the poor growth of this organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are short, Gram-positive rods, obligately anaerobic, non-motile and non-sporing.</s><s>Individual cells are about 0.2-0.3 by 1.5 μm, occurring singly or in clumps.</s><s>On BHI-blood agar plates they form minute colonies &#x003C;1 mm in diameter even after prolonged incubation in an anaerobic glove box, which are circular, convex and translucent.</s><s>Growth in broth media is poor with or without carbohydrates.</s><s>No haemolysis occurs around colonies on BHI-blood agar plates.</s><s>The cells are nonfermentative and do not utilize adonitol, amygdalin, arabinose, cellobiose, erythritol, aesculin, fructose, galactose, glucose, glycogen, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, melezitose, melibiose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, starch, sucrose, trehalose or xylose.</s><s>Catalase, urease and indole are not produced, and ammonia is not produced from arginine.</s><s>They produce phenyl acetate (4 mM) as the sole metabolic end product in PY or PYGbroth.</s><s>TheG­C content is 46 mol%.</s><s>This strain can be distinguished from <i>Mogibacterium pumilum</i> according to the almost complete sequence of the 16S rRNA gene and DNA relatedness values.</s><s>The type strain is D5-2<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 700697<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Isolated from human periodontal pockets.</s></p></content></protolog>