<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1218_nm.11057" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11057" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5628" rank="species">Streptococcus dysgalactiae</organism><reference id="rid.1218"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Garvie</surname><given-names>E.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Farrow</surname><given-names>J.A.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bramley</surname><given-names>A.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptococcus dysgalactiae, Diernhofer nom. rev.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>404</fpage><lpage>405</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-2-404</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptococcus dysgalactiae</i> nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptococcus dysgalactiae</i> (dys.ga.lac'ti.ae, Gr. pref. <i>dys</i> ill, hard; Gr. n. <i>galactia</i> pertaining to milk; N. L. n. <i>dysgalactia</i> loss or impairment of milk secretion, dysgalactia; N. L. gen. n. <i>dysgalactiae</i> of dysgalactia)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive cocci or oval cells in short- to medium-length chains.</s><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan contains L-Lys-L-Ala linkage.</s><s>Growth in glucose nutrient broth is poor and has a final pH of 4.7 to 4.9.</s><s>On blood agar plates colonies are surrounded by a wide zone of alpha hemolysis (greening).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 37°C.</s><s>Growth does not occur at 10 or 45°C, in 6.5% NaCl, in 10% bile, or at pH 9.6.</s><s>Cells do not survive at 60°C for 30 min.</s><s>Growth occurs only on complex media, but vitamin and amino acidrequirements are unknown.</s><s>Litmus milk is usually reduced, acidified, and clotted.</s><s>Acid is formed from glucose, lactose, maltose, sucrose, and trehalose.</s><s>No acid is formed from raffinose, inulin, glycerol, or mannitol.</s><s>The reaction in sorbitol is variable.</s><s>Esculin is not hydrolyzed, but some strains hydrolyze salicin.</s><s>Hippurate is not attacked.</s><s>Ammonia is formed from arginine.</s><s>Hyaluronidase is usually produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Serological group C.</s><s>A fibrinolysin for bovine fibrin but not for human fibrin may be produced.</s><s>Low pathogenicity for mice.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The lactate dehydrogenase is activated by fructose 1,6-diphosphate, but inhibition by phosphate is slight, particularly at pH 5.5.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 39 to 40 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA-DNA hybridization shows that <i>S . dysgalactiae</i> is a distinct cluster with a low relationship to <i>Streptococcus agalactiae</i>, <i>Streptococcus acidominimus</i>, <i>Streptococcus uberis</i> or <i>Streptococcus bovis</i>.</s><s>These species all belong to a single cluster, as determined by DNA-ribonucleic acid hybridization.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>S. dysgalactiae</i> is commonly found in mastitic bovine udders, produces mastitis experimentally, and may also be isolated from teat skin lesions and bovine vaginas.</s></p><p class="description"><s>NCDO 2023 is the type strain.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of this strain was estimated to be 39.8 mol%.</s><s>Other characteristics agree with the description given above.</s></p></content></protolog>