<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9470_nm.14611" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14611" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14611" rank="species">Helcobacillus massiliensis</organism><reference id="rid.9470"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Renvoise</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Aldrovandi</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Raoult</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roux</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Helcobacillus massiliensis gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel representative of the family Dermabacteraceae isolated from a patient with a cutaneous discharge</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2346</fpage><lpage>2351</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.003319-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19620359</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Helcobacillus massiliensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Helcobacillus massiliensis</em> (mas.si.li.en′sis. L. masc. adj. <em>massiliensis</em> of Massilia, the old Roman name for Marseille, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-positive, short, irregular, straight, non-spore-forming, and non-motile rods.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Essentially aerobic but may show very weak growth under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 37 °C.</s><s>After 24 h growth on sheep blood agar, surface colonies are up to 1 mm diameter, smooth, circular, white and shiny.</s><s>The rods measure 0.7–1 μm in length and 0.4–0.7 μm in diameter (as determined by electron microscopy).</s><s>Using API ZYM, activities of <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase are detected.</s><s>Activities of leucine arylaminidase, valine arylaminidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), cystine arylaminidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are not detected.</s><s>Using API 50CH strips after an incubation time of 48 h, acid is produced from l-arabinose, d-xylose, d-glucose, d-fructose, inositol, d-mannitol, maltose, sucrose and turanose.</s><s>After an incubation time of 72 h, acid is produced (besides the characters previously quoted) from glycerol (weakly), erythritol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine (weakly), trehalose (weakly) and melezitose (weakly).</s><s>Acid is not produced from d-arabinose, d-ribose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl-<em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, d-sorbitol, methyl-<em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl-<em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin ferric citrate, salicin, cellobiose, d-lactose, melibiose, inulin, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabinol, l-arabinol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate and potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Using API Coryne, the following tests are positive: <em>α</em>-glucosidase, reduction of nitrate, pyrazinamidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, gelatin hydrolysis, glucose, xylose, mannitol, maltose and sucrose fermentation.</s><s>The others are negative: <em>β</em>-galactosidase, pyrolidonyl arylaminidase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, urease, ribose, lactose and glycogen fermentation.</s><s>The compounds used as sole carbon sources recovered when using the Biolog System are: dextrin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-mannosamine, l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-galactose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, m-inositol, maltotriose, d-mannitol, d-mannose (weakly), melezitose, 3-methylglucose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, d-xylose, l-lactic acid, pyruvic acid methyl ester, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanylglycine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, l-serine, glycerol, adenosine and thymidine.</s><s>The following are negative: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, glycogen, inulin, mannan, amygdalin, d-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, l-fucose, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, melibiose, <em>α</em>-methyl-d-galactoside, <em>β</em>-methyl-d-galactoside, <em>α</em>-methyl-d-glucoside, <em>β</em>-methyl-d-glucoside, <em>α</em>-methyl-d-mannoside, palatinose, d-psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, salicin, sedoheptulosan, stachyose, d-tagatose, xylitol, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, p-hydroxy-phenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, lactamide, d-lactic acid methyl ester, d-malic acid, l-malic acid, succinic acid mono-methyl ester, propionic acid, pyruvic acid, succinamic acid, succinic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, glycyl-l-glutamic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, 2′-deoxyadenosine, inosine, uridine, adenosine 5′-monophosphate, thymidine 5′-monophosphate, uridine 5′-monophosphate, d-fructose 6-phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate, d-glucose 6-phosphate and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>Utilization of the following is variable: Tween 40 and Tween 80.</s><s>The only respiratory quinone is MK-7 and polar lipids present are phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylcholine and unidentified glycolipids.</s><s>The major fatty acids are anteiso-C15 : 0 (34.3 %), anteiso-C17 : 0 (18.7 %), iso-C16 : 0 (18.6 %), iso-C14 : 0 (9 %), C18 : 1 <em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and iso-C15 : 0 (5.2 %).</s><s>Mycolic acids are absent.</s><s>The isomer of DAP is <em>meso</em>-Dpm.</s><s>Analysis of whole-cell sugars shows high amounts of galactose, ribose and some glucose.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA is 68.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, which was isolated from a human cutaneous discharge sample, is 6401990<sup>T</sup> (=CSUR P17<sup>T</sup>=CIP 109418<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 53859<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>