<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3713_nm.9375" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9375" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9375" rank="species">Martelella mediterranea</organism><reference id="rid.3713"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Rivas</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sánchez-Márquez</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mateos</surname><given-names>P.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martínez-Molina</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Velázquez</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Martelella mediterranea gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel alpha-proteobacterium isolated from a subterranean saline lake</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>955</fpage><lpage>959</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63438-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15774691</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Martelella mediterranea</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Martelella mediterranea</em> [me.di.ter.ra.ne′a. L. fem. adj. <em>mediterranea</em> inland (used to refer to the Mediterranean Sea), referring to the fact that the type strain was isolated from a Mediterranean island].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are non-motile coccobacillary rods, 1·0–1·1×1·3–1·5 μm in size.</s><s>Colonies on YED medium supplemented with 5 % (w/v) NaCl are circular, smooth, opaque, white- to cream-coloured pigmented colonies that are usually 1–3 mm in diameter within 5 days at 28 °C.</s><s>Grows in the presence of NaCl concentrations up to 5 % (w/v), although salt is not essential for growth.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 4–37 °C (optimal growth occurs at 28 °C) and the pH range for growth is 5–8·5 (optimal growth occurs at pH 7).</s><s>Urease-positive.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed.</s><s>Positive in the Voges–Proskauer reaction and for nitrate reduction.</s><s>The type strain utilizes gluconate, glucose, malate, maltose and mannitol as sole carbon sources, and does not grow in adipate, amygdalin, arabinose, caproate, citrate, inositol, mannose, melibiose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, phenylacetate, rhamnose, sorbitol or sucrose.</s><s>The type strain actively produces <em>β</em>-galactosidase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-gluconidase, <em>β</em>-gluconidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase.</s><s>It does not produce gelatinase, caseinase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase or H<sub>2</sub>S.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is MACL11<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 22193<sup>T</sup>=CECT 5861<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a water sample from a subterranean saline lake on Mallorca, Spain.</s></p></content></protolog>