<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1464_nm.4997" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4997" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4997" rank="species">Bacillus thermoruber</organism><reference id="rid.1464"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Manachini</surname><given-names>P.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fortina</surname><given-names>M.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Parini</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Craveri</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus thermoruber sp. nov., nom. rev., a red-pigmented thermophilic bacterium.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>493</fpage><lpage>496</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-35-4-493</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus thermoruber</i> (ther'mo.ru.ber. Gr. n. <i>therme</i> heat; L. adj. <i>ruber</i> red; M.L. masc. adj. <i>thermoruber</i> heat loving and red pigment producing)</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Cells are gram positive, straight rods 0.8 to 1.0 by 2.5 to 4.8 μm, with lateral flagellation; endospores are oval (0.9 to 1.2 by 1.4 to 1.7 μm) and terminal or subterminal and distinctly distend the sporangium. Colonies are red colored, circular, entire, and convex and have glossy and mucilaginous surfaces.</s></p><p class="description"><s>For growth, biotin or thiamine is required.</s><s>L-Arabinose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, glycerol, inositol, maltose, mannitol, D-ribose, trehalose, and D-xylose are utilized as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Utilization of acetate and succinate is weakly positive.</s><s>Ammonium sulfate, urea, tryptone, soytone, and peptone are utilized as nitrogen sources.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 34 to 58°C, and the optimum temperature is 45 to 48°C.</s><s>Positive physiological properties include gelatin liquefaction and starch and casein hydrolysis; negative properties include nitrate reduction, Voges-Proskauer reaction, indole production, tyrosine decomposition, hydrogen sulfide production, presence of catalase, and growth in the presence of 5% NaCl.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Iso-C<sub>15</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15</sub>, iso-C<sub>17</sub>, and anteiso-C<sub>17</sub> acids are the major cellular fatty acids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 57±0.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Distribution: isolated from compost used for mushroom production.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain BT2, which has been deposited in the collection of the Cattedra di Microbiologia Industriale, Universita di Milano, Milan, Italy, as strain MIM 30.8.38.</s></p></content></protolog>