<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2453_nm.11360" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11360" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11360" rank="species">Streptomyces synnematoformans</organism><reference id="rid.2453"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hozzein</surname><given-names>W.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces synnematoformans sp. nov., a novel actinomycete isolated from a sand dune soil in Egypt</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2009</fpage><lpage>2013</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65037-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17766864</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptomyces synnematoformans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomyces synnematoformans</em> (syn.ne.ma.to.for′mans. Gr. prep. <em>syn</em> in company with, together with; Gr. n. <em>nema</em> thread; N.Gr. n. <em>synnema</em> threads wrapping together; L. part. adj. <em>formans</em> forming; N.L. part. adj. <em>synnematoformans</em> synnemata-forming, referring to the ability of the organism to form synnemata).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, non-acid–alcohol-fast actinomycete which forms an extensively branched substrate mycelium that carries aerial hyphae which differentiate into short, straight to flexuous chains of smooth-surfaced spores (1–1.5 μm).</s><s>Forms synnemata-like structures but not sclerotia.</s><s>A greyish- to blackish-red aerial spore mass and a dark-red to reddish-black substrate mycelium are formed on synthetic agar media.</s><s>A deep greyish-red diffusible pigment is produced on inorganic salts-starch agar.</s><s>Grows from 10 to 37 °C and from pH 6.5 to 9.5.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse arbutin or degrade adenine or uric acid.</s><s>d-Cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose and trehalose are used as sole carbon sources for energy and growth, but not l-arabitol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, d-melezitose, d-salicin, d-sorbitol or d-xylitol (at 1 %, w/v).</s><s>Similarly, pyruvate is used as a sole carbon source, but not acetate, malonate or succinate (all 0.1 %, w/v).</s><s>Grows in the presence of 7 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Additional phenotypic properties are shown in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type and only strain, S155<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 4.2055<sup>T</sup> =DSM 41902<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a sand dune soil collected at Borg El-Arab in Egypt.</s><s>The species description is based on a single strain and hence serves as a description of the type strain.</s></p></content></protolog>