<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4067_nm.1491" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1491" rank="genus">Rhodoblastus</organism><reference id="rid.4067"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Rhodopseudomonas acidophila to the new genus Rhodoblastus as Rhodoblastus acidophilus gen. nov., comb. nov.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1863</fpage><lpage>1866</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11594619</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhodoblastus</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhodoblastus</i> (Rho.do.blas'tus. Gr. n. <i>rhodon</i> the rose; Gr. n. <i>blastos</i> bud shoot; N.L. masc. n. <i>Rhodoblastus</i> the budding rose, referring to the cell colour and the mode of cell division)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped, motile by means of flagella, show polar growth, budding and asymmetric cell division.</s><s>Gram-negative and belong to the α-2 proteobacteria.</s><s>Internal photosynthetic membranes appear as lamellae underlying and parallel to the cytoplasmic membrane.</s><s>Photosynthetic pigments are bacteriochlorophyll <i>a</i> and carotenoids.</s><s>Straight-chain monounsaturated C<sub>18:1</sub> and C<sub>16:1</sub> and saturated C<sub>16:0</sub> are the major cellular fatty acids.</s><s>Contain ubiquinones, rhodoquinones and menaquinones with 10 isoprene units (Q-10, MK-10 and RQ-10).</s><s>Preferred mode of growth is photoheterotrophic under anoxic conditions in the light.</s><s>Photoautotrophic growth may be possible under anoxic conditions with hydrogen as the electron donor.</s><s>Chemotrophic growth occurs under microoxic to oxic conditions, but with some substrates also occurs anaerobically by fermentation.</s><s>Growth factors are not required by the type species.</s><s>Mesophilic freshwater bacteria with a preference for acidic pH.</s><s>Habitat is slightly acidic freshwater ponds.</s><s>The G­+C content of the DNA is 62.2-66.8 mol% (buoyant density).</s><s>The type species is <i>Rhodoblastus (Rbl.) acidophilus</i> (basonym <i>Rhodopseudomonas acidophila</i> Pfennig 1969, 601<sup>AL</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>