<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5716_nm.2219" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2219" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2219" rank="species">Xanthomonas cynarae</organism><reference id="rid.5716"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Trébaol</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gardan</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Manceau</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanguy</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tirilly</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Boury</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Genomic and phenotypic characterization of Xanthomonas cynarae sp. nov., a new species that causes bacterial bract spot of artichoke (Cynara scolymus L.).</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1471</fpage><lpage>1478</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10939652</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Xanthomonas cynarae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Xanthomonas cynarae</i> (cy.na.rae. L. fem. gen. n. <i>cynara</i> from genus name of artichoke, <i>Cynara scolymus</i> L.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Typical symptoms caused by <i>Xanthomonas cynarae</i> consist of water-soaked then dark green spots which occur on the abaxial part of the capitulum bracts.</s><s>As the infection progresses, large brown necrosis spots result.</s><s>Bacterial cells are Gram-negative, non-sporeforming, straight rods, motile by one polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies grown on YBGA for 2 d at 28 °C are circular (2 mm in diameter), smooth, glistening, slightly convex and produce the yellow xanthomonadin pigment.</s><s>They are strictly aerobic.</s><s>They do not produce cytochrome c oxidase, nitrate reductase, urease or indole.</s><s>They hydrolyse casein, gelatin and aesculin, but not starch.</s><s>Acid is produced from galactose, glucose and mannose, but not from arabinose, erythritol, inositol or sorbitol.</s><s>Using BIOLOG GN microplates, <i>Xanthomonas cynarae</i> gives metabolic activity on the following carbon substrates: dextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, Tween 80, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, cellobiose, D-fructose, L-fucose, D-galactose, gentiobiose, α-D-glucose, lactulose, maltose, D-mannose, D-melibiose, D-psicose, D-raffinose, sucrose, D-trehalose, turanose, methylpyruvate, monomethylsuccinate, acetic acid, citric acid, α-hydroxybutyric acid, α-ketobutyric acid, α-ketoglutaricacid, DL-lacticacid,succinicacid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, alaninamide, D-alanine, L-alanine, L-asparagine, L-aspartic acid, L-glutamic acid, glycyl-glutamic acid, histidine, proline, L-serine, threonine, urocanic acid, uridine, glycerol, DL-α-glycerophosphate and glucose 1-phosphate.</s><s>It lacks metabolic activity on: α-cyclodextrin, N-acetyl-D- galactosamine, adonitol, L-arabinose, D-arabitol, <i>meso</i>-inositol, D-mannitol, L-rhamnose, xylitol, formic acid, D-galactonic acid lactone, D-galacturonic acid, D-gluconic acid, D-glucosaminic acid, D-glucuronic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, D-saccharic acid, glucuronamide, L-leucine, L-ornithine, L-phenylalanine, L-pyroglutamic acid, D-serine, DL-carnitine, γ-aminobutyric acid, thymidine, phenyl ethylamine, putrescine and 2-aminoethanol. <i>Xanthomonas cynarae</i> induces a hypersensitive reaction on tobacco leaves.</s><s>Strains pathogenic to artichoke (<i>Cynara scolymus</i> L.) give typical symptoms after inoculation on detached scarified bracts.</s><s>The DNA G­+C content is 63 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is CFBP 4188<sup>T</sup> and has been deposited in the Collection Française de Bactéries Phytopathogénes (CFBP), Angers, France.</s></p></content></protolog>