<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12951_nm.6418" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6418" rank="genus">Nocardia</organism><reference id="rid.12951"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Everest</surname><given-names>G.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cook</surname><given-names>A.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>le Roes-Hill</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Meyers</surname><given-names>P.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardia rhamnosiphila sp. nov., isolated from soil.</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>34</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>508</fpage><lpage>512</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2011.03.006</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21596508</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Nocardia rhamnosiphila</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>id="par0065"&#x003E;<em>Nocardia rhamnosiphila</em> (rham.no.si.phi’la. N.L. neut. n. rhamnosum rhamnose, N.L. fem. adj. phila (from Gr. fem. adj. philê) friend, loving, N.L. fem. adj. rhamnosiphila rhamnose loving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>id="par0070"&#x003E;Strains are Gram positive, catalase positive and oxidase negative.</s><s>The type strain produces pale orange aerial mycelium and extensively branched, dark orange substrate mycelium on ISP 2, whereas strain C2 produces white to pink aerial mycelium.</s><s>No melanin is produced on peptone-yeast extract-iron agar (ISP 6) or tyrosine agar (ISP 7) and diffusible pigments are not formed on glycerol-asparagine agar (ISP5).</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Degrades aesculin and arbutin, but not allantoin, casein, cellulose, DNA, gelatin, guanine, hypoxanthine, starch, l-tyrosine, urea, xanthine or xylan (no growth occurs on adenine plates).</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S production and Tween 80 degradation vary between strains.</s><s>Pectin and hippurate are not hydrolysed by the type strain.</s><s>d(+)-Galactose, d(+)-glucose, l(+)-rhamnose (strongly for the type strain) and trehalose are used as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Weak growth occurs on dulcitol, glycerol, maltose, salicin, sodium acetate, sodium citrate and sodium succinate.</s><s>Unable to utilize adonitol, l(+)-arabinose, d(+)-cellobiose, <em>meso</em>-inositol, inulin, d(–)-mannitol, d(+)-mannose, d(+)-melezitose, d(+)-melibiose, d(+)-raffinose, d(+)-sorbitol, sucrose, xylitol and d(+)-xylose as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Some strains grow weakly on d(–)-fructose and d(–)-ribose.</s><s>In addition, the type strain utilises sodium butyrate, sodium dl-malate, sodium propionate and sodium pyruvate as sole carbon sources, but cannot utilize dextrin, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, sodium benzoate, sodium formate, sodium hippurate, sodium maleate, sodium malonate, sodium oxalate, sodium salicylate, sodium l(+)-tartrate and l(–)-sorbose.</s><s>l-Asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamine, l-histidine, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, potassium nitrate and l-serine are utilized as sole nitrogen sources, with weak growth occurring on l-cysteine.</s><s>dl-α-Alanine, dl-α-amino-n-butyric acid, l-hydroxyproline, d-leucine and l-phenylalanine are not utilized as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>Utilisation of l-methionine, l-threonine and l-valine varies between strains.</s><s>Furthermore the type strain uses ammonium phosphate, l-arginine, l-glutamic acid and dl-β-phenylalanine as sole nitrogen sources, but cannot utilize β-alanine, 4-aminobenzoic acid and dl-ornithine.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 7.0–10.0 and at 30 and 37 °C, but not at pH 4.3 and 45 °C.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 4% (w/v) NaCl; some strains grow weakly in the presence of 7% (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Resistant to lincomycin hydrochloride (100 μg mL<sup>−1</sup>), oleandomycin phosphate (100 μg mL<sup>−1</sup>), penicillin G (10 I.U. mL<sup>−1</sup>) and rifampicin (50 μg mL<sup>−1</sup>), but sensitive to cephaloridine (100 μg mL<sup>−1</sup>), neomycin sulphate (50 μg mL<sup>−1</sup>), streptomycin sulphate (100 μg mL<sup>−1</sup>), tobramycin sulphate (50 μg mL<sup>−1</sup>) and vancomycin hydrochloride (50 μg mL<sup>−1</sup>).</s><s>dl-Diaminopimelic acid (<em>meso</em>–DAP) is the diagnostic diamino acid of the peptidoglycan.</s><s>Arabinose and galactose are present in whole-cell hydrolysates, indicating a chemotype IV cell wall <a href="#bib0090">[18]</a>.</s><s>Mycolic acids are present.</s><s>The phospholipid pattern contains diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylinositol, phosphatidylinositol mannosides and an unidentified glycolipid.</s><s>The major menaquinone of the type strain is MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>, ω-cycl) (81%), with minor amounts of MK-7(H<sub>4</sub>) (8%), MK-9(H<sub>0</sub>) (6%), MK-8(H<sub>0</sub>) (1%), MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>) (1%), MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>) (0.5%) and MK-10(H<sub>2</sub>) (0.5%).</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are C<sub>18:1</sub>ω9<em>c</em>, C<sub>16:0</sub> and C<sub>16:1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15:0</sub> 2-OH.</s><s>No antibacterial activity is detected.</s></p><p class="description"><s>id="par0075"&#x003E;The type strain is 202GMO<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 45147<sup>T</sup> = NRRL B-24637<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a suburban compost heap in Cape Town, South Africa.</s></p></content></protolog>