<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8749_nm.13324" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13324" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13324" rank="species">Flavobacterium anhuiense</organism><reference id="rid.8749"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>S.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gao</surname><given-names>W.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>C.X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>K.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flavobacterium anhuiense sp. nov., isolated from field soil.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>756</fpage><lpage>760</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65536-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18398165</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Flavobacterium anhuiense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Flavobacterium anhuiense</em> (an.hui.en′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>anhuiense</em> pertaining to Anhui, the province where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming, aerobic rods, 1.0–2.5 μm in length and 0.2–0.4 μm in width and motile by gliding.</s><s>Each cells is surrounded by a layer of capsular material.</s><s>Colonies are yellow, circular and smooth with entire margins.</s><s>Grows at 5–37 °C (optimum, 25–30 °C), at pH 4.0–10.0 (optimum, pH 6.0–8.0) and with 0–2 % NaCl (optimum, 0–1 %).</s><s>Growth occurs on trypticase–soy agar, nutrient agar and cetrimide agar, but not on Simmons' citrate agar or MacConkey agar.</s><s>Congo red is not adsorbed by colonies.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are produced.</s><s>Catalase, ornithine decarboxylase, lysine decarboxylase and arginine dihydrolase activities are present.</s><s>Oxidase, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucosidase, phenylalanine deaminase, arginine decarboxylase, DNase and urease activities are absent.</s><s>Starch and casein are hydrolysed, but gelatin, pectin, chitin, Tween 20, Tween 80, agar and CM-cellulose are not.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, l-fucose, l-rhamnose and amygdalin, but not from adonitol, d-arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, d-galactose, inositol, d-lactose, d-mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, d-sorbitol or sucrose.</s><s>Utilizes d-xylose, maltose, d-fructose, d-glucose, d-lactose, sucrose, l-sorbose, d-arabinose, salicin, raffinose, cellobiose, xylitol, melibiose, d-galactose and dextrin, but does not utilize erythritol, l-arabitol, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, d-mannose, inositol, adonitol, d-mannitol, inulin, turanose, citrate, acetate, d-erythrose, malonate, melezitose or tartrate.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Negative for indole and H<sub>2</sub>S production and in the methyl red and Voges–Proskauer reactions (API 20E).</s><s>In the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase activities are present, but lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>Weak enzymic activities are observed for esterase (C4), <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>Resistant to gentamicin, ceftazidime, vancomycin, kanamycin, carbenicillin and polymyxin B, but sensitive to streptomycin, penicillin G, ampicillin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, tetracycline, ofloxacin, amoxicillin, cefazolin and rifampicin.</s><s>MK-6 is the major isoprenoid quinone.</s><s>The major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (28.2 %), summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH, 11.9 %) and C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (11.3 %).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 31.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, D3<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22128<sup>T</sup>=CGMCC 1.6859<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil sample from Anhui Province, PR China.</s></p></content></protolog>