<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8181_nm.13203" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13203" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13203" rank="species">Alicyclobacillus ferrooxydans</organism><reference id="rid.8181"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>C.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Y.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>You</surname><given-names>X.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Guo</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Alicyclobacillus ferrooxydans sp. nov., a ferrous-oxidizing bacterium from solfataric soil.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2898</fpage><lpage>2903</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.2008/000562-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19060079</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Alicyclobacillus ferrooxydans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Alicyclobacillus ferrooxydans</em> (fer.ro.ox′y.dans. L. n. <em>ferrum</em> iron; Gr. adj. <em>oxys</em> sharp, acid; N.L. v. <em>oxydare</em> to make acid, to oxidize; N.L. part. adj. <em>ferrooxydans</em> iron-oxidizing).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, strictly aerobic, non-motile, endospore-forming coccoids or rods with rounded ends (0.4–0.6×1.0–1.5 μm).</s><s>Colonies on plates of modified Norris broth are brown in the centre, with the peripheries being yellow–orange, with diameters of 0.3–0.5 mm.</s><s>Colonies on modified BAM agar are non-pigmented, pinpoint and circular, with entire margins, with diameters of 0.3–0.5 mm.</s><s>Growth is stimulated by yeast extract.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–3 % NaCl, but not in 4 % NaCl.</s><s>Oxidase, catalase and indole production are positive, but nitrate reduction, methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests are negative.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide (H<sub>2</sub>S) is not produced.</s><s>Starch and casein are hydrolysed, but gelatin, Tween 80, aesculin and DNase are not.</s><s>Phosphatase, esterase and lipase activities are positive.</s><s>l-Lysine decarboxylases, l-ornithine decarboxylases and l-phenylalanine deaminase are absent.</s><s>Utilizes the following carbon sources: l-arabinose, cellobiose, erythritol, l-fucose, d-mannose, maltose, d-fructose, d-sorbitol, d-galactose and d-glucose, but not glycerol, aesculin, melezitose, d-mannitol, raffinose, inositol, d-lactose, l-phenylalanine, l-cysteine, peptone or xylitol.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-arabinose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, trehalose, sorbitol, d-glucose, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, 5-ketogluconate and aesculin, but not from glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, d-xylose, l-xylose, d-galactose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, inositol, d-mannitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, d-lactose, melibiose, sucrose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, glycogen, xylitol, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, d-fucose, l-fucose or d-arabitol.</s><s>Uses Fe<sup>2+</sup>, K<sub>2</sub>S<sub>4</sub>O<sub>6</sub> and pyrite for energy.</s><s>Cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Major isoprenoid quinone is menaquinone 7 (MK-7).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 48.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, TC-34<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 15090<sup>T</sup>=CGMCC 1.6357<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from solfataric soil of Tengchong county of Yunnan province, China.</s></p></content></protolog>