<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3857_nm.8554" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8554" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8554" rank="species">Corynebacterium tuberculostearicum</organism><reference id="rid.3857"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Feurer</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Clermont</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bimet</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Candréa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jackson</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Glaser</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bizet</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dauga</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic characterization of nine strains isolated from clinical and environmental specimens, and proposal of Corynebacterium tuberculostearicum sp. nov.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1055</fpage><lpage>1061</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02907-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15280269</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Corynebacterium tuberculostearicum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Corynebacterium tuberculostearicum</em> (tu.ber.cu.lo.stea′ri.cum. N.L. neut. adj. <em>tuberculostearicum</em> of tuberculostearic acid, which is contained in the cells).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are pleomorphic, Gram-positive rods, non-motile and non-spore-forming, developing coccoid forms in stationary cultures.</s><s>Colonies on trypto casein soy agar supplemented with Tween 80 are circular, convex, glistening and 1 mm in diameter.</s><s>Aerobic to facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Lipophilic.</s><s>Oxidase-negative and catalase-positive. <em>Corynebacterium</em> mycolic acids are present and the fatty acid profiles contain tuberculostearic acid.</s><s>Acid is produced from galactose, glucose, glycerol, fructose, mannose, ribose and 5-ketogluconate but not from mannitol, glycogen, starch, sorbitol, lactose, inulin or xylose.</s><s>Production of acid from trehalose, maltose, gluconate, sucrose and <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine is variable.</s><s>Urea, aesculin and gelatin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Presence of nitrate reductase is variable.</s><s>DNase is absent.</s><s>Esterase (C4) and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase activities are detected.</s><s>Presence of esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and alkaline phosphatase is variable.</s><s>No activity is detected for <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, lipase (C14), trypsin or <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized in 2 or 4 days: d-glucose, sucrose, d-ribose, glycerol, l-malate, 2-ketogluconate, succinate, fumarate, l-aspartate, l-glutamate, l-proline and l-serine.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized in 6 days: caprate, citrate and dl-glycerate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Medalle X<sup>T</sup> (=LDC-20<sup>T</sup>=CIP 107291<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 45418<sup>T</sup>=ATCC 35529<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a case of lepromatous leprosy in the Philippines (Brown <em>et al.</em>, 1984).</s><s>The type strain has all the properties given for the species.</s><s>In addition, it assimilates d-mannose.</s></p></content></protolog>