<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7888_nm.10918" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10918" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4930" rank="species">Paenibacillus larvae</organism><reference id="rid.7888"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Genersch</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Forsgren</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pentkänen</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ashiralieva</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rauch</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kilwinski</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fries</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Paenibacillus larvae subsp. pulvifaciens and Paenibacillus larvae subsp. larvae as Paenibacillus larvae without subspecies differentiation.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>501</fpage><lpage>511</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63928-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16514018</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Paenibacillus larvae</em></s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>The morphological, chemotaxonomic and general characters of <em>Paenibacillus larvae</em> are as already described for this species (Heyndrickx <em>et al.</em>, 1996).</s><s>All representatives of this species are pathogenic to honey bee larvae, but differ in virulence.</s><s>Decaying larvae will develop a ropy thread and a non-powdery scale.</s><s>Depending on the LT<sub>100</sub>, infected or dead larvae will be removed by the nurse bees before entering the pupation stage or left decaying in the capped cell.</s><s>Growth in nutrient broth on repeated subculture depends on genotype.</s><s>Strains will produce non-pigmented or yellow–orange to red-pigmented colonies when cultivated on Columbia blood agar or MYPGP agar, depending on genotype.</s><s>Different isolates may be catalase-negative or weak-delayed positive, depending on age and genotype.</s><s>The type strain of the former subspecies <em>P. larvae larvae</em>, ATCC 9545<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 7030<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 28515<sup>T</sup>), could now serve as the reference strain for <em>P. larvae</em> genotype ERIC I.</s><s>Two field isolates of genotype ERIC II, 03-522ger and 03-525ger, have been deposited as DSM 16115 and DSM 16116, respectively.</s><s>All Swedish and Finnish field isolates of genotype ERIC II, as well as two German isolates of genotype ERIC II, 00-1163ger and 03-522ger, have been deposited at CCUG.</s><s>A table detailing all strains deposited at CCUG with the respective accession numbers is available as Supplementary Table S1 in IJSEM Online).</s><s>Only one reference strain of genotype ERIC III (Gilliam 2=NRRL NRS-1684=LMG 16252) is available, originating from a single isolation (Gilliam &#x0026; Dunham, 1978).</s><s>Several type and reference strains for the former subspecies <em>P. larvae pulvifaciens</em>, ATCC 49843<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 3615<sup>T</sup>=LMG 6911<sup>T</sup>), LMG 16247 and CCUG 7427, can now serve as reference strains for the <em>P. larvae</em> genotype ERIC IV.</s></p></content></protolog>