<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5721_nm.826" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.826" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.826" rank="species">Azospirillum doebereinerae</organism><reference id="rid.5721"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Eckert</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weber</surname><given-names>O.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kirchhof</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Halbritter</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stoffels</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hartmann</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Azospirillum doebereinerae sp. nov., a nitrogen-fixing bacterium associated with the C4-grass Miscanthus.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>17</fpage><lpage>26</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11211255</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Azospirillum doebereinerae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Azospirillum doebereinerae</i> (doeb«er.ein.er.ae. N.L. gen. fem. n. <i>doebereinerae</i> of Döbereiner, in honour of Johanna Döbereiner, who isolated and characterized many <i>Azospirillum</i> spp. and other diazotrophic plant-associated bacteria and greatly stimulated the whole field of rhizosphere microbiology, plant-associated nitrogen fixation and plant growth promotion by root-colonizing diazotrophs)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The bacteria are Gram-negative curved rods or S-shaped, 1.0-1.5 μm in width, 2.0-30 μm in length (longer cells occur especially in alkaline semi-solid NFb or JNFb media) and motile with a winding or snake-like movement.</s><s>A single polar flagellum is observed when the cells are grown in liquid medium.</s><s>Ageing cells contain intracellular granules.</s><s>Cells are not encapsulated.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is 30 °C and no growth occurs at 37 °C.</s><s>The best growth is observed at pH values between 6.0 and 7.0.</s><s>The metabolism is of a typical respiratory nature; arabinose, D-fructose, gluconate, glycerol, malate, mannitol and sorbitol can be used as carbon sources.</s><s>Dinitrogen fixation occurs in microaerobic nitrogen-limited conditions.</s><s>Microaerobic dinitrogen-fixing-dependent growth occurs with malate, sorbitol, mannitol, fructose and glycerol.</s><s>Catalase, oxidase and urease activities are positive and gelatin is not hydrolysed.</s><s>NO<sup>-</sup><sub>3</sub> is reduced to NO<sup>-</sup><sub>2</sub>.</s><s>The G+­C content of the DNA is 69.6 ± 3 mol%.</s><s>The most closely related species, according to 16S rRNA sequence data, are <i>Azospirillum lipoferum</i>, <i>Azospirillum largimobile</i> and <i>Azospirillum brasilense</i>.</s><s>The type strain is GSF71<sup>T</sup> (=DSM13131<sup>T</sup>) and its G­+C content is 70.7 mol%.</s><s>The bacterium is associated - as far as is known - with the roots of <i>Miscanthus sinensis</i> cv. `Giganteus' and <i>Miscanthus sacchariflorus</i> and occurs also in the rhizosphere soil of these plants.</s></p></content></protolog>