<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6831_nm.10190" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10190" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10190" rank="species">Azorhizobium doebereinerae</organism><reference id="rid.6831"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Moreira</surname><given-names>F.M.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cruz</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Faria</surname><given-names>S.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Marsh</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martínez-Romero</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pedrosa</surname><given-names>F.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pitard</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>J.P.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Azorhizobium doebereinerae sp. Nov. Microsymbiont of Sesbania virgata (Caz.) Pers.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>29</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>197</fpage><lpage>206</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2005.09.004</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16564956</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Azorhizobium doebereinerae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>[doe.ber.ein’erae, N.L. gen. n. doebereinerae, named in honour of Johanna Döbereiner, an outstanding Brazilian microbiologist (1924–2000)]</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic gram-negative, non-spore-forming rods, isolated from <em>S. virgata</em> root nodules, strains can establish an effective nitrogen-fixing symbiosis by forming root nodules.</s><s>They are also able to induce ineffective root nodules in <em>Sesbania rostrata</em>, <em>Phaseolus vulgaris</em> and <em>Macroptilium atropurpureum</em> and pseudo-nodules on <em>S. rostrata</em> stems.</s><s>Cells are approximately 0.6–0.9 μm wide and 1.5 long (<a href="#fig5">Fig. 5</a>) and they are motile by means of two to four lateral flagella.</s><s>These characteristics distinguish the species from the other species of the genus, <em>A. caulinodans,</em> which has cells 0.5–0.6 μm in diameter <a href="#bib9">[9]</a> and only one lateral flagellum in liquid medium but can be peritrichous in solid medium.</s><s>Members of the species grow in PY, TY and YM but not in LB medium.</s><s>They are able to grow in N-free semi-solid LO modified medium by fixing nitrogen.</s><s>Colonies are visible after 3–4 days in YMA, where they reach 1 mm diameter and have a translucent appearance with little exopolysaccharide production, characteristics that are quite similar to <em>A. caulinodans</em>.</s><s>All strains exhibited very similar total protein profiles obtained by polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis (SDS-PAGE).</s><s>They are not able to use sucrose, mannitol or glucose as sole carbon sources, however they are able to use lactic acid.</s><s>Strains have a distinct SSU-rRNA gene sequence and low levels of DNA–DNA hybridization with the type strain of its closest phylogenetic relative <em>A. caulinodans</em> (between 25% and 33%) and with <em>Bradyrhizobium japonicum</em> and <em>B. elkanii</em> reference and type strains (15% and 11.8%, respectively).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is UFLA1-100<sup>T</sup> (=BR5401<sup>T</sup>, LMG9993<sup>T</sup>, SEMIA6401<sup>T</sup>) isolated from root nodules of <em>S. virgata</em> (Caz.) Pers. grown in Seropédica, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</s></p></content></protolog>