<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8593_nm.13631" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13631" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13631" rank="species">Streptococcus henryi</organism><reference id="rid.8593"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Milinovich</surname><given-names>G.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Burrell</surname><given-names>P.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pollitt</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bouvet</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trott</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptococcus henryi sp. nov. and Streptococcus caballi sp. nov., isolated from the hindgut of horses with oligofructose-induced laminitis.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>262</fpage><lpage>266</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65063-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18175719</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptococcus henryi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptococcus henryi</em> [hen.ry′i. N.L. gen. n. <em>henryi</em> named in honour of Dr Dick Peter Henry (AM) (1924–2003), a highly respected Australian veterinarian and microbiologist].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-motile ovoids, typically occurring in pairs or short chains.</s><s>When grown anaerobically for 24 h on sheep blood agar, colonies are round, flat, shiny, 2 mm in diameter, off-white in colour and exhibit <em>α</em>-haemolysis.</s><s>Cells are facultatively anaerobic and catalase-negative.</s><s>Cells react to streptococcal group D antisera and are able to grow in the presence of 40 % bile and 0.016 % potassium tellurite, but do not grow in the presence of 6.5 % NaCl.</s><s>In API 20 Strep and Rapid ID32 Strep kits, cells are able to produce acid from starch, glycogen, inulin, lactose, maltose, mannitol, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pullulan, sucrose and trehalose, but not from d-arabinose, l-arabinose, cyclodextrin, melezitose, raffinose, ribose, sorbitol or tagatose.</s><s>Cells do not produce acetoin (Voges–Proskauer-negative) or hydrolyse arginine or hippurate, but do hydrolyse aesculin.</s><s>Positive for alanyl-phenylalanyl-proline arylamidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and leucine aminopeptidase, but negative for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, glycyl tryptophan arylamidase, <em>β</em>-mannosidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase and urease.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 38.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 126<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-1484<sup>T</sup> =DSM 19005<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the caecum of a horse with oligofructose-induced laminitis.</s></p></content></protolog>