<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12613_nm.22140" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22140" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22140" rank="species">Mucilaginibacter myungsuensis</organism><reference id="rid.12613"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Joung</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Joh</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mucilaginibacter myungsuensis sp. nov., isolated from a mesotrophic artificial lake</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1506</fpage><lpage>1519</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.022798-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20656811</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Mucilaginibacter myungsuensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mucilaginibacter myungsuensis</em> (myung.su.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>myungsuensis</em> pertaining to Myungsu, the name of the mesotrophic freshwater lake from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile, aerobic rods, 0.7–0.8 µm in diameter and 1.4–1.5 µm long.</s><s>Colonies on R2A are pale yellow, mucoid, convex and round and approximately 5 mm in diameter after 2 days at 25 °C.</s><s>Good growth occurs on blood agar, TSA and R2A agar.</s><s>No growth occurs on DNA test agar or MacConkey agar.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–1.0 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 0.5 %), at pH 5–9 (optimum pH 7) and at 10–30 °C (optimum 30 °C).</s><s>Oxidase and catalase activities and aesculin hydrolysis activity are present, but arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase and l-phenylalanine deaminase activities are absent.</s><s>Casein and starch are hydrolysed, but gelatin and tyrosine are not.</s><s>Citrate is not utilized.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are produced.</s><s>In the API ZYM gallery, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase and α-fucosidase activities are present, but lipase (C14), α-chymotrypsin, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase and α-mannosidase activities are absent.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon sources in Biolog GN2 microplates: cellobiose, d-fructose, gentiobiose, α-d-glucose, maltose, sucrose, l-glutamic acid and l-proline.</s><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized: α-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, i-erythritol, l-fucose, d-galactose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, lactulose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl β-d-glucoside, d-psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, α-, β- and γ-hydroxybutyric acids, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, α-ketobutyric acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, d- and l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d- and l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, γ-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-α-glycerol phosphate, α-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>The major fatty acids are summed feature 3 (iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>) and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 46.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, HMD1056<sup>T</sup> ( = KCTC 22746<sup>T</sup>  = CECT 7550<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a mesotrophic freshwater lake in Wangsan, Yongin, Gyeonggi, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>