<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3782_nm.876" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.876" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.876" rank="species">Acetobacter orientalis</organism><reference id="rid.3782"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lisdiyanti</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kawasaki</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seki</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamada</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Uchimura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Komagata</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Identification of Acetobacter strains isolated from Indonesian sources, and proposals of Acetobacter syzygii sp. nov., Acetobacter cibinongensis sp. nov., and Acetobacter orientalis sp. nov.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>119</fpage><lpage>131</lpage><source id="120">The Journal of General and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Gen Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-1260</issn><essn>1349-8037</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12483554</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Acetobacter orientalis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Acetobacter orientalis</i> (o.ri.en'ta.lis. M. L. adj. <i>orientalis</i> "oriental," referring to the region where the strains were isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative rods measuring from 0.6 to 0.8 by 2.0–3.0 μm, and mostly motile with peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Colonies are circular, convex, glistening, and non-pigmented.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Positive for catalase, oxidation of ethanol to acetic acid, oxidation of acetate and lactate to carbon dioxide and water, growth at 20 to 37°C, at pH 3.5 to 8.0, in the presence of 0.35% acetic acid (pH 3.5), in the presence of 5% D-glucose, and in the presence of 2 to 7% ethanol, production of D-gluconate and 2-keto-Dgluconate from D-glucose, and acid production from Dglucose, ethanol, and <i>n</i>-propanol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Weakly positive for growth at 42°C, at pHs 3.0 and 9.0, in the presence of 20% D-glucose, and in the presence of 10% ethanol.</s><s>Variable for acid production from L-arabinose, D-xylose, D-galactose, and D-mannose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Negative for oxidase, gelatinase, reduction of nitrate, production of cellulose, water soluble-brown pigment, H<sub>2</sub>S, indole, ammonia from L-arginine, and γ-pyrones from both D-glucose and D-fructose, production of 5-keto-D-gluconate and 2,5-diketo-D-gluconate from D-glucose, ketogenesis from glycerol, growth in the presence of 30% D-glucose and in the presence of 15% ethanol, and acid production from D-fructose, Lsorbose, D-arabinose, L-rhamnose, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, glycerol, trehalose, sucrose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, raffinose, dulcitol, methanol, and starch.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major quinone is Q-9.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base composition ranges from 52.0 to 52.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolation sources are canna flower, fruits (starfruit and coconut), and traditional fermented foods (curd of tofu and tempe) in Indonesia.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is 21F-2<sup>T</sup> (=NRIC 0481<sup>T</sup>=IFO 16606<sup>T</sup>=JCM 11195<sup>T</sup>), and was isolated from canna flower (<i>Canna hybrida</i>), of which the G+C content is 52.3 mol%</s></p></content></protolog>