<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7441_nm.7765" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7765" rank="family">Chlamydiaceae</organism><reference id="rid.7441"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Everett</surname><given-names>K.D.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bush</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Andersen</surname><given-names>A.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended description of the order Chlamydiales, proposal of Parachlamydiaceae fam. nov. and Simkaniaceae fam. nov., each containing one monotypic genus, revised taxonomy of the family Chlamydiaceae, including a new genus and five new species, and standards for the identification of organisms.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>415</fpage><lpage>440</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-2-415</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10319462</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the family <i>Chlamydiaceae</i></s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The family <i>Chlamydiaceae</i> was previously described by Rake (1957). In accordance with rRNA analyses and corroborating sequence data, the emended family <i>Chlamydiaceae</i> is divided into two genera. Rules 39a and 39b of the International Code of Nomenclature of Bacteria state that when a genus is subdivided, the original generic name must be retained by the genus containing the original type species (Lapage et al., 1992). Therefore, the genus name <i>Chlamydia</i> must remain with <i>Chlamydia trachomatis</i>, which contains A/Har-13<sup>T</sup>, the original type strain. A new name, <i>Chlamydophila</i>, has been coined for the genus containing non-<i>Chlamydia trachomatis</i>-like species and strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The family <i>Chlamydiaceae</i> includes current members of the order <i>Chlamydiales</i> that have &#x003C;10% overall 165 rRNA gene diversity, &#x003C;10% overall 23s rRNA gene diversity, a genome size of 1.0-1.24 Mbp, either one or two ribosomal operons in each genome, no tRNA in the 16s-23s intergenic spacer, little or no muramic acid, and the antigenic LPS trisaccharide αKdo-(2→8)-αKdo-(2→4)-αKdo.</s><s>The G + C content for the <i>Chlamydiaceae</i> spp. is about 40%: 42-7 1.4 mol% according to Moulder et al. (1984) and 40.5±1.5 mol% according to Cox et al. (1988), using thermal denaturation methods; 39.5±0.3 mol% according to Fukushi &#x0026; Hirai (1992) using an HPLC method.</s><s>Among the nearly 100 16s rRNA genes that have been analysed for the <i>Chlamydiaceae</i>, the gene from strain B577 is most similar to a consensus sequence for the family (Table 3).</s><s>Therefore, to be identified as a member of the <i>Chlamydiaceae</i>, the 16s rRNA gene of a new chlamydia-like isolate should have &#x003E;90 % identity with the 16s rRNA gene of B577 (accession no. D85709).</s><s>The <i>Chlamydiaceae</i> are Gram-negative.</s><s>Host-cell ATP is known to be required by some strains of <i>C. psittaci</i> and <i>C. trachomatis</i>, and may possibly be a requirement for all members of this family.</s><s>The extracellular osmotic stability of the <i>Chlamydiaceae</i> EBs is maintained by a complex of disulfide-cross-linked envelope proteins.</s><s>These include a major outer-membrane protein (MOMP; translation product of ompA) with a molecular mass of 40 kDa, a hydrophilic cysteine-rich 60 kDa protein, and a low-molecular-mass cysteine-rich bacterial lipoprotein.</s><s>When chlamydiae infect cells, the disulfide cross-links within and among these envelope proteins become chemically reduced, allowing transformation of EBs into RBs.</s><s>Penicillin binding studies and genetic analyses indicate that at least some of the genes that are required for the synthesis of peptidoglycan are present in the chlamydial genome.</s><s>However, chlamydiae do not contain muramic acid, indicating that chlamydial cell walls do not contain significant amounts of peptidoglycan.</s><s>The bright flickering appearance, varying in intensity and duration, that is seen in chlamydiae-filled inclusions using visible light microscopy, suggests some degree of bacterial motility for strains of <i>C. trachomatis</i>, <i>C. trachomatis</i>-like swine strains, <i>C. psittaci</i> strains FP Baker, 6BC<sup>T</sup>, VS1, CP3 and B577, and <i>C. pecorum</i> strain IPA (A.</s><s>A.</s><s>Andersen, unpublished data).</s><s>Many, but not all, members of the <i>Chlamydiaceae</i> possess an extrachromosomal plasmid of about 7.5 kbp (Table 4).</s><s>These plasmids exhibit 60-80% interspecies conservation of sequence (Thomas et al., 1997), and shared features suggest that these plasmids have a monophyletic origin.</s><s>These shared features include the conserved organization of eight open reading frames and an iteron in the origin of replication, which may regulate plasmid copy number (Nördstrom, 1990; Thomas et al., 1997).</s><s>The iteron consists of four highly conserved tandem repeats.</s><s>Plasmid copy number in some strains may also be regulated by antisense RNA (Nordstrom, 1990 ; Thomas et al., 1997).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The family <i>Chlamydiaceae</i> is distinguished from <i>Simkaniaceae</i> by 16s rRNA sequence differences (18.6±0.1%), 23s rRNA sequence differences (18.6±0.3%), and by the absence of detectable <i>Chlamydiaceae</i>-specific Kdo trisaccharide antigen in '<i>Simkania</i>' using a family-specific mAb (Kahane et al., 1999).</s><s>The <i>Chlamydiaceae</i> spp. are distinguished from '<i>Candidatus</i> Parachlamydia' by 16s rRNA sequence differences (14.9±0.7 %), 23s rRNA sequence differences (17.7±0.5%), and by the variable responses of '<i>Candidatus</i> Parachlamydia' EBs to Gram staining (Amann et al., 1997; R.</s><s>J.</s><s>Birtles, personal communication).</s><s>Members of the <i>Chlamydiaceae</i> can be readily identified and differentiated by signature sequence analysis (Figs 3 and 4).</s><s>The type genus for the family <i>Chlamydiaceae</i> is <i>Chlamydia</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>