<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1865_nm.9611" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9611" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9611" rank="species">Tetrathiobacter kashmirensis</organism><reference id="rid.1865"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ghosh</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bagchi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mandal</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dam</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roy</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Tetrathiobacter kashmirensis gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel mesophilic, neutrophilic, tetrathionate-oxidizing, facultatively chemolithotrophic betaproteobacterium isolated from soil from a temperate orchard in Jammu and Kashmir, India</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1779</fpage><lpage>1787</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63595-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16166666</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Tetrathiobacter kashmirensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Tetrathiobacter kashmirensis</em> (kash.mir.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>kashmirensis</em> of Kashmir, after the name of the province from where the original strains of the species were isolated.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Can reduce nitrate to nitrite, utilize ammonium salts and urea but not glutamate, aspartate or nitrate as the nitrogen source and requires no yeast extract or vitamins for growth.</s><s>Can grow in 1 M NaCl.</s><s>The following sole carbon compounds are assimilated chemo-organotrophically: succinate, citrate, malate, acetate, d-fructose, d-glucose, d-xylose, d-lactose, d-galactose, l-glutamate, l-lysine, l-arabinose and l-cysteine.</s><s>None of following compounds are utilized: benzoate, sucrose, glycerol, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-isoleucine, <em>myo</em>-inositol, oxalate, mandelate, d-mannitol, d-raffinose, dl-lactate, l-tyrosine, l-threonine and l-serine.</s><s>Utilization of d-mannose, d-maltose, l-arginine, l-tryptophan and l-aspartic acid as the sole carbon source is strain dependent.</s><s>The following fatty acid components are present: 12 : 0, an unknown fatty acid having an equivalent chain-length of 13·957, 14 : 0, summed feature 2, summed feature 3, 16 : 0, 17 : 0 cyclo, 17 : 0, 16 : 0 3-OH, 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, 18 : 0, 19 : 0 cyclo <em>ω</em>8<em>c</em>, 19 : 0 10-methyl and 20 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is WT001<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 22695<sup>T</sup>=MTCC 7002<sup>T</sup>) and its characteristics are as described above for the species.</s><s>In addition, the type strain utilizes d-mannose, l-tryptophan and l-aspartic acid but not maltose or l-arginine as single heterotrophic substrates.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 55·1 mol% (by HPLC).</s><s>All strains of the species identified to date have been isolated from bulk soils of a temperate orchard in Srinagar, Jammu and Kashmir, India.</s></p></content></protolog>