<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4195_nm.2666" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2666" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2666" rank="species">Pseudomonas plecoglossicida</organism><reference id="rid.4195"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nishimori</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kita-Tsukamoto</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wakabayashi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas plecoglossicida sp. nov., the causative agent of bacterial haemorrhagic ascites of ayu, Plecoglossus altivelis.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>83</fpage><lpage>89</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10826790</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudomonas plecoglossicida</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudomonas plecoglossicida</i> (ple.co.glos.si.ci'da. M.L. masc. n. <i>Plecoglossus</i> systematic name of a fish genus; L. suffix masc. n. -<i>cida</i> killer ; M.L. masc. n. <i>plecoglossicida</i> the killer of <i>Plecoglossus</i>, the genus to which ayu belongs)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative rods (0.5-1x2.5-4.5 μm), and are motile by means of polar multitrichous flagella, and in some cases exhibit single or no flagellum.</s><s>Intracellular granules of poly-β-hydroxybutyrate are not accumulated.</s><s>Metabolism is oxidative.</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures between 10 and 30 °C in the presence of 0.5% (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Catalase and cytochrome oxidase are produced.</s><s>Fluorescent pigment is produced weakly on King medium B.</s><s>Hydrolysis of gelatin, starch and Tween 80 is negative.</s><s>Lecithinase is not produced.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase is produced.</s><s>Lysine and ornithine are not decarboxylated.</s><s>These organisms are not able to form levan from sucrose.</s><s>They reduce nitrate to nitrite but do not denitrificate it to N<sub>2</sub> gas.</s><s>They are haemolytic on blood agar.</s><s>They utilize the following substrates as sole carbon sources for growth: caprate, succinate, citrate, L-alanine, β-alanine, L-aspartate, L-glutamate, L-arginine, ltyrosine, glucose, D-fructose, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate, D-malate, propylene glycol, ethanol, <i>n</i>-butanol, phenyl acetate, glycine, L-leucine, L-valine, L-lysine, L-ornithine, L-citrulline, L-histidine and L-phenylalanine.</s><s>They do not use the following compounds as sole carbon sources: maltose, cellobiose, lactose, starch, inulin, L-threonine, mannitol, D-xylose, L-arabinose, L-rhamnose, D-mannose, D-galactose, sucrose, trehalose, adipate, D-(-)-tartrate, L-(­+)-tartrate, <i>m</i>-tartrate, erythritol, sorbitol, <i>m</i>-inositol, adonitol, geraniol, phenol, testosterone, L-tryptophan, L-kynurenine, anthranilate or nicotinate.</s><s>The following enzymes are produced (determined by using API ZYM): alkaline phosphatase, caprylate esterase (C<sub>8</sub>), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase and phosphoamidase.</s><s>The following enzymes are not produced (determined by using API ZYM): butyrate esterase (C<sub>4</sub>), myristate lipase (C<sub>14</sub>), cystine arylamidase, chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase or α-fucosidase.</s><s>The G­+C content of the DNA is 62.8 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is FPC 951<sup>T</sup>; it has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection, Manassas, VA, USA, as strain ATCC 700383T.</s><s>This strain was isolated in 1994 from bacterial haemorrhagic ascites of ayu (<i>Plecoglossus altivelis</i>) in Tokushima Prefecture, Japan.</s><s>One additional strain, FPC 941 (=ATCC 700384), which was isolated in 1994 from the diseased ayu in Shiga Prefecture in Japan, is a reference strain of this species.</s></p></content></protolog>