<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4403_nm.6292" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6292" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6292" rank="species">Gordonia amicalis</organism><reference id="rid.4403"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brown</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oldfield</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gilbert</surname><given-names>S.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Iliarionov</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Gordonia amicalis sp. nov., a novel dibenzothiophene-desulphurizing actinomycete</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>2031</fpage><lpage>2036</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11155977</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Gordonia amicalis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Gordonia amicalis</i> (am.i.cal'is. L. adj. <i>amicalis</i> pertaining to friendship, reflecting the collaborative nature of the study)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, slightly acid-alcohol-fast actinomycete which forms short rods and coccoid elements.</s><s>Red colonies are formed on modified Bennett's, ISP 2 and peptone-yeast-extract agars.</s><s>Neither aerial hyphae nor diffusible pigments are produced.</s><s>Adipic acid, arbutin, glycerol, sodium fumarate, sodium propionate and sodium salicylate (but not N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, D-arabinose, betaine, D-cellobiose, sodium oxalate or 1-propanol) are used as sole sources of carbon for energy and growth.</s><s>The organism grows in the presence of oleic acid (0.8%, v/v) and zinc chloride (0.001%, w/v), within the temperature range 10-40°C and within the pH range 5.5-10.</s><s>Starch is degraded but hypoxanthine, tributyrin, Tween 80, tyrosine and xanthine are not degraded.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Aesculin, allantoin, arbutin and urea are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Cells contain major amounts of meso-A<sub>2</sub>pm, arabinose and galactose.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>), though substantial amounts of MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>) are present.</s><s>The mycolic acids have 50-58 carbon atoms.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 64.2 mol%, as determined using the HPLC procedure.</s><s>The organism was isolated from a garden soil in the vicinity of Perm, Russia.</s><s>The type strain is strain IEGM<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 44461<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 9899<sup>T</sup>).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Gordonia amicalis</i> strain IEGM<sup>T</sup> is able to grow in mineral media containing dibenzothiophene as the sole source of sulphur and in the presence of an organic compound as a source of carbon and energy, using the same pathway as <i>Rhodococcus erythropolis</i> strain IGTS8 (Oldfield et al., 1997, 1998).</s><s>It is unable to grow using benzothiophene as a sole source of sulphur (C.</s><s>Oldfield &#x0026; S.</s><s>C.</s><s>Gilbert, unpublished results).</s><s>The presence of the dibenzothiophene-desulphurization pathway in the <i>G. amicalis</i> strain is consistent with the emerging status of the gordoniae as a source of metabolic diversity rivalling that of the rhodococci.</s><s>Other gordoniae possessing desulphurization pathways include <i>Gordonia</i> sp. strain CYSK1 (Rhee et al., 1998) and <i>G. aichiensis</i> strain 51 (Finkel'shtein et al., 1999), both of which are reported to desulphurize dibenzothiophene, and <i>G. desulfuricans</i> strain 213E, which desulphurizes benzothiophene (Gilbert et al., 1998; Kim et al., 1999).</s><s>In addition, Kummer et al. (1999) isolated <i>G. alkanivorans</i> strain HKI<sup>T</sup> (DSM 44369<sup>T</sup>), which is capable of growth using an alkane as the sole source of carbon and energy, while Linos et al. (1999) described <i>G. polyisoprenivorans</i> strain Kd2<sup>T</sup>, a rubber-degrading bacterium isolated from an automobile tyre.</s></p></content></protolog>