<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8365_nm.13307" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13307" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13307" rank="species">Desulfovibrio marinisediminis</organism><reference id="rid.8365"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Takii</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hanada</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hase</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tamaki</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Uyeno</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sekiguchi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsuura</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Desulfovibrio marinisediminis sp. nov., a novel sulfate-reducing bacterium isolated from coastal marine sediment via enrichment with Casamino acids.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2433</fpage><lpage>2438</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65750-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18842870</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Desulfovibrio marinisediminis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Desulfovibrio marinisediminis</em> (ma.ri.ni.sed′i.mi′nis. L. adj. <em>marinus</em> of the sea, marine; L. gen. n. <em>sediminis</em> of a sediment; N.L. gen. n. <em>marinisediminis</em> of a marine sediment).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Vibrioid cells (0.7–1.0 μm wide and 1.0–3.5 μm long) rapidly change to a coccoid form after the exponential phase of growth.</s><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of single polar flagella.</s><s>Mesophilic.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 37 °C and at a pH around 7.5.</s><s>Grows with NaCl at 0.5–35 g l<sup>−1</sup> (optimally at 20–25 g l<sup>−1</sup>).</s><s>Strictly anaerobic.</s><s>Able to use sulfate, sulfite and thiosulfate as electron acceptors, with the production of sulfide, but unable to use elemental sulfur, nitrate, fumarate, acrylate or 2,4,6-tribromophenol.</s><s>Does not show disproportionation of thiosulfate.</s><s>Hydrogen, formate, lactate, pyruvate, fumarate, malate, succinate, ethanol, propanol, glycerol, glycine, alanine, serine, aspartate, Casamino acids, peptone and yeast extract are used as electron donors.</s><s>Pyruvate, fumarate, Casamino acids, peptone and yeast extract can be utilized fermentatively.</s><s>Acetate, propionate, butyrate, benzoate, butanol, valine, leucine, isoleucine, proline, methionine, phenylalanine, tryptophan, threonine, cysteine, asparagine, glutamine, glutamate, histidine, lysine, arginine, gelatin and sugars (glucose, mannose, fructose, maltose and sucrose) are not used as sole substrates for growth.</s><s>Desulfoviridin, <em>c</em>-type cytochromes and catalase are present.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 46.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, C/L2<sup>T</sup> (=NMRC 101113<sup>T</sup>=JCM 14577<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17456<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a Casamino acid-containing enrichment culture inoculated with anoxic sediment collected from a highly eutrophic area of Tokyo Bay, Japan.</s></p></content></protolog>