<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7210_nm.6212" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6212" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6212" rank="species">Corynebacterium durum</organism><reference id="rid.7210"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Riegel</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ruimy</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Renaud</surname><given-names>F.N.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Freney</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prevost</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jehl</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Monteil</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Corynebacterium singulare sp. nov., a new species for urease-positive strains related to Corynebacterium minutissimum</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>1092</fpage><lpage>1096</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-4-1092</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9336912</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Corynebacterium singulare</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Corynebacterium singulare</i> (sin.gu.la're. L. adj. <i>singulare</i>, single, unique)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on the data obtained for the two strains included in this study.</s><s>The bacteria are gram-positive, irregular rods.</s><s>All cells are nonmotile, do not form spores, and are arranged in typical V-shaped forms or palisades.</s><s>They are not acid fast.</s><s>They are catalase positive, oxidase negative, and facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Nonhemolytic colonies (1 to 2 mm in diameter) are grayish and smooth after 24 h at 37°C on sheep blood agar.</s><s>The colonies are circular and slightly convex with entire margins.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Urea and tyrosine are degraded, but gelatin and esculin are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, maltose, and sucrose but not from lactose, glycogen, ribose, trehalose, mannitol, and D-xylose.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, pyrrolidonyl-arylamidase, and pyrazinamidase are produced but α-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-galactosidase, and N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase are not produced.</s><s>Cells utilize D-glucose, D-fructose, D-trehalose, D-mannose, sucrose, maltose, glycerol, D-turanose, L-malate, phenylacetate, putrescine, DL-lactate, caprylate, L-histidine, succinate, fumarate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, L-aspartate, L-glutamate, D-alanine, L-serine, propionate, and L-tyrosine as sole carbon sources.</s><s>D-Ribose, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, and D-gluconate are not utilized.</s><s>Propionic acid is not produced by anaerobic metabolism of glucose.</s><s>The cell wall contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, arabinose, galactose, and short-chain mycolic acids (C<sub>26</sub> to C<sub>36</sub>).</s><s>The main fatty acids are oleic, hexadecanoic, and octadecanoic acids.</s><s>The G + C content of the DNA is 62 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is strain IBS B52218 (= CCUG 37330);it was isolated from a human semen specimen.</s></p></content></protolog>