<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5857_nm.5416" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5416" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5416" rank="species">Lactobacillus paraplantarum</organism><reference id="rid.5857"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Curk</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hubert</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bringel</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lactobacillus paraplantarum sp. nov., a new species related to Lactobacillus plantarum.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>595</fpage><lpage>598</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-2-595</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15551474</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Lactobacillus paraplantarum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Lactobacillus paraplantarum</i> (pa. ra. plan. tar' um. Gr. prep. <i>para</i>, resembling; L. gen. n. <i>plantarum</i>, specific epithet of L. <i>plantarum</i>; M. L. adj. <i>paraplantarum</i>, resembling L. <i>plantarum</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod shaped and occur singly, in pairs, and sometimes in short chains.</s><s>Colonies grown on MRS agar are round, smooth, dome shaped, and creamy colored.</s><s>Cells are nonmotile, Gram positive, catalase negative, and facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Grows at 15 (slowly), 30, and 37°C, but not at 45°C.</s><s>Grows in MRS medium at pHs 5 and 7, but not at pH 4.</s><s>Grows in MRS medium containing NaCl up to a concentration of 8%.</s><s>Facultatively heterofermentative, producing D-(-)- and L-(+)-lactic acids.</s><s>All strains ferment ribose, galactose, D-glucose, D-fructose, D-mannose, mannitol, N-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, melezitose, β-gentiobiose, and gluconate.</s><s>All strains do not ferment glycerol, erythritol, D-arabinose, D-xylose, L-xylose, adonitol, β-methyl-xyloside, L-sorbose, dulcitol, inositol, α-methyl-D-mannoside, α-methy-D-glucoside, inulin, starch, glycogen, xylitol, D-lyxose, D-tagatose, D-fucose, L-fucose, L-arabitol, 2-keto-gluconate, and 5-keto-gluconate.</s><s>Some strains ferment L-arabinose, L-(+)-rhamnose, sorbitol, D-raffinose, D-turanose, and D-arabitol.</s><s>Esculin is hydrolyzed.</s><s>Arginine is not deaminated.</s><s>The peptidoglycan is characterized by the presence of <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA ranges from 44 to 45 mol%.</s><s>Strains have been isolated from beer and human feces in France.</s><s>The type strain is CNRZ 1885.</s><s>In most respects, the description of the type strain resembles that of the species.</s><s>The type strain was isolated from beer, ferments D-raffinose, and does not ferment L-arabinose, sorbitol, D-turanose, and D-arabitol.</s><s>Its DNA G+C content is 44 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>