<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2027_nm.11061" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11061" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11061" rank="species">Streptococcus orisuis</organism><reference id="rid.2027"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Takada</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hirasawa</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptococcus orisuis sp. nov., isolated from the pig oral cavity</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1272</fpage><lpage>1275</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64741-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17551042</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptococcus orisuis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptococcus orisuis</em> (o.ri.su′is. L. gen. n. <em>oris</em> of the mouth; L. gen. n. <em>suis</em> of a pig; N.L. gen. n. <em>orisuis</em> from/of the mouth of a pig).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-spore-forming cocci, 0.5–0.75 μm in diameter, that occur in pairs or in short chains.</s><s>Colonies on blood agar are small and white, 0.75–1.0 mm in diameter and non-haemolytic at 37 °C.</s><s>On mitis salivarius agar, colonies are small, dark blue and crinkled.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and catalase-negative.</s><s>No Lancefield carbohydrate antigens (streptococcal grouping kit; Oxoid) are detected.</s><s>According to API systems, strains produce acid from d-glucose, galactose, d-fructose, d-mannose, mannitol, sorbitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, d-raffinose, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside and d-tagatose.</s><s>Alanine phenylalanine proline arylamidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, acid phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and glucosyltransferase are produced.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase are not produced.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer test is positive.</s><s>Hippurate hydrolysis test is negative.</s><s>Resistant to bacitracin.</s><s>An adhesive, insoluble glucan is produced from sucrose.</s><s>The bacterium is cariogenic when monoassociated with specific pathogen-free rats.</s><s>The serotype is type <em>d</em>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 43 mol %.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, NUM 1001<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 14035<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18307<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from clinical specimens from the oral cavities of pigs.</s></p></content></protolog>