<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6636_nm.1279" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1279" rank="genus">Rhizobium</organism><reference id="rid.6636"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kuykendall</surname><given-names>L.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martínez-Romero</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kerr</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sawada</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A revision of Rhizobium Frank 1889, with an emended description of the genus, and the inclusion of all species of Agrobacterium Conn 1942 and Allorhizobium undicola de Lajudie et al. 1998 as new combinations: Rhizobium radiobacter, R. rhizogenes, R. rubi, R. undicola and R. vitis.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>89</fpage><lpage>103</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11211278</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emendation of the genus <i>Rhizobium</i></s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhizobium</i> (Rhi.zo'bi.um. Gr. n. <i>rhiza</i> a root; Gr. n. <i>bios</i> life; M. L. neut. n. <i>Rhizobium</i> that which lives in a root)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rods, 0.5-1.0x1.2-3.0 μm.</s><s>Non-sporeforming.</s><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Motile by one to six flagella.</s><s>Insertion usually peritrichous or peritrichous/subpolar.</s><s>Fimbriae have been described on some strains.</s><s>Aerobic, possessing a respiratory type of metabolism with oxygen as the terminal electron acceptor.</s><s>Optimum temperature for growth is 25-30 °C; some species can grow at temperatures above 40°C.</s><s>Optimum pH, 6.7; range, pH 4-10.</s><s>Generation times of <i>Rhizobium</i> strains are 1.5-3.0 h.</s><s>Colonies are usually white or beige, circular, convex, semi-translucent or opaque, raised and mucilaginous, usually 2-4 mm in diameter within 3-5 d on yeast/mannitol}mineral salts agar(YMA).Growthon carbohydrate media is usually accompanied by copious amounts of extracellular polysaccharide slime.</s><s>Pronounced turbidity develops after 2 or 3 d in aerated or agitated broth.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic, utilizing a wide range of carbohydrates and salts of organic acids as sole carbon sources, without gas formation.</s><s>Cellulose and starch are not utilized.</s><s>Produce an acidic reaction in mineral salts medium containing mannitol or other carbohydrates.</s><s>Ammonium salts, nitrate, nitrite and most amino acids can serve as nitrogen sources.</s><s>Strains of some species will grow in a simple mineral salts medium with vitamin-free casein hydrolysate as the sole source of both carbon and nitrogen, but strains of many species require one or more growth factors such as biotin, pantothenate or nicotinic acid.</s><s>Peptone is poorly utilized.</s><s>Casein, starch, chitin and agar are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Members of <i>Rhizobium</i> are distinguished from those in the related genera, <i>Mesorhizobium</i> and <i>Phyllobacterium</i>, by differences in growth rate, fatty acid profiles and 16S rDNA sequence.</s><s>Closely related in terms of 16S rDNA sequence similarity, all known <i>Rhizobium</i> species include strains that induce hypertrophisms in plants.</s><s>Hypertrophisms in most species are root nodules either with or without symbiotic nitrogen fixation, while in other species they occur as unregulated oncogenic (tumorigenic or rhizogenic) growths.</s><s>Some cells of symbiotic bacterial species enter root hair cells of leguminous plants (family <i>Leguminosae</i>) via invagination or by wounds (`crack entry') and elicit the production of root nodules, wherein the bacteria engage as intracellular symbionts, usually fixing nitrogen.</s><s>Many well-defined nodulation (nod) and nitrogen fixation (nif) genes are clustered on large or megaplasmids (pSyms).</s><s>Plant-host specificity is usually for a few legume genera but may, in some strains, extend to many legume genera and is largely determined by the chemical structure of lipochitooligosaccharide Nod factors produced (De!narie! et al., 1992, 1996).</s><s>These highly specific ` cell-walllike ' molecules induce nodule organogenesis in the absence of bacteria.</s><s>Strains of plant-pathogenic <i>Rhizobium</i> (previously <i>Agrobacterium</i>) species invade the crown, roots and stems of many dicotyledonous and some gymnospermous plants via wounds.</s><s>Self-proliferating tumours are induced by the genetic transfer of a small DNA region carried on large tumour-inducing Ti or hairy-root-inducing Ri plasmids into the host plant genome.</s><s>Plasmid transfer between species results in the expression and stable inheritance of the particular plant-interactive properties of the plasmid-donor species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 57-66 mol% (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i>).</s><s>The type species is <i>Rhizobium leguminosarum</i> (Frank 1879) Frank 1889, 338<sup>AL</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>