<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2002_nm.11037" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11037" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11037" rank="species">Sphingomonas mucosissima</organism><reference id="rid.2002"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Reddy</surname><given-names>G.S.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garcia-Pichel</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sphingomonas mucosissima sp. nov. and Sphingomonas desiccabilis sp. nov., from biological soil crusts in the Colorado Plateau, USA</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1028</fpage><lpage>1034</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64331-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17473253</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sphingomonas mucosissima</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sphingomonas mucosissima</em> (mu.co.sis′si.ma. L. fem. superlative adj. <em>mucosissima</em> slimiest, referring to the appearance of the strains).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are orange-pigmented, extremely mucoid, convex, round and smooth.</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile rods of 0.75 μm diameter and 1.7 μm in length.</s><s>Grows at 15–30 °C, but not at 37 °C, with an optimum growth temperature of 25 °C and a pH of 7.</s><s>Can tolerate up to 2.5 % NaCl.</s><s>Cells are positive for catalase, oxidase, phosphatase and do not grow on test media plates of lipase and urease.</s><s>Negative result in tests for <em>β</em>-galactosidase, gelatinase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, phenylalanine deaminase and arginine dihydrolase activities.</s><s>Can hydrolyse starch, but not aesculin.</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate to nitrite and cannot produce H<sub>2</sub>S gas.</s><s>Negative results in methyl red, Voges–Proskauer, indole and Simmons' citrate tests.</s><s>Can utilize acetate, l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, glucose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, inulin, d-melibiose, pyruvate, d-ribose, sucrose, sorbose, sucrose, d-xylose, l-alanine as sole carbon source but not adonitol, citrate, dulcitol, dextran, ethanolamine, fumaric acid, glucuronic acid, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, lactic acid, d-levulose, d-maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, myristic acid, oxalic acid, raffinose, d-rhamnose, l-sorbose, sorbitol, succinate, trehalose, l-arginine, l-aspartic acid, l-aspargine, l-cysteine, l-glycine, l-glutamine, l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-phenylalanine and l-proline.</s><s>Cells are sensitive to (per disc): azithromycin (30 μg), bacitracin (10 U), ceftriaxone (30 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), ciprofloxacin (5 μg), doxycycline (30 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), novobiocin (30 μg), rifampicin (30 μg), tetracycline (30 μg) and vancomycin (30 μg), but resistant to aztreonam (30 μg), carbenicillin (100 μg), cephalothin (30 μg), colistin (10 μg), erythromycin (2 μg), ethambutol (50 μg), ethionamide (30 μg), nitrofurantoin (150 μg), penicillin (10 μg), polymyxin B (300 μg), streptomycin (10 μg), sulfisoxazole (300 μg), sulfathiazole (300 μg) and trimethoprim (5 μg).</s><s>The fatty acids and their contribution to the total fatty acid content are listed in Table 2.</s><s>The major lipids present are phosphatidylglycerol (PG), cardiolipin (DPG), phosphatidyldimethyl ethanolamine (PDE) and sphingoglycolipid (SGL).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain CP173-2<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-1239<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17494<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a biological soil crust from the Colorado Plateau, USA.</s></p></content></protolog>