<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12644_nm.22184" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22184" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22184" rank="species">Streptomyces sanyensis</organism><reference id="rid.12644"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sui</surname><given-names>J.-L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>X.-X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Qu</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>H.-L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>H.-P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xie</surname><given-names>Q.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ruan</surname><given-names>J.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hong</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces sanyensis sp. nov., isolated from mangrove sediment</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1632</fpage><lpage>1637</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.023515-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20693357</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptomyces sanyensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomyces sanyensis</em> (sa.ny.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>sanyensis</em> pertaining to Sanya, a coastal city in Hainan Province, where the mangrove sediment was collected from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive actinomycete.</s><s>Forms extensively branched substrate mycelium and aerial hyphae that differentiate into long <em>Rectiflexibiles</em> spore chains of up to 20 spores.</s><s>Spores are elliptical or short rods with a smooth surface.</s><s>Pale yellow to dark yellowish-brown colonies that carry white to grey aerial spore mass are formed on ISP media 1, 2, 3, 4 and 6, modified Bennett’s agar, Czapek’s agar and nutrient agar.</s><s>No diffusible pigment is produced on any of the media tested.</s><s>Melanin is produced on peptone-yeast extract-iron agar and tyrosine agar.</s><s>Negative in tests for starch hydrolysis, nitrate reduction, l-tyrosine degradation, aesculin degradation and carboxymethyl-cellulose degradation; positive for gelatin liquefaction, milk coagulation and peptonization, H<sub>2</sub>S production, urease production, catalase production, degradation of Tweens 20 and 80, growth on cellulose, and the oxidase test.</s><s>Dextrin, glucose, mannose, maltose, glycerol, d-ribose and trehalose are utilized as sole carbon sources, but l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-galactose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, inulin, lactose, d-mannitol, raffinose, l-rhamnose, salicin, sucrose and d-xylose are not.</s><s>l-Alanine, d-arginine, l-asparagine, glycine, l-histidine, l-serine and l-ornithine are metabolized as sole nitrogen sources, but not l-cysteine, l-hydroxyproline, l-methionine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline or l-valine.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 5.0–9.0 (optimum, pH 7.0), at 10–40 °C (optimum, 28 °C) and with 0–10 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum, 0 % NaCl).</s><s>The cell wall contains ll-DAP with nearly the same amount of <em>meso</em>-DAP.</s><s>Whole-cell hydrolysates contain galactose and glucose.</s><s>Predominant menaquinones are MK-9(H<sub>8</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>).</s><s>The diagnostic phospholipid is phosphatidylethanolamine.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, 10-methyl C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω9<em>c</em> and summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is 219820<sup>T</sup> ( = CGMCC 4.5626<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 42014<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a composite mangrove sediment sample collected in Sanya, Hainan Province, China, and exhibits cytotoxic activity against the human colon tumour cell line HCT-116.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 73.24 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>