<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8425_nm.13506" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13506" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13506" rank="species">Paenibacillus contaminans</organism><reference id="rid.8425"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chang</surname><given-names>P.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus contaminans sp. nov., isolated from a contaminated laboratory plate.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>125</fpage><lpage>129</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.001495-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19126735</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus contaminans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus contaminans</em> (con.ta′mi.nans. L. part. adj. <em>contaminans</em> contaminating).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Facultatively anaerobic, Gram-variable, sporulating, motile and rod-shaped, 0.8–1.0 μm in diameter and 2.0–3.0 μm in length.</s><s>Grows at pH 6.5–8.0, 0–2.0 % NaCl and 10–37 °C.</s><s>Positive for DNase, cytochrome oxidase and catalase.</s><s>Negative for lipase (corn oil) and hydrolysis of skimmed milk, starch, and Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80.</s><s>Positive (API 20E) for <em>β</em>-galactosidase, citrate utilization, acetoin production, and acid production from glucose, arabinose and rhamnose, but negative for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, urease, trytophan deaminase, gelatinase, H<sub>2</sub>S production, indole production, and acid production from mannitol, inositol, sorbitol, sucrose, melibiose and amygdalin.</s><s>In the API 20NE enzyme assay, positive for <em>β</em>-galactosidase, aesculin hydrolysis and assimilation of glucose and maltose, but negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose acidification, arginine dihydrolase, urease, gelatinase, and assimilation of arabinose, mannose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate and phenylacetate.</s><s>In the API ZYM enzyme assay, positive for C4 esterase, leucine arylamidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, but negative for alkaline phosphatase, C8 lipase, C14 lipase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>The following carbon sources were utilized (positive with the API 50 CH system): glycerol, d-glucose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, amygdalin, arbutin, cellobiose, maltose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, gentiobiose and turanose.</s><s>The following substrates were not utilized as carbon sources (negative with the API 50 CH system): erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, aesculin, ferric citrate, salicin, d-lactose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate and potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Resistant to sulfamethoxazole (23.75 μg) plus trimethoprim (1.25 μg); sensitive to ampicillin (10 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg), novobiocin (30 μg), penicillin G (10 U), rifampicin (5 μg), streptomycin (10 μg) and tetracycline (30 μg).</s><s>The major fatty acid components are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The major cellular phospholipids are phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylethanolamine.</s><s>MK-7 is the predominant isoprenologue.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CKOBP-6<sup>T</sup> (=BCRC 17728<sup>T</sup>=LMG 24216<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a contaminated laboratory plate.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 51.2 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>