<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7115_nm.1578" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1578" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1578" rank="species">Xanthobacter tagetidis</organism><reference id="rid.7115"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Padden</surname><given-names>A.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kelly</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wood</surname><given-names>A.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Xanthobacter tagetidis sp. nov., an organism associated with Tagetes species and able to grow on substituted thiophenes.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>394</fpage><lpage>401</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-2-394</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9103627</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Xanthobacter tagetidis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Xanthobacter tagetidis</i> (ta.ge.ti'dis. M. L. n., of <i>Tagetes</i>, the marigold genus of flowering plants)</s></p><p class="description"><s>(i) Morphology.</s><s>Colonies are low, entire, smooth, convex, mucoid, and egg yolk yellow.</s><s>Cells are gram-negative, pleomorphic, short, fat rods (0.5 by 1.0 μm) with large, dark inclusion bodies which may occur at one or both ends of the cells.</s><s>Motile.</s><s>No spores are produced.</s><s>A capsule is formed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(ii) Cellular characteristics.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 68 ± 2 mol% (as determined by the UV spectroscopy and melting point methods).</s><s>The predominant ubiquinone is coenzyme Q10, and some coenzyme Q8 is present.</s><s>Ribulose bisphosphate carboxylase is present in thiosulfate-grown cells (108 ± 6 nmol of CO<sub>2</sub> fixed/min/mg of cell extract protein).</s><s>Catalase and oxidase positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(iii) Growth characteristics.</s><s>Obligately aerobic but potentially microaerophilic.</s><s>For growth on T2C the temperature range is 4 to 43°C, the optimum temperature is 28 to 31°C; and the optimum pH is 7.6 to 7.8 (pH range tested, pH 6.8 to 8.7).</s><s>The initial rates of growth on T2C in static cultures are similar to those in shaken cultures.</s><s>Static cultures produce less slime than shaken cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(iv) Metabolic characteristics.</s><s>Chemoorganotroph characterized by an ability to grow on substituted thiophenes; facultative chemolithoautotroph on inorganic sulfur compounds and hydrogen; facultative methylotroph.</s><s>Uses molecular dinitrogen as a nitrogen source.</s><s>Utilizes T2A, T2C, thiophene-3-carboxylate, dibenzothiophene, furan-2-carboxylate, pyrrole-2-carboxylate, thiosulfate, tetrathionate (with added CO<sub>2</sub>), sulfide, hydrogen (with added CO<sub>2</sub>), carbonyl sulfide, carbon disulfide, methylamine (with added CO<sub>2</sub>), methanol, dimethyl sulfide, methanethiol, formate, acetate, ethanol, succinate, pyruvate, citrate, yeast extract, nutrient broth, galactose, sucrose, fructose, and glucose.</s><s>In sulfate-free medium, T2C supports growth as a sole source of carbon, energy, and sulfur.</s><s>Inhibited by ampicillin and chloramphenicol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(v) Habitat.</s><s>The organism has been isolated only from the root balls of marigold plants (<i>T. patula</i> and <i>T. erecta</i>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>(vi) Type strain. <i>X. tagetidis</i> TagT2C was isolated from a <i>T. patula</i> root ball and has been deposited as the type strain of the species in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen as strain DSM11105.</s><s>This strain is one of several apparently identical strains isolated from <i>T. patula</i> and <i>T. erecta</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>We propose that on the basis of its morphological and physiological characteristics, including its facultative autotrophy on hydrogen and thiosulfate, its ability to grow by using dinitrogen as a nitrogen source, the G+C content of its DNA, its levels of 16s rDNA sequence homology with other <i>Xanthobacter</i> spp., and its association with thiophene-producing marigold plants, strain TagT2C should be included in the genus <i>Xanthobacter</i> as the type strain of a new species, <i>X. tagetidis</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>