<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3464_nm.3012" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3012" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3012" rank="species">Vibrio viscosus</organism><reference id="rid.3464"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lunder</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sørum</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Holstad</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mowinckel</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phenotypic and genotypic characterization of Vibrio viscosus sp. nov. and Vibrio wodanis sp. nov. isolated from Atlantic salmon (Salmo salar) with 'winter ulcer'.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>427</fpage><lpage>450</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10758846</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Vibrio viscosus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Vibrio viscosus</i> (vis.co'sus. L. masc. adj. <i>viscosus</i> viscous, because of its thread-forming, adherent colonies)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Conforms to the description of the family <i>Vibrionaceae</i> and of the genus <i>Vibrio</i> (Baumann &#x0026; Schubert, 1984).</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative, short or elongated, nonspore-forming rods that are motile by a single polar flagellum when grown on solid or in liquid media.</s><s>Colonies on bovine blood agar containing 2% NaCl after 48 h incubation at 15 °C are round, translucent, grey, haemolytic, non-swarming and non-luminescent.</s><s>Colonies are viscous and can form long threads when removed from the agar surface.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Produce acid, but not gas aerobically and anaerobically from d-glucose.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4-25 °C, but not at 30°C.</s><s>NaCl is required for growth, at 1-4%.</s><s>Negative reactions in tests for indole production and Voges±Proskauer.</s><s>A majority of the strains (95%) have a negative methyl red reaction.</s><s>Lysine is decarboxylated, but arginine dihydrolase and ornithine decarboxylase tests are negative.</s><s>Gelatin, casein, DNA, Tween 80, urea and lecithin are hydrolysed.</s><s>A majority of the strains hydrolyse starch.</s><s>Alginate and aesculin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Acid is produced from dextrin and D-galactose, but not from L-arabinose, cellobiose, glycerol, inositol, lactose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, melibiose, raffinose, L-rhamnose, salicin, D-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose nor D-xylose.</s><s>Susceptible to 2,4-diamino-6,7-diisopropylpteridine (O/129 vibriostatic agent), penicillin, ampicillin, sulphamethizol, oxytetracycline and oxolinic acid.</s><s>The enzymes alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, butyrate esterase, caprylate esterase, myristate lipase, leucine arylamidase and naphthol phosphohydrolase are produced.</s><s>A minority of the strains (5%) produce valine arylamidase.</s><s>Chymotrypsinase, trypsinase, cystine arylamidase, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucoronidase, acetyl β-glucosaminidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase and α-mannosidase are not produced.</s><s>Isolated from and pathogenic for Atlantic salmon, plaice and perhaps other marine fish, causing an ulcerative skin disease called winter ulcer.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain of <i>Vibrio viscosus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>V. viscosus</i> is NVI 88/478<sup>T</sup>, isolated in 1988 in Norway from an Atlantic salmon with winter ulcer.</s><s>The characteristics of the type strain are identical to those given in the species description.</s><s>The G+­C content is 42.5 mol%.</s><s>This strain has been deposited at the National Collection of Industrial and Marine Bacteria (Aberdeen, UK) as NCIMB 13584<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>