<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2867_nm.958" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.958" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.958" rank="species">Rickettsia bellii</organism><reference id="rid.2867"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Philip</surname><given-names>R.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Casper</surname><given-names>E.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Anacker</surname><given-names>R.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cory</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hayes</surname><given-names>S.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Burgdorfer</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yunker</surname><given-names>C.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rickettsia bellii sp. nov.: a tick-borne rickettsia, widely distrbuted in the United States, that is distinct from the spotted fever and typhus biogroup.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>94</fpage><lpage>106</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-1-94</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rickettsia bellii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Rods 0.3 to 0.4 by 2.0 to 3.0 μm during the log phase of growth, sometimes 10.0 to 15.0 μm under suboptimal conditions of tissue culture. Cells possess an outer slime layer and a trilaminar cell wall with the inner leaflet about twice as thick as the outer leaflet, but no discernible microcapsular layer. Optimally cultivated in cell culture (Vero, <i>X. laevis</i>, and tick cell lines [Yunker and Cory, submitted for publication]). Many strains give rise to plaques and a characteristic cytopathic effect in Vero cells, which distinguishes them from other plaque-forming rickettsiae. An obligate intracellular parasite. Replication by binary fission occurs primarily in the cytoplasm and rarely in the nuclei of host cells. Nonpathogenic or of low pathogenicity for chicken embryos when the yolk sac route of inoculation is used. A few strains can be established in chicken embryos, but growth of rickettsiae in yolk sacs is never luxuriant. Nonpathogenic for randomly bred adult white Swiss mice, guinea pigs, and <i>M. pennsylvanicus</i>. Limited replication of some strains may occur in voles, but these strains cannot be maintained by serial passage in this vertebrate. Cells possess surface antigens that cross-react with convalescent sera from Rocky Mountain spotted fever, epidemic typhus, and murine typhus patients, as determined by indirect immunofluorescence. Cross-reactions may also occur with antisera prepared in guinea pigs, rabbits, and goats against <i>R. rickettsii</i>, but not in randomly bred white Swiss mice. Protein composition as determined by SDS-PAGE is unlike the proteip compositions of TG and SFG rickettsiae. The G+C content of the DNA is approximately 30 mol% (as determined by thermal denaturation), a level similar to the G+C content of TG rickettsiae but lower than the G+C content of SFG organisms. The type strain, RML 369-C, is held in The Rocky Mountain Laboratories Collection.</s></p><p class="description"><s>At present, there is no evidence that rickettsiae of the <i>R. bellii</i> serogroup cause human illness (Philip and Casper, manuscript in preparation).</s><s>Nothing is known about the mechanism for maintenance of <i>R. bellii</i> in nature except that strains of the <i>R. bellii</i> serogroup have been recovered from two argasid and six ixodid tick species from various regions of the United States and that transovarial transmission and transstadial transmission of these organisms have been demonstrated in <i>D. andersoni</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>