<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1530_nm.6089" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6089" rank="genus">Aureobacterium</organism><reference id="rid.1530"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Takeuchi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sakane</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of six new species in the genus Aureobacterium and transfer of Flavobacterium esteraromaticum Omelianski to the genus Aureobacterium as Aureobacterium esteraromaticum comb. nov.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>555</fpage><lpage>564</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-3-555</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8347513</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <i>Aureobacterium</i> Collins, Jones, Keddie, Kroppenstedt, and Schleifer.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Aureobacterium</i> (Aur.e.o.bac.te'ri.um. L. adj. <i>aureus</i>, golden; Gr. neut. n. <i>bakterion</i>, a small rod; M. L. neut. n. <i>Aureobacterium</i>, small golden rod)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The salient characteristics of this genus, based on the description of Collins et al. (2) and our own observations, are as follows.</s><s>In young cultures, small irregular rods occur; some cells are arranged at an angle, forming V shapes.</s><s>In older cultures (ca. 3 to 7 days) the rods are shorter, but a marked rod-coccus cycle (characteristic of the genus <i>Arthrobacter</i>) is not observed.</s><s>Primary branching is uncommon.</s><s>The rods are gram positive and not acid fast; metachromatic granules are not formed; endospores are not formed.</s><s>Growth occurs on suitable solid media in air.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by 6.5% NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs at ca. 10 to 40°C; the optimum temperature is ca. 25 to 30°C.</s><s>Obligately aerobic.</s><s>Slow and weak oxidative production of acid from some carbohydrates occurs.</s><s>Nutritionally exacting.</s><s>Some organic acids are utilized.</s><s>Catalase positive.</s><s>Oxidase negative.</s><s>Indole negative.</s><s>Esculin is hydrolyzed.</s><s>Noncellulolytic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan is based on D-ornithine or D-hydroxyornithine (type B2β of Schleifer and Kandler [22]) ([L-Hsr]-D-Glu-Gly-D-Orn) or on D- and L-ornithine (type B2α of Schleifer and Kandler [22]) ([L-Orn]-D-Glu-D-Orn).</s><s>The glycan moiety of peptidoglycan contains glycolyl and acetyl residues.</s><s>Contains no mycolic acids.</s><s>The nonhydroxylated fatty acids are predominantly anteiso- and iso-methyl branched-chain acids; small amounts of straight-chain saturated acids and traces of monounsaturated acids may be present.</s><s>Menaquinones are the sole respiratory quinones.</s><s>The major menaquinone isoprenologs contain various numbers of isoprene units (10, 11, 12, 13, and 14 isoprene units).</s><s>The polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, and unidentified glycolipids.</s><s>DNA base compositions range from 65 to 76 mol% G+C (8).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <i>Aureobacterium liquefaciens</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>