<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6237_nm.6824" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6824" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6824" rank="species">Streptomyces acidiscabies</organism><reference id="rid.6237"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lambert</surname><given-names>D.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Loria</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces acidiscabies sp. nov.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>393</fpage><lpage>396</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-4-393</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptomyces acidiscabies</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces acidiscabies</i> (ac.i.di.sca'bies. L. adj. <i>acidus</i>, acid; L. n. <i>scabies</i>, mange; <i>acidiscabies</i>, referring to the ability of the organism to cause acid scab of potatoes)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Spores are 0.4 to 0.5 by 0.6 or 0.9 to 1.1 μm, smooth, and white (reddish on certain high-pH media) and are borne in mature flexuous chains containing 20 or more spores.</s><s>A diffusible pigment is produced which is red above pH 8.3 and golden yellow below pH 8.3.</s><s>Melanin is not produced.</s><s>L-Arabinose, D-fructose, D-glucose, D-mannitol, rhamnose, sucrose, and D-xylose are used as carbon sources, but not raffinose is not.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of this species is 71 mol%.  <i>S. acidiscabies</i> differs from all other streptomycetes that cause typical raised or pitted symptoms and have white spores, red pigment, and acid tolerance.</s><s>It differs in at least one major characteristic from all other strains described in the International <i>Streptomyces</i> Project having red pigments or spores.</s><s>Species characteristics, including those which differentiate <i>S. acidiscabies</i> from other pathogens, are shown in Table 1. <i>S. acidiscabies</i> is placed in the genus <i>Streptomyces</i>, as it possesses typical morphology and cell walls with the LL-diaminopimelic acid isomer.</s><s>To date, <i>S. acidiscabies</i> has been isolated only from potatoes (<i>Solanum tuberosum</i>), and its pathogenicity on other species has not been determined.</s><s>The ability of this species to persist in soil is relatively poor, and it is usually transmitted by infected seed tubers (10).</s><s>The five strains which we studied (strains RL-45, RL-104, RL-110<sup>T</sup> [=ATCC 49003<sup>T</sup>], RL-182, and U30 [=ATCC 490041) are presently the only examples of the species in culture.</s><s>Specific characteristics of type strain RL-110 (=ATCC 49003) are listed in Table 1 or are mentioned above.</s><s>The phenotypes of other strains studied previously by Bonde and McIntrye (2) are in agreement with the phenotype described here.</s><s>All strains appear to differ very little from each other.</s></p></content></protolog>