<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1236_nm.1038" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1038" rank="genus">Rhodobacter</organism><reference id="rid.1236"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trüper</surname><given-names>H.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pfennig</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rearrangements of the species and genera of the phototrophic "purple nonsulfur bacteria."</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>340</fpage><lpage>343</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-3-340</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhodobacter</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhodobacter</i> (Rho.do.bac'ter. Gr.n. <i>rhodon</i> rose; M. L.masc.n. <i>bacter</i> equivalent of Gr.neut.n. <i>bakterion</i> rod; M.L.masc.n. <i>Rhodobacter</i> red-colored rod)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species of <i>Rhodobacter</i> is <i>Rhodobacter capsulatus</i> (Molisch 1907) van Niel 1944 comb. nov.</s><s>Other species: <i>Rhodobacter sphaeroides</i> van Niel 1944 comb. nov., <i>Rhodobacter sulfidophilus</i> Hansen and Veldkamp 1973 comb. nov., and <i>Rhodobacter adriaticus</i> Neutzling et al. 1984 comb. nov.</s><s>All species were formerly included in the genus <i>Rhodopseudomonas</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All species of this genus have very similar properties.</s><s>The cells are ovoid to rod shaped and motile or nonmotile, divide by binary fission, and have vesicular photosynthetic membranes.</s><s>All species require thiamine, and most of them require biotin and a different third vitamin as growth factors.</s><s>The three species analyzed reduce sulfate via 3'-phosphate adenosine 5'-phosphosulfate.</s><s>Bacteriochlorophyll <i>a</i> and carotenoids of the spheroidene group are present as photosynthetic pigments.</s><s>All species contain the large type of cytochrome <i>c</i><sub>2</sub> (<i>Rhodobacter adriaticus</i> has not been analyzed yet) and Q-10 as the sole quinone component.</s><s>The species are very similar according to 16s rRNA analyses and DNA-rRNA hybridization studies.</s><s>Differences occur in the oxidation products of sulfide, which is oxidized by all four species.</s><s>The species can also be differentiated by their lipid compositions.</s><s>Despite the small variation in their phenotypic properties, DNA-DNA hybridization shows only a low degree of homology among the DNA molecules of the different species.</s><s>A study of 17 strains of <i>Rhodobacter capsulatus</i>, <i>Rhodobacter sphaeroides</i>, and <i>Rhodobacter sulfidophilus</i> revealed levels of homology of less than 30% (one exception was a value of 40%) between DNA molecules of different species.</s></p></content></protolog>