<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6116_nm.9493" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9493" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9493" rank="species">Nocardia polyresistens</organism><reference id="rid.6116"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>H.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>C.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardia polyresistens sp. nov.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1465</fpage><lpage>1470</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63352-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16014467</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Nocardia polyresistens</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Nocardia polyresistens</em> [poly.re.sis′tens. Gr. adj. <em>polus</em> many; L. part. adj. <em>resistens</em> resisting; N.L. part. adj. <em>polyresistens</em> resisting many (antibiotics)].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, catalase-positive and slightly acid–alcohol-fast.</s><s>Aerial mycelium and substrate mycelium are extensively branched and fragment irregularly into rod-shaped, non-motile elements.</s><s>A pale-yellow to moderate orange–yellow substrate mycelium carries sparse to abundant, white aerial hyphae on yeast extract-malt extract agar, Czapek's agar, modified Sauton's agar, modified Bennett's agar, potato agar and nutrient agar.</s><s>A pale-yellow to yellow–white substrate mycelium bears pale-yellow to yellow–white aerial hyphae on glycerol-asparagine or inorganic salts-starch agar.</s><s>Diffusible pigments are not formed.</s><s>Ribose, glucose, mannose, fructose, sorbose, melibiose, xylose, sucrose, arabinose, galactose, maltose, lactose, cellobiose, raffinose, melezitose, mannitol, inositol, xylitol, dulcitol, adonitol, salicin, glycerol and dextrin are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources, but not rhamnose, trehalose, sorbitol, arabitol, acetate, malonate, citrate, oxalate or tartrate.</s><s>Acid is not formed from these tested carbon sources.</s><s>l-Valine, l-proline (weak), l-asparagine, l-tyrosine (weak), l-alanine and l-histidine are used as sole nitrogen sources, but not acetamide, l-hydroxyproline, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-tryptophan, l-threonine, l-glutamic acid, glycine, l-arginine, l-cysteine or phenylalanine.</s><s>Urea, xanthine, hypoxanthine, amygdalin, keratin and chitin are hydrolysed.</s><s>Tweens 20 and 80 are degraded, but not cellulose, starch, allantoin, glucosamine, aesculin, DNA or adenine.</s><s>Tests for gelatin hydrolysis, nitrate reduction, melanin production, milk coagulation and peptonization, H<sub>2</sub>S production and resistance to KCN are negative.</s><s>Grows between 28 and 37 °C, from pH 7 to 9, and in the presence of phenol at 0·1 %, but not in the presence of sodium chloride.</s><s>Resistant to lysozyme, penicillin G, ciprofloxacin, vancomycin, polymyxin B, erythromycin, terramycin, aureomycin (weak), tobramycin, gentamicin sulfate, amikacin, netilmicin, novobiocin, kanamycin and oleandomycin but sensitive to tetracycline, streptomycin and chloramphenicol.</s><s>The cell wall of strain YIM 33361<sup>T</sup> contains <em>meso</em>-DAP.</s><s>Whole-cell sugars are galactose and arabinose.</s><s>MK-8(H<sub>4</sub><em>ω</em>-cycl.) is the major menaquinone and a minor amount of MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>) is also present.</s><s>The phospholipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylinositol and phosphatidylinositol mannosides.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (22·14 %), <em>cis</em>6,9-C<sub>18 : 2</sub> (10·86 %), <em>cis</em>9-C<sub>18 : 1</sub> (10·05 %), C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (21·16 %) and 10-methyl-C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (10·5 %).</s><s>The G+C content of genomic DNA of the type strain is 65·6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM 33361<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AA 204004<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 19027<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil in Yunnan, China.</s></p></content></protolog>