<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12895_nm.22713" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22713" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22713" rank="species">Acinetobacter rudis</organism><reference id="rid.12895"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vaz-Moreira</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Novo</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hantsis-Zacharov</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lopes</surname><given-names>A.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gomila</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nunes</surname><given-names>O.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Manaia</surname><given-names>C.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Halpern</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Acinetobacter rudis sp. nov., isolated from raw milk and raw wastewater</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2837</fpage><lpage>2843</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.027045-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21239566</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Acinetobacter rudis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Acinetobacter rudis</em> (ru′dis. L. adj. <em>rudis</em>, -<em>is</em> raw, not processed; N.L. gen. n. <em>rudis</em> of/from raw unprocessed products).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are white, circular, convex and smooth after 24 h of incubation on PCA.</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative, strictly aerobic, non-motile coccobacilli (0.56±0.10 µm diameter).</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–37 °C, pH 5.0–9.5 and in the presence of up to 3 % NaCl.</s><s>After 7 days of incubation, no growth is observed at 6 or 40 °C or in the presence of 5 % NaCl.</s><s>Growth does not occur in an anaerobic atmosphere and nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Haemolysis is not observed.</s><s>Utilization of Simmons’ citrate (growth) is positive.</s><s>Aesculin is not hydrolysed.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced.</s><s>Glucose is not fermented.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glucose.</s><s>Produces the enzymes alkaline and acid phosphatase, esterase C4, esterase lipase C8, leucine arylamidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase; produces valine and cystine arylamidases weakly.</s><s>The enzymes α- and β-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine and ornithine decarboxylase, urease, tryptophan deaminase, gelatinase, lipase (C14), trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, β-glucuronidase, α- and β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase are not produced.</s><s>Sole carbon sources assimilated include l-malate, citrate, phenylacetate, sodium malonate, sodium acetate, l-alanine, l-histidine, ethanol, sodium benzoate, 2,3-butanediol, l-phenylalanine and propionic, lactic, capric, valeric, 3-hydroxybutyric and 4-hydroxybenzoic acids.</s><s>l-Leucine is assimilated weakly after 48 h of incubation.</s><s>Carbon sources not assimilated include d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, potassium gluconate, adipate, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, inositol, sucrose, itaconic acid, suberic acid, potassium 5-ketogluconate, glycogen, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid, l-serine, salicin, melibiose, l-fucose, d-sorbitol, potassium 2-ketogluconate, l-proline, l-arginine, putrescine, l-aspartate and histamine.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω9<em>c</em> and C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>/iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and the major respiratory quinones are ubiquinones Q-9 and Q-8.</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content is 39–40 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain G30<sup>T</sup> ( = LMG 26107<sup>T</sup>  = CCUG 57889<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 24031<sup>T</sup>  = CECT 7818<sup>T</sup>) is the type strain, isolated from raw milk.</s></p></content></protolog>