<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5957_nm.8524" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8524" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8524" rank="species">Brevundimonas mediterranea</organism><reference id="rid.5957"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Fritz</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Strömpl</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nikitin</surname><given-names>D.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lysenko</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Abraham</surname><given-names>W.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Brevundimonas mediterranea sp. nov., a non-stalked species from the Mediterranean Sea.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>479</fpage><lpage>486</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02852-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15653922</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Brevundimonas mediterranea</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Brevundimonas mediterranea</em> (me.di.ter.ra′ne.a. N.L. fem. adj. <em>mediterranea</em> of the Mediterranean Sea).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is as that of the genus with the following additions.</s><s>Colonies measure 2–5 mm in diameter on MB agar, have a soft and slimy consistency with a glistening surface and smooth margin, a slightly concave shape and are cream-white coloured with a characteristic slightly brownish spot in the centre.</s><s>Pigmentation is not present.</s><s>Flexible, non-stalked, occasionally bent rods with a length of 1·5–4 μm and a diameter of 0·5–1·0 μm.</s><s>Some strains but not the type strain may possess a branching cell morphology.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Alkaline and acid phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), <em>β</em>- and weak <em>α</em>-glucosidase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase and trypsin activities are always positive.</s><s>Activities for the following enzymes are not detected: chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>N</em>-acetylglucosaminidase.</s><s>Urease activity is present in some strains but not the type strain.</s><s>Gelatin is not liquefied.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed.</s><s>As determined by API galleries, the following substrates are utilized by all strains: amygdalin, arbutin, cellobiose, d-fructose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, maltose, salicin and starch.</s><s>The following substrates are used as sole carbon and energy sources by some strains including the type strain: l-arabinose, fumarate, l-glutamate, dl-lactate, l(−)-malate, maltotriose, l-proline, propionate and turanose.</s><s>The following substrates were utilized by some strains but not by the type strain: adipate, l-alanine, rhamnose and l-serine.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized: d(+)-malate, malonate, maltitol, mannitol, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-galactopyranoside, methyl <em>β</em>-galactopyranoside, methyl <em>β</em>-glucopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>β</em>-xyloside, mucate, palatinose, phenylacetate, 3-phenylpropionate, protocatechuate, putrescine, (−)-quinate, d-raffinose, d(−)-ribose, d-saccharate, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, d-tagatose, d(−)-tartrate, l(+)-tartrate, <em>meso</em>-tartrate, trehalose, tricarballylate, trigonelline, tryptamine, tyrosine, l-xylitol, xylitol, d-xylose and l-xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>As measured by Biolog tests, Tween 40 and <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin serve as electron donors for the artificial electron acceptor tetrazolium violet and thus may be metabolized by all strains.</s><s>Some strains including the type strain use acetic acid, alaninamide, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, 2-aminoethanol, l-asparagine, 2,3-butanediol, dextrin, d-galactonic acid lactone, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, hydroxy-l-proline, methylpyruvate, monomethyl succinate, l-ornithine, l-pyroglutamic acid, sebacic acid, l-threonine and Tween 80 as electron donors.</s><s>l-Alanyl glycine is utilized by some strains but not by the type strain.</s><s>None of the following are used as electron donors by any strain: <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, bromosuccinic acid, dl-carnitine, formic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, glucose 1-phosphate, glucose 6-phosphate, glucuronamide, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, inosine, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, l-leucine, phenylethylamine, l-phenylalanine, d-psicose, d-serine, succinamic acid, succinic acid, sucrose, thymidine, uridine and urocanic acid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>NaCl is not strictly required but promotes growth at optimal concentrations.</s><s>The optimum NaCl concentration for growth is 1 % (w/v), with good growth at 0–3 % and no growth at 6 % or above.</s><s>Optimal growth temperature is 30 °C.</s><s>The species grows between 15 and 37 °C, but not above 42 °C.</s><s>Some strains including the type strain show weak growth at 7 °C.</s><s>Nitrogen is not fixed.</s><s>Neither nitrate nor nitrite is utilized as a terminal electron acceptor with the exception of strain V4.BO.18, which is capable of reducing nitrate to nitrite but not to nitrogen.</s><s>Polar lipids are 18 : 1/14 : 0-, 18 : 1/15 : 0-, 18 : 1/16 : 1-, 18 : 1/16 : 0-, 18 : 1/17 : 1-, 18 : 1/18 : 1-, 19 : 1/16 : 0- and 19 : 1/18 : 1-PG, 18 : 1/17 : 0-SQDG and PGLs of 1411, 1413, 1425, 1427, 1439 and 1453 Da.</s><s>The main fatty acids of the cellular hydrolysate are C<sub>18 : 1</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub>, C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em>, C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and 11-Me-C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>t</em>; the main hydroxy-fatty acid is 3-OH-C<sub>12 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The G+C content is between 67·1 and 67·5 mol%.</s><s>Main ubiquinone is Q-10 (Abraham <em>et al.</em>, 1999).</s><s>DNA–DNA relatedness between strain V4.BO.10<sup>T</sup> and <em>B. intermedia</em> ATCC 15262<sup>T</sup>, <em>B. vesicularis</em> LMG 2350<sup>T</sup> and <em>B. aurantiaca</em> DSM 4731<sup>T</sup> is 27, 33 and 33 %, respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain V4.BO.10<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 21911<sup>T</sup>=CIP 107934<sup>T</sup>) is the type strain.</s><s>The strains were isolated from water samples from the western Mediterranean Sea near Nice.</s></p></content></protolog>