<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1052_nm.2874" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2874" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2874" rank="species">Moritella yayanosii</organism><reference id="rid.1052"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nogi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kato</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic studies of extremely barophilic bacteria isolated from the Mariana Trench and description of Moritella yayanosii sp. nov., a new barophilic bacterial isolate.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>3</volume><fpage>71</fpage><lpage>77</lpage><source id="119">Extremophiles : Life Under Extreme Conditions</source><abbrev>Extremophiles</abbrev><issn>1431-0651</issn><essn>1433-4909</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s007920050101</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10086847</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Moritella yayanosii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Moritella yayanosii</i> (yayanos.ii. M. L. gen. n. yayanosii, of Yayanos, in honor of American deep-sea biologist, A. Aristides Yayanos)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod shaped; cell width ranges from 0.8 to 1.0 μm, and cell length ranges from 2 to 4 μm.</s><s>Cells are gram-negative and motile by means of a single unsheathed polar flagellum.</s><s>The bacterium is halophilic and psychrophilic.</s><s>Best growth occurs at an NaCl concentration of about 3%.</s><s>No growth occurs in the absence of NaCl, and the organism is not able to grow at atmospheric pressure at any temperature.</s><s>However, this strain is able to grow under hydrostatic pressures in the range of 60-100 MPa at 10°C.</s><s>It is a facultatively anaerobic chemoorganotroph displaying both respiratory and fermentative types of metabolism.</s><s>Catalase and cytochrome oxidase test results are positive.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-mannose but no gas is produced.</s><s>The organism does not produce H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite are not reduced.</s><s>Acid is formed oxidatively from maltose, D-mannose, and xylose.</s><s>No acid is produced from L-arabinose, cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, glycerol, myo-inositol, D-lactose, D-mannitol, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-sorbitol, sucrose, or D-trehalose.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is about 44.6mol%.</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is Q-8.</s><s>The dominant cellular fatty acids are 14:0, 14:1, 16:0, 16:1, and 22:6 (DHA).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is <i>Moritella yayanosii</i> strain DB21MT-5, which has been deposited in the Japan Collection of Microorganisms (Wako-shi, Saitama, Japan) as strain JCM 10263.</s></p></content></protolog>