<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11586_nm.18621" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.18621" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.18621" rank="species">Gemella asaccharolytica</organism><reference id="rid.11586"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ulger-Toprak</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Summanen</surname><given-names>P.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rowlinson</surname><given-names>M.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Finegold</surname><given-names>S.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Gemella asaccharolytica sp. nov., isolated from human clinical specimens</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1023</fpage><lpage>1026</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.001966-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19666813</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Gemella asaccharolytica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Gemella asaccharolytica</em> (a.sac′cha.ro.ly′ti.ca. Gr. pref. <em>a</em>- not; Gr. n. <em>saccharon</em> sugar; N.L. fem. adj. <em>lytica</em> from Gr. adj. <em>lutikos</em> able to lyse, able to loose; N.L. fem. adj. <em>asaccharolytica</em> not digesting sugar).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells stain Gram-variable and are non-motile cocci, approximately 0.5 μm in diameter.</s><s>Colonies on Brucella blood agar plates at 5 days are small, smooth, convex, circular, entire, semi-translucent, 0.4–0.5 mm in diameter and surrounded by a zone of greening (<em>α</em>-haemolysis).</s><s>Non-pigmented.</s><s>Grows under strictly anaerobic conditions and after a number of subcultures in the presence of 2 and 6 % O<sub>2</sub> and 5 % CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Negative for catalase and oxidase activity, indole production and nitrate reduction.</s><s>Asaccharolytic; acid is not produced from glucose or the following other carbohydrates: adonitol, amygdalin, arabinose, cellobiose, erythritol, fructose, galactose, glycogen, inositol, inulin, lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, xylose and xylan.</s><s>In PYG broth, moderate amounts of acetic acid and small amounts of lactic acid are produced.</s><s>Esterase lipase, esterase (weak), naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, arginine arylamidase, proline arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, tyrosine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, serine arylamidase and pyroglutamic acid arylamidase are produced.</s><s>Hippuric acid is hydrolysed.</s><s>Acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, alanyl-phenylalanyl-proline arylamidase, glycyl-tryptophan arylamidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, urease and trypsin are not produced.</s><s>Aesculin, starch and gelatin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer test is negative.</s><s>Sensitive to vancomycin (5 μg), kanamycin (1000 μg) and SPS (1000 μg) and resistant to colistin sulfate (10 μg) special-potency identification discs. <em>β</em>-Lactamase-negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, WAL 1945J<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-1630<sup>T</sup> =CCUG 57045<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a human wound infection.</s><s>Habitat is unknown.</s><s>Strains WAL 1822M and WAL 1990F are additional strains of the species.</s></p></content></protolog>