<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4511_nm.3049" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3049" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3049" rank="subspecies">Aeromonas hydrophila ranae</organism><reference id="rid.4511"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Huys</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pearson</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Denys</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cnockaert</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Inglis</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aeromonas hydrophila subsp. ranae subsp. nov., isolated from septicaemic farmed frogs in Thailand.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>885</fpage><lpage>891</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02357-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12807217</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Aeromonas hydrophila</em> subsp. <em>ranae</em> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Aeromonas hydrophila</em> subsp. <em>ranae</em> (ra′.nae. N.L. fem. n. <em>Rana</em> generic name of frog; N.L. gen. n. <em>ranae</em>, of a frog).</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains of the newly proposed subspecies were isolated from farmed frogs in Thailand.</s><s>All strains of <em>Aeromonas hydrophila</em> subsp. <em>ranae</em> display the following characteristics typical of the genus <em>Aeromonas</em>: Gram-negative straight motile rods, chemo-organotrophic with both oxidative and fermentative metabolism, and cytochrome oxidase and catalase are positive.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs after 24 h at 28 °C on TSA medium.</s><s>No brown water-soluble pigment is produced on TSA medium.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and indole are positive.</s><s>Three out of the seven strains, i.e. LMG 19709, LMG 19710 and LMG 19713, are Voges–Proskauer-positive.</s><s>Urease, tryptophan deaminase, ornithine decarboxylase and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced.</s><s>The following substrates are used as the sole carbon and energy sources: l-alanine (except strains LMG 19710 and LMG 19712), arbutin, l-arginine, l-aspartate (except strains LMG 19710 and LMG 19713), d-fructose, fumarate, d-galactose, d-gluconate, d-glucosamine, d-glucose, glycerol, l-histidine, dl-lactate, l-malate, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-maltose, l-proline, pyruvate, d-ribose, l-serine, succinate and d-trehalose.</s><s>None of the strains use acetamidocaprate, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, <em>trans</em>-aconitate, adipate, adonitol, 4-aminobutyrate, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, dl-aspartate (except strain LMG 19707<sup>T</sup>), azelate, betaine, cadaverine, caprate, d-cellobiose, l-citrulline, erythritol, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronate, glutarate, d-glutamate, l-glycine, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, inositol, isobutyrate, isovalerate, itaconate, lactose, lactulose, l-leucine, l-lysine, maltitol, d-melibiose, mesaconate, <em>α</em>-methyl d-mannoside, l-ornithine (except strain LMG 19707<sup>T</sup>), phenylacetate, l-phenylalanine, propionate, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, sorbate, d-sorbitol, spermidine, spermine, suberate, d-sucrose, l-tryptophan, l-valine, d-xylitol or d-xylose.</s><s>Acid is uniformly produced from d-glucose, d-maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose and d-trehalose, but not from adonitol, amygdalin, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, d-cellobiose, dulcitol (except strain LMG 19711), erythritol, inositol, <em>α</em>-d-melibiose, methyl-d-glucoside, lactose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, salicin, d-sorbitol, d-sucrose or d-xylose.</s><s>All strains hydrolyse the following substrates: l-alanine-<em>p</em>NA, 2-deoxythymidine-5′-<em>p</em>NP-phosphate, gelatin, bis-<em>p</em>NP-phosphate, <em>ortho</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, <em>p</em>NP-<em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>p</em>NP-phenylphosphonate, <em>p</em>NP-phosphoryl choline and l-proline-<em>p</em>NA.</s><s>None of the strains are able to hydrolyse aesculin, l-glutamate-<em>γ</em>-3-carboxy-<em>p</em>NA, <em>p</em>NP-<em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside or <em>p</em>NP-<em>β</em>-d-glucuronide.</s><s>All strains are resistant to ampicillin and penicillin but sensitive to kanamycin (except strain LMG 19711), streptomycin (except strain LMG 19711) and tetracycline.</s><s>Strains LMG 19707<sup>T</sup>, LMG 19709, LMG 19710 and LMG 19713 were resistant to nalidixic acid.</s><s>Isolated in 1994 from the liver and kidneys of septicaemic farmed frogs (<em>Rana rugulosa</em>) in Thailand.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain has been deposited in the BCCM/LMG Bacteria Collection, Ghent University (Belgium), as strain LMG 19707<sup>T</sup> and in the CCUG Culture Collection, University of Göteborg (Sweden), as strain CCUG 46211<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>