<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1694_nm.4644" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4644" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4644" rank="species">Mycoplasma collis</organism><reference id="rid.1694"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hill</surname><given-names>A.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycoplasma collis, a new species isolated from rats and mice.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>847</fpage><lpage>851</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-4-847</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycoplasma collis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycoplasma collis</i> (col'lis. L. gen. n. <i>collis</i> of a hill [intended to allude to the name, in Latinized form, of the author who described this species])</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies of strains S8B<sup>T</sup>, Gough, and LIL were visible after 2 to 3 days of incubation under both aerobic and anaerobic conditions.</s><s>The colonies (Fig. 1 ) had a typical fried-egg appearance.</s><s>The growth characteristics are shown in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No motility was observed under dark-field microscopy, and helical forms were not seen.</s><s>Liquid cultures stained by Giemsa stain showed pleomorphic forms.</s><s>The organisms were similar in ultrastructure to other mycoplasmas when they were viewed by electron microscopy.</s><s>The cells were bounded by a single unit membrane and lacked any evidence of cell wall material (Fig. 2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Filtration of the mycoplasmas showed that of 6 x 10<sup>7</sup> organisms per ml in the original dilution, reduced numbers passed through the 300-nm (6 x 10<sup>5</sup> cells per ml) and 220-nm (8 x 10<sup>4</sup> cells per ml) membranes and that no organisms passed through the 100-nm membrane.</s></p><p class="description"><s>These organisms required cholesterol (1 μg/ml) for growth.</s><s>They were susceptible to digitonin and sodium polyanethol sulfonate, with zones of growth inhibition of 9 and 7 to 8 mm, respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The strains related to strain S8B<sup>T</sup> belong to the genus <i>Mycoplasma</i>, because they are nonhelical, depend upon sterol for growth, and are susceptible to digitonin and sodium polyanethol sulfonate and because urease could not be demonstrated.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical activities are shown in Table 2.</s><s>The strains metabolized some carbohydrates (glucose, maltose, mannose, and sucrose) but did not hydrolyze arginine or ferment arabinose, arbutin, cellobiose, dulcitol. fructose, galactose, glycerol, inositol, lactose, mannitol, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, trehalose, or xylose.</s><s>They lysed but did not adsorb or agglutinate</s></p><p class="description"><s>erythrocytes.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The three strains gave similar electrophoretic protein patterns, and these patterns were distinct from those of the previously decribed rodent mycoplasmas.</s><s>The pattern of strains 58B<sup>T</sup> is compared with the pattern of <i>M. pulmonis</i> in Fig. 3.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA was denatured at midpoint temperatures of 80.75 to 81.0°C (corrected for thermal expansion) in several tests.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of 28 mol% was determined by the following equation: <i>T<sub>m</sub></i> = 69.3 + 0.41 (guanine-plus-cytosine content), where <i>T<sub>m</sub></i> is the thermal denaturation temperature (17).</s><s>This value is similar to the values obtained for other <i>Mycoplasma</i> species.</s><s>This result agreed with that obtained by A.</s><s>Liss, New York, N.Y., who examined DNA extracted from strain S8B (personal communication).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Serological techniques showed high levels of cross-reactions among the three isolates (Table 3).</s><s>No cross-reactions were detected with any of the species listed in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains 58B<sup>T</sup>, Gough, and LIL belong to the same species, as they have similar characteristics and were found to be closely related or identical in the serological tests.</s><s>As there were no cross-reactions with any of the species listed in Table 1, strain 58B<sup>T</sup> is a new species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of this species is strain 58B (= NCTC 10197)</s></p></content></protolog>