<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9153_nm.14346" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14346" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14346" rank="species">Paenibacillus pectinilyticus</organism><reference id="rid.9153"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeong</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>H.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>B.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>H.Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus pectinilyticus sp. nov., isolated from the gut of Diestrammena apicalis.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1342</fpage><lpage>1347</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.002261-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19502313</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus pectinilyticus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus pectinilyticus</em> [pec.ti′ni.ly.ti′cus. N.L. n. <em>pectinum</em> (from French n. <em>pectine</em>), pectin; N.L. adj. <em>lyticus</em> (from Gr. adj. <em>lutikos</em>), dissolving; N.L. masc. adj. <em>pectinilyticus</em> pectin-dissolving bacteria].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, catalase-positive, oxidase-positive, motile rods and have a terminal ellipsoidal spore in a swollen sporangium.</s><s>Colonies on TSB agar are round, smooth, cream-white and approximately 1–2 mm in diameter.</s><s>Single cells are slightly curved rods, measuring 2.0–3.0×0.5–0.7 μm.</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures between 15 and 30 °C in TSB medium, with optimum growth at 30 °C.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 0–0.5 % NaCl and at pH 6.0–8.7.</s><s>Good growth is observed on TSB agar when incubated under aerobic or anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Gelatin, pectin and Tween 80 are hydrolysed, but casein, cellulose, starch or xylan are not.</s><s>Positive reactions are obtained for acetoin production, citrate utilization, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and nitrate reduction.</s><s>Negative reactions are obtained for arginine dihydrolase, H<sub>2</sub>S production, indole production, phenylalanine deaminase, tryptophan deaminase and urease.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-arabinose, arbutin, fructose, aesculin, galactose, glycerol, glucose, inositol, maltose, melibiose, melezitose, mannose, mannitol, raffinose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose and turanose, but not from adonitol, d-arabinose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, d-fucose, l-fucose, glycogen, inulin, lactose, d-lyxose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucose, rhamnose, sorbose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylose, d-tagatose, xylitol or l-xylose.</s><s>MK-7 is the predominant isoprenoid quinone.</s><s>Does not contain diaminopimelic acid in the cell-wall peptidoglycan.</s><s>Cells cultured in TSB medium contain anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> as the predominant cellular fatty acid.</s><s>Major polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylmonomethylethanolamine, phosphatidylethanolamine and phosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 51.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, RCB-08<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13222<sup>T</sup>=CECT 7358<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the gut of an insect, <em>Diestrammena apicalis</em>, collected in the Daejeon district, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>