<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4450_nm.8720" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8720" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8720" rank="species">Mycobacterium parascrofulaceum</organism><reference id="rid.4450"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Turenne</surname><given-names>C.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cook</surname><given-names>V.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Burdz</surname><given-names>T.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pauls</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thibert</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wolfe</surname><given-names>J.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kabani</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium parascrofulaceum sp. nov., novel slowly growing, scotochromogenic clinical isolates related to Mycobacterium simiae</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1543</fpage><lpage>1551</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02940-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15388708</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Mycobacterium parascrofulaceum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mycobacterium parascrofulaceum</em> (pa.ra.scro.fu.la′ce.um. Gr. prep. <em>para</em> like; N.L. neut. adj. <em>scrofulaceum</em> specific epithet of a bacterial species; N.L. neut. adj. <em>parascrofulaceum</em> referring to the phenotypic resemblance of the isolate to <em>M. scrofulaceum</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Microscopy shows pleomorphic bacillary forms of AFB with moderate beading.</s><s>Strains are slowly growing and scotochromogenic and grow on Löwenstein–Jensen medium at 25–37 °C, optimally at 37 °C.</s><s>Isolates are positive for urease, 68 °C catalase and pyrazinamidase; negative for Tween 80 hydrolysis, nitrate reductase, iron uptake, tolerance to 5 % NaCl, growth on MacConkey agar, niacin, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, acid phosphatase and 3-day arylsulfatase; variable results seen for the semi-quantitative catalase test and 14-day arylsulfatase test.</s><s>Morphology and biochemical profile indistinguishable from <em>M. scrofulaceum</em>.</s><s>Isolates show <em>in vitro</em> susceptibility to rifampicin, clarithromycin, amikacin and sulfamethoxazole and resistance to isoniazid.</s><s>The organism is almost identical to MAC and some <em>M. scrofulaceum</em> by HPLC.</s><s>Various molecular targets confirm this organism as a distinct species.</s><s>16S rRNA gene sequence analysis reveals that the organism contains the characteristic short helix 18 of the <em>M. simiae</em> group and whose closest established species is the recently described <em>M. palustre</em>.</s><s>Five sequevars each of <em>hsp65</em> and ITS1 have been observed among isolates of <em>M. parascrofulaceum</em>, none corresponding to established strains of known species in public sequence databases.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, HSC-68<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-614<sup>T</sup>=DSM 44648<sup>T</sup>), was the first isolate studied in our laboratory and was representative of the most common <em>hsp65</em> or ITS1 sequevar (I) of <em>M. parascrofulaceum</em>.</s><s>Most isolates were from human respiratory samples and, in at least one case, was felt to be clinically significant, requiring anti-mycobacterial therapy.</s></p></content></protolog>