<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11908_nm.19995" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.19995" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.19995" rank="species">Succinatimonas hippei</organism><reference id="rid.11908"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Morotomi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nagai</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Watanabe</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanaka</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Succinatimonas hippei gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from human faeces</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1788</fpage><lpage>1793</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.015958-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19749029</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Succinatimonas hippei</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Succinatimonas hippei</em> (hip.pe′i. N.L. gen. masc. n. <em>hippei</em> of Hippe, named after Dr Hans Hippe for his contribution to bacteriology, especially to the classification of the family <em>Succinivibrionaceae</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of the species is as given for the genus above.</s><s>In addition, cells are 0.5–1.4×1.4–4.8 μm with round ends and occur mostly singly and rarely in pairs or in short chains.</s><s>No helical structures are observed.</s><s>Non-haemolytic and not resistant to 20 % bile.</s><s>Positive for acid production from glucose, maltose and d-xylose.</s><s>Acid production from l-arabinose is weakly positive.</s><s>Cellobiose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melezitose, raffinose, d-sorbitol, trehalose, glycerol, lactose, l-rhamnose, salicin and sucrose are not utilized.</s><s>By using the commercially available API test systems (API Rapid ID 32A and API ZYM), positive reactions are obtained for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, acid phosphatase, alanine arylamidase, arginine arylamidase, esterase (C4) and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>Negative for alkaline phosphatase, <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, arginine dihydrolase, chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, esterase lipase (C8), 6-phospho-<em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-mannosidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, proline arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, serine arylamidase, trypsin, tyrosine arylamidase and valine arylamidase.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is YIT 12066<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 22608<sup>T</sup> =JCM 16073<sup>T</sup>), isolated from human faeces.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 40.3 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>