<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1209_nm.1062" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1062" rank="genus">Hyphomonas</organism><reference id="rid.1209"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>R.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weiner</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gerbers</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Genus Hyphomonas Pongratz 1957 nom. rev. emend., Hyphomonas polymorpha Pongratz 1957 nom. rev. emend., and Hyphomonas neptunium (Leifson 1964) comb. nov. emend. (Hyphomicrobium neptunium).</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>71</fpage><lpage>73</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of the genus <i>Hyphomonas</i> nom. rev. emend.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Hyphomonas</i> (Hy.pho.mo’nas. Gr. n. <i>hyphos</i> filament; M.L. n. <i>monas</i> small motile organism; M.L. fem.n. <i>Hyphomonas</i> hypha-bearing monad)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains are gram-negative, aerobic, heterotrophic, nonsporeforming, prosthecate, and budding.</s><s>Young daughter cells are oval to pear shaped, smaller than the main body of the mother cell, and motile by means of a polar to lateral flagellum.</s><s>Branching of the hyphae is rare during normal growth.</s><s>Reproduction normally occurs by budding from the tip of the hypha, although bud formation directly from the mother cell may occur infrequently.</s><s>Detailed investigations on the cell cycle have been described previously (10, 18).</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains investigated thus far are catalase positive, peroxidase	positive, coagulase negative, non-proteolytic, non-saccharolytic, nonpathogenic, and not acid-fast.</s><s>Rapid lysis takes place in saline ethylenediaminetetraacetate supplemented with 1% sodium dodecyl sulfate.</s><s>The cells contain both poly-β-hydroxybutyrate and polyphosphate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Good growth occurs on Casamino Acids, blood agar, and other rich media; the addition of sea salts is required by some strains and is stimulatory to others (4).</s><s>Growth in a defined medium supplemented with a mixture of glutamic acid, aspartic acid, methionine, and serine as substrates and with or without added growth factors (depending on strain), has been reported (4).</s><s>Some strains exhibit brown pigmentation and alpha-hemolysis on salt-supplemented sheep blood agar.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth ranges from 22 to 42°C; the optimum pH ranges from 7.0 to 8.6.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Hyphomonas</i> cells are 0.5 to 1.0 μm in diameter, approximately 1.0 to 3.0 μm long, prolate, and spheroid.</s><s>The narrow pole grows a tubelike extension (prostheca or hypha) about 0.2 to 0.3 μm wide, which is commonly one to five times the length of the main cell body.</s><s>Older cultures often contain abnormal cell types, including giant cells, spindles, and triangular forms, occasionally with more than one prostheca.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Motility is due to a single, subpolarly inserted flagellum which can be retained after the development of a stalk and new daughter cell.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Staining is gram negative and not acid-fast.</s><s>No endospores.</s><s>Cells stain well with anilin dyes, neutral red, gentian violet, etc.</s><s>The use of Lugol iodine as a mordant facilitates the staining of the narrow hyphae.</s><s>Best results are obtained with silver impregnation.</s><s>Upon isolation on solid media, colonies appear as smooth or rough types.</s><s>The smooth colonies are round, convex, watery, and translucent and can be emulsified easily.</s><s>The smooth organisms carry heavy capsules on the mother cells but usually not on the hyphae or buds.</s><s>Rough colonies are rare; they are smaller and dry, forming a central crater after several days.</s><s>The organisms cannot be readily emulsified, and suspensions thus remain granular.</s><s>They lack capsules and are nonmotile.</s><s>Smooth forms are stable variants, and rough forms split into both smooth and rough derivatives.</s><s>The often voluminous capsules of the smooth organisms are readily stainable with Ziehl-Neelsen hot carbol-fuchsin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth in broth is characterized by a fragile pellicle or granular turbidity or both.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic; catalase and peroxidase positive.</s><s>Heterotrophic.</s><s>Not proteolytic, hemolytic, or saccharolytic.</s><s>Gelatin is not digested, and plasma is not coagulated.</s><s>Pigments are not formed on complex media.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Optimum temperature, 37°C.</s><s>Growth is slow at 18 to 20°C and better at 30°C.</s><s>The optimum pH is 7.0 to 7.4; the pH range for growth is 6.5 to 8.5.</s><s>Poor or no growth on acid media commonly used for cultivation of fungi.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth is not influenced by light.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No growth on poor media, such as tap water supplemented with KNO<sub>3</sub> and phosphate.</s><s>Does not grow on mineral salts media which contain CaC0<sub>3</sub>, formate, acetate, propionate, lactate, methanol, ethanol, glycerol, or glycine as the sole source of carbon.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Does not attack arabinose, rhamnose, xylose, glucose, fructose, galactose, lactose, saccharose, maltose, trehalose, melibiose, raffinose, amidon, inulin , dextrin, glycogen, esculin, glycerol, erythritol, mannitol, sorbitol, or urea.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Good growth in coagulated serum, gelatin, blood agar, Loewenstein-Jensen medium, Dorset agar, and other rich media.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Reduces nitrate, nitrite, neutral red, methylene blue, and Janus green.</s><s>Produces H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>Indole is formed from tryptophane.</s><s>NH<sub>3</sub> is produced, and the growth medium turns alkaline.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Resistant to penicillin (2 U), bacitracin (2 U), and furadoine (10 μg).</s><s>Very susceptible to chloramphenicol(30 μg), streptomycin (50 μg), neomycin (30 μg), and sulfadiazine (1 μg).</s><s>Susceptible to tetracycline (30 μg) and erythromycin (15 μg).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Not virulent for mice (5ml), rats (1ml), guinea pigs (1ml) or rabbits (1ml) if a suspension which contains 5 x 10<sup>9</sup> cells per ml is injected subcutaneously or intraperitoneally .</s><s>The organisms cannot be recovered from treated animals.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Pure cultures survive at room temperature or in a refrigerator for several months if they are suspended in peptone or nutrient broth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated only once from nasal mucous from a patient with infectious sinusitis.</s></p></content></protolog>