<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5607_nm.9876" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9876" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9876" rank="species">Acaricomes phytoseiuli</organism><reference id="rid.5607"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Pukall</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schütte</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gols</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dicke</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Acaricomes phytoseiuli gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from the predatory mite Phytoseiulus persimilis</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>465</fpage><lpage>469</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63930-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16449459</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Acaricomes phytoseiuli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Acaricomes phytoseiuli</em> (phy.to.sei′u.li. N.L. gen. masc. n. <em>phytoseiuli</em> of <em>Phytoseiulus</em>, the nomenclatural genus name of the host mite).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Shows the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are 0·5–0·8×1–1·5 μm in size.</s><s>Colonies on TSA are circular, convex, 1–2 mm in diameter and coloured yellowish.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–30 °C with an optimum of 25 °C.</s><s>Grows at pH 6·0–9·5.</s><s>Utilizes dextrin, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-d-fructose, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannose, sucrose, turanose, l-glutamic acid and glucose 1-phosphate.</s><s>Only weak reactions for utilization of Tween 80, palatinose, l-pyroglutamic acid and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized: <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, glycogen, inulin, mannan, Tween 40, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-mannosamine, amygdalin, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, arbutin, d-cellobiose, l-fucose, d-galactose, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, d-gluconic acid, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, d-mannitol, d-melezitose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, 3-methyl glucose, methyl <em>α</em>-glucoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, sedoheptulosan, d-sorbitol, stachyose, d-tagatose, d-trehalose, xylitol, d-xylose, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, lactamide, d-lactic acid methyl ester, l-lactic acid, d-malic acid, methylpyruvate, monomethyl succinate, propionic acid, pyruvic acid, succinamic acid, succinic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-serine, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, adenosine, 2′-deoxyadenosine, inosine, thymidine, uridine, adenosine 5′-monophosphate, thymidine 5′-monophosphate, uridine 5′-monophosphate, fructose 6-phosphate and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>Cell-wall sugars are galactose and glucose.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 57·7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CSC<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 14247<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 49701<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the predatory mite <em>Phytoseiulus persimilis</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>