<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11780_nm.19887" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.19887" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.19887" rank="species">Enterobacter arachidis</organism><reference id="rid.11780"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Madhaiyan</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Poonguzhali</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Saravanan</surname><given-names>V.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Santhanakrishnan</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Enterobacter arachidis sp. nov., a plant-growth-promoting diazotrophic bacterium isolated from rhizosphere soil of groundnut</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1559</fpage><lpage>1564</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.013664-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19684326</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Enterobacter arachidis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Enterobacter arachidis</em> (a.ra.chi′dis. N.L. gen. n. arachidis, of Arachis, isolated from groundnut).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-stain-negative, straight rods, motile, 0.5–0.7 μm wide, 2.0–3.7 μm long and occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>Grows on AMS, TSA, R2A, NA+1 % methanol and MacConkey agar.</s><s>Catalase-positive and weakly oxidase-positive.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 0–5 % (w/v) NaCl, but not in the presence of 6 % (w/v) NaCl or higher concentrations.</s><s>Growth occurs between 20 and 30 °C with an optimum at 28 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is pH 4–10, with optimal growth at pH 7.</s><s>Starch hydrolysis is positive, but aesculin and gelatin hydrolysis are absent.</s><s>Nitrate reduction is positive and indole production is negative.</s><s>Positive for protease, lipase, pectinase, cellulase, ornithine decarboxylase and arginine dihydrolase enzymes and negative for urease.</s><s>Positive for Voges–Proskauer and negative for methyl red tests.</s><s>Able to tolerate and grow in the presence of NiCl<sub>2</sub> or CdCl<sub>2</sub> up to 1 mM or 4 mM, respectively, when supplemented in the growth plates.</s><s>Positive for utilization of dextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, 1-<em>O</em>-Methyl <em>α-</em>galactopyranoside, d-psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, dulcitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, d-saccharic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole carbon sources: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, d-melibiose, putrescine, mucate, 3-<em>O</em>-methyl d-glucopyranoside, d-galactonic acid lactone, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, sebacic acid, succinamic acid, l-hydroxyproline, l-leucine, l-phenylalanine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol and 2,3-butanediol.</s><s>The type strain is highly resistant (up to 500 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) to bacitracin, penicillin G, novabiocin and cephalosporin, but sensitive (lowest concentration tolerated) to spectinomycin (25 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), carbenicillin (500 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), kanamycin (25 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), nalidixic acid (25 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), chloramphenicol (25 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), erythromycin (50 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), polymyxin B (25 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), rifampicin (25 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), vancomycin (500 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), trimethoprim (25 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), cefotoxime (125 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), doxycyclin (125 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), ampicillin (500 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), gentamicin (250 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) and tetracycline (25 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>).</s><s>The <em>mxaF</em> and <em>nifH</em> genes for methanol dehydrogenase and nitrogenase activity, respectively, are present.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub> cyclo and summed features 2 (iso-C<sub>16 : 1</sub> I and/or C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 3-OH) and 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Ah-143<sup>T</sup> (=NCIMB 14469<sup>T</sup> =KCTC 22375<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from rhizosphere soil of groundnut (<em>Arachis hypogaea</em> L. ‘ALR-2’), the sample being collected at the pod initiation stage from an experimental field, Tamilnadu Agricultural University (TNAU), Coimbatore, Tamilnadu, India.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 53.2 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>