<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12329_nm.20352" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20352" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20352" rank="species">Miniimonas arenae</organism><reference id="rid.12329"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ue</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsuo</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kasai</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Miniimonas arenae gen. nov., sp. nov., an actinobacterium isolated from sea sand</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>123</fpage><lpage>127</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.019596-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20173007</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Miniimonas arenae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Miniimonas arenae</em> (a.re′na.e. L. gen. n. <em>arenae</em> of sand, isolated from sea sand).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Rod-shaped cells are 0.6–3.7 μm in length.</s><s>Cells exhibit a rod-coccus cycle.</s><s>The diameters of the cocci are 1.0–1.7 μm.</s><s>Growth occurs weakly at 25–30 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 5–11, with optimum growth at pH 7–7.5.</s><s>Cells grow in the absence of NaCl, but tolerate up to 5 % NaCl (w/v).</s><s>When grown aerobically for 7 days on LB agar or IL8 medium agar, the type strain forms a vermilion-coloured cell mass.</s><s>Does not form spores.</s><s>Cells form circular and smooth colonies that are 1–4 mm diameter after 7 days at 30 °C on LB agar.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>Hydrolysis of starch is negative.</s><s>The type strain forms vermilion-coloured colonies.</s><s>Based on API ZYM tests, cells are positive for esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, naphthol AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase, but negative for alkaline phosphatase, lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl<em>-β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Cells are weakly positive for esterase (C4) and acid phosphatase.</s><s>Utilizes the following substrates as sole carbon sources: l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-xylose, d-glucose, d-fructose, l-rhamnose and maltose monohydrate, but does not utilize d-mannitol.</s><s>Anaerobic formation of acid from API 20A is positive for glucose, sucrose, maltose, d-xylose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, raffinose, l-rhamnose and trehalose, weakly positive for cellobiose and negative for d-mannitol, lactose, salicin, glycerol, melezitose and d-sorbitol.</s><s>Based on API 20A tests, cells are anaerobically positive for the hydrolysis of aesculin, but negative for the hydrolysis of gelatin and for the production of indole, arginine dihydrolase and urease.</s><s>The peptidoglycan type, polar lipids, fatty acid pattern and major menaquinone are as given in the genus description.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YM18-15<sup>T</sup> (=NBRC 106267<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 19750<sup>T</sup>=MBIC 08348<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from sea sand in Teguma fishing harbour in Nagasaki Prefecture, Japan.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA is 74.2 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>