<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1594_nm.10848" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10848" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10848" rank="species">Marinobacter vinifirmus</organism><reference id="rid.1594"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Liebgott</surname><given-names>P.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Casalot</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Paillard</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lorquin</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Labat</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Marinobacter vinifirmus sp. nov., a moderately halophilic bacterium isolated from a wine-barrel-decalcification wastewater</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2511</fpage><lpage>2516</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64368-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17082382</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Marinobacter vinifirmus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Marinobacter vinifirmus</em> [vi.ni.fir′mus. L. n. <em>vinum</em> wine; L. adj. <em>firmus</em> firm (as opposed to frail), stable, strong; N.L. masc. adj. <em>vinifirmus</em> wine-resistant, pertaining to the resistance to wine-barrel-decalcification wastewater, from which the type strain was isolated].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, weakly motile, non-spore-forming, pleomorphic rods, 0.5–2.0 μm long and 0.5–0.7 μm in diameter.</s><s>Colonies are round and slightly convex with regular margins, 1.0–3.0 mm in diameter after incubation for 2 days on marine agar 2216 and are white, opaque and have a smooth surface.</s><s>They produce a homogeneous suspension.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is 25 °C.</s><s>No growth is detected at 55 °C.</s><s>The optimum pH for growth is 6.5.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs in the presence of 6 % (w/v) NaCl and thus the strain could be classified as a moderately halophilic bacterium according to Kushner &#x0026; Kamekura (1988).</s><s>Anaerobic growth does not occur in the absence or presence of nitrate as the final electron acceptor.</s><s>Catalase-positive and weakly oxidase-positive.</s><s>Tween 80, chitin and aesculin are hydrolysed, whereas casein, gelatin, starch and agar are not.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Acid is produced (weakly) only from fructose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from the following sugars: d-glucose, sucrose, d-galactose, l- and d-arabinose, d-mannose, d-maltose, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, d-trehalose, d-ribose, d-cellobiose, l-rhamnose and d-xylose.</s><s>Acetate, lactate and succinate, but not citrate, are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>Although phenolic compounds inhibit many micro-organisms, strain FB1<sup>T</sup> displays a high degree of tolerance to a few of these substances.</s><s>As an example, growth occurs with high levels (up to 10 mM) of phenol as the sole carbon source.</s><s>Strain FB1<sup>T</sup> is susceptible to ampicillin (10 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), polymyxin (25 μg) and penicillin (10 μg) but resistant to tetracycline (30 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), neomycin (30 μg) and streptomycin (10 μg).</s><s>The following enzymes are present with the API ZYM system: esterase, esterase lipase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosamidase and acid phosphatase.</s><s>Negative for urease, lipase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities.</s><s>On the basis of the 16S rRNA gene sequence, the species belongs to the genus <em>Marinobacter</em> within the <em>Gammaproteobacteria</em>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 58.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, FB1<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 17747<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 52119<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from wine-barrel-decalcification wastewater.</s></p></content></protolog>