<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7615_nm.3639" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3639" rank="family">Geobacteraceae</organism><reference id="rid.7615"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Holmes</surname><given-names>D.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nevin</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lovley</surname><given-names>D.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Comparison of 16S rRNA, nifD, recA, gyrB, rpoB and fusA genes within the family Geobacteraceae fam. nov.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1591</fpage><lpage>1599</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02958-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15388715</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Geobacteraceae</em> fam. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Geobacteraceae</em> (Ge.o.bac′te.ra.ce.ae. N.L. masc. n. <em>Geobacter</em> the type genus of the family; -<em>aceae</em> ending to denote a family; N.L. neut. pl. n. <em>Geobacteraceae</em> the <em>Geobacter</em> family).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The family <em>Geobacteraceae</em> is located within the domain <em>Bacteria</em> and the <em>δ</em>-subclass of the <em>Proteobacteria</em>.</s><s>This family branches phylogenetically between the orders ‘<em>Desulfovibrionales</em>’ and ‘<em>Desulfobacterales</em>’.</s><s>The family <em>Geobacteraceae</em> comprises five genera: <em>Geobacter</em>, <em>Desulfuromonas</em>, <em>Desulfuromusa</em>, <em>Pelobacter</em> and <em>Malonomonas</em>.</s><s>The type genus is <em>Geobacter</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Micro-organisms within this family have mostly been isolated from anoxic sedimentary environments.</s><s>All species of the <em>Geobacteraceae</em> are able to reduce Fe(III) and some are able to utilize S<sup>0</sup> and/or the humics analogue AQDS as terminal electron acceptors.</s><s>With the exception of <em>Pelobacter</em> and <em>Malonomonas</em>, all genera of the <em>Geobacteraceae</em> contain species that can oxidize acetate and other multi-carbon organic substrates to carbon dioxide.</s><s>This family includes species with rod-like morphology, and members of all of the genera within this family, except <em>Pelobacter</em>, contain abundant <em>c</em>-type cytochromes.</s><s>In addition, cells of members of the <em>Geobacteraceae</em> are non-motile or are motile by means of flagella.</s></p></content></protolog>