<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5374_nm.6709" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6709" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6709" rank="species">Amycolatopsis coloradensis</organism><reference id="rid.5374"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Labeda</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Amycolatopsis coloradensis sp. nov., the avoparcin, LL-AV290-producing strain.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>124</fpage><lpage>127</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Amycolatopsis coloradensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Amycolatopsis coloradensis</i> (co.lo.rad.en'sis. L. adj. <i>coloradensis</i>, of Colorado, the source of the soil sample from which the type strain was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>When aerial mycelium is formed, it produces cylindrical to ovoid conidia in straight to flexuous chains.</s><s>Vegetative mycelium is branched.</s><s>The aerial mycelium is sparse and white to olive-buff, while the substrate mycelium is yellowish to orange.</s><s>A yellowish soluble pigment is produced on many growth media.</s><s>Casein, esculin, gelatin, hypoxanthine, starch, and tyrosine are hydrolyzed; adenine, allantoin, urea, and xanthine are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Phosphatase and nitrate reductase are produced.</s><s>Acetate, malate, propionate, pyruvate, and succinate are decarboxylated; benzoate, citrate, mucate, oxalate, and tartrate are not decarboxylated.</s><s>Acid is produced from cellobiose, dextrin, fructose, galactose, glucose, glycerol, inositol, mannitol, mannose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, salicin, trehalose, and xylose; no acid is produced from adonitol, arabinose, dulcitol, erythritol, lactose, maltose, melezitose, β-methyl-xyloside, raffinose, rhamnose, sorbitol, and sucrose.</s><s>Grows at 10 to 37°C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 45°C.</s><s>Produces the glycopeptide antibiotic avoparcin (LL-AV290).</s><s>Isolated from a soil sample collected in Colorado.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 66 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).</s><s>The type strain is strain NRRL 3218.</s></p></content></protolog>