<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4445_nm.2434" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2434" rank="genus">Methylosarcina</organism><reference id="rid.4445"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wise</surname><given-names>M.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McArthur</surname><given-names>J.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shimkets</surname><given-names>L.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Methylosarcina fibrata gen. nov., sp. nov. and Methylosarcina quisquiliarum sp.nov., novel type 1 methanotrophs.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>611</fpage><lpage>621</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11321107</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of Methylosarcina gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Methylosarcina (Me.thyl.o.sar.ci'na. N.L. neut. n. <i>methylum</i> the methyl group; L. fem. n. <i>sarcina</i> pack, bundle; N.L. fem. n. <i>Methylosarcina</i> methane-utilizing bundle of cells)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Members are Gram-negative, oxidase-negative and catalase-positive.</s><s>Light brown to buff coloured colonies are present on NMS agar.</s><s>Cell morphology can vary from coccoid to rod, or fusiform shape.</s><s>In liquid culture, growth can be flocculating or evenly dispersed.</s><s>Cells often grow in sarcinal-like aggregations covered by a capsule or diffuse slime layer.</s><s>Individual cells, diplococci and tetrads are occasionally motile by means of one, or rarely two, polar flagella.</s><s>In stationary phase, cells tend to increase in size and eventually form desiccation- and heat-sensitive cysts.</s><s>Cells utilize only methane and methanol as carbon sources.</s><s>Nitrate, ammonia, peptone, urea, yeast extract, L-glutamine, L-asparagine, L-aspartate and L-glutamate are accepted as nitrogen sources.</s><s>No nitrogen fixation occurs.</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Ribulose bisphosphate carboxylase and soluble methane monooxygenase are absent.</s><s>Phylogenetic analysis of 16S rDNA places members in the family <i>Methylococcaceae</i>, most closely related to the genera <i>Methylobacter</i> and <i>Methylomicrobium</i>.</s><s>Major fatty acids are 16:1<i>ω</i>8<i>c</i>, 16:1<i>ω</i>7<i>c</i>, 16:1<i>ω</i>5<i>t</i> and 16:0. 16:1<i>ω</i>5<i>c</i> is absent or present in trace amounts.</s><s>G­+C content is approximately 54 mol%.</s><s>Type species is <i>Methylosarcina fibrata</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>