<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5_nm.5264" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5264" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5264" rank="species">Staphylococcus pasteuri</organism><reference id="rid.5"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chesneau</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Morvan</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Labischinski</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>el Solh</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Staphylococcus pasteuri sp. nov., isolated from human, animal, and food specimens.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>237</fpage><lpage>244</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-2-237</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8098615</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Staphylococcus pasteuri</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Staphylococcus pasteuri</i> (pas' teur. i. L. gen. n. <i>pasteuri</i> of Pasteur, honoring the French microbiologist Louis Pasteur for his contribution in 1878 to the recognition of staphylococci as pathogenic agents and also referring to the research institute, Institut Pasteur, Paris, France, where the new species was characterized)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of <i>S. pasteuri</i> is based on a total of seven strains isolated from different sources.</s><s>The cells are nonsporulating, nonmotile, gram-positive cocci, 0.5 to 1.5 μm in diameter, occurring singly, in pairs, in tetrads, or in clusters.</s><s>These organisms grow on P agar at 15 to 45°C.</s><s>After incubation on P agar at 35°C for 3 days and at 25°C for an additional 2 days, colony diameter varies from 4 to 7 mm.</s><s>The colonies are smooth, glistening, and raised with slightly elevated centers and regular edges.</s><s>The yellow pigment produced by six of the seven strains is better visualized when P agar is supplemented with skim milk.</s><s>Growth is evident throughout a tube of thioglycolate medium and on P agar supplemented with 5 to 15% (wt/vol) sodium chloride.</s><s>All strains produce both D- and L-lactate isomers from glucose under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>They exhibit catalase, urease, β-glucuronidase, and β-glucosidase activities.</s><s>They clear egg yolk medium and give synergistic hemolysis with β-toxin.</s><s>They produce acid aerobically from D-glucose, glycerol, β-D-fructose, sucrose, and D-trehalose.</s><s>In contrast, negative results are obtained for the following tests: free coagulase, clumping factor, fibrinolysin, oxidase, DNase, p-galactosidase, alkaline phosphatase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, arginine arylamidase, ornithine decarboxylase, and esculin hydrolysis.</s><s>No acid is produced aerobically from L-arabinose, D-cellobiose, α-D-melibiose, D-raffinose, xylitol, D-xylose, D-mannose, or D-ribose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Agar disk diffusion tests show that the seven strains are resistant to lysostaphin, vibriostatic agent 0/129, and bacitracin, whereas they are susceptible to oxacillin, cefalotin, spectinomycin, streptomycin , kanamycin , neomycin , tobramycin, gentamicin, minocycline, pristinamycin 11, sulfonamides, trimethoprim, pefloxacin, fusidic acid, rifampin, fosfomycin, vancomycin, nitrofurantoin, novobiocin, cadmium acetate, mercuric nitrate, cetyltrimethylammonium bromide, propamidine isothionate, chlorhexidine digluconate, and desferal (Tables 2 and 3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>Strain BM9357<sup>T</sup> (= ATCC 51129<sup>T</sup>) was isolated from a vomit sample.</s><s>In addition to all the characteristics shared by the seven <i>S. pasteuri</i> strains, the type strain has the following properties: gelatin and casein hydrolysis; acetoin production; arginine dihydrolase activity; acid production from α-lactose, maltose, and D-mannitol; inability to reduce nitrates, to hydrolyze N-acetylglucosamine, or to produce acid from D-melezitose or D-turanose; and resistance to penicillin G by penicillinase production, to erythromycin and oleandomycin (inducible MLS phenotype), and to sodium arseniate.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 37 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>