<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7236_nm.5325" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5325" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5325" rank="species">Lactobacillus acidipiscis</organism><reference id="rid.7236"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tanasupawat</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shida</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Okada</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Komagata</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lactobacillus acidipiscis sp. nov. and Weissella thailandensis sp. nov., isolated from fermented fish in Thailand.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1479</fpage><lpage>1485</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10939653</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Lactobacillus acidipiscis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Lactobacillus acidipiscis</i> (a.ci.di'pis.cis. L. adj. <i>acidus</i> sour; L. n. <i>piscis</i> fish; L. adj. <i>acidipiscis</i> pertaining to sour fish, an isolation source of strains of this species)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive rods (0.4-0.6x1.2-5.0 μm), non-motile, non-sporing and occur singly, in pairs and in chains.</s><s>Colonies on MRSH agar plate are circular, slightly convex with an entire margin and unpigmented.</s><s>Microaerophilic.</s><s>Utilizes D-glucose homofermentatively and does not produce gas from glucose.</s><s>Produces L-lactic acid from glucose (&#x003E;91%).Negative for catalase activity, nitrate reduction, hydrolysis of arginine, aesculin, gelatin and starch and for the formation of slime from sucrose.</s><s>Most strains show no reaction in litmus milk.</s><s>Grows at 25-37 °C but not at 15 or 42 °C.</s><s>Does not grow at pH 4.0 or pH 8.5.</s><s>Grows in 10% NaCl.</s><s>Some strains grow in 12% NaCl.</s><s>Produces acid from D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose and D-mannose but does not produce acid from cellobiose, gluconate, D-melibiose, D-melezitose, methyl α-D-glucoside, raffinose, D-sorbitol and dxylose.</s><s>Some strains produce acid weakly from lactose and salicin.</s><s>Variable reactions for D-amygdalin, L-arabinose, glycerol, maltose, D-mannitol, L-rhamnose, sucrose and D-trehalose.</s><s>Requires niacin and calcium pantothenate for growth.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are straight-chained C<sub>16:0</sub> and C<sub>18:1</sub>.</s><s>L-Lys-D-Asp in the cell wall.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA ranges from 38.6 to 41.5 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from fermented fish (pla-ra and pla-chom) in Thailand.</s><s>The type strain is FS60-1<sup>T</sup> (=PCU 207<sup>T</sup>=NRIC 0300<sup>T</sup>=HSCC 1411<sup>T</sup>=JCM 10692<sup>T</sup>=TISTR 1386<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The type strain has the characteristics given in the description of species and in Tables 1 and 2.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 38.7 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>