<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.147_nm.1619" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1619" rank="genus">Burkholderia</organism><reference id="rid.147"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gillis</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Van</surname><given-names>T.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bardin</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goor</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hebbar</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Willems</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Segers</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heulin</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fernandez</surname><given-names>M.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Polyphasic taxonomy in the genus Burkholderia leading to an emended description of the genus and proposition of Burkholderia vietnamiensis sp. nov. for N2-fixing isolates from rice in Vietnam.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>274</fpage><lpage>289</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-2-274</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <i>Burkholderia</i>  (Yabuuchi, Kosako, Oyaio, Yano, and Ezaki 1992)</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Burkholderia</i> (Burk.hold.er'i.a. M.L. dim. ending <i>-ia</i>; M.L. fem. n. <i>Burkholderia</i>, named after W. H. Burkholder, the American bacteriologist who first discovered the etiological agent of sour skin of onions)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Burkholderia</i> cells are gram-negative, nonfermentative, straight rods that have a single polar flagellum or a tuft of polar flagella.</s><s>A single species, <i>B. mallei</i>, is atrichous and nonmotile.</s><s>Catalase is produced, and oxidase activity varies between species.</s><s>The cellular fatty acids are characterized by the presence of 3-hydroxy C<sub>16:0</sub>.</s><s>The type strains of several species are characterized by the presence of two types of ornithine lipids.</s><s>Most species grow at 40°C.</s><s>All species can grow with the following substrates as sole carbon sources: glucose, glycerol, inositol, galactose, sorbitol, and mannitol.</s><s>Some species are pathogenic for humans, animals, or plants.</s><s>Isolated from plant material, soil, or clinical samples.</s><s>Can be recognized on the basis of 16s rRNA characteristics (sequence and/or DNA-rRNA hybridization data).</s><s>Most strains accumulate polyhydroxybutyrate as carbon reserve material and are capable of <i>ortho</i> cleavage of protocatechuate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content is 59.0 to 69.5 mol%.</s><s>The type species is <i>B. cepacia</i> (73).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The emended genus <i>Burkholderia</i> contains the following species: <i>B. andropogonis</i> comb. nov., <i>B. caryophylli</i>, <i>B. cepacia</i>, <i>B. cocovenenans</i> comb. nov., <i>B. gladioli</i>, <i>B. glumae</i>, <i>B. mallei</i>, <i>B. plantarii</i>, <i>B. pseudomallei</i>, <i>B. vandii</i>, and <i>B. vietnamiensis</i> sp. nov.</s><s>Descriptions of <i>B. caryophylli</i>, <i>B. cepacia</i>, <i>B. gladioli</i>, <i>B. glumae</i>, <i>B. mallei</i>, <i>B. plantani</i>, <i>B. pseudomallei</i>, and <i>B. vandii</i> can be found elsewhere (2, 43, 63, 73).</s><s>These taxa can be further differentiated on the basis of phenotypic characteristics (Table 2) and genotypic characteristics (Tables 4 and 5).</s></p></content></protolog>