<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5567_nm.8880" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8880" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8880" rank="species">Tenuibacillus multivorans</organism><reference id="rid.5567"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ren</surname><given-names>P.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>P.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Tenuibacillus multivorans gen. nov., sp. nov., a moderately halophilic bacterium isolated from saline soil in Xin-Jiang, China.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>95</fpage><lpage>99</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63180-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15653860</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Tenuibacillus multivorans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Tenuibacillus multivorans</em> (mul.ti.vor′ans. L. part. adj. <em>multus</em> many, numerous; L. v. <em>voro</em> to devour, swallow; N.L. part. adj. <em>multivorans</em> devouring numerous kinds of substrates).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to characteristics given above for the genus, the followings are characteristic of <em>T. multivorans</em>.</s><s>Gram staining of fresh culture is positive but variable in old culture.</s><s>KOH test is negative.</s><s>Cells are motile by one polar flagellum.</s><s>After 2 days growth, colonies are circular, translucent, convex and 1–2 mm in diameter; older colonies become brown from the centre outwards on HM medium.</s><s>Optimal NaCl concentration for growth is 5 % for strain 28-1<sup>T</sup> (8 % for strain 28-4); NaCl growth range is 1–20 % and no growth is observed at either 37 or 20 °C in rich media without NaCl.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 21–42 °C (optimum 36–41 °C).</s><s>pH range for growth is 6·5–9·0 (optimum 7·0–8·0).</s><s>Able to utilize but not produce acid from all saccharides, polysaccharides and sugar alcohols tested, including arabinose, xylose, d-fructose, glucose, d-mannose, rhamnose, dl-sorbose, cellobiose, d-galactose, lactose, maltose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, melezitose, d-raffinose, inulin, dulcitol, erythritol, glycerol, inositol, mannitol and salicin.</s><s>Hydrolyses gelatin, casein, aesculin and Tweens 40 and 60, but not starch or Tweens 20 or 80.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain 28-1<sup>T</sup> (=AS 1.3442<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 100370<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a hypersaline lake, Ai-Ding Lake, in the Xin-Jiang Uigur Autonomous Area of north-west China.</s></p></content></protolog>