<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6841_nm.8113" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8113" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8113" rank="species">Flavobacterium scophthalmum</organism><reference id="rid.6841"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mudarris</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Austin</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Segers</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bernardet</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flavobacterium scophthalmum sp. nov., a pathogen of turbot (Scophthalmus maximus L.).</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>447</fpage><lpage>453</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-3-447</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8068540</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Flavobucterium scophthalmum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Flavobucterium scophthalmum</i> (scoph. thal' mum. N.L. n. <i>Scophthalmus</i>, turbot; N.L. adj. <i>scophthalmum</i>, pertaining to turbot).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Uniformly shaped gram-negative rods that are approximately 2.0 by 0.5 μm and have rounded ends after incubation for 18 h.</s><s>Shorter rods, approximately 1.0 by 0.5 μm, are present in late-exponential-phase cultures after incubation for 48 h.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Fresh isolates appear to exhibit gliding motility; flagella are not produced.</s><s>However, after storage, the presence of gliding motility cannot be confirmed.</s><s>Therefore, isolates may be considered nonmotile.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall is approximately 50 nm thick (Fig. 1).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Resting stages are not observed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on medium K (18), marine 2216E agar, and TSA are shiny, smooth, round, raised, entire, and 5 to 6 mm in diameter after incubation for 48 h at 25°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A nondiffusible, nonfluorescent orange (flexirubin-like) pigment is produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Broth cultures are uniformly turbid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultures are chemoorganotrophic (metabolism is respiratory and fermentative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrates are not reduced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Ammonia is produced from arginine; catalase, oxidase, phenylalanine deaminase, and phosphatase are produced, but arginine dihydrolase, H<sub>2</sub>S, indole, and lysine and ornithine decarboxylases are not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The methyl red test and the Voges-Proskauer reaction are negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Esculin, blood (betα-hemolysis), casein, DNA, gelatin, tributyrin, Tween 20, Tween 40, Tween 60, Tween 80, Tween 85, tyrosine, and urea are degraded, but agar, cellulose, chitin, and starch are not degraded.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid is not readily produced from carbohydrates (arabinose, cellobiose, glucose, lactose, mannitol, raffinose, salicin, sucrose, and xylose).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cellobiose, ethanol, D-fructose, D-glucose, maltose, pectin, polypectate, and <i>m</i>-xylitol are utilized as sole sources of carbon for energy and growth, but alginate, L-arabinose, L-arabitol, carboxymethyl cellulose, erythritol, glycerol, heparin, inositol, inulin, L-leucine, lysine, mannitol, methanol, L-methionine, L-phenylalanine, D-ribose, raffinose, sodium benzoate, sodium citrate, sodium succinate, sorbitol, sucrose, and D-xylose are not utilized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Hydrolyzes the following substrates (as determined with the API ZYM system; scores of 2 to 5 are considered positive): 2-naphthyl-phosphate, 2-naphthyl-butyrate, 2-naphthyl-caprylate, L-leucyl-2-naphthylamide, L-valyl-2-naphthylamide, L-cystyl-2-naphthylamide, N-benzoyl-DL-arginine-2-naphthylamide, 2-naphthyl-phosphate, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphate, 2-naphthyl-α-D-glucopyranoside, and 1-naphthyl-N-acetyl-β-D-glucosaminide</s></p><p class="description"><s>Does not hydrolyze the following substrates (as determined with the API ZYM system; scores 0 and 1 are considered negative): 2-naphthyl-myristate, N-glutaryl-phenylalanine-2-naphthylamide, 6-Br-2-naphthyl-α-D-galactopyranoside, 2-naphthyl-β-D-galactopyranoside, naphthol-AS-BI-β-D-glucuronide, 6-Br-2-naphthyl-β-D-glucopyranoside, 6-Br-2-naphthyl-α-D-mannopyranoside, and 2-naphthyl-α-L-fucopyranoside.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Sodium nitrate, vitamin-free Casamino Acids, and yeast extract are utilized as nitrogen sources.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth occurs at 15 to 25°C (weak growth occurs at 4°C and no growth occurs at 35°C) and in the presence of 0 to 4% NaCl, but not in the presence of 5% (wt/vol) NaCl, or on MacConkey agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All of the strains which we studied are characterized by the following fatty acids: 15:0 iso, 15:0 iso-3-OH, 16:0, 16:0 3-OH, 17:0 iso, 17:0 iso-3-OH, iso 17:1 ω9c, summed feature 4 (i.e., 15:0 iso-2-OH and/or 16:1 ω7t), and two unidentified fatty acids with equivalent chain lengths of 13.556 and 16.580.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultures are found in coastal waters and are capable of producing gill disease and hemorrhagic septicemia in turbot.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 33 to 35 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is MM1, which was isolated in 1987 from the gills of diseased turbot in Scotland; a culture of this strain has been deposited in the Czechoslovak Collection of Microorganisms, Brno, Czechoslovakia, as CCM 4109 and in the culture collection of the Laboratorium voor Microbiologie, Ghent, Belgium, as LMG 13028.</s><s>The characteristics of the type strain conform to the description given above.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Six additional strains of <i>Flavobacterium scophthalmum</i>, MMlA (isolated from the gills of diseased turbot), MMlB (isolated from diseased turbot), M1D (isolated from diseased turbot), MM2B (isolated from seawater), MM2C (isolated from seawater), and MM4 (isolated from the gills of diseased turbot), have been deposited in the culture collection of the Laboratorium voor Microbiologie, Ghent, Belgium, as LMG 13029, LMG 13030, LMG 13031, LMG 13032, LMG 13033, and LMG 13034, respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Differential characteristics for <i>Flavobacterium scophthalmum</i> and allied bacteria are shown in Tables 1 and 5.</s></p></content></protolog>