<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2748_nm.14094" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14094" rank="genus">Alcalilimnicola</organism><reference id="rid.2748"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yakimov</surname><given-names>M.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Giuliano</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chernikova</surname><given-names>T.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gentile</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Abraham</surname><given-names>W.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lünsdorf</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Timmis</surname><given-names>K.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Golyshin</surname><given-names>P.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Alcalilimnicola halodurans gen. nov., sp. nov., an alkaliphilic, moderately halophilic and extremely halotolerant bacterium, isolated from sediments of soda-depositing Lake Natron, East Africa Rift Valley.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>2133</fpage><lpage>2143</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11760957</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Alcalilimnicola</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Alcalilimnicola</i> (Al.ca.li.lim.ni'co.la. N.L. n. <i>alcali</i> from Arabic n. <i>al qaliy</i> soda ash; Gr. n. <i>limnos</i> lake; L. suffix <i>cola</i> a dweller of; N.L. masc. n. <i>Alcalilimnicola</i> a dweller of alkaline lakes)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, short, straight, oval-shaped cells occurring singly or in pairs.</s><s>Motile by means of a single polarly inserted flagellum.</s><s>Non-spore-forming and non-encapsulated cells, usually producing an extracellular matrix of non-fibrillar appearance.</s><s>Respiratory metabolism.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Nitrate but not nitrite is reduced.</s><s>Non-phototrophic, without any observable internal photosynthetic membranes.</s><s>No photosynthetic pigments are produced under conditions that favour the phototrophic mode of metabolism.</s><s>Optimal growth is observed under alkaline conditions (pH&#x003E;8.5).</s><s>Members of this genus are moderately halophilic and extremely halotolerant organisms.</s><s>Storage products are detected as large amounts of electron-translucent intracellular storage material, similar to polyhydroxybutyrate.</s><s>Phylogenetically, the genus is placed in the γ-<i>Proteobacteria</i> within the family <i>Ectothiorhodospiraceae</i>.</s><s>The G­+C content of the DNA of the type strain of the type species is 65.6 mol%.</s><s>The type species is found in extremely alkaline sediments of Lake Natron with moderate to extremely high salinities.</s><s>The type and only species is <i>Alcalilimnicola halodurans</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>