<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5826_nm.10059" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10059" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10059" rank="species">Emticicia oligotrophica</organism><reference id="rid.5826"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Saha</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chakrabarti</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emticicia oligotrophica gen. nov., sp. nov., a new member of the family 'Flexibacteraceae', phylum Bacteroidetes.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>991</fpage><lpage>995</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64086-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16627643</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Emticicia oligotrophica</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Emticicia oligotrophica</em> (o.li.go.tro′phi.ca. Gr. adj. <em>oligos</em> few; Gr. adj. <em>trophikos</em> nursing, tending or feeding; N.L. fem. adj. <em>oligotrophica</em> eating little, referring to a bacterium living on low-nutrient media).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to properties described for the genus, the species has the following characteristics.</s><s>Colonies on TSBA100 medium after 2 days growth at 37 °C appear round, mucoid, light pink and convex with almost entire margins; with prolonged incubation, the colony colour deepens, it produces slime and appears glistening.</s><s>Cells are usually 2–5 μm long and 0.3–0.4 μm wide; in an aged culture, some cells may be longer.</s><s>No gliding motility observed.</s><s>No flexirubin pigment detected.</s><s>Grows at 15–42 °C and pH 5.0–11.0; cannot grow in 1 % NaCl.</s><s>Positive for methyl red, but negative for Voges–Proskauer test.</s><s>Cannot grow on most of the common nutritionally rich culture media (e.g. TSBA, NA, LBA, PCA, MHA, TSIA and ZMA), but grows on R2A, R3A and 100-fold dilutions of all these media.</s><s>It can hydrolyse gelatin, starch, Tween 60 and urea, but not casein, ONPG, hypoxanthine, chitin, cellulose (CMC or filter paper), xylan, tyrosine or Tween 20, 40 or 80.</s><s>Can utilize d-cellobiose, d-lactose, d-melezitose, d-raffinose and arbutin; weakly utilizes l-arabinose, l-arabitol, d-amygdalin, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-melibiose and sucrose as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Cannot utilize adonitol, dulcitol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose or xylitol as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Produces acids from arbutin, d-cellobiose, d-glucose, d-lactose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, salicin, d-trehalose and d-xylose and weakly from d-galactose, d-maltose, d-mannose, d-melibiose, d-melezitose and sucrose, but not from adonitol, d-amygdalin, l-arabinose, l-arabitol, dulcitol, aesculin, erythritol, d- or l-fucose, d-fructose, glycerol, glycogen, <em>myo</em>-inositol, inulin, 2-ketogluconate, d-mannitol, d-raffinose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose or xylitol.</s><s>Sensitive to ampicillin, bacitracin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, gentamicin, kanamycin, lincomycin, neomycin, novobiocin, norfloxacin, penicillin G, polymyxin B, rifampicin, streptomycin, sulfasomidine and tetracycline.</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content of the type strain is 36.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is GPTSA100-15<sup>T</sup> (=MTCC 6937<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17448<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a warm spring water sample from Assam, India.</s></p></content></protolog>