<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3615_nm.10181" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10181" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10181" rank="species">Thermovirga lienii</organism><reference id="rid.3615"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dahle</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Birkeland</surname><given-names>N.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thermovirga lienii gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel moderately thermophilic, anaerobic, amino-acid-degrading bacterium isolated from a North Sea oil well.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1539</fpage><lpage>1545</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63894-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16825627</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Thermovirga lienii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Thermovirga lienii</em> (li.en.i′i. N.L. gen. n. <em>lienii</em> named in honour of the Norwegian microbiologist Professor Torleiv Lien, for his important contribution in the study of anaerobes from petroleum reservoirs).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are motile and typically 2–3 μm in length and 0.4–0.8 μm wide.</s><s>Cells occur singly or in chains and can form aggregates of up to several hundred cells.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 37–68 °C (optimum, 58 °C; see Supplementary Fig. S2 available in IJSEM Online).</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6.2–8.0 (optimum, pH 6.5–7.0).</s><s>The NaCl range for growth is 5–80 g l<sup>−1</sup> (optimum, 20–30 g l<sup>−1</sup>).</s><s>Substrates that can be utilized by strain Cas60314<sup>T</sup> in medium not supplied with yeast extract are as follows: peptone, Casamino acids, meat extract, tryptone and casein.</s><s>Yeast extract is required for fermentation of pyruvate, serine and 2-oxoglutarate.</s><s>Substrates that can be utilized only in medium supplied with yeast extract and cystine are as follows: glutamate, alanine, leucine, isoleucine, valine and arginine.</s><s>The following substrates are not fermented in the presence of yeast extract, but were not tested in medium supplied with cystine: xylose, ribose, sucrose, arabinose, fructose, lactose, mannose, maltodextrin, xylane, cellulose, starch and chitin.</s><s>Substrates that cannot be utilized in the presence of yeast extract and in the presence or absence of cystine are as follows: H<sub>2</sub>, glucose, maltose, threonine, glycine, methanol, ethanol, phenol, lactate, acetate, propionate, malate, succinate, citrate and formate.</s><s>Strain Cas60314<sup>T</sup> does not perform the Stickland reaction when alanine is provided as electron donor and serine or arginine is provided as electron acceptor.</s><s>Cystine stimulates growth.</s><s>Cystine and elemental sulfur, but not thiosulfate, are reduced to hydrogen sulfide.</s><s>Amorphous Fe(III) does not stimulate growth, and, in its presence, magnetite is not formed.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA is 46.6 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Cas60314<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 17291<sup>T</sup>=ATCC BAA-1197<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from production-water samples from an oil reservoir in the North Sea.</s></p></content></protolog>