<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4_nm.6191" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6191" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6191" rank="subspecies">Corynebacterium afermentans afermentans</organism><reference id="rid.4"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Riegel</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>de Briel</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prévost</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jehl</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Monteil</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Minck</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic study of Corynebacterium Group ANF-1 strains: Proposal of Corynebacterium afermentans sp. nov. containing the subspecies C. afermentans subsp. afermentans subsp. nov. and C. afermentans subsp. lipophilum subsp. nov.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>287</fpage><lpage>292</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-2-287</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8494739</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Corynebacterium afermentans</i> subsp. <i>afermentans</i> subsp. nov</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Corynebacterium afermentans</i> subsp. <i>afermentans</i> (a.fer.men'tans. Gr. pref. <i>a</i>, not; L. part. adj. <i>fermentans</i>, leavening; M.L. adj. <i>afementans</i>, nonfermenting carbohydrates)</s></p><p class="description"><s>This description is based on observations of the authors and descriptions of the literature of <i>Corynebacterium</i> group ANF-1 strains (2, 4, 7, 12, 13).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The bacteria are gram-positive, irregular rods or coccobacilli that sometimes contain metachromatic granules.</s><s>All are nonmotile and nonspore forming and are arranged in typical V-shaped forms or palisades.</s><s>They are not acid fast, and no rod-coccus cycle is present.</s><s>They are catalase positive and oxidase negative.</s><s>They exhibit good growth under aerobic conditions and very slight growth under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Nonhemolytic colonies (1 to 2 mm in diameter) are grayish-white and smooth after 24 h at 37°C on fresh sheep blood agar.</s><s>On 1% Tween 80-supplemented medium, bright colonies (2 mm in diameter) are beige, and Tween 80 esterase activity is detected.</s><s>Acid is not produced from D-glucose, glycogen, lactose, sucrose, ribose, D-xylose, D-mannose, D-galactose, trehalose, and D-mannitol or on triple sugar iron agar.</s><s>Tyrosine, gelatin, DNA, starch, and urea are not degraded.</s><s>Esculin is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>The methyl red test is negative, and acetoin, indole, and H<sub>2</sub>S (on triple sugar iron agar) are not produced.</s><s>Hydrolysis of hippurate is variable.</s><s>Growth is visible in 6.5% NaCl.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, esterase, lipase, and acid phosphatase are produced.</s><s>α-Galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, and β-glucosidase are not produced.</s><s>Cells utilize acetate and lactate.</s><s>Propionate, D-glucose, L-arabinose, D-mannose, D-mannitol, N-acetyl-glucosamine, maltose, gluconate, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate, and phenyl acetate are not utilized.</s><s>The strains are susceptible to ampicillin, mezlocillin, piperacillin, ticarcillin, cephalotin, cefotaxime, gentamicin, netilmicin, amikacin, norfloxacin, ciprofloxacin, vancomycin, teicoplanin, rifampicin, pristinamycin, tetracycline, and fusidic acid, and some strains are susceptible to erythromycin, virginiamycin, and nitrofurantoin.</s><s>All strains</s></p><p class="description"><s>are resistant to fosfomycin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, arabinose, and galactose.</s><s>Straight-chain saturated fatty acids are mainly palmitic and stearic acids.</s><s>Branched saturated fatty acids are heptadecanoic acid and pentadecanoic acid.</s><s>Straight-chain unsaturated fatty acids are mainly oleic acid and linoleic acid.</s><s>The predominant types of mycolic acids are C<sub>30:0</sub>, C<sub>30:1</sub>, C<sub>32:1</sub>, C<sub>33:1</sub>, C<sub>34:2</sub>, and C<sub>36:2</sub>.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 66 to 67 mol% G+C. <i>C. aftermentans</i> subsp. <i>afermentans</i> strains were isolated from human clinical specimens such as blood samples, skin, and ears, but no pathogenic relationships were reported.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LCDC 88199 (= CIP 103499).</s><s>It was isolated in Canada from a human blood culture.</s><s>Strain CIP 103499<sup>T</sup> has all of the above properties for the species.</s><s>Hippurate is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>The G+C content of its DNA is 66 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>