<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6924_nm.8127" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8127" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8127" rank="species">Aequorivita sublithincola</organism><reference id="rid.6924"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nichols</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aequorivita gen. nov., a member of the family Flavobacteriaceae isolated from terrestrial and marine Antarctic habitats.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1533</fpage><lpage>1541</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.01976-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12361255</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Aequorivita sublithincola</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Aequorivita sublithincola</i> (sub.lith.in'co.la. L. pref. <i>sub</i> below; Gr. n. <i>lithos</i> stone; L. nom. n. <i>incola</i> an inhabitant; N.L. n. <i>sublithincola</i> an inhabitant below stone)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is the same as that of the genus unless specified otherwise.</s><s>Cells appear as rods or filaments in young cultures (0.5-20x0.4-0.5 μm).</s><s>Forms orange colonies.</s><s>Requires sodium ions for growth (at least 1.0% NaCl).</s><s>Weakly tolerates 6%NaCl, but not 10% NaCl.</s><s>No growth occurs in the presence of 1%ox-bile salts.</s><s>Detectable levels of acid are not produced from carbohydrates nor can strains utilize D-glucose as a sole carbon and energy source in the presence of 0.02% yeast extract.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase are negative.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide is not formed from L-cysteine.</s><s>Produces a strong urease and can hydrolyse Tween 80, gelatin and L-tyrosine (no diffusible pigment).</s><s>Unable to hydrolyse starch, aesculin, agar, cellulose, CMC, xylan, dextran, DNA, tributyrin, urate, xanthine, casein or elastin.</s><s>Lipase (olive oil) and lecithinase are not produced.</s><s>Produces an alkaline phosphatase.</s><s>Strains produce N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, but not α-glucosidase, α-galactosidase, α-arabinosidase, β-galactosidase, 6-phospho-bgalactosidase, β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase or afucosidase.</s><s>The G+C content of cells is 36-37 mol%.</s><s>The type and only available strain is strain 9-3<sup>T</sup> (= ACAM 643<sup>T</sup>=DSM 14238<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from a quartz stone sublithic cyanobacterial community found in the Vestfold Hills, Antarctica.</s></p></content></protolog>