<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2385_nm.11243" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11243" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11243" rank="species">Brevundimonas aveniformis</organism><reference id="rid.2385"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ryu</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yun</surname><given-names>P.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>C.O.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Brevundimonas aveniformis sp. nov., a stalked species isolated from activated sludge</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1561</fpage><lpage>1565</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64737-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17625194</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Brevundimonas aveniformis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Brevundimonas aveniformis</em> (a.ven.i.for′mis. L. n. <em>avena</em> stalk; L. suff. -<em>formis</em> of the shape of; N.L. fem. adj. <em>aveniformis</em> stalk-shaped).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, rod-like bacteria that can produce stalks; the size of the main cell body is 0.3–0.4×1.0–2.0 μm.</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar are white, slightly raised and circular with entire margins.</s><s>Growth occurs optimally at 30 °C and pH 7.5–8.5.</s><s>The optimum NaCl concentration is 0–1 % (w/v); no growth occurs at ≥3 %.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite and nitrogen gas is produced.</s><s>Hydrolyses casein, urea, tyrosine and gelatin, but not Tween 80 and 20, aesculin or starch.</s><s>Negative for indole, H<sub>2</sub>S and acetoin production and citrate utilization (API 20E).</s><s>Produces acids from raffinose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannose and d-mannitol, but not from d-glucose, d-fructose, d-galactose, l-arabinose, melibiose, lactose, arbutin or salicin.</s><s>Produces leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and urease, but not esterase (C4), lipase (C14), arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Weak enzymic activities are observed for esterase lipase (C8), alkaline phosphatase, trypsin, tryptophan deaminase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin and acid phosphatase.</s><s>The predominant polar lipid is phosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>Utilizes glycogen, pyruvic acid methyl ester, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine and urocanic acid (Biolog GN2).</s><s>Other organic substrates included in Biolog GN2 MicroPlate system are not utilized.</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is Q-10.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω7c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, and the main hydroxy fatty acid is iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 64.1 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, EMB102<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12609<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17977<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from activated sludge that performed EBPR in a laboratory-scale sequencing batch reactor.</s></p></content></protolog>