<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3930_nm.8529" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8529" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8529" rank="species">Burkholderia xenovorans</organism><reference id="rid.3930"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Goris</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Caballero-Mellado</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Quensen</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tiedje</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Classification of the biphenyl- and polychlorinated biphenyl-degrading strain LB400T and relatives as Burkholderia xenovorans sp. nov.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1677</fpage><lpage>1681</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63101-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15388727</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Burkholderia xenovorans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Burkholderia xenovorans</em> [xe.no′vo.rans. Gr. adj. <em>xenos</em> foreign; L. part. pres. <em>vorans</em> devouring, digesting; N.L. part. adj. <em>xenovorans</em> digesting foreign (xenobiotic) compounds].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, motile, non-sporulating, straight rods (1–2 μm long and 0·5 μm wide).</s><s>The strains grow on nutrient agar at 28 °C, but not at 42 °C.</s><s>No growth is observed on <em>N</em>-cetyl-<em>N</em>,<em>N</em>,<em>N</em>-trimethylammonium bromide (cetrimide) or on 10 % (w/v) lactose.</s><s>The strains do not grow in the presence of acetamide or in the presence of 3·0, 4·5 or 6·0 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth in the presence of 0·5 or 1·5 % (w/v) NaCl is strain-dependent (negative for the type strain).</s><s>All strains grow on blood agar at 30 °C and on Drigalski agar, while growth on blood agar at 37 °C is strain-dependent (negative for the type strain).</s><s>Haemolysis of horse blood is not observed.</s><s>Liquefaction of gelatin or hydrolysis of aesculin is not observed.</s><s>Tween 80 is hydrolysed.</s><s>No production of acid or H<sub>2</sub>S in triple-sugar-iron agar, no indole or pigment production.</s><s>Acetylene is reduced.</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite reduction is strain-dependent (negative for the type strain).</s><s>In O–F medium, d-glucose, d-fructose and d-xylose are oxidized, but not maltose or adonitol.</s><s>d-Glucose is not fermented.</s><s>Assimilation of d-glucose, dl-norleucine, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-gluconate, caprate, adipate, l-malate, citrate, phenyl acetate, dl-lactate and dl-lactate with methionine, but not of trehalose, l-arabinose, maltose or sucrose.</s><s>Assimilation of l-arginine is strain-dependent (positive for the type strain).</s><s>Catalase, oxidase, alkaline and acid phosphatase, esterase C4, ester lipase C8, leucine arylamidase and phosphoamidase activity is present.</s><s>Amylase, DNase, lipase C14, tryptophanase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase and arginine dihydrolase activity are not detected.</s><s>Activities of urease, valine arylamidase and cysteine arylamidase are strain-dependent (enzyme activities are, respectively, absent, present and present in the type strain).</s><s>The whole-cell fatty acid profile comprises 14 : 0 (4·7 %), 14 : 0 3OH (8·5 %), 16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (19·1 %), 16 : 0 (18·2 %), 17 : 0 cyclo (5·1 %), 16 : 1 2OH (2·2 %), 16 : 0 2OH (2·2 %), 16 : 0 3OH (7·1 %), 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (27·3 %), 18 : 0 (0·5 %), 19 : 0 cyclo <em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> (3·6 %) and 18 : 1 2OH (0·9 %) as major components [summed feature 2 (comprising 14 : 0 3OH, 16 : 1 iso I, an unidentified fatty acid with equivalent chain-length value of 10·928 or 12 : 0 ALDE or any combination of these fatty acids) and summed feature 3 (comprising 16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> or 15 iso 2OH or both) are mentioned above as 14 : 0 3OH and 16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, respectively, as these fatty acid have been reported in <em>Burkholderia</em> species (Stead, 1992)].</s><s>The G+C content varies between 62·4 and 62·9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain (LB400<sup>T</sup>=LMG 21463<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 46959<sup>T</sup>=NRRL B-18064<sup>T</sup>) was isolated from a PCB-contaminated soil collected from a landfill in Moreau, New York.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 62·6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Currently, whole-genome sequence analysis of strain LB400<sup>T</sup> is in progress (http://genome.jgi-psf.org/draft_microbes/burfu/burfu.home.html).</s></p></content></protolog>