<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9234_nm.14494" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14494" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14494" rank="species">Massilia niastensis</organism><reference id="rid.9234"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Weon</surname><given-names>H.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>B.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hong</surname><given-names>S.-B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>Y.-A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Koo</surname><given-names>B.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kwon</surname><given-names>S.-W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Massilia niabensis sp. nov. and Massilia niastensis sp. nov., isolated from air samples</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1656</fpage><lpage>1660</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.006908-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19542125</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Massilia niastensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Massilia niastensis</em> (ni.as.ten′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>niastensis</em> pertaining to NIAST, the National Institute of Agricultural Science and Technology, where taxonomic studies of the type strain were conducted).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-negative rods (0.6–0.8×1.5–5.0 μm) that are motile by means of single polar flagella.</s><s>Colonies are ivory-coloured, round and convex with clear margins.</s><s>Grows well on R2A and nutrient agar, but does not grow on trypticase soy agar or MacConkey agar.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Grows at 5–40 °C (optimally at 28 °C) on R2A, at pH 6–8 (optimally at pH 7) and 0–1 % NaCl.</s><s>Positive for aesculin hydrolysis, gelatin hydrolysis and <em>β</em>-galactosidase, but negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase and urease (API 20NE test strips).</s><s>Degrades hypoxanthine, starch and tyrosine, but does not degrade casein, chitin, CM-cellulose, DNA, pectin, Tween 80 or xanthine.</s><s>Assimilates d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, potassium gluconate, malic acid, l-rhamnose, itaconic acid, sodium acetate, l-alanine, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid, salicin, 3-hydroxybutyric acid, 4-hydroxybenzoic acid and l-proline, but not d-mannitol, capric acid, adipic acid, trisodium citrate, phenylacetic acid, d-ribose, inositol, sucrose, suberic acid, sodium malonate, lactic acid, potassium 5-ketogluconate, glycogen, l-serine, melibiose, l-fucose, d-sorbitol, propionic acid, valeric acid, l-histidine or potassium 2-ketogluconate (API 20NE and API ID 32GN test strips).</s><s>Positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, but negative for esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase (API ZYM test strips).</s><s>The major fatty acids (&#x003E;10 %) are summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>.</s><s>The predominant ubiquinone is Q-8.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 66.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 5516S-1<sup>T</sup> (=KACC 12599<sup>T</sup> =DSM 21313<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from an air sample collected from Suwon, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>