<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7037_nm.5891" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5891" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5891" rank="species">Kocuria polaris</organism><reference id="rid.7037"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Reddy</surname><given-names>G.S.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prakash</surname><given-names>J.S.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prabahar</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsumoto</surname><given-names>G.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shivaji</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Kocuria polaris sp. nov., an orange-pigmented psychrophilic bacterium isolated from an Antarctic cyanobacterial mat sample.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>183</fpage><lpage>187</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02336-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12656171</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Kocuria polaris</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Kocuria polaris</em> (po.la′ris. M.L. adj. <em>polaris</em> of, or pertaining to, a pole).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are coccoid (1·0–1·5 μm in diameter), occurring in pairs, tetrads or clusters.</s><s>Non-motile, Gram-positive and aerobic.</s><s>Colonies on peptone/yeast extract medium are 0·1–2·0 mm in diameter and appear smooth, round, uniformly edged, translucent, mucoid and orange in colour.</s><s>Psychrophilic.</s><s>Grows between 5 and 30 °C, with optimum growth at 20 °C.</s><s>Grows in ABM adjusted to pH 7–12 and tolerates up to 2·9 % NaCl.</s><s>Catalase- and lipase-positive.</s><s>Negative for l-lysine decarboxylase, l-arginine decarboxylase, β-galactosidase, l-arginine dihydrolase and levan formation.</s><s>Negative results in the indole test, the methyl red test and the Voges–Proskauer test.</s><s>Utilizes l-rhamnose, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, d-mannose, d-xylose, acetate, sorbitol, l-glutamine, l-glycine, l-serine and l-threonine as sole carbon sources, but can not utilize <em>meso</em>-erythritol, melezitose, d-ribose, d-sorbose, citrate, dextran, lactic acid, dulcitol, sucrose, succinic acid, thioglycollate, d-trehalose, l-cysteine, l-histidine, l-isoleucine, l-lysine, l-proline, l-methionine, l-tyrosine, l-tryptophan, l-valine or β-hydroxybutyric acid as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Does not produce gas from d-glucose, d-fructose, l-arabinose, d-xylose, l-rhamnose, d-galactose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, lactose or sucrose.</s><s>Acid is produced in the presence of d-fructose, d-galactose, lactose and sucrose.</s><s>Oxidizes d-glucose, d-maltose, d-ribose, d-trehalose and d-xylose, but not l-arabinose or d-galactose.</s><s>Ferments d-fructose, but not l-arabinose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-maltose, d-ribose, d-trehalose or d-xylose.</s><s>Other characteristics of the species can be found in Table 1.</s><s>Sensitive to ampicillin, cefoperazone, co-trimoxazole, amikacin, cefazoline, ciprofloxacin, penicillin, vancomycin, tetracycline, lomefloxacin, erythromycin, roxithromycin, tobramycin, cephotaxime, lincomycin, chloramphenicol, streptomycin, kanamycin, norfloxacin, amoxycillin and cefuroxime, but resistant to nitrofurantoin, nalidixic acid and colistin.</s><s>Cell-wall peptidoglycan is l-Lys–Ala<sub>3</sub> (type A3α).</s><s>d-Galactose, d-glucose and d-ribose are the major cell-wall sugars.</s><s>Menaquinones and fatty acid composition of the species are shown in Tables 1 and 2, respectively.</s><s>Polar lipids are phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol and an unidentified phospholipid.</s><s>Cells contain six water-insoluble pigments that are soluble in methanol; pigment production is not dependent on any specific growth conditions or on the composition of the medium.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 72·5 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from a cyanobacterial mat sample from McMurdo Dry Valley, Antarctica (77°33′3″S, 160°38′E).</s><s>The type strain is CMS 76or<sup>T</sup> (=MTCC 3702<sup>T</sup> =DSM 14382<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>