<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7179_nm.3202" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3202" rank="genus">Klebsiella</organism><reference id="rid.7179"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Carter</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bowden</surname><given-names>F.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bastian</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Myers</surname><given-names>G.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sriprakash</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kemp</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic evidence for reclassification of Calymmatobacterium granulomatis as Klebsiella granulomatis comb. nov.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1695</fpage><lpage>1700</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-4-1695</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10555350</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <i>Klebsiella</i></s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Klebsiella</i> species are facultatively anaerobic, Gram-negative, non-motile, generally straight rods arranged singly, in pairs or in short chains and measuring 0.3-1.0 μm in diameter and 0.6-6.0 μm in length (Orskov, 1984). <i>K. granulomatis</i> is pleomorphic (Dienst &#x0026; Bronwell, 1984), i.e. curved or straight rods, coccoid, diplococcoid, ovoid or elliptical in shape. Most <i>Klebsiella</i> species are capsulated (Orskov, 1984) though <i>K. granulomatis</i> may be capsulated (mature form) or non-capsulated (immature form) (Hart, 1997). Most species are cultivable on routine microbiological media (0rskov, 1984). <i>K. granulomatis</i> is facultatively intracellular, residing within the cytoplasm of large mononuclear cells and cannot be cultured on routine microbiological media (Dienst &#x0026; Bronwell, 1984). There are currently five recognized species of <i>Klebsiella</i>: <i>K. pneumoniae</i>, <i>Klebsiella oxytoca</i>, <i>Klebsiella terrigena</i>, <i>Klebsiella planticola</i> and <i>Klebsiella ornithinolytica</i> (Orskov, 1984; Sakazaki et al., 1989) and three recognized subspecies of <i>K. pneumoniae</i>; <i>K. pneumoniae</i> subsp. <i>pneumoniae</i>, <i>K. pneumoniae</i> subsp. <i>ozaenae</i> and <i>K. pneumoniae</i> subsp. <i>rhinoscleromatis</i> (Orskov, 1984). In the absence of DNA-DNA hybridization studies it is not possible to determine whether <i>K. granulomatis</i> is a sixth <i>Klebsiella</i> species or a fourth subspecies of <i>K. pneumoniae</i>. For a complete description of the characteristics of the genus <i>Klebsiella</i> see Orskov (1984).</s></p></content></protolog>