<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3138_nm.14084" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14084" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.473" rank="species">Fervidobacterium pennavorans</organism><reference id="rid.3138"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Friedrich</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Antranikian</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Keratin Degradation by Fervidobacterium pennavorans, a Novel Thermophilic Anaerobic Species of the Order Thermotogales.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>62</volume><fpage>2875</fpage><lpage>2882</lpage><source id="228">Applied and Environmental Microbiology</source><abbrev>Appl Environ Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0099-2240</issn><essn>1098-5336</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16535379</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Fervidobacterium pennavorans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Screening for feather degradation by thermophilic microorganisms. Nineteen strains of extremely thermophilic and hyperthermophilic anaerobic archaea and bacteria were investigated for their ability to grow on native feathers. The investigated strains were <i>Thermococcus stetteri</i>, <i>Thermococcus</i> sp. strain AN1, <i>Thermococcus litoralis</i>, <i>Thermococcus celer</i>, <i>Staphylothermus marinus</i>, <i>Pyrococcus furiosus</i>, <i>Pyrococcus woesei</i>, <i>Thermoanaerobacter brockii</i>, <i>Thermoanaerobacter thermohydrosulfuricus</i>, <i>Thermoanaerobacter ethanolicus</i>, <i>Thermoanaerobacter finnii</i>, <i>Thermobacteroides proteolyticus</i>, <i>Thermosipho africanus</i>, <i> Thermotoga maritima</i>, <i>Thermotoga neapolitana</i>, <i>Thermotoga thermarum</i>, <i>F. nodosum</i>, <i>F. islandicum</i>, and <i>F. pullulanolyticum</i>. Of the 19 investigated extremely thermophilic microorganisms, 18 strains were unable to attack feathers. <i>F. pullulanolyticum</i> could attack feathers to a very low extent and only after incubation for 7 days. In vitro experiments with proteases from <i>Thermococcus stetteri</i>, <i>Thermococcus</i> sp. strain AN1, and <i>Thermosipho africanus</i> have also shown that the structure of native feathers was not altered significantly even after incubation at 75°C for 7 days.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolation of feather-degrading bacteria.</s><s>After incubation of samples from hot springs of the island San Miguel (Azores, Portugal) in I medium with native feathers at 70°C under anaerobic conditions enrichments of mixed populations of microorganisms were obtained.</s><s>The mixed cultures grew to a cell density of 10<sup>7</sup>/ml within 12 h.</s><s>The cultures were then diluted to 10 cells per ml and plated on agar plates, which were incubated under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>After 3 days milky colonies surrounded by clear substrate lysing zones were picked and transferred into liquid media (I media).</s><s>After three transfers in liquid cultures and on agar plates a pure culture was obtained.</s><s>The new isolate was found to degrade native feathers completely within 48 h (Fig. 1).</s><s>Stock cultures of the newly isolated organism remained viable even after storage for 12 months at 4°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology.</s><s>The feather-degrading isolate was rod shaped with a characteristic outer sheath-like structure.</s><s>During the exponential growth phase short rods about 2 μm long occurred singly or in pairs, whereas cells grown for 24 h reached a length of 20 mm.</s><s>At one end of the cell a characteristic bleb was visible (Fig. 2).</s><s>In stationary-phase cultures spheroids were observed containing up to four cells.</s><s>The isolate stained gram negative, and no endospores were observed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Optimal growth conditions.</s><s>Growth of the newly isolated strain occurred between pH 5.5 and 8.0 (Fig. 3a) and between 50 and 80°C (Fig. 3b) with an optimum at pH 6.5 and 70°C.</s><s>Growth was detected between 0 and 4% (wt/vol) NaCl; the optimal NaCl concentration was 0.4% (wt/vol) (Fig. 3c).</s><s>Under optimal growth conditions the doubling time was 2.1 h.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth substrates.</s><s>The new isolate was able to use starch, glycogen, pullulan, glucose, fructose, maltose, and xylose as growth substrates.</s><s>Starch was the preferred carbon source.</s><s>The new isolate was not able to utilize lactose, amylose, arabinose, casein, collagen, succinate, or Tween 80.</s><s>The presence of 0.05% yeast extract was required for growth.</s><s>Hydrogen gas had an inhibitory effect which could be eliminated by the addition of elemental sulfur or thiosulfate to the medium.</s><s>The new isolate was a fermentative and strictly anaerobic microorganism.</s><s>As fermentation products ethanol and acetate were found after 48 h of incubation at 70°C; acetate was the major fermentation product.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base composition.</s><s>The G+C content of the new isolate was 40.0 ± 0.6 mol% (n 5 3).</s><s>This is a typical G+C content for members of the <i>Thermotogales</i> order.</s><s>16S rDNA analysis.</s><s>Similarities among 16S rDNA sequences of members of the <i>Thermotogales</i> family are shown in Fig. 4.</s><s>The isolated strain showed high levels of homology with <i>F. pullulanolyticum</i> (99.0%) and with <i>F. islandicum</i> (98.7%).</s><s>These three strains formed a cluster.</s><s>Low-level homology was found with <i>Petrotoga miotherma</i> (80.2%), <i>Geotoga petraea</i> (82.2%), <i>Dictyoglomus thermophilum</i> (80.7%), and <i>Aquifex pyrophilus</i> (80.2%).</s><s>On the basis of the physiological, morphological, enzymological, and 16S rDNA studies the new isolate was characterized as a strain of the <i>Thermotogales</i> order, named <i>Fervidobacterium pennavorans</i>, and deposited at the German Collection for Microorganisms and Cell Cultures (DSMZ) as strain DSM 7003.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Purification and properties of the heat-stable keratinase.</s><s>The cell-bound keratinase of <i>F. pennavorans</i> was purified 32- fold with a yield of 7% (Table 1).</s><s>Since the enzyme activity was not influenced by 0.1% (wt/vol) SDS, it could be purified by preparative SDS-PAGE (Fig. 5).</s><s>Analytical SDS-PAGE and zymogram staining showed that the purified native enzyme has a molecular mass of 130 kDa (Fig. 6).</s><s>The enzyme, which was inhibited by phenylmethylsulfonyl fluoride and 3,4-dichloroisocoumarin, was characterized as a serine protease.</s><s>EDTA and iodoacetate (1 to 5 mM) had only little effect on the enzyme activity.</s><s>The keratinase was active in a broad pH and temperature range, namely, between pH 6.0 and 10.5 and between 50 and 100°C (Fig. 7 and 8).</s><s>After isoelectric focusing one single protein band was observed at pH 3.8 (data not shown).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Degradation of native feather meal by <i>F. pennavorans</i>.</s><s>As shown in Table 2, feather meal degradation was observed after incubation with cell extracts, membrane fractions, and the purified keratinase of <i>F. pennavorans</i>.</s><s>In these experiments amino acids and peptides were released when native feather meal was incubated with cell extracts or membrane fractions.</s><s>After incubation of feather meal with cell extracts all amino acids present in feathers were detected: aspartate, threonine, serine, glutamate, proline, glycine, alanine, valine, isoleucine, leucine, tyrosine, phenylalanine, histidine, lysine, and arginine.</s><s>After incubation with membrane fractions no release of aspartate, glutamate, proline, glycine, or lysine was observed.</s><s>Incubation of feather meal with the purified enzyme, however, resulted in its conversion to peptides but not amino acids.</s><s>In control experiments containing buffer and feather meal, no amino acids or peptides were detected and the feather meal 	residual dry weight (total recovery) remained 100%.</s></p></content></protolog>