<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3040_nm.1384" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1384" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1384" rank="species">Brucella neotomae</organism><reference id="rid.3040"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Stoenner</surname><given-names>H.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lackman</surname><given-names>D.B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A new species of Brucella isolated from the desert wood rat, Neotoma lepida Thomas.</article-title><year>1957</year><volume>18</volume><fpage>947</fpage><lpage>951</lpage><source id="224">American Journal of Veterinary Research</source><abbrev>Am J Vet Res</abbrev><issn>0002-9645</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">13470254</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thermus oshimai</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Five strains of <i>Br. neotomae</i> were recovered from 36 pools of tissue from <i>N. lepida</i>, representative of 108 animals. These illolates are designated as follows: 5K33, 5E1169, 5E1266, 6D152, and 5G239. The serological status of the animals had not been determined at the time when the majority were subjected to necropsy. Hence, cultures were made from auquots of suspension frozen at the time they were originally tested for various other pathogens. However, at the time specimen 5K33 was examined, agglutinins against Brucella had already been detected in the serum of this animal. From organs of this rat, cultured individually, an isolation was made only from the liver.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The organism grows aerobically and increased CO<sub>2</sub> tension is not required for primary isolation.</s><s>Maximum growth on agar slants is obtained at 37 C. incubation; growth is delayred at 30 C., and at 42 C. growth is inhibited.</s><s>Very little growth occurs on tryptose agar incubated anaerobically and, in agar shake cultures, growth is restricted to the medium within 2 mm. of the surface.</s><s>On tryptose agar plates inoculated with infectious tissue suspensions, growth appears after incubation for three days.</s><s>After six days of incubation, isolated colonies may reach a diameter of 3 mm.</s><s>Colonial morphology of this organism is similar to that of other Brucella.</s><s>Colonies are convex, amorphous, smooth, glistening, and their edges are entire.</s><s>Young colonies are semitransparent and appear uniformly opalescent when viewed with transmitted light, whereas older colonies develop distinctly brown centers.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The newly isolated Brucella is a non-motile coccobacillary organism.</s><s>In cultures grown on tryptose agar for three days, cells are approximately 0.6 μ in diameter by 0.6 to 1.4 μ in length.</s><s>It is gram-negative and, like other Brucella, the organism also retains the basic fuchsin of Macehiavello stain.</s><s>No flagella, capsille, or endospore could be demonstrated with recommended stains.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Br. neotomae</i> does not produce indol and is negative to the Voges-Proskauer and methyl red tests; nitrates are reduced to nitrites.</s><s>Gelatin is not liquified and litmus milk remains unchanged.</s><s>With Bauer's urease test, all five stains are positive after ten minutes of incubation.</s><s>Maltose, sucrose, lactose, raffinose, salicin, melezitose, rhamnose, trehalose, inulin, inositol, sorbitol, mannitol, and glycerol are not fermented.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A moderate amount of acid without gas was produced in galactose, dextrose, and arabinose (table 1).</s><s>Although the final pH of levulose and xylose at 14 days after inoculation with <i>Br. neotomae</i> was only slightly lower than that in uninoculated tubes of control sugars, the pH of these two sugars inoculated with three known species of Brucclla was significantly higher.</s><s>The final pH of sugar-free tryptose, base inoculated with three recognized species of Brucella was more alkaline than the same medium inoculated with <i>Br. neotomae</i>; this increased alkalinity may possibly reflect differences in the ability to deaminate amino acids in the base.</s><s>With the example of arabinose inoculated with <i>Br. suis</i>, the pH of other sugars inoculated with the three recognized species of Brucella remained above the pH values  of inoculated control sugars.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Production of H<sub>2</sub>S on tryptose agar by strains of <i>Br. neotomae</i> was similar to that of <i>Br. suis</i> (fig. 1).</s><s>Slightly less H<sub>2</sub>S was formed by  the first <i>Br. neotomae</i> during the first 24-hour period but, thereafter, the amount and duration of H<sub>2</sub>S production was essentially the same as that of<i>Br. suis</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Results of dye sensitivity tests (table 2) were obtained freshly isolated cultures were obtained of <i>Br. neotomae</i>.</s><s>These cultures were inhibited by dilutions (1:100,000) of thionin and basic fuchsin that are usually recommened for the typing of Brucella.</s><s>However, the sensitivity of subcultrues of strains 5G239 and 5K33 changed during eultivation on tryptose agar for five and nine months, respectively.</s><s>After such prolonged cultivation on artificial medium, these subcultures were partially inhibited by a dilution of 1:50,000 but they were not inhibited by a 1:100,000 dilution of thionin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The results of cross-absorption tests (table 3) clearly indicate a close antigenic relationship between <i>Br. abortus</i> and <i>Br. neotomae</i> and a dissimilarity between these two and <i>Br. melitensis</i>.</s><s>Antibodies in approporiate dilutions of <i>Br. neotomae</i> antiserum were completely removed by absorption with <i>Br. abortus</i> antigen and vice versa.</s><s>However, agglutinins in <i>Br. melitensis</i> antiserum were not completely removed by absorption with <i>Br. abortus</i> or <i>Br. neotomae</i> antigens.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Based on limited titrations, the intraperitoneal m.i.d. for mice was determined to be two to three organimsms, whereas a comparable dose for guinea pigs was about a hundredfold greater.</s><s>The organism was regularly recovered from mice and guinea pigs for 42 days after inoculation.</s><s>After 60 days postinoculation, some guinea pigs had cleared their tissues of the organisms but others remained infected for 150 days the longest interval tested.</s><s>Gross pathological changes in infected mice and guinea pigs were minimal.</s><s>Although testicular abscesses were occasionally observed, multiple nerotic foci, such as are found in livers and spleens of guinea pigs infected with any of the three common species of Brucella, were infrequently observed.</s><s>In immature <i>N. lepida</i> which were infected by ingestion or intraperitoneal injection of organisms, no significant gross pathological changes were observed.</s><s>Details of studies on the pathogenesis and pathology of <i>Br. neotomae</i> infections in laboratory animals will be published later.</s></p></content></protolog>