<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6527_nm.1471" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1471" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1471" rank="species">Agromonas oligotrophica</organism><reference id="rid.6527"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ohta</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hattori</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Agromonas oligotrophica gen. nov., sp. nov., a nitrogen-fixing oligotrophic bacterium.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>429</fpage><lpage>446</lpage><source id="227">Antonie van Leeuwenhoek</source><issn>0003-6072</issn><essn>1572-9699</essn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Agromonas oligotrophica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Agromonas oligotrophica</i> is described as follows. Bent, branched and budding cells, 0.6-1.0 μm by 2-7 μm, are produced on dilute nutrient broth. Several cells adhere to each other and form a rosette. Motile by a polar flagellum. Endospores not formed. Gram-negative. On dilute nutrient broth agar, colonies are punctiform, pulvinate, entire and colourless. Oligotrophic, i.e. growth can occur in a medium containing less than 1 mg/I of an organic carbon source. NaCl, KCl, casamino acids, peptone and meat extract inhibit growth at 0.5-1.0 %. Several sugars and many organic acids are utilized. Aromatic acids such as ferulic aciid, p-coumaric acid and p-anisic acid are used but not benzoic acid. Neither acid nor gas is produced from glucose. Not proteolytic to casein and gelatin. Cellulose and starch not hydrolysed. Aerobic. Catalase- and oxidase- positive. Atmospheric nitrogen is fixed under low O<sub>2</sub>-pressure. Cellular fatty acids mainly consist of C<sub>18:1</sub>; a small amount of C<sub>16:0</sub> and a 19-carbon unsaturated acid with a double bond and possibly with a side chain are found as minor components. Ubiquinone Q-10 is present. The GC content of the DNA ranges from 65.1-66.0 mol %.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>Agrom. oligotrophica</i> is JCM 1494.</s></p><p class="description"><s>We observed that irregular rod-shaped, oligotrophic bacteria were abundant in the roots of rice plants and many of them were identical to <i>Agrom. oligotrophica</i> (Ohta and Hattori, to be published).</s><s>This observation suggests that <i>Agrom. oligotrophica</i> would play an important role in the cycle of nitrogen on the roots of rice plants.</s></p></content></protolog>