<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9039_nm.10813" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10813" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5430" rank="species">Lactobacillus salivarius</organism><reference id="rid.9039"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Raftis</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Canchaya</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fitzgerald</surname><given-names>G.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Van Sinderen</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>O'Toole</surname><given-names>P.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Polyphasic analysis indicates that Lactobacillus salivarius subsp. salivarius and Lactobacillus salivarius subsp. salicinius do not merit separate subspecies status.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2397</fpage><lpage>2403</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64426-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17012569</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Lactobacillus salivarius</em> Rogosa <em>et al.</em> 1953</s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-motile, non-spore-forming, catalase-negative, nitrate reduction-negative rods with rounded ends, 0.6-0.9×1.5-5 μm, occurring singly and in chains of varying length.</s><s>Sometimes, the cells are not exactly cylindrical and straight, but are instead slightly bent and swollen on one end.</s><s>Colonies on MRS agar show a milky-white or light-brown colour and are convex, with a smooth edge and smooth surface.</s><s>Mainly isolated from the mouth and intestinal tract of humans and hamster and the intestinal tract of chicken and swine.</s><s>All strains grow at 45 °C, but not at 15 °C.</s><s>Optimal growth temperature is 37 °C.</s><s>Growth is stimulated in the presence of 5 % CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Glucose, fructose, mannose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and sucrose are fermented by all strains.</s><s>Galactose (30/32 strains tested), sorbitol (28/32), maltose (31/32), lactose (28/32), trehalose (26/32), raffinose (25/32) and melibiose (27/32) are fermented by most strains, including the type strains of the two previously recognized subspecies.</s><s>Rhamnose is fermented weakly by many strains.</s><s>A few strains ferment ribose, adonitol, xylitol, d-arabitol, arbutin and salicin and hydrolyse aesculin, but the type strains of the two subspecies do not ferment pentoses or pentitols.</s><s>Glycerol, erythritol, arabinose, xylose, sorbose, inositol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-gluconoside, amygdalin, cellobiose, melezitose, starch, glycogen, gentiobiose and gluconate are not fermented.</s><s>The species contains both homofermentative and facultatively heterofermentative strains.</s><s>Most strains produce l-lactic acid from available hexoses by homofermentation.</s><s>Heterofermentative end products (lactic acid, acetic acid and ethanol) are produced from hexoses by some strains that can ferment ribose.</s><s>Some strains have d-lactate dehydrogenase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA G+C content is 33–36 mol%.</s><s>Many strains of the species contain megaplasmids of sizes ranging from 100 kb to 380 kb, as well as smaller plasmids.</s><s>16S rRNA gene sequences or 16S–23S rRNA ISR sequences do not provide reliable discrimination between strains.</s><s>Based on <em>groEL</em> phylogeny, the species can be separated into two major clades.</s><s>Each clade contains one of the type strains of the two previously recognized subspecies, DSM 20554<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 11742<sup>T</sup>=JCM 1150<sup>T</sup>) (the type strain of <em>L. salivarius</em> subsp. <em>salicinius</em>) and DSM 20555<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 11741<sup>T</sup>=JCM 1231<sup>T</sup>) (the type strain of <em>L. salivarius</em> and of <em>L. salivarius</em> subsp. <em>salivarius</em>).</s></p></content></protolog>