<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4199_nm.4128" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4128" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4128" rank="species">Anaerostipes caccae</organism><reference id="rid.4199"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schwiertz</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hold</surname><given-names>G.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Duncan</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gruhl</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Flint</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Blaut</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Anaerostipes caccae gen. nov., sp. nov., a new saccharolytic, acetate-utilising, butyrate-producing bacterium from human faeces.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>25</volume><fpage>46</fpage><lpage>51</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1078/0723-2020-00096</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12086188</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Anaerostipes caccae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Anaerostipes caccae</i> (cac'cae, pronounced kak'ka Gr. n. <i>kakke</i> faeces: N.L. gen. n. <i>caccae</i> of faeces)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells consist of non-motile, non spore-forming rods.</s><s>Individual cells are 0.5–0.6 μm in width x 2.0–4.0 μm in length and occur in chains of up to 4 cells.</s><s>Cells stain Gram-positive but older cultures (&#x003E;16 h) may stain Gram-negative.</s><s>On Columbia blood agar, white-opaque colonies are formed that are 1–3 mm in diameter, circular, convex, smooth, shiny and sticky, which are non haemolytic.</s><s>The strains are strictly anaerobic and catalase and oxidase negative.</s><s>Butyrate, acetate and lactate are the major products of glucose metabolism.</s><s>Acetate is utilised.</s><s>Using conventional tests acid is produced from D-fructose, FOS, D-glucose, D-galactose, inositol, maltose, D-mannose, ribose (weak), soluble starch, sucrose, L-sorbose and sorbitol.</s><s>Acid may or may not be produced from salicin.</s><s>Acid is not produced from L-arabinose, cellobiose, glycerol, inulin, lactose, lactulose, melibiose, melezitose, L-rhamnose, D-trehalose or D-xylose.</s><s>Using the miniaturised API 50 system acid is produced from adonitol, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, D-arabinose, dulcitol, erythritol, galactose, D-glucose, gluconate, D-fructose, inositol, D-lyxose, maltose, D-mannose, mannitol, melibiose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, N-acetyl-glucosamine, D-raffinose (weak), ribose (weak), L-sorbose, sorbitol, sucrose, D-tagatose, D-turanose and xylitol but not from amygdalin, L-arabinose, cellobiose, D-fucose, b-gentiobiose, glycerol, glycogen, inulin, lactose, 5-keto-gluconate, melezitose, α-methyl-D-mannoside, b-methyl-D-xyloside, rhamnose, trehalose, D-xylose or L-xylose.</s><s>Acid may or may not be produced from arbutin, salicin and 2-keto-gluconate.</s><s>Aesculin hydrolysis is variable.</s><s>Using API ZYM and API rapid ID32A systems activity is detected for acid phosphatase and phosphoamidase, and arginine dihydrolase, α-galactosidase and nitrate reductase (weak reaction) respectively.</s><s>No activity is detected for alanine arylamidase, alkaline, phosphatase, arginine arylamidase, α-arabinosidase, chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, esterase C4, ester lipase C8, α-fucosidase, β-galactosidase, β-galactosidase-6-phosphate, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, glycine arylamidase, glutamylglutamic acid arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, leucylglycine arylamidase, lipase C14, α-mannosidase, N-acetyl-α-glucosaminidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, proline arylamidase, serine arylamidase, trypsin, tyrosine arylamidase, valine arylamidase or urease.</s><s>Gelatin is not hydrolysed and indole is not produced.</s><s>The DNA G + C content is 45.5–46.0 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from human faeces.</s><s>The type strain is L1-92<sup>T</sup> (= DSM 14662<sup>T</sup> = NCIMB 13811<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The GenBank accession number of the 16S rRNA sequence of the type strain is AJ270487.</s></p></content></protolog>