<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3822_nm.7810" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7810" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7810" rank="species">Spirochaeta smaragdinae</organism><reference id="rid.3822"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Magot</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fardeau</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arnauld</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lanau</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ollivier</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thomas</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Spirochaeta smaragdinae sp. nov., a new mesophilic strictly anaerobic spirochete from an oil field.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>155</volume><fpage>185</fpage><lpage>191</lpage><source id="123">FEMS Microbiology Letters</source><abbrev>FEMS Microbiol Lett</abbrev><issn>0378-1097</issn><essn>1574-6968</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1574-6968.1997.tb13876.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9351200</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Spirochaeta smaragdinae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Spirochaeta smaragdinae</i> (sma.rag.di.nae. M. L. masc. smaragdus, emerald; gen. smaragdinae, from Emerald, the name of the oil field in Congo, Central Africa)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Spirochetes with corkscrew-like motility which produce translucent colonies with regular edges and a diameter of 0.5 mm after 2 weeks incubation at 37°C.</s><s>Spiral cells that are 0.3-0.5 by 5-30 μm.</s><s>Cells stain Gram-negative and are chemoorganotrophic obligately anaerobic members of the domain <i>Bacteria</i>.</s><s>The isolate contains a 1-2-1 flagella arrangement, a typical characteristic of most members of the genus <i>Spirochaeta</i>.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 37°C with growth occurring between 20°C and over 40°C.</s><s>The optimum pH is 7.0 with growth occurring between pH 5.5 and 8.0.</s><s>Obligately halophilic.</s><s>The optimum NaCl concentration for growth is 5% and the NaCl concentration range for growth is 1.0-10%.</s><s>Doubling time under optimal conditions is about 25 h in the presence of glucose and thiosulfate.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of fructose, galactose, o-xylose, o-glucose, ribose, D-mannose, mannitol, glycerol, yeast extract, biotrypcase and fumarate, but not with D-arabinose, rhamnose, sorbose, L-xylose, sucrose, maltose, acetate, butyrate, propionate, pyruvate, lactate and casamino acids.</s><s>Yeast extract is required for growth and cannot be replaced by a vitamin mixture.</s><s>Fumarate was fermented to acetate and succinate.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub> and ethanol were produced as minor end-products and lactate as a major end-product from glucose fermentation.</s><s>Thiosulfate and elemental sulfur were reduced to sulfide.</s><s>The end-products formed from glucose oxidation in the presence of thiosulfate were lactate. acetate, CO<sub>2</sub> and H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 50% (as determined by HPLC).</s><s>Isolated from an oil-injection water.</s><s>The type strain is SEBR 4228<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 11293).</s></p></content></protolog>