<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11761_nm.19864" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.19864" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.19864" rank="species">Koreibacter algae</organism><reference id="rid.11761"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>D.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Koreibacter algae gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from
seaweed</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1510</fpage><lpage>1515</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.014647-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19684316</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Koreibacter algae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Koreibacter algae</em> (al′gae. L. gen. n. <em>algae</em> of alga, seaweed).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The morphological and chemotaxonomic characteristics are the same as those given in the genus description.</s><s>Colonies are light yellow, circular, convex with entire margins and approximately 0.5–0.8 mm in diameter after incubation on MA at 30 °C for 5 days.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–37 °C (optimum 25–30 °C) and at pH 4.1–12.1 (optimum pH 7.1), but not at pH 3.5 and 13.0, and with 0–10 % NaCl (optimum 1–4 %).</s><s>DNA is degraded, but casein, cellulose, chitin, elastin, hypoxanthine, starch, l-tyrosine and xanthine are not.</s><s>Enzyme tests with the API ZYM system are positive for <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, weakly positive for esterase (C4) and esterase lipase (C8) and negative for alkaline phosphatase, lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Acid is produced from maltose, l-rhamnose, trehalose and glycerol, but not from d-arabinose, l-arabinose, cellobiose, dextrin, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, inulin, lactose, d-mannose, melezitose, <em>α</em>-methyl d-glucoside, <em>α</em>-methyl d-mannoside, raffinose, salicin, l-sorbose, sucrose, d-xylose, d-dulcitol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol or d-xylitol.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acid is ai-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 68.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, DSW-2<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13436<sup>T</sup> =DSM 22126<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a seaweed sample taken on the coast of Mara Island, Jeju, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>