<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5528_nm.9842" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9842" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9842" rank="species">Mesorhizobium thiogangeticum</organism><reference id="rid.5528"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ghosh</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roy</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mesorhizobium thiogangeticum sp. nov., a novel sulfur-oxidizing chemolithoautotroph from rhizosphere soil of an Indian tropical leguminous plant.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>91</fpage><lpage>97</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63967-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16403872</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Mesorhizobium thiogangeticum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mesorhizobium thiogangeticum</em> (thi.o.gan.ge′ti.cum. Gr. neut. n. <em>thion</em> sulfur; L. neut. adj. <em>gangeticum</em> from Ganga; N.L. neut. adj. <em>thiogangeticum</em> because the bacterium is so far the only sulfur-lithotrophic member of <em>Mesorhizobium</em> and is a native of the Gangetic plains of India).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, aerobic, non-spore-forming, irregularly elongated or rod-shaped bacterium (cells 1·2–1·5×0·2–0·4 μm).</s><s>Colonies on LB or MSTY media are shining white, convex, opaque and reach 1–3 mm in diameter within 4–5 days at 30 °C.</s><s>Maximum temperature for growth is 37 °C and range of pH tolerance is 5·5–8·5.</s><s>Catalase-positive, but oxidase-negative.</s><s>Strain SJT<sup>T</sup> cannot liquefy gelatin, produce indole or solubilize phosphate.</s><s>It can grow heterotrophically in complex media like LB, NB, YMA and MS-peptone casein hydrolysate.</s><s>In synthetic media supplemented with 50 mg yeast extract l<sup>−1</sup> or vitamin mixture, the isolate utilizes only a few carbon compounds, d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-galactose, d-mannitol, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-isoleucine, l-glutamine, succinate and sodium benzoate, as the sole source of energy for chemo-organoheterotrophic growth.</s><s>No growth is observed with citrate, oxalate, malate, acetate, maltose, sucrose, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, mandelate, dl-lactate, d-fructose, d-raffinose, d-xylose, d-lactose, l-aspartic acid, l-lysine, l-cysteine, l-cystine, l-tyrosine, l-threonine, l-alanine, l-serine, d-mannose, l-arginine or tryptophan.</s><s>No growth is observed in nitrogen-free Burk medium under aerobic conditions.</s><s>Chemolithoautotrophic growth is observed with thiosulfate and elemental sulfur, but not tetrathionate, thiocyanate, soluble sulfides, sulfite or arsenite.</s><s>Synthesizes the following fatty acids: 14 : 0 (0·88 %), 15 : 0 iso (8·23 %), summed feature 3 (16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>/15 : 0 iso 2-OH) (1·82 %), 16 : 0 (2·46 %), 15 : 0 iso 3-OH (0·41 %), 17 : 0 iso (0·85 %), 17 : 1<em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> (0·51 %), 17 : 0 (0·81 %), 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (77·41 %), 18 : 0 (1·28 %), 11-methyl 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (4·23 %), 19 : 0 cyclo <em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> (0·64 %) and 18 : 0 3-OH (0·47 %).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 59·6 mol%, as determined by HPLC.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain SJT<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 22697<sup>T</sup>=MTCC 7001<sup>T</sup>), is the only known strain of the species, isolated from soil adjacent to the roots of the leguminous plant <em>Clitoria ternatea</em>, a native of the lower Gangetic plains of India.</s></p></content></protolog>