<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9930_nm.14901" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14901" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14901" rank="species">Bacillus neizhouensis</organism><reference id="rid.9930"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.-Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.-X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Z.-X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Klenk</surname><given-names>H.-P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>H.-D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>X.-L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus neizhouensis sp. nov., a halophilic marine bacterium isolated from a sea anemone</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>3035</fpage><lpage>3039</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.009522-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19643899</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus neizhouensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus neizhouensis</em> (nei.zhou.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>neizhouensis</em> pertaining to Neizhou Bay, from which the sample that yielded the type strain was collected).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-stain-positive, non-motile, catalase- and oxidase-positive, aerobic, straight rods, approximately 0.5–0.6 μm wide and 3.0–5.0 μm long, occurring singly, as pairs or as short chains, producing ellipsoidal endospores that lie in subterminal swollen sporangia.</s><s>Colonies are pale-yellow pigmented, low convex and translucent with circular/slightly irregular margins, 1–2 mm in diameter after incubation for 3–5 days at 25 °C on marine agar 2216 (Difco).</s><s>Slightly halophilic and facultatively alkaliphilic; growth occurs with 0.5–10 % (w/v) total salts (optimum 2–4 %) and at pH 6.5–10.0 (optimum pH 8.5).</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–30 °C, with an optimum of 25 °C.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced but nitrite is not.</s><s>Negative for tests of methyl red, Voges–Proskauer, H<sub>2</sub>S and indole production.</s><s>Aesculin and gelatin are hydrolysed, but casein, cellulose, DNA, starch, Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80 and urea are not.</s><s>Acids are produced from d-fructose, d-glucose, maltose, sucrose and trehalose, but not from adonitol, l-arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, d-galactose, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-salicin, starch, d-sorbitol or d-xylose.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole sources of carbon and energy or sole sources of carbon, nitrogen and energy: d-glucose, maltose, trehalose and l-leucine; the following substances are not utilized: l-arabinose, cellobiose, dextrin, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-lactose, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-salicin, sucrose, d-xylose, adonitol, d-arabitol, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, acetate, butyrate, citrate, gluconate, propionate, succinate, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, glycine, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-isoleucine, l-methionine, l-proline, l-serine and l-valine.</s><s>Constitutive enzymes expressed are alkaline phosphatase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, leucine arylamidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase; acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-mannosidase, trypsin and valine arylamidase are not observed.</s><s>Susceptible to (μg per disc) ampicillin (30), carbenicillin (30), chloramphenicol (30), gentamicin (10), kanamycin (30), nitrofurantoin (30), novobiocin (30), polymixin B (30), rifampicin (5) and streptomycin (10), but not to lincomycin (2), nalidixic acid (20), tetracycline (30) or tobramycin (10).</s><s><em>meso</em>-Diaminopimelic acid is present in the cell-wall peptidoglycan as the diagnostic diamino acid.</s><s>Possesses MK-7 as the predominant menaquinone and diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylethanolamine as polar lipids.</s><s>The major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 39.8 mol% (HPLC method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, JSM 071004<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AB 207161<sup>T</sup> =DSM 19794<sup>T</sup> =KCTC 13187<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from homogenates of a sea anemone collected from Neizhou Bay in the South China Sea.</s></p></content></protolog>