<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9063_nm.2583" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2583" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2583" rank="species">Pseudomonas cedrina</organism><reference id="rid.9063"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Behrendt</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Meyer</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ulrich</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas cedrina subsp. fulgida subsp. nov., a fluorescent bacterium isolated from the phyllosphere of grasses; emended description of Pseudomonas cedrina and description of Pseudomonas cedrina subsp. cedrina subsp. nov.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1331</fpage><lpage>1335</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.005025-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19502311</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Pseudomonas cedrina</em> corrig. Dabboussi <em>et al.</em> 2002</s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>Possesses the following characteristics in addition to those described by Dabboussi <em>et al.</em> (1999).</s><s>Cells are motile by means of one or two polar flagella.</s><s>All strains are positive for the utilization of <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, caprate, citrate, d-fructose, d-galactose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, gluconate, d-mannitol, d-mannose, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, malate, malonic acid, propionic acid, d-saccharic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy l-proline, l-leucine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, l-threonine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, 2-aminoethanol and glycerol.</s><s>None of the strains uses adipate, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tweens 40 or 80, <em>n</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, cellobiose, l-fucose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-lactose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, phenylacetate, d-raffinose, turanose, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, itaconic acid, sebacic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, l-phenylalanine, dl-carnitine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, 2,3-butanediol, glucose 1-phosphate or glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase reactions are positive whereas DNase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and urease activities are negative.</s><s>The strains do not produce indole from tryptophan.</s><s>Hydrolysis of aesculin and tyrosine is negative.</s><s>All strains are able to grow on cetrimide agar.</s><s><em>β</em>-Haemolysis of sheep blood does not occur.</s></p></content></protolog>