<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6799_nm.5660" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5660" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5660" rank="species">Streptococcus minor</organism><reference id="rid.6799"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Devriese</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Graef</surname><given-names>E.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baele</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lefebvre</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Snauwaert</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Haesebrouck</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptococcus minor sp. nov., from faecal samples and tonsils of domestic animals.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>449</fpage><lpage>452</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02818-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15023958</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptococcus minor</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptococcus minor</em> (mi′nor. L. masc. adj. <em>minor</em> smaller).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are very small (&#x003C;1 μm in diameter), Gram-positive, ovoid and arranged predominantly in small groups.</s><s>Colonies on Columbia sheep blood agar are about 0·5 mm in diameter, unpigmented, regular, translucent and surrounded by narrow zones of <em>α</em>-haemolysis.</s><s>Growth is enhanced slightly by incubation in 5 % CO<sub>2</sub> and is definitely better at 37 °C than at 42 °C, and growth at 25 °C is almost equal to growth at 30 or 37 °C.</s><s>Strains show homogeneous growth in brain heart infusion broth (Oxoid).</s><s>They grow on Edwards medium (Oxoid), but not on Slanetz and Bartley agar (Oxoid).</s><s>On bile aesculin agar (Oxoid), blackening is observed.</s><s>None of the strains reacts with Lancefield groups A, B, C, D, G or F antisera.</s><s>All strains tested positive for leucine arylamidase (API), hydrolysis of l-valine-AMC (Crystal), l-phenylalanine-AMC (Crystal), 4MU-<em>α</em>-d-glucoside (Crystal), l-tryptophan-AMC (Crystal), l-arginine-AMC (Crystal), l-isoleucine-AMC (Crystal) and aesculin (API, often delayed).</s><s>In API 50 CH tests, acid is produced from galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, mannitol (often delayed), <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, sucrose, trehalose, glycogen and <em>β</em>-gentiobiose (often delayed).</s><s>All strains tested negative for activity of hippurate (API), pyrrolidonyl arylamidase (API), <em>β</em>-glucuronidase (API), <em>β</em>-galactosidase (API) and alkaline phosphatase, and for acid production from glycerol, erythritol, dl-arabinose, ribose, dl-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-xyloside, l-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-glucoside, melibiose, melezitose, xylitol, d-turanose, d-lyxose, dl-fucose, dl-arabitol, gluconate and 2- and 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Results are strain-dependent for <em>α</em>-galactosidase (often weak) and alkaline phosphatase activity (one of nine strains was positive), hydrolysis of <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl phosphate (Crystal) and acid production from sorbitol, amygdalin, arbutin, inulin, d-raffinose, starch and d-tagatose.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 40·6–41·5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is ON59<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 21734<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 47487<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from the tonsils of a dog.</s><s>Habitat: tonsils and intestinal tract of dogs and tonsils of cats and cattle.</s></p></content></protolog>