<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.14653_nm.7980" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7980" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7980" rank="species">Bacteroides pyogenes</organism><reference id="rid.14653"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sakamoto</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Benno</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>hsp60 and 16S rRNA gene sequence relationships among species of the genus Bacteroides with the finding that Bacteroides suis and Bacteroides tectus are heterotypic synonyms of Bacteroides pyogenes</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2984</fpage><lpage>2990</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.021154-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20118288</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Bacteroides pyogenes</em> Benno <em>et al.</em> 1983</s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>The description is as given by Benno <em>et al.</em> (1983) and Love <em>et al.</em> (1986) with the following modification: the major cellular fatty acid is anteiso-15 : 0.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In conclusion, this study suggests that the <em>hsp60</em> gene is an alternative phylogenetic marker for the classification of species of the genus <em>Bacteroides</em>.</s><s>Analysis based on the <em>hsp60</em> gene sequences in combination with other housekeeping gene sequences may provide a highly reliable identification system for species of the genus <em>Bacteroides</em>.</s><s>In addition, the greater variability of the <em>hsp60</em> gene sequences should be useful in designing specific primers for PCRs capable of assisting in the rapid identification of species of the genus <em>Bacteroides</em>.</s><s>We are currently planning the analysis of multiple genes (<em>dnaJ</em>, <em>gyrB</em>, <em>recA</em>, <em>rpoB</em>, etc.) other than <em>hsp60</em> to generate more useful data.</s></p></content></protolog>