<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9128_nm.14230" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14230" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14230" rank="species">Lactobacillus tucceti</organism><reference id="rid.9128"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chenoll</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Macián</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Aznar</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lactobacillus tucceti sp. nov., a new lactic acid bacterium isolated from sausage.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>29</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>389</fpage><lpage>395</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2005.09.006</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16824960</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>L. tucceti</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>L. tucceti</em> (tuc.ce’ti L. gen. n. <em>tucceti</em>, isolated from sausage)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod shaped, 3 μm length by 1 μm width, Gram-positive, catalase negative, non-spore forming and non-motile. <em>L. tucceti</em> grows better in MRS composed in the laboratory than in the commercially available medium and, after 3 days of incubation at 30 °C, colonies are small, circular, translucent and gray.</s><s>It grows at 13 and 37 °C but not at 4 or 45 °C.</s><s>It is homofermentative.</s><s>Both d- and l-lactic acid are produced.</s><s>It is able to hydrolyze arginine and aesculin.</s><s>Strain produces acid from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, l-fucose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, l-rhamnose and d-ribose, whereas the acid production is negative for d-adonitol, amygdalin, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, arbutin, d-cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, d-fucose, d-galactose, gentibiose, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, d-lactose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, inuline, d-lyxose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, d-melezitose, methyl <em>β</em>−xyloside, d-raffinose, salicine, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, starch, d-sucrose, d-tagatose, d-turanose, xylitol, d-xylose, and l-xylose.</s><s>Peptidoglycan is l-Lys-Gly-d-Asp.</s><s>The type strain is R 19c<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 20183<sup>T</sup>=CECT 5920<sup>T</sup>), isolated from sausage by Reuter in 1970 <a href="#bib16">[16]</a>.</s></p></content></protolog>