<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2252_nm.9568" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9568" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9568" rank="species">Quadrisphaera granulorum</organism><reference id="rid.2252"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Maszenan</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tay</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>H.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tay</surname><given-names>S.T.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Quadrisphaera granulorum gen. nov., sp. nov., a Gram-positive polyphosphate-accumulating coccus in tetrads or aggregates isolated from aerobic granules</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1771</fpage><lpage>1777</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63583-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16166665</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Quadrisphaera granulorum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Quadrisphaera granulorum</em> (gra.nu.lo′rum. L. gen. pl. neut. n. <em>granulorum</em> from, or of, granules).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Results obtained with the Biolog GN and GP systems and the API 20E system showed that strain AG019<sup>T</sup> has the following characteristics (in addition to those described in the genus description).</s><s>Utilizes <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, <em>α</em>-dl-glycerol phosphate, Tween 40, arbutin, glucose 1-phosphate, Tween 80, glucose 6-phosphate, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, glucuronamide, cellobiose, d-psicose, d-mannitol, d-melezitose, d-melibiose, l-serine, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, psicose, d-xylose, methyl pyruvate, pyruvate, 2-aminoethanol, mono-methyl succinate, glycerol, l-serine, turanose and glycerol.</s><s>Strain AG019<sup>T</sup> cannot metabolize the following: <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, inulin, mannan, <em>N</em>-acetyl d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetylmannosamine, amygdalin, d-arabitol, cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>m</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactulose, <em>α</em>-lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melezitose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, 3-methyl glucose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, palatinose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, salicin, sedoheptulosan, d-sorbitol, stachyose, sucrose, d-trehalose, xylitol, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, itaconic acid, malonic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, lactamide, d-lactic acid methyl ester, d-malic acid, l-malic acid, propionic acid, succinamic acid, succinic acid, <em>N</em>-acetylglutamic acid, bromosuccinic acid, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl-glycine, l-asparagine, glycyl-l-glutamic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, glycyl-l-aspartic acid, l-histidine, hydroxyl-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, adenosine, 2′-deoxyadenosine, inosine, thymidine, uridine, adenosine 5′-monophosphate, thymidine 5′-monophosphate, uridine 5′-monophosphate, phenylethylamine or putrescine.</s><s>The following acid and acid derivatives are utilized by strain AG019<sup>T</sup>: glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, uroconic acid and pyruvic acid.</s><s>The enzyme activities detected by both API ZYM and API 20E are as follows: esterase, esterase lipase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>Activities of the following enzymes are not detected by API ZYM: alkaline phosphatase, lipase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Activities of the following enzymes are not detected by API 20E: arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, urease, tryptophan deaminase and gelatinase.</s><s>Strain AG019<sup>T</sup> does not produce H<sub>2</sub>S or indole.</s><s>It is Voges–Proskauer-negative, does not produce acetoin and does not reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>It is catalase-positive but oxidase-negative.</s><s>The genomic G+C content is 75 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, AG019<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-1104<sup>T</sup>=DSM 44889<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from aerobic granules.</s></p></content></protolog>