<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.753_nm.1321" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1321" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1308" rank="species">Agrobacterium vitis</organism><reference id="rid.753"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ophel</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kerr</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Agrobacterium vitis sp. nov. for strains of Agrobacterium biovar 3 from grapevines</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>235</fpage><lpage>241</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-3-236</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Agrobacterium vitis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Agrobacterium vitis</i> (vi' tis. L. n. <i>Vitis</i>, generic name of grapevines)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The morphology of cells and colonies is as described for the genus.</s><s>Strains produce acid from mannitol and adonitol but not from erythritol, dulcitol, melezitose, and arabitol.</s><s>Acid production from ethanol is variable.</s><s>All strains produce alkali from sodium L-tartrate and grow on medium containing 2% (wt/vol) NaCl.</s><s>They do not produce 3-ketolactose and do not grow at 37°C.</s><s>Some strains require biotin for growth.</s><s>On the selective medium of Brisbane and Kerr (7) colonies are white, round, smooth, and mucoid after 5 days of incubation; on the selective medium of Roy and Sasser (Phytopathology 73:810,1983) colonies are small, round, and white with red centers after 5 to 7 days of growth at 28°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The levels of DNA homology with the type strains of other <i>Agrobacterium</i> species are less than 47% in all cases when the optimal reassociation method is used.</s><s>The levels of DNA homology between strains of <i>A. vitis</i> are 78 to 90% when the same method is used.</s><s>All strains of <i>A. vitis</i> tested to date react positively with monoclonal antibody Ab F21- ID3G7C8.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The species <i>A. vitis</i> comprises strains previously referred to as <i>Agrobacterium</i> biovar 3.</s><s>Strains are generally isolated from grapevines (7, 19, 26; T.</s><s>J.</s><s>Burr and B.</s><s>Hurwitz, Phytopathology, 71:206, 1981; Perry and Kado, Phytopathology 71:249, 1981) but have also been reported from chrysanthemums (3).</s><s>The host range is not limited to grapevines in most cases but includes a variety of dicotyledonous plants.</s><s>Strains may be tumorigenic or nontumorigenic, but to date no rhizogenic isolates have been described.</s><s>All strains that have been tested are also capable of causing the watery decay on grapevine roots described by Burr et al. (8).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain K309 (= NCPPB 3554).</s><s>This strain is typical of <i>A. vitis</i> for all tests shown in Table 2.</s><s>It requires biotin for growth.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 59 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from grapevines in South Australia in 1977, strain NCPPB 3554<sup>T</sup> is tumorigenic on grapevine shoots, on tomatoes, on carrot disks, and on sunflowers.</s><s>Galls incited by strain NCPPB 3554<sup>T</sup> contain octopine, and this strain catabolizes octopine as a sole carbon and nitrogen source.</s></p></content></protolog>