<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.508_nm.2902" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2902" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2902" rank="species">Pseudoalteromonas sagamiensis</organism><reference id="rid.508"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kobayashi</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Imada</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hiraishi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tsujibo</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Miyamoto</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Inamori</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hamada</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Watanabe</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudoalteromonas sagamiensis sp. nov., a marine bacterium that produces protease inhibitors.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1807</fpage><lpage>1811</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02516-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14657108</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudoalteromonas sagamiensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudoalteromonas sagamiensis</em> (sa.ga.mi.en′sis. N.L. adj. <em>sagamiensis</em> referring to Sagami Bay, the place of isolation).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative rods that are 0·7–1·4 μm wide and 2·5–3·7 μm long.</s><s>Motile by means of one polar flagellum.</s><s>Spore formation is not observed.</s><s>Strict aerobe.</s><s>Colonies on PYG-D plate medium supplemented with 2 % (w/v) NaCl are flat, circular and wrinkled and have a light-yellow pigmentation.</s><s>A light-brown pigment is produced around 2-day-old colonies.</s><s>Marine bacterium that grows in the presence of 1·5–5 % (w/v) NaCl, with the optimum being 2 % NaCl.</s><s>Grows well at 15 and 35 °C, but not at 10 or 40 °C; optimum growth at 27 °C.</s><s>Grows well at pH 6·0 and 8·5; optimum growth at pH 8·0.</s><s>Weakly catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Oxidative acid formation from d-glucose is observed.</s><s>Produces some protease inhibitors, namely, marinostatin, monastatin and leupeptin.</s><s>Produces protease, gelatinase and amylase, but not alginase, chitinase or lecithinase.</s><s>Able to hydrolyse Tween 80, but not tributyrin.</s><s>Nitrate reduction and production of hydrogen sulfide are not observed.</s><s>Poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate is not accumulated as an intracellular reserve product.</s><s>Organic growth factors are required.</s><s>d-Glucose, maltose, maltotriose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, l-threonine, l-serine, l-arginine, l-proline, l-<em>α</em>-alanine and l-glutamate are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>d-Mannose, d-galactose, d-fructose, sucrose, cellobiose, melibiose, lactose, salicin, d-gluconate, fumarate, dl-lactate, dl-glycerate, citrate, d-mannitol, glycerol, sarcosine, putrescine, d-sorbitol, dl-malate, 2-oxoglutarate, d-ribose, d-xylose, l-arabinose, l-rhamnose, trehalose, glucuronate, acetate, propionate, butyrate, isobutyrate, valerate, isovalerate, heptanoate, caprylate, l-tartrate, dl-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate, pyruvate, <em>meso</em>-inositol, propyleneglycol, ethanol, n-propanol, n-butanol, glycine, d-<em>α</em>-alanine, <em>β</em>-alanine, l-isoleucine, l-lysine, l-ornithine, l-citrulline, l-histidine, betaine and trigonelline are not utilized.</s><s>Susceptible to fradiomycin, gentamicin, lividomycin, ribostamycin, streptomycin, erythromycin, oleandomycin, rifampicin, chloramphenicol and tetracycline, but not to dibekacin, kanamycin, lincomycin, ampicillin, carbenicillin, oxacillin, penicillin G, the vibrio-static agent O-129 or vancomycin.</s><s>Ubiquinone-8 is the major respiratory quinone.</s><s>Menaquinone is absent.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>.</s><s>16S rDNA sequence analyses places the species among the <em>γ</em>-<em>Proteobacteria</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain B-10-31<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 11461<sup>T</sup>=DSM 14643<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The G+C content of its DNA is 42·0 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from neritic sea water at the Aburatsubo Inlet of Sagami Bay in Kanagawa Prefecture, Japan, at a depth of 5 m.</s></p></content></protolog>