<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8725_nm.13512" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13512" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13512" rank="species">Paenibacillus provencensis</organism><reference id="rid.8725"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Roux</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fenner</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Raoult</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus provencensis sp. nov., isolated from human cerebrospinal fluid, and Paenibacillus urinalis sp. nov., isolated from human urine.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>682</fpage><lpage>687</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65228-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18319478</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus provencensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus provencensis</em> (pro.ven.cen′cis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>provencensis</em> pertaining to Provence, the region of France where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative straight rods that form endospores in swollen sporangia.</s><s>Grows in an aerobic atmosphere but not under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Catalase-positive but oxidase-negative.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 30–37 °C; growth occurs in the presence of 5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>After 24 h growth on sheep-blood agar, surface colonies are circular, greyish, smooth, shiny and up to 5 mm in diameter.</s><s>Rods are 1.9–4.2 μm long and 0.8–1.1 μm in diameter (estimated by electronic microscopy).</s><s>Voges–Proskauer test (API 20E) is negative.</s><s>Using API ZYM, <em>β</em>-galactosidase activity is detected; activities of alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, N-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase tests are not detected.</s><s>Using API 50CH strips after an incubation time of 24 h, acid is produced from d-glucose, d-fructose, aesculin ferric citrate, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, d-lactose, melibiose, raffinose, starch and glycogen.</s><s>After an incubation time of 48 h, acid is produced from d-galactose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and amygdalin.</s><s>Acid is produced weakly from l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, arbutin, sucrose, gentiobiose and potassium gluconate.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, glycogen, xylitol, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d- or l-fucose, d- or l-arabitol, potassium 2-ketogluconate or potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Using the API 20NE strip, reduction of nitrates to nitrites, indole production, arginine dihydrolase, urease and hydrolysis of gelatin are negative.</s><s>Hydrolysis of aesculin is positive.</s><s>Tests for assimilation of d-glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid, trisodium citrate and phenylacetic acid are negative.</s><s>The fatty acid profile is characterized by the predominance of 15 : 0 anteiso (55.3 %), 16 : 0 iso (13.5 %), 16 : 0 (3.6 %), 15 : 0 (2.8 %), 17 : 0 anteiso (7.5 %), 14 : 0 iso (2.7 %) and 15 : 0 iso (3.4 %).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain 4401170<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 109358<sup>T</sup> =CCUG 53519<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from human cerebrospinal fluid.</s></p></content></protolog>