<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2424_nm.11303" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11303" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11303" rank="species">Loktanella maricola</organism><reference id="rid.2424"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>T.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Loktanella maricola sp. nov., isolated from seawater of the East Sea in Korea</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1799</fpage><lpage>1802</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65050-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17684260</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Loktanella maricola</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Loktanella maricola</em> [ma.ri′co.la. L. n. <em>mare</em> sea; L. suff. -<em>cola</em> (from L. n. <em>incola</em>) a dweller, inhabitant; N.L. n. <em>maricola</em> inhabitant of the sea].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile and rod-shaped (0.3–0.6×0.8–3.0 μm).</s><s>Colonies on MA are circular, slightly convex, glistening, light orange in colour and 1.0–2.0 mm in diameter after 7 days incubation at 25 °C.</s><s>Growth does not occur on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4 and 34 °C, but not at 35 °C.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is between 7.0 and 8.0; growth occurs at pH 5.5, but not at pH 5.0.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 7 % (w/v) NaCl, but not in the absence of NaCl or in the presence of more than 8 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Anaerobic growth does not occur on MA and on MA supplemented with nitrate.</s><s>Hypoxanthine and Tweens 20, 40 and 60 are hydrolysed, but tyrosine and xanthine are not.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced.</s><s>BChl <em>a</em> is produced.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and tryptophan deaminase are absent.</s><s>In assays with the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4) and esterase lipase (C8) are present and leucine arylamidase and acid phosphatase are weakly present, but lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are absent.</s><s>Utilizes the following substrates as carbon and energy sources: d-cellobiose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, acetate, citrate, succinate, l-malate and pyruvate.</s><s>l-Arabinose, maltose, d-mannose, sucrose, d-trehalose, d-xylose, benzoate, formate, l-glutamate and salicin are not utilized.</s><s>Acid is not produced from l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, d-melezitose, melibiose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, d-trehalose, d-xylose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol or d-sorbitol.</s><s>Sensitive to ampicillin, carbenicillin, cephalothin, chloramphenicol, gentamicin, neomycin, novobiocin, oleandomycin, penicillin G, streptomycin and tetracycline, but not to kanamycin, lincomycin or polymyxin B.</s><s>The predominant ubiquinone is Q-10.</s><s>The major fatty acid is C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>.</s><s>Major polar lipids are phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 56.8 mol% (determined by HPLC).</s><s>Other phenotypic characteristics are given in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, DSW-18<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12863<sup>T</sup>=JCM 14564<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from seawater off Dokdo in the East Sea, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>