<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2444_nm.11329" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11329" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11329" rank="species">Thalassococcus halodurans</organism><reference id="rid.2444"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>O.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tsoi</surname><given-names>M.M.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wong</surname><given-names>P.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Qian</surname><given-names>P.Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thalassococcus halodurans gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel halotolerant member of the Roseobacter clade isolated from the marine sponge Halichondria panicea at Friday Harbor, USA</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1919</fpage><lpage>1924</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64801-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17684282</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Thalassococcus halodurans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Thalassococcus halodurans</em> (ha.lo.du′rans. Gr. n. <em>hals</em> salt, L. part. pres. <em>durans</em> withstanding, N.L. part. adj. <em>halodurans</em> withstanding salt).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exhibits the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are 0.7–1.0 μm in diameter and colonies are milky, 1.1–1.4 mm in diameter, raised and circular with a smooth surface and an entire edge when cultivated on marine agar at 28 °C for 48 h.</s><s>Cells do not produce flexirubin-type or diffusible pigments.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 6–10 and 12–44 °C, with optimal growth at 28–36 °C; no growth below pH 5 or at 4 or 52 °C.</s><s>Cells require a minimum of 2.0 % NaCl for growth and tolerate up to 18.0 % NaCl (optimum growth at 2.0–6.0 %).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 58.8 mol%.</s><s>Cells are susceptible to 1.0 μg benzylpenicillin, chloramphenicol and ampicillin, 5.0 μg kanamycin and tetracycline and 10.0 μg streptomycin.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse starch, casein, chitin, cellulose, agar, gelatin or Tween 20, 40 or 80.</s><s>Acetoin is produced but not indole or H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite but not to nitrogen gas.</s><s>Citrate is not utilized.</s><s>Positive for activities of DNase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C<sub>4</sub>), esterase lipase (C<sub>8</sub>), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidases, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-glucosidases and arginine dihydrolase.</s><s>Negative for activities of urease, lipase (C<sub>14</sub>), cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and tryptophan deaminase.</s><s>Utilizes glycerol, d-glucose, sucrose, d-mannitol, d-galactose, starch, d-sorbitol, d-arabinose and d-melibiose as sole carbon sources on agar medium supplemented with 4 % (w/v) carbon source, glycerol, l-arabinose, d-xylose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, inositol, d-mannitol, d-cellobiose, maltose, d-melibiose, sucrose, trehalose and potassium 2-ketogluconate in the API 50 CH system and d-sorbitol in the MicroLog 3 system.</s><s>Utilization of other carbon sources included in the MicroLog 3, API 20 NE and 50 CH systems is not observed.</s><s>Acid is produced from glycerol, l-arabinose, d-xylose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, d-melibiose, sucrose, d-fucose and potassium 2-ketogluconate in API 50 CH, but no acid production is observed in the API 20E system.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is UST050418-052<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 13833<sup>T</sup> =NRRL B-41465<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the surface of the marine sponge <em>Halichondria panicea</em> collected from Friday Harbor, San Juan Island, WA, USA.</s></p></content></protolog>