<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2776_nm.7759" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7759" rank="genus">Pirellula</organism><reference id="rid.2776"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schlesner</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rensmann</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gade</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rabus</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pfeiffer</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hirsch</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic heterogeneity within the Planctomycetales as derived by DNA-DNA hybridization, description of Rhodopirellula baltica gen. nov., sp. nov., transfer of Pirellula marina to the genus Blastopirellula gen. nov. as Blastopirellula marina comb. nov. and emended description of the genus Pirellula.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1567</fpage><lpage>1580</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63113-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15388712</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <em>Pirellula</em> Schlesner and Hirsch 1987</s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>The description of the genus <em>Pirellula</em> is largely based on physiological, biochemical and morphological properties, and it would be appropriate to emend the description to take into account both additional data and our changing appreciation of the taxonomy of this group.</s><s>The biochemical, physiological and morphological characteristics are described by Schlesner &#x0026; Hirsch (1984).</s><s>The major polyamine is <em>sym</em>-homospermidine.</s><s>The major respiratory lipoquinone present is MK-6.</s><s>The major phospholipid present is phosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>A number of other lipids are present that have characteristic <em>R</em><sub>f</sub> values, but whose structures are not currently known.</s><s>However, the lipid pattern is characteristic of this genus.</s><s>The major fatty acids present are 14 : 0, 16 : 1Δ9, 16 : 0, 18 : 1Δ9, 18 : 1Δ11, 18 : 0 and 20 : 1Δ9.</s><s>It is also evident that 16S rRNA gene sequence similarity values are of significance in delineating this genus.</s><s>Nevertheless, the extent cannot be defined at present, since strains with less than 95 % sequence similarity to members of this genus should probably be placed in separate genera.</s><s>The type species of the genus is <em>Pirellula staleyi</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>