<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3147_nm.8376" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8376" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8376" rank="species">Ilyobacter tartaricus</organism><reference id="rid.3147"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schink</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Fermentation of tartrate enantiomers by anaerobic bacteria, and description of two new species of strict anaerobes, Ruminococcus pasteurii and Ilyobacter tartaricus</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>139</volume><fpage>409</fpage><lpage>414</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00408388</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Ilyobacter tartaricus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Ilyobacter tartaricus</i> (tar. ta'ri, cus.M.L.n, <i>acidum tartaricum</i> tartaric acid; <i>tartarieus</i> referring to tartaric acid as isolation substrate)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Short, straight rods, 1.0 x 1.2-1.2-2.5 μm in size, often in chains, surrounded by slime capsules, non-motile, Gram-negative, non-sporeforming.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic chemoorganotroph.</s><s>Grows on L-tartrate, citrate, pyruvate, oxaloacetate, glucose, fructose, raffinose, glycerol.</s><s>Fermentation products include acetate, formate, and ethanol.</s><s>No growth on formate, acetate, lactate, methanol, ethanol, ethylene glycol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerate, malate, fumarate, glyoxylate, glycolate, mannose, maltose, lactose, sucrose, cellobiose, sorbose, rhamnose, trehalose, xylose, arabinose, peptone, yeast extract.</s><s>Grows in saltwater medium with at least 1% sodium chloride.</s><s>Oxidized sulfur compounds or nitrate not reduced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Indole not formed, gelatin or urea not hydrolyzed.</s><s>No catalase activity, no cytochromes.</s><s>No vitamin requirements.</s><s>Selective enrichment from marine sediments with L-tartrate as sole carbon and energy source.</s></p><p class="description"><s>pH range: 5.5 - 8.0; optimum pH 6.5- 7.2.</s><s>Temperature range: 10- 40°C; optimum temperature 28-34°C.</s><s>DNA base ratio: 33.1±1.0% G+C (thermal denaturation).</s><s>Habitats: anoxic marine sediments.</s><s>Type strain: GraTa2, DSM 2382, deposited in Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen, Göttingen.</s></p></content></protolog>