<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1403_nm.2775" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2775" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2775" rank="species">Acinetobacter lwoffii</organism><reference id="rid.1403"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bouvet</surname><given-names>P.J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomy of the genus Acinetobacter with the recognition of Acinetobacter baumannii sp. nov., Acinetobacter haemolyticus sp. nov., Acinetobacter johnsonii sp. nov., and Acinetobacter junii sp. nov., and emended descriptions of Acinetobacter calcoaceticus and Acinetobacter lwoffii.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>228</fpage><lpage>240</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-36-2-228</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Acinetobacter lwoffii</i> (Audureau 1940) Brisou and Prévot 1954</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Also called genospecies 8 in this study.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Characteristics as given previously for the genus (19, 20).</s><s>Colonies on tryptocasein soy agar are circular, convex, smooth, and slightly opaque with entire margins; colonies are 1.0 to 1.5 mm in diameter after 24 h and 3.0 to 4.0 mm in diameter after 48 h at 30°C.</s><s>Good growth occurs at 15 to 37°C</s></p><p class="description"><s>in 1 day.</s><s>No growth occurs at 41°C and above.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrates are not reduced to nitrites in complex medium.</s><s>No growth occurs on citrate (Simmons).</s><s>Acid is not produced from D-glucose (since the number of strains assigned to this species by DNA hybridization was very small, we cannot be certain that no glucose-positive strain can be assigned to this species).</s><s>β-Xylosidase is not produced (see remark above concerning D-glucose) .</s><s>γ-Glutamyltransferase is not produced.</s><s>Horse or sheep blood is not hemolyzed; gelatin is not hydrolyzed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Azelate and DL-lactate are utilized as sole sources of carbon and energy.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized: glutarate, L-phenylalanine, malonate, L-histidine, L-aspartate, L-leucine, histamine, β-alanine, 2,3-butanediol, <i>trans</i>-aconitate, and L-arginine.</s><s>Some strains can utilize phenylacetate, D-malate, L-tyrosine, ethanol, L-ornithine, and DL-4-aminobutyrate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 46 mol% (as determined by thermal denaturation [17, 23]).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat unknown.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain ATCC 15309 (= CIP 64.10).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Unnamed genospecies 9 (which may contain occasional strains that oxidize D-glucose) cannot be differentiated with certainty from <i>Acinetobacter lwoffii</i> on the basis of biochemical characteristics.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>Strain CIP 64.10<sup>T</sup> (= ATCC 15309<sup>T</sup>) has all of the characteristics given above for the species.</s><s>In addition, this strain utilizes phenylacetate, D-malate, and ethanol and fails to utilize L-tyrosine, L-ornithine, and DL-4-aminobutyrate.</s><s>Source unknown.</s></p></content></protolog>