<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.582_nm.7350" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7350" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7350" rank="species">Streptomyces yeochonensis</organism><reference id="rid.582"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seong</surname><given-names>C.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic study of neutrotolerant acidophilic actinomycetes isolated from soil and description of Streptomyces yeochonensis sp. nov.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>211</fpage><lpage>214</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02519-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14742482</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptomyces yeochonensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomyces yeochonensis</em> (ye.o.chon.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>yeochonensis</em> of Yeochon, a province in Korea, referring to the place where the organism was first isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on the present and previous studies (Lonsdale, 1985; Seong, 1992).</s><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, non-motile, neutrotolerant acidophilic streptomycete that forms extensively branched substrate and aerial mycelia.</s><s>Smooth-surfaced spores are borne in flexuous spore-chains.</s><s>Aerial spore-mass colour is grey.</s><s>Substrate mycelia have no distinctive colour; diffusible pigments are not produced.</s><s>pH range for growth is 4·3–7·3.</s><s>Casein, gelatin, guanine, starch and Tween 80 are degraded, but elastin, hypoxanthine, testosterone, Tween 20, tyrosine and xanthine are not.</s><s>Good growth occurs between 25 and 37 °C, but not at 12 or 45 °C.</s><s>The sugars erythritol, inulin, melezitose, salicin, ribitol and sorbitol (all at 1 %, w/v) are used as sole carbon sources, as are <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, d-gluconic acid, hippuric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, 2-keto-d-glucuronic acid, lactic acid, malic acid, malonic acid, oxalic acid, pyruvic acid and succinic acid (as sodium salts), albeit at 0·1 %, w/v.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CN732<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 9926<sup>T</sup>=IMSNU 50114<sup>T</sup>=NRRL B-24245<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from acidic soil collected in the Yeochon area of the Republic of Korea.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The results of this and earlier studies (Lonsdale, 1985; Park <em>et al.</em>, 1991; Seong, 1992) indicate that neutrotolerant sporoactinomycetes form a heterogeneous group of actinomycetes that belong to the genus <em>Streptomyces</em>, thereby underpinning the physiological diversity encompassed by this taxon (Williams <em>et al.</em>, 1989).</s><s>It is also evident that neutrotolerant streptomycetes can be distinguished readily from their acidophilic counterparts, which are classified in the genus <em>Streptacidiphilus</em> (Kim <em>et al.</em>, 2003).</s><s>It is clear that further comparative taxonomic studies are needed to formally describe the range of taxonomic variation encompassed by neutrotolerant streptomycetes.</s></p></content></protolog>