<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12789_nm.22578" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22578" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22578" rank="species">Salinicoccus sesuvii</organism><reference id="rid.12789"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>W.-A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rekha</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.-M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Salinicoccus sesuvii sp. nov., isolated from the rhizosphere of Sesuvium portulacastrum</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2348</fpage><lpage>2352</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.027524-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21037029</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Salinicoccus sesuvii</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Salinicoccus sesuvii</em> [se.su′vi.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>sesuvii</em> of <em>Sesuvium</em>, isolated from <em>Sesuvium portulacastrum</em> L. (sea purslane)].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-staining-positive cocci, about 1.0–1.2 µm in diameter.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive; an oxidative metabolism is shown.</s><s>Good growth occurs after 48 h on tryptone soy agar and marine agar 2218 at 28 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs on MacConkey agar at 28 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 2 or 45 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs with 1–25 % (w/v) NaCl [optimum 8–10 % (w/v) NaCl].</s><s>Colonies on nutrient agar are smooth, pinkish, circular, translucent and shiny with entire edges.</s><s>The characteristic diamino acid of the cell wall is lysine.</s><s>The quinone system is composed mostly of menaquinone MK-6, with traces of MK-7.</s><s>The polar lipid profile contains major amounts of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and an unidentified glycolipid, and minor amounts of two unidentified lipids.</s><s>The polyamine pattern contains major amounts of spermidine.</s><s>The characteristic fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Physiological tests (including differentiating characters obtained using identical conditions) are indicated in Table 2.</s><s>Acid is weakly produced from d-glucose and maltose, but no acid is produced from sucrose, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, melibiose, methyl α-d-glucoside, raffinose, l-rhamnose, salicin, d-sorbitol or d-xylose.</s><s>Urease, indole production and hydrolysis of casein, gelatin, starch, DNA and tyrosine are negative.</s><s>Aesculin hydrolysis and arginine dihydrolase are positive, but H<sub>2</sub>S production and lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and β-galactosidase (ONPG) are negative.</s><s>Only a few compounds are utilized, among them <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-glucose, maltose, pyruvate and dl-lactate.</s><s>As sole sources of carbon, d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose, d-fructose and trehalose are utilized, but not acetate, propionate, <em>N</em>-acetylgalactosamine, l-arabinose, l-arbutin, cellobiose, d-galactose, gluconate, glycerol, d-mannitol, maltitol, α-melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, salicin, d-xylose, adonitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-sorbitol, putrescine, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, <em>trans</em>-aconitate, 4-aminobutyrate, adipate, azelate, fumarate, glutarate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, itaconate, 2-oxoglutarate, suberate, citrate, mesaconate, l-alanine, β-alanine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-aspartate, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-proline, l-tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate or phenylacetate.</s><s>The chromogenic substrate <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-β-d-glucopyranoside is hydrolysed weakly, but <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-α-d-glucopyranoside, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-β-d-galactopyranoside, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-β-d-xylopyranoside, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-β-d-glucuronide, bis-<em>p</em>-nitrophenyl-phosphate, bis-<em>p</em>-nitrophenylphenylphosphonate, bis-<em>p</em>-nitrophenylphosphorylcholine, 2-deoxythymidine-2′-<em>p</em>-nitrophenylphosphate, l-alanine-<em>p</em>-nitroanilide, γ-l-glutamate-<em>p</em>-nitroanilide and l-proline-<em>p</em>-nitroanilide are not hydrolysed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CC-SPL15-2<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 23267<sup>T</sup>  = CCM 7756<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the rhizosphere of <em>Sesuvium portulacastrum</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>