<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5737_nm.4318" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4318" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4318" rank="species">Desulfitobacterium dehalogenans</organism><reference id="rid.5737"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Utkin</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Woese</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wiegel</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Isolation and characterization of Desulfitobacterium dehalogenans gen. nov., sp. nov., an anaerobic bacterium which reductively dechlorinates chlorophenolic compounds.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>612</fpage><lpage>619</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-4-1010</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7981092</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Desulflobacterium frappieri</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Desulflobacterium frappieri</i> (frap.pi.e'ri M. L. gen. n. <i>frappieri</i>, of Frappier, in honor of Armand Frappier, a renowned Canadian microbiologist)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain PCP-1 is the type strain of <i>Desulfitobacterium frappieri</i>.</s><s>This strain has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection.</s></p><p class="description"><s>We isolated a member of a new bacterial species that is responsible for dechlorination of PCP to 3-CP in a methanogenic consortium.</s><s>On the basis of the results of a 16s rRNA sequence analysis, strain PCP-1<sup>T</sup> is closely related to <i>Desulfitobacterium dehalogenans</i> JW/IU-DCl (23).</s><s>No other bacterial species are closely related to these two bacteria.</s><s>Strain PCP-1<sup>T</sup> and <i>Desulfitobacterium dehalogenans</i> share several characteristics.</s><s>They are both rod-shaped bacteria that are asaccharolytic and grow on media containing pyruvate and 0.1% yeast extract.</s><s>Both organisms can use sulfite, thiosulfate, or nitrate, but not sulfate, as an inorganic electron acceptor.</s><s>They are gram positive, although PCP-1<sup>T</sup> stained gram negative.</s><s>The G+C contents of their genomic DNAs are similar (46 mol% for PCP-1<sup>T</sup> and 45 mol% for <i>Desulfitobacterium dehalogenans</i>).</s><s>Finally, they can reductively dehalogenate several chlorophenols.</s><s>However, <i>Desulfitobacterium dehalogenans</i> can dehalogenate only chloro henols with chlorines in <i>ortho</i> positions, whereas strain PCP-1<sup>T</sup> is not limited to dehalogenation at this position.</s></p><p class="description"><s>There are several differences between the two species.</s><s>PCP-1<sup>T</sup> forms spores, does not have flagella, and grows on 1.5% (wt/vol) agar plates. <i>Desulfitobacterium dehalogenans</i> apparently does not form spores, has flagella, and grows on solid media containing 0.6 to 0.9% agar but not in the presence of higher agar concentrations.</s><s>The 16s rRNA gene sequences of these organisms exhibited 95% homology, and there was a 128-nucleotide insertion that was unique to PCP-1<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>These results suggest that PCP-1<sup>T</sup> is a member of a species that is distinct from <i>Desulfitobacterium dehalogenans</i>.</s><s>However, the similarities between the two bacteria suggest that PCP-1<sup>T</sup> belongs to the recently proposed genus <i>Desulfitobactevium</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain PCP-1<sup>T</sup> is the first anaerobic microorganism isolated that can dechlorinate PCP to 3-CP.</s><s>PCP and the tetrachlorophenols are first dechlorinated at the <i>ortho</i> positions, then dechlorinated at the <i>para</i> positions, and then dechlorinated at the <i>meta</i> positions.</s><s>Also, <i>para</i> dechlorination occurs only if chlorine residues are present in both <i>meta</i> positions.</s><s>Other anaerobic microorganisms, including <i>Desulfitobacterium dehalogenans</i> JW/IU-DC1 (22, 23), strain DCB-2 (16), and the recently described organism strain XZ-1 (24), can generally dechlorinate only at <i>ortho</i> positions.</s><s>Strain DCB-2 can remove a <i>meta</i>-substituted chlorine only from 3,5-dichlorophenol.</s><s>However, Desulfomonile tiedjei DCB-1 <i>meta</i> dehalogenates a variety of substituted halobenzoates (9) and chlorophenols (18). <i>Desulfitobacterium dehalogenans</i> can remove the halogen at the <i>ortho</i> position when the <i>para</i> position is substituted, as it is in chlorinated <i>p</i>-hydroxyphenylacetate, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoates, <i>p</i>-nitrophenols, and <i>p</i>-cresols (22).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The kinetics of dechlorination of PCP by strain PCP-1<sup>T</sup> revealed that PCP was rapidly dechlorinated to 3,4,5-trichlorophenol and that there was a 36-h lag period before this compound was dechlorinated to 3,5-dichlorophenol and 3-CP.</s><s>This result suggests that two different enzyme systems are involved in PCP dechlorination.</s><s>The first system dechlorinates PCP rapidly and dechlorinates 2,3,4,5-tetrachlorophenolo nly at the <i>ortho</i> position to generate 3,4,5-trichlorophenol, while the second system dechlorinates 3,4,5-trichlorophenol at the <i>meta</i> and <i>para</i> positions to generate 3-CP.</s><s>PCP and tetrachlorophenols may act as inducers of the <i>ortho</i> dechlorination, and 3,4,5-trichloropheno1 may act as an inducer of dechlorination in the <i>para</i> and <i>meta</i> positions.</s><s>For 3,4,5-trichlorophenol, a 36-h lag period is probably needed for the bacterial cells to induce and generate the dechlorination enzymes, whereas for PCP no lag period is needed.</s><s>This hypothesis for induction of <i>ortho</i> and <i>meta</i>-<i>para</i> dechlorinations could explain the differences observed with 2,3,5-trichlorophenol dechlorination.</s><s>2,3,5,6-Tetrachlorophenol induced <i>ortho</i> dechlorination and the intermediate 2,3,5-trichlorophenol was dechlorinated to 3,5-dichlorophenol.</s><s>However, when 2,3,5-trichlorophenol was tested separately, <i>meta</i> dechlorination was induced, and this chlorophenol was dechlorinated to 2,5-dichlorophenol.</s><s>This hypothesis is currently being tested.</s></p><p class="description"><s>To our knowledge, PCP-1<sup>T</sup> is the first anaerobic bacterium that is able to reductively dechlorinate PCP and different chlorophenols at <i>ortho</i>, <i>meta</i>, and <i>para</i> positions.</s><s>Experiments are now being carried out to optimize the conditions for culturing PCP-I<sup>T</sup> and to evaluate the potential for transforming other classes of halogenated compounds.</s></p></content></protolog>