<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6922_nm.2618" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2618" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2618" rank="species">Pseudomonas grimontii</organism><reference id="rid.6922"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Baïda</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yazourh</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Singer</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Izard</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas grimontii sp. nov.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1497</fpage><lpage>1503</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.01971-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12361251</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudomonas grimontii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudomonas grimontii</i> (gri.mon'ti.i. N.L. gen. n. <i>grimontii</i> of Grimont, in honour of the French bacteriologist P. A. D. Grimont, for all his work in the field of bacterial taxonomy)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, asporogenous, rod-shaped and motile by means of a single polar flagellum (Fig. 1).</s><s>Colonies are smooth on nutrient agar, circular, non-pigmented and haemolytic (98%of strains) when grown on blood agar.</s><s>All strains produce a fluorescent pigment on both King B medium and S1 medium (Gould et al., 1985).</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, tributyrin esterase (93%of strains), catalase and oxidase are also produced.</s><s>Lysine and ornithine are not decarboxylated.</s><s>Cells can reduce nitrate to nitrite and can grow at low salt concentrations (0.8%) but not at high salt concentrations (5 or 7%).</s><s>Strains do not possess any DNase, coagulase, tetrathionate reductase (95% of strains), elastase or Tween esterase activities.</s><s>Fibrinolysis and acetyl-methylcarbinol (acetoin) tests are negative.</s><s>Acid is formed from starch.</s><s>Poly-β-hydroxybutyrate is not accumulated.</s></p><p class="description"><s>At least 90% of strains utilize the following substrates as carbon and energy sources: α-D-glucose, β-dfructose, D-galactose, L-arabinose, sucrose, D-arabitol, glycerol, D-glucosamine, D-saccharate, L-malate, cisaconitate, citrate, D-glucuronate, D-galacturonate, 5-keto-D-gluconate, N-acetyl D-glucosamine, D-gluconate, protocatechuate, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, quinate, betaine, putrescine, DL-lactate, caprate, caprylate, succinate, fumarate, glutarate, DL-glycerate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, L-aspartate, L-glutamate, L-proline, dalanine, L-alanine, L-serine, propionate, L-tyrosine and 2-oxoglutarate.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized by 90% or more of the strains: L-sorbose, α-dmelibiose, maltotriose, D-raffinose, maltose, α-lactose, lactulose, 1-O-methyl β-galactopyranoside, 1-Omethyl α-galactopyranoside, D-cellobiose, β-gentiobiose, 1-O-methyl β-D-glucopyranoside, palatinose, α-L-fucose, D-melezitose, L-arabitol, xylitol, dulcitol, dtagatose, maltitol, D-turanose, hydroxyquinoline bglucuronide, 1-O-methyl α-D-glucopyranoside, 3-O-methyl D-glucopyranose, L-tartrate, <i>trans</i>-aconitate, tricarballylate, phenylacetate, gentisate, 3-phenylpropionate and <i>m</i>-coumarate.</s><s>The other characteristics are displayed in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>At least 90% of strains possess the following enzyme activities : esterase C%, alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase C<sub>4</sub> and leucine arylamidase.</s><s>At least 90% of strains do not possess the following enzyme activities: trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase.</s><s>All strains have been isolated from natural mineral water.</s><s>No clinical significance is known.</s><s>The type strain is CFML 97-514<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 106645<sup>T</sup>=ATCC BAA-140<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>