<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2200_nm.8136" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8136" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8136" rank="species">Capnocytophaga cynodegmi</organism><reference id="rid.2200"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hollis</surname><given-names>D.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fanning</surname><given-names>G.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weaver</surname><given-names>R.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Capnocytophaga canimorsus sp. nov. (formerly CDC group DF-2), a cause of septicemia following dog bite, and C. cynodegmi sp. nov., a cause of localized wound infection following dog bite</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>27</volume><fpage>231</fpage><lpage>235</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2915017</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Capnocytophaga cynodegmi</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Capnocytophaga cynodegmi</i> (sy.no.deg'mi. Gr. <i>kyon</i>, <i>kyno-</i>, dog; Gr. <i>degmos</i>, a bite; N.L. gen. n. <i>cynodegmi</i> of a dog bite)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Capnocytophaga cynodegmi</i> is proposed for group DF-2-like organisms.</s><s>Cells are thin, gram-negative, nonsporeforming rods 1 to 3 μm long.</s><s>Longer rods and filaments, often curved, are also present.</s><s>Flagella are not present; gliding motility as seen by bright-field microscopy.</s><s>Colonies on blood agar at 18 to 24 h are either punctate (less than 0.5 mm in diameter) and convex or flat and irregular in shape with a diameter of 0.5 to 1 mm.</s><s>After incubation for 48 h, colonies are 3 to 4 mm or larger in diameter.</s><s>The surface is smooth or slightly uneven.</s><s>Some colonies have a narrow, flat, spreading edge.</s><s>Five of nine strains produced beta-like hemolysis in rabbit blood agar, best demonstrated by stabbing an inoculum into the agar.</s><s>Confluent growth at 24 h, and colonies at 48 h frequently appeared to be light purple.</s><s>The cell mass when removed from the plate on a loop, however, was light yellow.</s><s>No growth on MacConkey agar; no growth or a neutral reaction on triple sugar iron agar.</s><s>Microaerophilic, grows best on heart infusion agar supplemented with 5% rabbit or sheep blood incubated at 35 to 75°C in the presence of CO<sup>2</sup> (candle extinction jar).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Positive reactions in tests for oxidase (some strains were weakly positive), catalase, arginine dihydrolase, <i>o</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-galactopyranoside, esculin hydrolysis (delayed), and acid production from cellobiose (delayed), dextrin, fructose, D-glucose, glycogen (delayed), lactose, maltose, D-mannose, melibiose, and starch and in most strains from inulin, raffinose, and sucrose.</s><s>Variable reactions (10 to 75% positive) in tests for nitrate reduction, nitrite reduction, and acid production from D-galactose.</s><s>Negative reactions in tests for indole production, growth on citrate, urease, lysine and ornithine decarboxylases, gelatin hydrolysis, gas from D-glucose, and acid production from D-mannitol and D-xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C contents of DNAs from the type strain and another strain were 34 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from human wounds and mouths of apparently healthy dogs.</s><s>Pathogenic for humans, causing wound infections.</s><s>The route of infection is through the skin after a dog bite or, in one case, a cat scratch.</s><s>No evidence of systemic infection or predisposing factors.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is E6447 (=ATCC 49044), isolated in Virginia from the mouth of a dog in 1979.</s></p></content></protolog>