<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2213_nm.6229" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6229" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6229" rank="species">Corynebacterium imitans</organism><reference id="rid.2213"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Funke</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Efstratiou</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kuklinska</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hutson</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Zoysa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Engler</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Corynebacterium imitans sp. nov. isolated from patients with suspected diphtheria</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>1978</fpage><lpage>1983</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9230366</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Corynebacterium imitans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Corynebacterium imitans</i> (i'mi.tans. L. part. adj. <i>imitans</i>, imitating, copying, indicating that this bacterium was isolated from patients with an illness that was imitating the clinical picture of pharyngeal diphtheria and also indicating that the biochemical profile of the newly described bacterium imitates the biochemical profiles of other <i>Corynebacterium</i> species)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-positive, nonmotile, asporogenous diphtheroids.</s><s>Colonies are white-grayish, glistening, circular, convex, creamy, and 1 to 2 mm in diameter with entire edges after 24 h of incubation on sheep blood agar at 37°C.</s><s>The organism is catalase positive.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-arabinose, ribose, D-glucose, D-fructose, D-mannose, maltose, lactose, and L-fucose and weakly from sucrose but not from glycerol, erythritol, L-arabinose, xylose, adonitol, β-methylxyloside, galactose, L-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, α-methylmannoside, α-methylglucoside, N-acetylglucosamine, amygdaline, arbutine, salicin, cellobiose, melibiose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, D-raffinose, glycogen, xylitol, β-gentiobiose, D-turanose, D-lyxose, D-tagatose, D-fucose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, gluconate, and 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Urea, esculin, and tyrosine are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>The CAMP reaction is positive.</s><s>Pyrazinamidase (weakly), alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase-lipase (C8), acid phosphatase, and phosphoamidase activities are detected, but lipase, pyrrolidonylarylamidase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase, and α-fucosidase activities are not detected.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall contains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Mycolic acids are present.</s><s>The main straight-chain saturated fatty acids are palmitic and stearic acids; oleic acid is the predominant unsaturated fatty acid.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 62 mol% G+C.</s><s>The strain is isolated from humans.</s><s>The type strain has been deposited in the National Collection of Type Cultures, London, United Kingdom, as NCTC 13015, in the German Collection of Microorganisms and Cell Cultures, Braunschweig, Germany, as DSM 44264, and in the Culture Collection of the University of Göteborg, Göteborg, Sweden, as CCUG 36877.</s></p></content></protolog>