<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2743_nm.10326" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10326" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10326" rank="species">Propionicicella superfundia</organism><reference id="rid.2743"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>H.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moe</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yan</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tiago</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>da Costa</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Propionicicella superfundia gen. nov., sp. nov., a chlorosolvent-tolerant propionate-forming, facultative anaerobic bacterium isolated from contaminated groundwater.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>29</volume><fpage>404</fpage><lpage>413</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2005.11.004</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16338112</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Propionicicella superfundia</i> sp. nov. (Rainey, da Costa, and Moe)</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Propionicicella superfundia</i> (su.per.fun'di.a. L. prep. <i>super</i>, above/on top, L. masc. n. <i>fundus</i>, land owned by someone, referring to land designated as an Environmental Protection Agency Superfund Site)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Propionicicella superfundia</i> cells are non-motile, non-spore forming, and 0.5 μm in diameter 1.0–2.5 μm in length.</s><s>Colonies are white, circular, convex, smooth and 2–3mm in diameter on PYG agar.</s><s>Growth occurs between 15 and 37 °C; the optimum growth temperature is about 30 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs between pH 4.5 and 8.5; the optimum pH for growth is 6.5.</s><s>Grows in the presence of up to 4.0% (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Catalase, oxidase, and nitrate reduction is negative.</s><s>Formic acid, acetic acid, propionic acid, and succinic acid are fermentation products from glucose.</s><s>Cells grow on adonitol, erythritol, fructose, glucose, glycerin, lactate, maltose, mannitol, mannose, pyruvate, sorbitol, sucrose, and xylose but did not utilize acetate, arabinose crystalline cellulose, dulcitol, ethanol, fucose, galactose, lactose, malate, meliobiose, methanol, raffinose, rhamnose, starch, succinate, and fumarate.</s><s>This bacterium was isolated from the Brooklawn site, Baton Rouge, LA (USA).</s><s>The type strain is BL-10<sup>T</sup> and has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection, Manassas, Virginia, USA as strain ATCC BAA-1218 and in the BCCM/LMG Bacteria Collection, Ghent, Belgium as strain LMG 23096.</s></p></content></protolog>