<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1858_nm.5543" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5543" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5543" rank="species">Enterococcus mundtii</organism><reference id="rid.1858"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Farrow</surname><given-names>J.A.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Enterococcus mundtii sp. nov.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>8</fpage><lpage>12</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-36-1-8</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Enterococcus mundtii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Enterococcus mundtii</i> (mund'ti.i. L. gen. n. <i>mundtii</i> of Mundt; named after the late J. 0. Mundt, an American microbiologist)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are ovoid and occur mostly in pairs or short chains.</s><s>The cells are gram positive and nonmotile.</s><s>Surface colonies on blood agar or nutrient agar are circular, smooth, and entire.</s><s>A yellow pigment is produced.</s><s>Nonhemolytic.</s><s>Catalase negative.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10 and 45°C, in 6.5% NaCl, and at pH 9.6.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>L-Lactic acid is the major product of glucose fermentation.</s><s>Acid is produced from N-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, L-arabinose, arbutin, cellobiose, D-fructose, galactose, β-gentiobiose, lactose, maltose, D-mannose, mannitol, melibiose, ribose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose, and D-xylose.</s><s>Most strains produce acid from α-methyl-D-mannoside, D-raffinose, and rhamnose; variable results are obtained for glycerol and sorbitol.</s><s>Acid is not produced from adonitol, D-arabinose, D-arabitol, L-arabitol, dulcital, erythritol, D-fucose, L-fucose, glycogen, gluconate, inositol, 2-keto-gluconate, 5-keto-gluconate, D-lyxose, melezitose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, α-methyl-xyloside, L-sorbose, D-tagatose, D-turanose, xylitol, or L-xylose.</s><s>All strains are Voges-Proskauer positive and hydrolyze esculin; hippurate is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>All strains are arginine dehydrolase, β-galactosidase, leucine arylamidase, and pyrolidonylarylamidase positive; most strains are agalactosidase positive.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Reacts with Lancefield group D antisera.</s><s>Group A type of peptidoglycan based upon lysine (Lys-D-Asp).</s><s>The long-chain fatty acids are of the straight-chain saturated, monounsaturated, and cyclopropane ring types (Table 3).</s><s>The major fatty acids are hexadecanoic, octadecenoic (Δ11) , and <i>cis</i>-11,12-methylenoctadecanoicacids.</s><s>The G +C content of the DNA ranges from 38 to 39 mol%, as determined by the melting temperature method.</s><s>The strains form a distinct homology group, as determined by DNA-DNA hybridization.</s><s>Isolated from cows, the hands of milkers, plants, and soil.</s><s>The type strain is strain NCDO 2375.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>In most respects the description of the type strain resembles the description of the species.</s><s>The type strain produces acid from glycerol, α-methyl-D-mannoside, sorbitol, rhamnose, and D-raffinose; acid is not produced from amidon or inulin.</s><s>The type strain is α-galactosidase positive.</s></p></content></protolog>