<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9149_nm.14342" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14342" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14342" rank="species">Mycobacterium insubricum</organism><reference id="rid.9149"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tortoli</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baruzzo</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heijdra</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Klenk</surname><given-names>H.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lauria</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mariottini</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>van Ingen</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium insubricum sp. nov.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1518</fpage><lpage>1523</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.003459-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19502346</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Mycobacterium insubricum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mycobacterium insubricum</em> (in.su′bri.cum. L. neut. adj. <em>insubricum</em> from Insubria, the Latin name of part of the Lombardy region of Italy that includes the cities in which four of the first five strains were isolated, including the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive-staining, acid-fast and non-motile.</s><s>Does not form spores and produces smooth, white, non-chromogenic colonies within 7 days at 25–37 °C.</s><s>Standard biochemical tests for identification of mycobacteria are negative with the exception of tellurite reduction and cannot be used for differentiation from other mycobacteria.</s><s>The result of lipid investigations are noteworthy, with three approaches (TLC, GLC and HPLC) revealing a close resemblance to <em>M. brumae</em>, <em>M. fallax</em> and <em>M. triviale</em>.</s><s>Susceptible <em>in vitro</em> to all of the most frequently used antimycobacterial drugs.</s><s>Substantial divergence from other known mycobacteria is present in the sequences of the 16S rRNA, <em>hsp65</em> and <em>rpoB</em> genes; observed divergence in these sequences generally exceeds the limits considered acceptable for differentiation of mycobacterial species (Turenne <em>et al.</em>, 2001; Adékambi <em>et al.</em>, 2003; Hall <em>et al.</em>, 2003).</s><s>The structure of the ITS shows low similarity to any other <em>Mycobacterium</em> species.</s><s>The PRA pattern differs from any reported so far.</s><s>The most closely related species on the basis of the phylogenetic analysis of the 16S rRNA gene sequence are <em>M. farcinogenes</em>, <em>M. houstonense</em> and <em>M. senegalense</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, FI-06250<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 45132<sup>T</sup> =CIP 109609<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a sputum sample.</s><s>Four other strains of the species, FI-06215, FI-05244, FI-03111 and NLA000701900, were isolated from sputum samples from independent patients with lung disease.</s><s>It seems unlikely that the isolates were of clinical significance.</s></p></content></protolog>