<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3151_nm.7554" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7554" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7554" rank="species">Nocardiopsis umidischolae</organism><reference id="rid.3151"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Peltola</surname><given-names>J.S.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Andersson</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Auling</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Salkinoja-Salonen</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Isolation of toxigenic Nocardiopsis strains from indoor environments and description of two new Nocardiopsis Species, N. exhalans sp. nov. and N. umidischolae sp. nov.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>67</volume><fpage>4293</fpage><lpage>4304</lpage><source id="228">Applied and Environmental Microbiology</source><abbrev>Appl Environ Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0099-2240</issn><essn>1098-5336</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1128/AEM.67.9.4293-4304.2001</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11526036</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Nocardiopsis umidischolae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Nocardiopsis umidischolae</i> (u.mi.di.scho'lae L. adj. <i>umidus</i>, moist; L. fem. n. <i>schola</i>, school; N.L. gen. fem. n. <i>umidischolae</i>, of a moist school)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The vegetative hyphae are yellowish and penetrate agar.</s><s>The aerial hyphae are white and 0.2 μm in diameter, and they form thick bundles.</s><s>No soluble pigment is produced.</s><s>Gram positive.</s><s>Catalase positive and aerobic.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 7.5% NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10, 28, and 37°C; no growth at 50°C.</s><s>Assimilates N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, arabinose, arbutin, cellobiose, fructose, galactose, gluconate, glucose, mannose, maltose, melibiose, rhamnose, ribose, sucrose, trehalose, xylose, maltitol, mannitol, acetate, propionate, cisaconitate, 4-aminobutyrate, citrate, fumarate, glutarate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, lactate, malate, oxoglutarate, pyruvate, L-alanine, β-alanine, aspartate, histidine, phenylalanine, proline, serine, and phenylacetate, but not salicin, adonitol, inositol, sorbitol, putrescine, adipate, azelate, itaconate, mesaconate, suberate, leucine, ornithine, tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoate, or 4-hydroxybenzoate.</s><s>Esculin is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Produces α- and β-glucosidases, phosphatase, and peptidases.</s><s>The fatty acid profile includes straight-chain saturated and unsaturated fatty acids, branched-chain fatty acids of the iso and anteiso types, and 10-methyl branched-chain fatty acids.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone was MK-10 (H<sub>6</sub>), and relatively high concentrations of MK-10 (H<sub>4</sub>), MK-10 (H<sub>8</sub>), and MK-11 (H<sub>6</sub>) were found.</s><s>Mesodiaminopimelic acid was the diamino acid of the peptidoglycan.</s><s>The polar lipid pattern was composed of the diagnostic phosphatidylcholine, and phosphatitylinositol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphotidylmethylethanolamine,anddiphosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The type strain was isolated from the indoor dust of a water-damaged school.</s><s>The type strain of <i>Nocardiopsis umidischolae</i> is strain 66/93 (=DSM 44362 = NRRL B-24122).</s></p></content></protolog>