<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12677_nm.22416" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22416" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22416" rank="species">Chryseomicrobium imtechense</organism><reference id="rid.12677"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Arora</surname><given-names>P.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chauhan</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pant</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Korpole</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mayilraj</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jain</surname><given-names>R.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chryseomicrobium imtechense gen. nov., sp. nov., a new member of the family Planococcaceae</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1859</fpage><lpage>1864</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.023184-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20833890</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chryseomicrobium imtechense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chryseomicrobium imtechense</em> [im.tech.en′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>imtechense</em> pertaining to the Institute of Microbial Technology (IMTECH), where the type strain was characterized].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those described for the genus.</s><s>Forms yellow colonies.</s><s>Cells are 0.3–0.7 µm wide and 1.7–2.9 µm long.</s><s>Grows at 4–45 °C, pH 6–9 and 0–6 % NaCl.</s><s>Casein is hydrolysed but gelatin, starch and aesculin are not.</s><s>Egg yolk reaction and oxidase test are negative.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S production, indole formation and urease test are negative.</s><s>Methyl red test, Voges–Proskauer test and oxidation/fermentation test are negative.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse ONPG.</s><s>No growth on MacConkey or Simmons’ citrate agar.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, salicin, fructose, maltose, sucrose, inulin, melibiose and cellobiose.</s><s>In the Biolog GP2 system, positive for oxidation of α<em>-</em>ketovaleric acid, glycerol, γ-hydroxybutyric acid, pyruvic acid, l-serine, d-ribose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, l-alanine, 2-deoxyadenosine and l-arabinose and negative for oxidation of α- and β-cyclodextrin, glycogen, inulin, mannan, lactose, methyl β-d-glucoside, l-alaninamide, trehalose, d-lactic acid methyl ester, d-alanine, arbutin, l-lactic acid, xylitol, d- and l-malic acid, raffinose, l-asparagine, l-fucose, l-rhamnose, adenosine 5′-monophosphate, melezitose, α-hydroxybutyric acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, Tweens 40 and 80, d-galacturonic acid, melibiose, salicin, propionic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, uridine 5′-monophosphate, gentiobiose, methyl α-d-galactoside, sedoheptulosan, d-fructose 6-phosphate, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosamine, d-gluconic acid, methyl β-d-galactoside, d-sorbitol, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, succinamic acid, putrescine, α-d-glucose 1-phosphate, amygdalin, <em>myo</em>-inositol, methyl α-d-glucoside, sucrose, <em>N</em>-acetyl l-glutamic acid and dl-α-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>The cellular fatty acid profile includes C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> alcohol, C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω11<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub>ω10<em>c</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, MW 10<sup>T</sup> ( = MTCC 10098<sup>T</sup>  = JCM 16573<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a seawater sample collected from the Bay of Bengal, India.</s></p></content></protolog>