<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1037_nm.7987" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7987" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7987" rank="species">Bacteroides suis</organism><reference id="rid.1037"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Benno</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Watabe</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mitsuoka</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacteroides pyogenes sp. nov., Bacteroides suis sp. nov., and Bacteroides helcogenes sp. nov., new species from absesses and feces of pigs</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>4</volume><fpage>396</fpage><lpage>407</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacteroides suis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacteroidds suis</i> (<i>su'is</i>. L. n. <i>sus</i> swine; L. gen. n. <i>suis</i> of the pig)]</s></p><p class="description"><s>Obligately anaerobic, Gram-negative, non-motile, non-pigmented, non-sporing rods.</s><s>Gram strains of single colonies from agar plates show predominantly short, Gram-negative rods, single or in pairs; longer rods only occasionally (0.4-0.6 μm by 0.5-2.0 μm).</s><s>After 2 days of incubation surface colonies are 0.5 to 1.5 mm in diameter, circular with entire edge, low convex, translucent to opaque, grey to grey-white, shiny and smooth.</s><s>Slight greening or indefinite hemolysis often apparent on blood agar plates.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No growth on blood agar plates incubated in a candle-extiction jar or in an  aerobic atmosphere.</s><s>Cultures in broth moderately turbid with a slight, smooth sediment.</s></p><p class="description"><s>After incubation for 1 day the pH in media containing a fermentable carbohydrate generally decreases to about 5.0 No, or markedly inhibited and delayed, growth in PYFG broth containing 20% bile.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Arabinose, xylose, glucose, manose, fructose, galactose, sucrose, maltose, cellobiose, lactose, melibiose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, inulin, salicin, amygdalin and xylan are fermented.</s><s>Esculin and starch are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Trehalose, melezitose, glycerol, adonitol, erythritol, inositol and gum arabic are not fermented.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced; indole or ammonium are not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acetic and succinic acids and very small amounts of propionic and isobutyric acids are produced in PYFG broth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains are susceptible to penicillin (10 μg/ml).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 42.3-45.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: swine abscess and feces.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is DSM 20612 ( = P38024), isolated from the feces of a healthy pig.</s></p></content></protolog>