<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3838_nm.3122" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3122" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3122" rank="species">Buttiauxella noackiae</organism><reference id="rid.3838"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>M체ller</surname><given-names>H.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fanning</surname><given-names>G.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>K채mpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended description of Buttiauxella agrestis with recognition of six new species of Buttiauxella and two new species of Kluyvera: Buttiauxella ferragutiae sp. nov., Buttiauxella gaviniae sp. nov., Buttiauxella brennerae sp. nov., Buttiauxella izardii sp. nov., Buttiauxella noackiae sp. nov., Buttiauxella warmboldiae sp. nov., Kluyvera cochleae sp. nov., and Kluyvera georgiana sp. nov.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>50</fpage><lpage>63</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-1-50</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11534554</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Buttiauxella noackiae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Buttiauxella noackiae</i> (no.ack'i.ae. M. L. fem. gen. n. <i>noackiae</i>, of Noack, in honor of Katrin Noack, who did most of the physiological tests at the Technische Universitat Berlin and spent many years studying the usefulness of miniaturized automated tests for differentiation of various bacterial groups)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Buttiauxella noackiae</i> was previously called enteric group 59 (10, 12) and in this study was referred to as DNA hybridization group 6.</s><s>Biochemical characteristics of 15 strains isolated from snails are shown in Table 2.</s><s>These characteristics are almost identical to those described for enteric group 59; the only exception is the result of the lactose test.</s><s>All snail isolates lack a yellow pigment and are lactose negative, but seven of the eight enteric group 59 strains isolated from humans and food were lactose positive (10, 12).</s><s>It is possible that there is a correlation between the ability to split and metabolize lactose and the ability to survive in humans.</s><s>Tests that are useful in differentiating <i>B. noackiae</i> from other <i>Buttiauxella</i> species are the N-acetyl-L-glutamine, L-arginine dihydrolase, melibiose, and L-ornithine decarboxylase tests.</s><s>In addition, 33% of the strains are phenylalanine deaminase positive and 40% produce indole.</s><s>A combination of several characteristics is necessary to distinguish <i>B. noackiae</i> from other <i>Buttiauxella</i> species.</s><s>Isolated from mollusks, human sputum, human wounds, and food.</s><s>It is not known whether this species is pathogenic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.<i>B. noackiae</i> type strain NSW 11 (= ATCC 51607 = DSM 9401 = serial no. 170), an EG59-like strain, was isolated from a snail captured in Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</s><s>Good growth occurs at 30 to 36째C.</s><s>Strain NSW 11<sup>T</sup> colonies are circular, convex, greyish, and smooth on nutrient agar and blood agar, 1 to 2 mm in diameter after 1 day, and 2 to 3 mm in diameter after 2 days.</s><s>Weak growth occurs at 42째C.</s><s>The type strain has all of the characteristics given for the genus in Table 7 and for the species in Table 2.</s></p></content></protolog>