<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10762_nm.17857" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17857" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5948" rank="species">Corynebacterium stationis</organism><reference id="rid.10762"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bernard</surname><given-names>K.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wiebe</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Burdz</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Reimer</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ng</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Singh</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schindle</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pacheco</surname><given-names>A.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Assignment of Brevibacterium stationis (ZoBell and Upham 1944) Breed 1953 to the genus Corynebacterium, as Corynebacterium stationis comb. nov., and emended description of the genus Corynebacterium to include isolates that can alkalinize citrate</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>874</fpage><lpage>879</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.012641-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19661509</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Corynebacterium stationis</em> (ZoBell and Upham 1944) comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Corynebacterium stationis</em> (sta.ti.o′nis. L. gen. n. <em>stationis</em> of a fixed position).</s></p><p class="nomenclature"><s>Basonym: <em>Brevibacterium stationis</em> (ZoBell and Upham 1944) Breed 1953.</s></p><p class="nomenclature"><s>Other synonym: ‘<em>Achromobacter stationis</em>’ ZoBell and Upham 1944.</s></p><p class="description"><s>This description is based on the description of <em>Brevibacterium stationis</em> given by Jones &#x0026; Keddie (1986) and from observations in this study for strains ATCC 14403<sup>T</sup> and ATCC 6872 and two human blood-culture isolates.</s><s>Gram-positive, asporogenic, short rods, 0.6–1 μm in diameter, occur singly, in pairs and in ‘V’ forms and can be club shaped.</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>Not acid-fast.</s><s>Colonies on blood agar after 24 h are grey–white but become yellowish with age, about 1 mm in diameter and raised, with no haemolysis observed.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic, but grows better under aerobic conditions.</s><s>Poor or no growth under strictly anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Grows at 25, 35 and 42 °C in air.</s><s>Not lipophilic.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Acid is produced, albeit slowly, from glucose, fructose and ribose.</s><s>Fucose found in the API 50CH gallery is also weakly reactive.</s><s>Weakly reactive for mannose.</s><s>Xylose, mannitol, lactose, sucrose, maltose, galactose, glycerol, glycogen, raffinose, salicin and trehalose are not reactive.</s><s>Triple-sugar iron remains neutral or alkaline or neutral.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 6–10 % NaCl.</s><s>Urease is produced.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite but nitrite is not reduced to nitrogen using either conventional or API Coryne panel methods.</s><s>Simmons’ citrate is alkalinized.</s><s>Tyrosine is hydrolysed but gelatin, aesculin, casein and starch are not.</s><s>Not reactive in tests for lysine, arginine or ornithine decarboxylases.</s><s>Christie–Atkins–Munch-Petersen (CAMP) and CAMP-inhibition reactions are not observed.</s><s>DNase and indole are not produced.</s><s>Pyrazinamidase may be produced, but otherwise most enzymes of the API ZYM panel are not detected.</s><s>Strains are generally susceptible to a wide variety of antimicrobials.</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan has <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid as the major diamino acid.</s><s>Cell-wall sugars are arabinose and galactose.</s><s>Mycolates are present.</s><s>Menaquinones are the sole respiratory quinones, MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>) being detected.</s><s>CFAs are of the saturated and monounsaturated types and tuberculostearic acid is detected.</s><s>The DNA G+C content for the type strain is 53.9 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub> method).</s><s>Members of the species may be discriminated from other <em>Corynebacterium</em> species by observation of the alkalinization of citrate and other described reactions, and by 16S rRNA and <em>rpoB</em> gene sequencing.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, ATCC 14403<sup>T</sup> =CCUG 43497<sup>T</sup> =CIP 104228<sup>T</sup> =DSM 20302<sup>T</sup> =NBRC 12144<sup>T</sup> =JCM 11611<sup>T</sup> =VKM B-1228<sup>T</sup>, was isolated from seawater.</s><s>Strain ATCC 6872, previously assigned to <em>C. ammoniagenes</em>, was isolated from human infant stools and strains NML 94-0424 and NML 03-0173 were recovered from human blood cultures.</s></p></content></protolog>