<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7511_nm.1437" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1437" rank="genus">Methylosinus</organism><reference id="rid.7511"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sly</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nichols</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hayward</surname><given-names>A.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Revised taxonomy of the methanotrophs: Description of Methylobacter gen.nov., emendation of Methylococcus, validation of Methylosinus and Methylocystis species, and a proposal that the family Methylococcaceae includes only the Group I Methanotrophs.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>735</fpage><lpage>753</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-4-735</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of the genus <i>Methylosinus</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Methylosinus</i> (Me.thyl.o.si'nus. N. L. n. <i>methylo</i>, methyl group; L. n. sinus, bend; N. L. masc. n. <i>Methylosinus</i>, methyl bender)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative pyriform or vibrioid cells that are 0.5 to 1.0 μm wide by 1.5 to 3.0 μm long.</s><s>Forms rosettes in logarithmic growth phase.</s><s>When not present in rosettes, cells are motile by means of a polar tuft of flagella.</s><s>Cells primarily reproduce by budding off heat- and desiccation-resistant exospores from the nonflagellated pole.</s><s>Cells are encapsulated but do not accumulate polyphosphate.</s><s>Cells contain type II intracytoplasmic membranes which are aligned parallel to the cell wall.</s><s>Cells are not susceptible to lysis by SDS.</s><s>Grows at temperatures between 20 and 37°C; no growth occurs at temperatures above 40°C; the optimal growth temperature is about 30°C.</s><s>Grows between pH 5.5 and 9.0; the optimal pH is 6.5 to 7.0.</s><s>Organic growth factors and NaCl are not required for growth.</s><s>Strictly aerobic chemoheterotrophs.</s><s>Group II methanotroph.</s><s>Obligate utilizer of C<sub>1</sub> compounds via the serine transhydroqmethylase pathway.</s><s>Compounds with carbon-carbon bonds do not serve as sole sources of carbon and energy.</s><s>No growth occurs on complex organic media such as nutrient agar.</s><s>Does not contain the Benson-Calvin cycle for CO<sub>2</sub> fixation but contains a complete tricarboxylic acid cycle, unlike the group I methanotrophs.</s><s>Fixes atmospheric nitrogen by means of an aerotolerant nitrogenase.</s><s>Produces oxidase and catalase.</s><s>Unable to grow autotrophically, to denitrify, or to reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Contains 18:1ω8c as the predominant PFLA.</s><s>The major quinone is ubiquinone 8 (12).</s><s>The DNA base composition ranges from 63 to 67 mol% G+C (T<sub>i</sub>). <i>Methylosinus trichosporium</i> is the type species.</s></p></content></protolog>