<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10566_nm.17806" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17806" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.17806" rank="species">Staphylococcus microti</organism><reference id="rid.10566"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nováková</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pantucek</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hubálek</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sedlácek</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Staphylococcus microti sp. nov., isolated from the common vole (Microtus arvalis)</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>566</fpage><lpage>573</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.011429-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19654347</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Staphylococcus microti</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Staphylococcus microti</em> (mi.cro′ti. N.L. gen. n. <em>microti</em> of <em>Microtus</em>, the zoological name for a genus of vole, referring to the isolation of the first strains from individuals of <em>Microtus arvalis</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-stain-positive cocci, occurring singly or in irregular clusters.</s><s>Colonies are smooth, circular, slightly concave, opalescent whitish with continuous margins, 0.8–1.8 mm in diameter.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase- and coagulase-negative.</s><s>Clumping factor is not detected by the latex test.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15, 37 and 45 °C and in the presence of 10 % NaCl, but not 15 % NaCl.</s><s>Produces <em>δ</em>-haemolysin on blood agar with sheep blood in synergy with a producer of <em>β</em>-haemolysin.</s><s>Produces alkaline and acid phosphatases, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine arylamidase and lecithinase.</s><s>Produces acid from d-glucose, d-fructose, lactose, trehalose, d-xylose, sucrose and <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, reduces nitrates and hydrolyses aesculin, Tween 80 and DNA.</s><s>Weak reactions are observed for esterase lipase (C 8) and leucine arylamidase in the API ZYM kit.</s><s>Other weak reactions are found for acetoin production and acid production from d-mannose.</s><s>Does not produce arginine dihydrolase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase or ornithine decarboxylase or acid from maltose, d-mannitol, xylitol, melibiose, raffinose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, d-ribose, cellobiose, turanose or l-arabinose.</s><s>Urea, starch, casein and gelatin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Cultures show negative responses for esterase (C4), lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Resistant to bacitracin (0.04 U) and lysozyme (400 mg l<sup>−1</sup>) but susceptible to novobiocin (5 μg), furazolidone (100 μg), amoxicillin/clavulanic acid (20/10 μg), oxacillin (1 μg), tetracycline (30 μg), trimethoprim/sulfamethoxazole (23.75/1.25 μg), erythromycin (15 μg), clindamycin (2 μg), vancomycin (30 μg), ciprophloxacin (5 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), rifampicin (5 μg), teicoplanin (30 μg) and lysostaphin (50 mg l<sup>−1</sup>).</s><s>Dominant fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 2</sub><em>ω</em>6,9<em>c</em>/anteiso-C<sub>18 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>.</s><s>Peptidoglycan type is A3<em>α</em> l-Lys–Gly<sub>2–3</sub>–l-Ser–Gly and the quinone system includes the major component menaquinone MK-7 and minor quantities of MK-6 and MK-8.</s><s>The polar lipid profile consists of the major compounds diphosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>Additionally, moderate amounts of an unknown glycolipid and an unknown aminophospholipid and minor amounts of another glycolipid, an aminophospholipid, a phospholipid and a polar lipid are detectable.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is 4005-LJ(m)<sup>T</sup> (=CCM 4903<sup>T</sup> =CCUG 55861<sup>T</sup> =DSM 22147<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the liver of a free-living common vole in the Czech Republic.</s><s>Its characteristics are in full agreement with those given in the species description.</s></p></content></protolog>