<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9567_nm.14743" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14743" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14743" rank="species">Bavariicoccus seileri</organism><reference id="rid.9567"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schmidt</surname><given-names>V.S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mayr</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wenning</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Glöckner</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Scherer</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bavariicoccus seileri gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from the surface and smear water of German red smear soft cheese</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2437</fpage><lpage>2443</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.006601-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19622668</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bavariicoccus seileri</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bavariicoccus seileri</em> (sei′le.ri. N.L. gen. masc. n. <em>seileri</em> named in honour of Herbert Seiler, former microbiologist of the Technical University of Munich with great merit in FT-IR spectroscopic identification of micro-organisms).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The characteristics are the same as those given in the description of the genus with the following additions.</s><s>Small, smooth colonies up to 1 mm in diameter are formed aerobically on TSA at 30 °C and up to 2 mm in diameter on APT agar under anaerobic conditions at 34 °C.</s><s>Cell diameter is 0.9–1.2 μm.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10 and 40 °C, at pH 5.5 and with 11 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Produces dl-lactic acid, ethanol and acetic acid from d-glucose.</s><s>Utilizes galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, trehalose, lactose (except isolates WCC 4189 and WCC 4190) and pyruvate as the sole sources of carbon and energy, but not glycerol, erythritol, d- or l-arabinose, ribose, d- or l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, l-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, glycogen, xylitol, melibiose, sucrose, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, d- or l-arabitol, gluconate, 2- or 5-ketogluconate, pullulan or starch.</s><s>Positive for <em>β</em>-glucosidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase and leucine arylamidase, but negative for <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase (except isolate WCC 4187), <em>β</em>-glucuronidase and alkaline phosphatase.</s><s>Hippurate is not hydrolysed.</s><s>In addition to the lipids listed in the genus description, several unknown lipids (polar lipids, glyco-, phospho- and aminolipids) are found in the polar lipid profile.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 38 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is WCC 4188<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 19936<sup>T</sup> =CCUG 55508<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The type strain and reference strains WCC 4187 (=CCUG 55507) and WCC 4189 (=CCUG 55509) were isolated from the surface and smear water of German smear-ripened soft cheeses.</s></p></content></protolog>