<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5648_nm.8296" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8296" rank="genus">Flectobacillus</organism><reference id="rid.5648"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Raj</surname><given-names>H.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Maloy</surname><given-names>S.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of Cyclobacterium marinus gen. nov., comb. nov., for a marine bacterium previously assigned to the genus Flectobacillus.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>337</fpage><lpage>347</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-4-337</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emendation of the genus <i>Flectobacillus</i> Larkin et al. 1977</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>(Flec.to. ba.cil'lus. L. v. <i>flecto</i>, to curve; L. n. <i>bacillus</i>, a little staff, rod; M. L. masc. n. <i>Flectobacillus</i>, curved rod.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative curved rods with variable degrees of curvature from cell to cell.</s><s>Most cells are shaped like the letter C (wide open rings), and sometimes cell ends touch or overlap (closed rings).</s><s>The outer ring diameter is 5 to 10 pm, and the cell width is 0.6 to 2.0 μm.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell termini are tapered or rounded or both.</s><s>Coils are less common, and spiral forms are rare.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Bizarre shapes and sizes (filaments &#x003E;50 μm long with bulbous structures, swollen involuted cells, and short rods) occur under certain cultural conditions.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nonflagellated, nonmotile, and nonflexible.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Optimum growth occurs at 20 to 25°C in or on freshwater media but not in or on media containing seawater or 3.0% NaCl.</s><s>Colonies on such media are large (diameter, 5 mm) with a pinkish or pale rose pigment.</s><s>A cottony pellicle but no ring is formed in broth cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strict aerobe.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic but not methylotrophic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Metabolism is oxidative, never fermentative.</s><s>Acid is produced from most carbohydrates, including cellobiose and dextrin, but not from ribose, sorbose, and sugar alcohols.</s><s>Glycerol phosphate, malonate, tartrate, and many TCA intermediates are not utilized as single carbon sources.</s><s>Tests for lipase, oxidase, and urease are positive.</s><s>Weakly positive for catalase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 39.5 to 40.3 mol% (thermal denaturation method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The natural habitat is freshwater lakes.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <i>F. major</i>; the type strain of this species is strain Gromov (= ATCC 29496).</s></p></content></protolog>