<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5530_nm.8868" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8868" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8868" rank="species">Streptomyces koyangensis</organism><reference id="rid.5530"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>H.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hwang</surname><given-names>B.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces koyangensis sp. nov., a novel actinomycete that produces 4-phenyl-3-butenoic acid</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>257</fpage><lpage>262</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63168-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15653884</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptomyces koyangensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomyces koyangensis</em> (ko.yang.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>koyangensis</em> pertaining to Koyang, Republic of Korea, the geographical origin of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, non-motile actinomycete.</s><s>Spore chains containing 10 or more spores per chain are <em>Rectiflexibiles</em>.</s><s>Spores are spherical (1·2 μm in diameter) with a smooth surface.</s><s>Whole-cell hydrolysates contain ll-DAP.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA is 67·8 mol%.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (16·54 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (28·77 %) and C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (11·60 %).</s><s>In addition, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (9·01 %), iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (8·84 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (7·02 %), C<sub>17 : 0</sub> cyclo (4·54 %), anteiso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub> (3·23 %), iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (1·94), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (1·33 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 1</sub> (1·86 %) and C<sub>16 : 1</sub> <em>cis</em>9 (2·57) were detected.</s><s>Grows well on yeast extract/malt extract agar (ISP2), oatmeal agar (ISP3), inorganic salts/starch agar (ISP4), peptone/yeast extract iron agar (ISP6) and tyrosine agar (ISP7).</s><s>Does not grow well on ISP5 medium.</s><s>The spore mass is white to grey and the reverse sides of colonies are brown on most agar media.</s><s>Aerial mycelia are abundant on most of these media.</s><s>The colour of substrate mycelium is pale brown to dark brown.</s><s>Production of spores on ISP4 is prolific.</s><s>Melanin pigments are produced on ISP6 and ISP7.</s><s>As the sole carbon source, it utilizes l-arabinose, d-fructose, mannitol and xylose for growth, but not adonitol, dextran, <em>meso</em>-inositol, d-melezitose, d-melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, sucrose or xylitol.</s><s>As a nitrogen source, utilizes l-cysteine, l-histidine, l-phenylalanine and l-valine.</s><s>However, it cannot utilize dl-<em>α</em>-amino-<em>n</em>-butyric acid or l-hydroxyproline.</s><s>Degrades casein, elastin, aesculin, gelatin, starch, tyrosine and xanthine, but not cellulose.</s><s>Pectin hydrolysis, nitrate reduction and H<sub>2</sub>S production are positive, whereas lecithinase, lipolysis and hippurate hydrolysis are negative.</s><s>The strain grows in the presence of 4, 7 and 10 % sodium chloride but not 13 %.</s><s>It grows in 0·02 % NaN<sub>3</sub> and 0·001 % thallous acetate, but not in 0·1 % phenol or 0·001 % potassium tellurite.</s><s>The strain is resistant to penicillin G, but sensitive to neomycin, rifampicin and oleandomycin.</s><s>Produces 4-phenyl-3-butenoic acid, which inhibits the mycelial growth of several plant-pathogenic fungi, such as <em>Alternaria mali</em>, <em>Cladosporium cucumerinum</em>, <em>Colletotrichum gloeosporioides</em>, <em>Colletotrichum orbiculare</em>, <em>Magnaporthe grisea</em> and <em>Fusarium oxysporum</em> f. sp. <em>cucumerinum</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is VK-A60<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 10555<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 100598<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>