<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4807_nm.2792" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2792" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2792" rank="species">Psychrobacter luti</organism><reference id="rid.4807"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bozal</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Montes</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tudela</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Guinea</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characterization of several Psychrobacter strains isolated from Antarctic environments and description of Psychrobacter luti sp. nov. and Psychrobacter fozii sp. nov.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1093</fpage><lpage>1100</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02457-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12892132</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Psychrobacter luti</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Psychrobacter luti</em> (lut′i. L. masc. gen. n. <em>luti</em> of mud, referring to the isolation of strains from Antarctic glacier mud).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile, non-pigmented, non-spore-forming coccobacilli, 0·4–1·8 μm long and 0·4–0·6 μm wide.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–30 °C.</s><s>Colonies on TSA are about 2 mm in diameter, smooth, opaque and non-circular, and spread little throughout the growth medium after 5 days at 15 °C.</s><s>Able to grow in the absence of NaCl and can tolerate 9·5 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Strictly aerobic; oxidase and catalase tests are positive.</s><s>Acid is not produced from carbohydrates.</s><s>Cells are able to reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Urease and tryptophan deaminase are not produced.</s><s>Positive in the following biochemical tests: phenylalanine deaminase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase and lecithinase.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of casein and Tween 80.</s><s>Growth occurs on l-histidine, l-proline, l-hydroxyproline, l-malic acid, sodium succinate, l-arginine, l-glutamine, Tween 80, dl-phenylalanine, putrescine, sodium acetate, l-ornithine, sodium citrate, 1-butanol and l-asparagine.</s><s>The main cellular fatty acids are 18 : 1<em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, 16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and 17 : 1<em>ω</em>8<em>c</em>.</s><s>The G+C content of DNA of the type strain is 45 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain NF11<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 21276<sup>T</sup> =CECT 5885<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from muddy soil collected from the inlet Admiralty Bay on King George Island, South Shetland Islands, Antarctica.</s></p></content></protolog>