<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.201_nm.2753" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2753" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2753" rank="species">Moraxella caprae</organism><reference id="rid.201"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kodjo</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tønjum</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Richard</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bøvre</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Moraxella caprae sp. nov., a new member of the classical Moraxellae with very close affinity to Moraxella bovis.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>467</fpage><lpage>471</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-3-467</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8590674</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Moraxella caprae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Moraxella caprae</i> (ca'prae. L. gen. n. <i>caprae</i>, of a goat)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Phenotypic characteristics are described in reference 14.</s><s>Cells are gram-negative, medium to large straight rods with a tendency to grow as diplobacilli or in short chains.</s><s>They are nonmotile, aerobic, and grow well at temperatures between 30 and 37°C.</s><s>Colonies are greyish white, smooth, and variable in size.</s><s>Colonies that are 1 to 1.5 mm in diameter after 18 h are smooth and convex; colonies become large and flat and are surrounded by a wide area of hemolysis after 36 to 48 h of incubation in an aerobic atmosphere with or without CO<sub>2</sub> on 5% sheep or human blood agar plates.</s><s>Weak growth under the same incubation conditions occurs on nutrient agar.</s><s>The oxidase and catalase reactions are strongly positive.</s><s>All strains hydrolyze Tween 80 and tributyrin and reduce nitrate.</s><s>No acid is produced from carbohydrates.</s><s>All strains are nonproteolytic (Loeffler slant and gelatin negative).</s><s>Indole and urease reactions are also negative.</s><s>The main traits that distinguish <i>M. caprae</i> from <i>M. bovis</i> are reduction of nitrate and absence of proteolysis.</s><s>Hemolysis on human or sheep blood agar is a clear-cut feature which differentiates <i>M. caprae</i> from all other <i>Moraxella</i> species.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 40 to 41.5 mol%.</s><s>The clinical significance of this organism is unknown.</s><s>Strain 8897 (= CCUG 33297 = NCTC 12877) is the type strain; it was isolated in 1988 from the nasal cavity of a healthy goat.</s></p></content></protolog>