<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1458_nm.6712" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6712" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6712" rank="species">Amycolatopsis fastidiosa</organism><reference id="rid.1458"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Henssen</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kothe</surname><given-names>H.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Pseudonocardia azurea and "Pseudonocardia fastidiosa" to the genus Amycolatopsis, with emended species description.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>292</fpage><lpage>295</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Amycolatopsis fastidiosa</i> (ex Celmer et al. 1977) sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Amycolatopsis fastidiosa</i> (fas. tid'i. os. a. M.L. adj. <i>fastidiosus</i>, disdainful, fastidious)</s></p><p class="description"><s>basonym: "Pseudonocardia fastidiosa" Celmer et al.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on data from Celmer et al. (U.S. patent no. 4,031,206, 1977) emended by our own results.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No acropetal budding of mycelium.</s><s>Substrate mycelium yellow to pale salmon, hyphae irregularly branched, up to 1 μm wide and frequently zig-zag shaped, occasionally with intercalary swellings.</s><s>Aerial mycelium white to pale pink; spores are rod shaped, smooth, 1.2 to 4.5 μm.</s><s>Growth good on various complex agar media but production of aerial mycelium was obtained only on Czapek sucrose, glucose yeast-extract and inorganic salts-starch agars; yellowish to brown soluble pigments are produced on yeast extract-malt agar or inorganic salts-starch agar.</s><s>No utilization of carbohydrates on ISP medium no. 9, but L-arabinose, D-fructose, D-glucose, raffinose, and D-xylose are utilized if ISP medium no. 4 minus starch was used; no growth on <i>meso</i>-inositol, D-mannitol, and L-rhamnose.</s><s>Optimal temperature for growth between 28 and 36°C. (For further physiological details, see Table 2.) The G+C content of DNA is 73 mol%.</s><s>The production of macrobicyclic peptide antibiotic substances by the type strain has been described by Celmer et al. (U.S. patent no. 4,031,206,1977).</s><s>The strain was isolated from a soil sample from Egypt.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is DSM 43855<sup>T</sup> (ATCC 31181).</s></p></content></protolog>