<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3364_nm.2742" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2742" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2742" rank="species">Rugamonas rubra</organism><reference id="rid.3364"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Austin</surname><given-names>D.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moss</surname><given-names>M.O.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Numerical taxonomy of red-pigmented bacteria isolated from a lowland river, with the description of a new taxon, Rugamonas rubra gen. nov., sp. nov.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>132</volume><fpage>1899</fpage><lpage>1909</lpage><source id="211">Journal of General Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Gen Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-1287</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rugamonas rubra</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rugamonas rubra</i> (rub'ra. L. fem.adj. <i>rubra</i> red)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rods, approximately 2.4-4.0 x 0.8-0.9 μm in size with rounded ends.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Intracellular granules of prodigiosin develop in old cells, i.e. ≥7 d.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Young cells are motile by one or more sub-polar/polar flagella, older cultures have reduced motility.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultures in Bennett's broth form pink/red flocs after 7 d.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on Bennett's agar at 20°C are white, shiny and circular after 2-3 d, become pink after 4 d, and deep red, wrinkled and rubbery in consistency after 5 d, with a diameter of about 3 mm.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrates are reduced to nitrogen.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Temperature range for growth: 4°C to 30°C, but not 37°C.</s><s>Optimum temperature is about 25°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth occurs in 0% to 0.5% (w/v) NaCl, and at pH 5-9.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Arginine decarboxylase is not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Lysine and ornithine decarboxylases are produced by some strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aesculin, chitin, DNA, RNA, gelatin, lecithin, Tween 20,40,60 and 80, tyrosine and urea are degraded but not allantoin, cellulose, elastin, hypoxanthine, starch and xanthine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>β-Galactosidase and phosphatase are produced but H<sub>2</sub>S and phenylalanine deaminase are not.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The gluconate and Koser's citrate tests but not the Voges-Proskauer, methyl red and malonate tests are positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following enzymes are produced:alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, esterase (some strains), esterase-lipase, leucine arylamidase and phosphoamidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Sensitive to chloramphenicol (10 μg), chlortetracycline (10 μg), erythromycin (10 μg), furazolidone (50 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), novobiocin (5 μg), oxytetracycline (10 μg), streptomycin (10 μg), sulphafurazole (500 μg), tetracycline (10 μg) and cotrimoxazole (25 μg) but resistant to ampicillin (2 μg), cloxacillin (5 μg), colistin sulphate (10 μg), neomycin (10 μg), nitrofurantoin (200 μg) and penicillin G (1.5 i.u.).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Utilizes D(-)-alanine, L(+)-arabinose, DL-arginine, <i>meso</i>-inositol, sodium DL-lactate, cellobiose, D(-)-fructose, D(+)-galactose, L(-)-histidine, maltose, D(+)-mannose, D(-)-raffinose, D(-)-ribose, DL-serine, sodium acetate, trisodium citrate, D(-)-sorbitol, sucrose and trehalose as sole carbon sources for energy and growth, but not adonitol, i-erythritol, sodium malonate, D(+)-melibiose, D(-)-melezitose, D(-)-rhamnose, DL-valine and D(+)-xylose.</s><s>Lactose is utilized by some strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G + C ratio of the DNA of the type strain is 66.7 ± 0.1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from river water.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is MOM 28/2/79 ; a culture of this strain has been deposited with the American Type Culture Collection, Rockville, Md, USA, as ATCC 43154, and the Czechoslovak Collection of Micro-organisms as CCM 3730.</s></p></content></protolog>