<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.304_nm.526" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.526" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.526" rank="species">Thermus oshimai</organism><reference id="rid.304"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Smith</surname><given-names>K.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Welch</surname><given-names>S.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Micallef</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thermus oshimai sp. nov., isolated from hot springs in Portugal, Iceland, and the Azores, and comment on the concept of a limited geographical distribution of Thermus species.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>403</fpage><lpage>408</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-2-403</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8934898</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thermus oshimai</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thermus oshimai</i> (Osh'i.ma.i. N.L. adj. <i>oshimai</i>, referring to T. Oshima, a prolific researcher who has studied the molecular biology of the genus <i>Thermus</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, heterotrophic, thermophilic short rods that are gram negative. <i>Thermus oshimai</i> forms a yellow pigment like <i>Themus brockianus</i>, but does not exhibit the distinctive spreading colonial morphology of <i>Thermus brockianus</i> on tryptone-yeast extract plates at 70°C.</s><s>Peptidoglycan has ornithine cross-links with glycine in the interpeptide bridge; the respiratory quinone is menaquinone 8; and the DNA G+C content is 62 to 65 mol% (63 mol% in SPS17).</s><s>More than 85% of the strains grow anaerobically in the presence of nitrate and form nitrite (39).</s><s>Most strains hydrolyze fibrin, casein, and hideazure in plate assays, and most strains grow on glutamate and asparagine, fructose, mannose, and galactose.</s><s>All strains grow on sucrose, maltose, and trehalose.</s><s>Unlike the strains of the four other phenetic groups (39), <i>Themus oshimai</i> strains grow on lactose (and form β-galactosidase) and on melibiose (and form α-galactosidase).</s><s>About one-half of the strains grow on glucose.</s><s>The type strain is strain SPS17, which was isolated by M.</s><s>S. da Costa from a sample obtained from Sao Pedro do Sul, Portugal (39); this strain has been deposited in the National Collection of Industrial and Marine Bacteria as strain NCIMB 13400.</s></p></content></protolog>