<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6430_nm.3171" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3171" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3171" rank="species">Erwinia cacticida</organism><reference id="rid.6430"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Alcorn</surname><given-names>S.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Orum</surname><given-names>T.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Foster</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fogleman</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomy and pathogenicity of Erwinia cacticida sp. nov.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>197</fpage><lpage>212</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-41-2-197</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1854634</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Erwinia cacticida</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Erwinia cacticida</i> (cac.ti.ci.da. Gr. n. <i>kaktos</i>, prickly plant; Gr. v. <i>cid</i>, to kill; M. L. adj. <i>cacticida</i>, cactus killing)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are motile, gram-negative, nonsporeforming rods (ca. 0.5 to 1.2 by 0.5 to 1.7 μm) with peritrichous flagella and fimbriae.</s><s>Capsules may be produced.</s><s>The cells of some strains are almost round (e.g., 0.8 by 0.9 μm); short chains of cells are frequent in some strains.</s><s>Colonies grown on PDP for 24 h at 30°C are small, smooth, glistening, circular, entire, slightly convex, ivory, and translucent and frequently have striations.</s><s>They produce a distinct odor and become opaque, off-white, and butyrous with age.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultures are catalase positive, oxidase negative, nitrate reducing, facultatively anaerobic, and pectolytic.</s><s>In addition, they produce acid from a number of carbohydrates, including D-glucose, D-ribose, D-galactose, D-fructose, Dmannose, D-mannitol, L-rhamnose, P-gentiobiose, esculin, salicin, <i>n</i>-acetylglucosamine, and usually trehalose, but not from L-arabinose, <i>myo</i>-inositol, cellobiose, melibiose, α-methylglucoside, maltose, or dulcitol.</s><s>Cultures usually do not produce acid from lactose, Strains utilize formate and malonate and grow in the presence of 5% NaCl but not in KCN broth.</s><s>Strains are usually not sensitive to erythromycin and do not produce reducing substances from sucrose.</s><s>They are most easily recognized by their positive reaction on pectate, growth at 43"C, and the seve<i>n</i>-digit API 20E profile of 1205131.</s><s>Complete biochemical characteristics are shown in Table 3.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Tests useful in differentiating <i>Erwinia cacticida</i> from other <i>Erwinia</i> species are shown in Table 6.</s><s>Fatty acid characteristics alone distinguish <i>Erwinia cacticida</i> from <i>Erwinia carotovora</i> but not from some other <i>Erwinia</i> species or <i>Enterobacter</i> (<i>Pantoea</i>) <i>agglomerans</i>.</s><s>However, the presence of C<sub>19:0</sub> Cyclo C11-12 and the absence of C<sub>13:0</sub>, C<sub>17:0</sub>, and C<sub>17:1 CIS 9</sub>, together with a positive test result for pectate hydrolysis, can be used to identify <i>Erwinia cacticida</i> strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 50.8 to 51.7 mol% (30).</s><s>Natural habitats are the soft-rotting tissues of cacti growing in the wild.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain 1-12 (= ATCC 49481), which was isolated from a saguaro cactus in 1958, is the type strain.</s><s>Strains ICPB EC186<sup>T</sup> and ICMP 1551-66<sup>T</sup> are subcultures of strain 1-12<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>Strain ICPB EC186<sup>T</sup> was sent to M.</s><s>Starr at the International Collection of Phyto athogenic Bacteria in 1959; Dye obtained ICPB EC186 , labeled it strain EH-3<sup>T</sup> in his studies, and deposited it with the Plant Disease Division, New Zealand Department of Scientific and Industrial Research, Auckland, New Zealand, in 1966, where it is now labeled strain ICMP 1551-66<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>This strain is troublesome.</s><s>Although ostensibly a subculture of strain 1-12<sup>T</sup>, it differs from 1-12<sup>T</sup> in its reactions in a number of tests, including tests for trehalose, lactose, reducing substances produced from sucrose, and fatty acids C<sub>13:0</sub>, C<sub>17:0</sub>, and C<sub>17:1 CIS 9</sub>.</s><s>On the other hand, strain ICMP 1551-66<sup>T</sup> exhibits 93% DNA relatedness to strain 1-12<sup>T</sup> at 60°C.</s></p></content></protolog>