<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.727_nm.1283" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1283" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1283" rank="species">Rhizobium fredii</organism><reference id="rid.727"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Scholla</surname><given-names>M.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Elkan</surname><given-names>G.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhizobium fredii sp. nov. a fast-growing species that effectively nodulates soybeans.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>484</fpage><lpage>486</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhizobium fredii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhizobium fredii</i> (fred'i.i. M.L. gen. n. <i>fredii</i> of E. B. Fred)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram negative, nonsporeforming, and rod shaped.</s><s>Motility is exhibited by only a small proportion (1 to 5%) of the strains: this proportion is increased when the organisms are cultured on soft agar.</s><s>Cells from late log phase to stationary phase YEM cultures tend to become large and pleomorphic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Within 7 days, colonies on YkM agar plates containing bromthymol blue are between 1.0 and 5.0 mm in diameter, produce an acidic reaction, and are circular, convex, and entire.</s><s>Extracellular polysaccharide production is minimal, but some strains produce watery colonies.</s><s>The amount of growth at 28°C on YEM agar containing 2% NaCl is variable, but all strains are inhibited at a concentration of 3%.</s><s>Inhibition of all strains is evident at pH 9.5, but they grow well at pH 4.5.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gelatinase, galactosidase, and 6-phosphogluconate dehfidrogenase are produced.</s><s>All strains grow on arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, fructose, fumarate, galactose, gluconate, glucose, glycerol, lactose, malate, mannose, pyruvate, raffinose, rhamnose, succinate, sucrose, trehalose, and xylose.</s><s>Litmus milk reactions are variable for acid and alkali, but most strains exhibit peptonization and reduction of litmus.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains are susceptible to gentamicin (30 μg/ml), rifampin (5 μg/ml), neomycin (100 μg/ml), and streptomycin (10 μg/ml).</s><s>All strains are resistant to penicillin G (50 μg/ml).</s><s>Resistance to kanamycin is variable at a concentration of 20 μg/ml, but all strains are susceptible to 50 μg of kanamycin per ml.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Large plasmids have been demonstrated in all strains.</s><s>Some of the plasmids contain DNA regions that hybridize with probes for the nip and nim genes from <i>Klebsiella pneumoniae</i>.</s><s>Plasmids involved in nodulation have also been identified.</s><s>The levels of DNA-DNA homology with type strains <i>R. meliloti</i> ATCC 9930, <i>R. trifolii</i> ATCC 14480, <i>R. leguminosarum</i> ATCC 10004, <i>R. phaseoli</i> ATCC 14482, and <i>B. japonicum</i> ATCC 10324 range from 5 to 43%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Effective nodules are formed on <i>Glycine max</i> cv. Peking (soybean), <i>Glycine soja</i> (wild soybean), <i>Vigna unguiculata</i> (cowpea), and <i>Cajunus cajan</i> (pigeon pea).</s><s>An ineffective symbiosis is formed on <i>Macroptilium atropurpureum</i> (siratro), <i>Macroptilium lathyroides</i> (phasey bean), <i>Sesbania cannahina</i>, <i>Vigna radiata</i> (mung bean), and United States cultivars of <i>Glycine max</i> (soybean). <i>Leucaena leucocephala</i> (Haole Koa), <i>Medicago sativa</i> (alfalfa), <i>Trifolium repens</i> (white clover), <i>Trifolium pratense</i> (red clover), <i>Astragalus sinicus</i> (milkvetch), and <i>Arachis hypogaea</i> (peanut) are pot nodulated.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>R. fredii</i> is strain USDA 205, a culture of which has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 35423.</s><s>This strain conforms to the above description of the species.</s><s>The levels of DNA hybridization with <i>R. meliloti</i> ATCC 9930<sup>T</sup> (T = type strain), <i>R. trifolii</i> ATCC 14480<sup>T</sup>, <i>R. phaseoli</i> ATCC 14482<sup>T</sup>, <i>R. leguminosarum</i> ATCC 10004<sup>T</sup>, and <i>B. japonicum</i> ATCC 10324<sup>T</sup> are 14, 18, 7, 5, and 8%, respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Within <i>R. fredii</i>, there appear to be two distinct subgroups which can be differentiated on the basis of DNA-DNA hybridization, acid production on YEM broth, kanamycin resistance, and serology.</s><s>As a result, we propose two new chemovars, <i>Rhizobium fredii</i> chemovar <i>fredii</i> chemovar nov. and <i>Rhizobium fredii</i> chemovar <i>siensis</i> chemovar nov.</s><s>Additional strains for which hybridization data are unavailable but serotyping has been done indicate that other serogroups exist (B.</s><s>Bohlool, personal communication) and may warrant additional chemovar designations.</s><s>These strains should be considered members of <i>R. fredii chemovar</i> unknown until more data are available.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>R. fredii</i> chemovar <i>fredii</i> is in accordance with the description of the species.</s><s>The strains of this chemovar are susceptible to kanamycin (20 μg/ml), do not reduce litmus, and produce a final pH of less than 6.1 in YEM broth after 4 days of incubation at 28°C.</s><s>The levels of DNA-DNA homology with strains USDA 205T (=ATCC 35423<sup>T</sup>) and USDA 201 are 91 to 96 and 24 to 63%, respectively.</s><s>Included in this chemovar are strains USDA 193 and USDA 206 and type strain USDA 205. <i>R. fredii</i> chemovar <i>siensis</i> is in accordance with the above description of the species and can be differentiated on the basis of kanamycin resistance (20 μg/ml), reduction of litmus, and a final pH in YEM broth of more than 6.1.</s><s>The levels of DNA-DNA homology with strains USDA 201 and USDA 205<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 35423<sup>T</sup>) are 95 and 24 to 53%, respectively.</s><s>Included in this chemovar are strain USDA 194 and the type strain of the chemovar, strain USDA 201.</s></p></content></protolog>