<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2830_nm.8085" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8085" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8085" rank="species">Flavobacterium frigidarium</organism><reference id="rid.2830"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Humphry</surname><given-names>D.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>George</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Black</surname><given-names>G.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cummings</surname><given-names>S.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flavobacterium frigidarium sp. nov., an aerobic, psychrophilic, xylanolytic and laminarinolytic bacterium from Antarctica</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1235</fpage><lpage>1243</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11491319</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Flavobacterium frigidarium</i></s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Flavobacterium frigidarium</i> (fri.gid.ar.i'um. L. n. <i>frigidarium</i> one who bathes in cold water)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Non-sporulating, non-motile rods, 0.8-2 μm long and 0.5-0.7 μm wide, with a thick capsule and pili.</s><s>Aerobic, psychrophilic, halotolerant, xylanolytic and laminarinolytic.</s><s>Gram-negative, non-flagellated and show no gliding motility.</s><s>Produces the bright yellow carotenoid pigment zeaxanthin.</s><s>Colonies on AOA are flat, round and entire.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA is 35 mol%.</s><s>Growth occurs on xylan at 0-24 °C; the minimum growth temperature on rich media is below 0 °C.</s><s>Grows at pH5.6-8.4, with an optimum of pH 7.5.</s><s>Grows in AOB containing 0-5% (w/v) NaCl, in XeMM containing 0-4% NaCl, and in LB broth containing 0-9% NaCl.</s><s>Grows on NA, TSA and seawater agar but not on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced, hydrogen sulphide is not produced under any conditions, and there is no indole production, no arginine dihydrolase, no urease, no DNase and no β-galactosidase.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin and gelatin.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer-negative.</s><s>Does not produce any acid or gas from glucose, fructose, xylose, mannitol or maltose.</s><s>No precipitate was produced on egg-yolk agar and no brown pigment was secreted on tyrosine agar.</s><s>Resistant to the following in LB agar:10 μg ampicillin ml<sup>-1</sup>, 200 μg neomycin ml<sup>-1</sup>, 1 mg kanamycin ml<sup>-1</sup>, 200 μg gentamicin ml<sup>-1</sup> and 200 μg streptomycin ml<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>Sensitive to 10 μg erythromycin ml<sup>-1</sup>, 50 μg chloramphenicol ml<sup>-1</sup>, 10 μg tetracycline ml<sup>-1</sup> and 10 μg rifampicin ml<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>The following antibiotic disks caused zones of inhibition of more than 8 mm on LB agar: 10 μg fusidic acid, 25 μg chloramphenicol, 10 μg tetracycline, 5 μg erythromycin and 25 μg ampicillin.</s><s>Disks of novobiocin (5 μg), penicillin G (1 IU), methicillin (10 μg) and streptomycin (10 μg) did not cause any growth inhibition.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic and utilizes xylan, laminarin, xylose, glucose, fructose, maltose, glycerol, tryptone, succinate, mannose, mannitol, gelatin and casein as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>Does not utilize CM-cellulose, pectin, starch, chitin, agar, acetate, phenyl-acetate, arabinose, N-acetylglucosamine, gluconate, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate, tyrosine, galactose, inositol, lactose, pyruvate, raffinose, ribose, sucrose or trehalose.</s><s>When grown up on NA, the substrates shown in Table 2 were or were not hydrolysed; when grown up on AOA, it additionally hydrolyses N-benzoyl-DL-arginine-2- naphthylamide and 6-Br-2-naphthyl-β-D-glucopyranoside.</s><s>Plasma membrane is composed of the following fatty acids: 3.66% branched C<sub>14</sub>; 1.6% C<sub>14</sub>; 8.8% iso-C<sub>15</sub>; 15.1% anteiso-C<sub>15</sub>; 2.2% branched C<sub>15</sub>:1; 4.9% C<sub>15</sub>; 1% C<sub>15</sub>:1; 8.9% iso-C<sub>16</sub>; 1.6% anteiso-C<sub>16</sub>; 1.4% branched C<sub>16</sub>:1; 3.1% C<sub>16</sub>; 43.5% C<sub>16</sub>:1<i>cis</i>; 3.13% unknown; 1% 16:0 2-OH and 1.7% 16:0 3-OH.</s><s>The single strain A2i<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 700810<sup>T</sup>=NCIMB 13737<sup>T</sup> type strain) was isolated from shallow-water Southern Ocean sediment recovered near Adelaide Island, Antarctica (67° 34' S, 68° 07' W).</s><s>The GenBank accession number for the 16S rDNA sequence of <i>Flavobacterium frigidarium</i> is AF162266.</s></p></content></protolog>