<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11588_nm.18623" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.18623" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.18623" rank="species">Staphylococcus massiliensis</organism><reference id="rid.11588"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Al Masalma</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Raoult</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roux</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Staphylococcus massiliensis sp. nov., isolated from a human brain abscess</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1066</fpage><lpage>1072</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.006486-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19666814</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Staphylococcus massiliensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Staphylococcus massiliensis</em> (mas.si.li.en′sis. L. masc. adj. <em>massiliensis</em> of Massilia, the old Roman name for Marseille, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, 0.5–0.8 μm in diameter, non-spore-forming, non-motile and occur singly, in pairs and in clusters.</s><s>Growth occurs preferentially in aerobic atmospheres.</s><s>After 48 h on 5 % sheep blood agar, colonies are white, glossy, circular, regular, bulged, non-haemolytic and 1–3 mm in diameter.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 25–45 °C, with optimum growth between 30 °C and 37 °C.</s><s>Grows at 37 °C in TSB containing 0–15 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Coagulase-negative, catalase-positive, oxidase-negative, novobiocin-susceptible and negative in tests for the presence of clumping factor.</s><s>Using API ZYM, activities of esterase (C4) and esterase lipase (C8) are weakly positive.</s><s>No activities for alkaline phosphatase, lipase (C14), acid phosphatase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylaminidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, cystine arylaminidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase are detected.</s><s>Using the API Rapid ID32 Staph system, reduction of nitrates is positive.</s><s>No activities for urease, arginine dihydrolase, ornithine decarboxylase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine arylamidase, alkaline phosphatase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase or <em>β</em>-glucuronidase.</s><s>Negative results for aesculin hydrolysis and acetoin production.</s><s>All reactions for fermentation of sugars are negative: d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, d-lactose, trehalose, d-mannitol, raffinose, d-ribose, cellobiose, d-sucrose, turanose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and l-arabinose.</s><s>Using API 50 CH after an incubation time of 48 h, acid is not produced from d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, maltose, d-lactose, sucrose, trehalose, d-xylose, melezitose, turanose, d-lyxose, d-ribose, d-mannose, glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin ferric citrate, salicin, cellobiose, d-melibiose, inulin, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate or potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Using the Biolog GP2 Microplate, the following tests are positive, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, d-ribose, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, l-lactic acid, pyruvic acid methyl ester, pyruvic acid, l-alanine, l-glutamic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, glycerol, adenosine and 2′-deoxyadenosine.</s><s>l-Arabinose and inosine are weakly positive.</s><s>l-Alaninamide is variable.</s><s>The following tests are negative: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, inulin, mannan, Tween 40, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-mannosamine, amygdalin, d-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, d-gluconic acid, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, 3-methyl d-glucose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, palatinose, d-psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, salicin, sedoheptulosan, d-sorbitol, stachyose, sucrose, d-tagatose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, d-xylose, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, lactamide, d-lactic acid methyl ester, d-malic acid, l-malic acid, succinic acid monomethyl ester, propionic acid, succinamic acid, succinic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, d-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, glycyl l-glutamic acid, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, thymidine, uridine, adenosine 5′-monophosphate, thymidine 5′-monophosphate, uridine 5′-monophosphate, d-fructose 6-phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate, d-glucose 6-phosphate and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>The respiratory quinones are MK-7 (93 %) and MK-6 (7 %), and the major fatty acids are C<sub>15 : 0</sub> iso, C<sub>17 : 0</sub> iso, C<sub>15 : 0</sub> anteiso and C<sub>19 : 0</sub> iso.</s><s>The peptidoglycan type is A3<em>α</em> l-Lys-Gly<sub>2-3</sub>–l-Ser-Gly.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 5402776<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 55927<sup>T</sup>=CSUR P23<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a human brain abscess.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain was 36.6 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>