<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6852_nm.4613" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4613" rank="order">Mycoplasmatales</organism><reference id="rid.6852"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tully</surname><given-names>J.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bové</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Laigret</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Whitcomb</surname><given-names>R.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Revised taxonomy of the class Mollicutes: proposed elevation of a monophyletic cluster of arthropod-associated mollicutes to ordinal rank (Entomoplasmatales ord. nov.), with provision for familial rank to separate species with nonhelical morphology (Entomoplasmataceae fam. nov.) from helical species (Spiroplasmataceae), and emended descriptions of the order Mycoplasmatales, family Mycoplasmataceae.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>378</fpage><lpage>385</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Mycoplasmatales</i> (Edward and Freundt 1967) Razin and Freundt 1984.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The characteristics of the order are as described for the family . The classification proposed herein permits mollicute taxonomy to be in close accord with phylogenetic concepts. Such a classification is highly desirable, since schemes that do not take phylogeny into account often encounter serious difficulties. Such difficulties surfaced in recent descriptions of new nonhelical mollicutes, in that insect- or plant-derived strains with the ability to grow without sterols, but in the presence of 0.04% Tween 80, were referred, of necessity, to the genus Acholeplasma. When the phylogenetic studies of Weisburg and colleagues (49) had been completed, it was evident that the insect and plant strains of non-sterolrequiring organisms belonged to an entirely different phylogenetic cluster than classic acholeplasmas. It therefore came as no surprise that the insect and plant organisms differed from classical acholeplasmas not only in their ability to grow in Tween 80-supplemented media but also in their genome sizes, in their usage of the UGA codon, and in their possession of a component (enzyme 11) of a phosphoenolpyruvate- dependent sugar transport system. Transfer of these organisms from Acholeplasma was therefore clearly mandated (15).</s></p></content></protolog>