<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3461_nm.6130" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6130" rank="genus">Leifsonia</organism><reference id="rid.3461"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Evtushenko</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dorofeeva</surname><given-names>L.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Subbotin</surname><given-names>S.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cole</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tiedje</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Leifsonia poae gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from nematode galls on Poa annua, and reclassification of 'Corynebacterium aquaticum' Leifson 1962 as Leifsonia aquatica (ex Leifson 1962) gen. nov., nom. rev., comb. nov. and Clavibacter xyli Davis et al. 1984 with two subspecies as Leifsonia xyli (Davis et al. 1984) gen. nov., comb. nov.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>371</fpage><lpage>380</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10826825</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Leifsonia</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Leifsonia</i> (Leif.so'ni.a. M.L. fem. n. <i>Leifsonia</i> named after Einar Leifson, who isolated and described the first organism of this genus)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The colonies are yellow or white, circular, somewhat convex, glistening, opaque and butyrous.</s><s>The cells are Gram-positive, non-spore-forming, irregular rods or filaments which usually fragment into shorter rods or coccoid elements.</s><s>Primary branching occurs in young cultures of some species.</s><s>Usually motile.</s><s>Non-acidfast.</s><s>Mesophilic.</s><s>Obligately aerobic.</s><s>Catalase-positive.</s><s>Oxidase test is variable among species.</s><s>Cell wall peptidoglycan of B-type contains glycine, glutamic acid, DAB and alanine in a molar ratio close to 1:1:2:1; both isomers, L-DAB and D-DAB, are usually present in almost equal proportions.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-11; MK-10 is present.</s><s>Cell wall sugars consist of a predominant amount of rhamnose and minor amounts of glucose, galactose and mannose; some species contain fucose.</s><s>Cell wall teichoic acids and mycolic acids are not present.</s><s>The principal phospholipids are phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>Among fatty acids, anteiso-15:0, anteiso-17:0 and iso-16:0 predominate.</s><s>Concentrations of polyamines are low; putrescine is the predominant compound.</s><s>The DNA G+­C content ranges from 66.0 to 73 mol%.</s><s>Some species distinguished by tolerance to antibiotics.</s><s>Forms a coherent phylogenetic cluster attached to the branch of <i>Agromyces</i> spp.</s><s>The type species of this genus is <i>Leifsonia aquatica</i>.</s><s>The genus description is based on the data cited above and obtained in this study.</s></p></content></protolog>