<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12495_nm.21336" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21336" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21336" rank="species">Myroides marinus</organism><reference id="rid.12495"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>S.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chae</surname><given-names>S.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.-T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Myroides marinus sp. nov., a member of the family Flavobacteriaceae, isolated from seawater</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>938</fpage><lpage>941</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.024067-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20495024</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Myroides marinus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Myroides marinus</em> (ma.ri′nus. L. masc. adj. <em>marinus</em> of the sea, marine).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, non-spore-forming, non-motile, short rods (0.6–1.0 µm long and 0.2–0.3 µm wide).</s><s>Colonies are yellowish orange, circular and convex with entire margins on MA.</s><s>The optimal temperature for growth is 30 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–37 °C but not at 4 or 42 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is pH 5–9, and optimal growth occurs at pH 6–7.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–5 % (w/v) NaCl within 7 days.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-6.</s><s>The major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH and a summed feature comprising iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer test is positive.</s><s>Citrate is utilized.</s><s>Indole is produced weakly.</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite are not reduced, and hydrogen sulphide is not produced.</s><s>Hydrolyses DNA and Tweens 40 and 60, but not casein, cellulose, starch or Tweens 20 or 80.</s><s>Acid is not produced from amygdalin, arabinose, glucose, inositol, mannitol, melibiose, rhamnose, sorbitol or sucrose.</s><s>As determined from API ZYM and API 20E strips, positive for alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, gelatinase and urease activities, but negative for lipase (C14), α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucosidase, α-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase, α-fucosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and tryptophan deaminase.</s><s>In Biolog GN2 microplates, the following compounds exhibit positive reactions: Tweens 40 and 80, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, α-hydroxybutyric acid, γ-hydroxybutyric acid, α-ketobutyric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, propionic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-leucine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, inosine, uridine and 2,3-butanediol.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 34.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, JS-08<sup>T</sup> ( = KCTC 23023<sup>T</sup>  = JCM 16529<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from seawater collected off Boryeong Province, Chungnam, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>