<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.327_nm.5003" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5003" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5003" rank="species">Bacillus vallismortis</organism><reference id="rid.327"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Roberts</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakamura</surname><given-names>L.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cohan</surname><given-names>F.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus vallismortis sp. nov., a close relative of Bacillus subtilis, isolated from soil in Death Valley, California.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>470</fpage><lpage>475</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-2-470</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8934905</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus vallismortis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus vallismortis</i> (val.lis.mor'tis. L. n. <i>vallis</i>, valley; L. fem. n. mom, death; M. L. gen. fem. n. <i>vallismortis</i>, of Death Valley)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Vegetative cells are bacilli that are 0.8 to 1.0 μm wide by 2.0 to 4.0 μm long (as determined by measurements obtained from photomicrographs) and occur singly and in short chains.</s><s>Motile.</s><s>Gram positive.</s><s>Forms ellipsoidal spores centrally and paracentrally in unswollen sporangia.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Agar colonies are opaque, smooth, circular, entire, and 1.0 to 2.0 mm in diameter after incubation for 2 days at 28°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase and oxidase are produced.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Acetylmethylcarbinol is produced.</s><s>The pH in Voges-Proskauer broth after 2 days ranges from 5.4 to 5.7.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Starch and casein are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Citrate is utilized, but propionate is not utilized.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide, indole, and dihydroxyacetone are not produced.</s><s>Egg yolk lecithin and urea are not decomposed.</s><s>Tween 80 is decomposed.</s><s>The pH in litmus milk is alkaline; casein is digested.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Phenylalanine and tyrosine are not decomposed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid but no gas is produced from L-arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, glucose, galactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, L-rhamnose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, and xylose.</s><s>Lactose and melibiose are not fermented.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimum growth temperature ranges from 28 to 30°C, the maximum growth temperature is about 50°C, and the minimum growth temperature ranges from 5 to 10°C.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 5.7 and in the presence of 10% NaCl.</s><s>Inhibited by 0.001% lysozyme.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The thermal denaturation temperature for DNA of the type strain is 86.9°C, and the G+C content determined from this value is 43 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description given above is virtually identical to the descriptions of <i>B. atrophaeus</i>, <i>B. mojavensis</i>, and <i>B. subtilis</i>. <i>B. vallismortis</i> can be differentiated from these previously described species by DNA reassociation data, by data from restriction digestion analyses of selected genes, and by fatty acid analysis data.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from desert soil.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain DV1-F-3, which has been deposited in the Agricultural Research Service Culture Collection as strain NRRL B-14890.</s></p></content></protolog>