<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6280_nm.8352" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8352" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8352" rank="subspecies">Fusobacterium nucleatum vincentii</organism><reference id="rid.6280"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dzink</surname><given-names>J.A.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sheenan</surname><given-names>M.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Socransky</surname><given-names>S.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of three subspecies of Fusobacterium nucleatum Knorr 1922: Fusobacterium nucleatum subsp. nucleatum subsp. nov., comb. nov.; Fusobacterium nucleatum subsp. polymorphum subsp. nov., nom. rev., comb. nov.; and Fusobacterium nucleatum subsp. vincentii subsp. nov., nom. rev., comb. nov.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>74</fpage><lpage>78</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-1-74</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2223601</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Fusobacterium nucleatum</i> subsp. <i>vincentii</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Fusobacterium nucleatum</i> subsp. <i>vincentii</i> (vin. cen'. ti. i. L. gen. n. <i>vincentii</i>, of Vincent, referring to H. Vincent who studied the organism originally isolated from Vincent’s angina and necrotizing ulcerative gingivitis)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>F. nucleatum</i> subsp. <i>vincentii</i> is strain ATCC 49256.</s><s>The proposed subspecies of <i>F. nucleatum</i> can be differentiated by SDS-PAGE patterns and DNA-DNA hybridization.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Phenotypic features.</s><s>The phenotypic features of 340 strains of <i>F. nucleatum</i> isolated from subgingival sites of healthy patients and periodontally involved patients, as well as strains from the American Type Culture Collection, were examined and were confirmed as <i>F. nucleatum</i> by using conventional phenotypic criteria (14, 23).</s><s>All of the strains were anaerobic, gram-negative, nonmotile, tapered rods and displayed either an irregular or flecked appearance on the surface of blood agar.</s><s>Carbohydrate fermentations were negative, with the exception of a few isolates which demonstrated weak acid production (decrease of 0.5 to 1.0 pH unit) from fructose, glucose, and sucrose.</s><s>Indole was produced by all strains.</s><s>Acid end products from broth cultures (with or without glucose) included major amounts of butyrate (&#x003C;10 meq/liter), with lesser amounts of propionate and acetate.</s><s>Subgroups within the species could not be distinguished on the basis of phenotypic characteristics.</s></p><p class="description"><s>PAGE protein patterns.</s><s>In accord with the findings of other workers (1, 21, 25), there was considerable heterogeneity in the protein profiles detected by the conventional silver stain, making grouping of strains difficult.</s><s>In our hands, the Gelcode stain was more useful for grouping isolates because of its ability to color the various proteins or other macromolecules.</s><s>After we examined the Gelcodestained protein profiles of all of the isolates, it became apparent that distinct marker bands were present in certain strains and absent from others.</s><s>A number of these marker bands were yellow, possibly denoting the presence of lipoproteins (26).</s><s>The most obvious banding pattern, and the distinguishing marker of group I, was an intense yellow band at 22,600±500 daltons (Fig. 1).</s><s>In contrast, group III strains exhibited a series of yellow bands, a doublet at 43,100±900 and 40,800±200 daltons and single bands at 32,700±1,000, 27,700±1,200, and 19,700±600 daltons, but no band at 22,600 daltons.</s><s>Group II strains did not exhibit bands at 32,700, 27,700, or 22,600 daltons.</s><s>While the marker bands were consistent within each group, heterogeneity was observed in the positions of many of the remaining bands of the groups.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Of 340 fresh isolates, 187 were assigned to group I, 34 were assigned to group 11, and 102 were assigned to group 111.</s><s>Strains ATCC 25586<sup>T</sup> and ATCC 23726 exhibited the banding pattern of group II, and strain ATCC 10953<sup>T</sup> exhibited the banding pattern of group 111.</s><s>However, there were strains which exhibited different banding patterns and could not be placed into any of the three groups.</s><s>These included <i>F. periodonticum</i> ATCC 33693<sup>T</sup> and <i>F. simiae</i> ATCC 33568<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The 17 unclassified fresh isolates of <i>F. nucleatum</i> might represent additional groups.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA-DNA hybridization.</s><s>The levels of DNA-DNA hybridization of DNAs isolated from the same strains on different occasions averaged 102.0±5.8%.</s><s>A cluster analysis of the complete data matrix of five cultures from the American Type Culture Collection and seven fresh isolates of <i>F. nucleatum</i> is shown in Fig. 2.</s><s>The dendogram shows the percentages of similarity for the different strains.</s><s>A dashed vertical line was arbitrarily placed at 80% similarity.</s><s>Three clusters were formed.</s><s>The three strains exhibiting the PAGE group III profile clustered at &#x003E;85% similarity and included strain ATCC 10953<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>Four strains representing PAGE group II, including strains ATCC 25586<sup>T</sup> and ATCC 23726, clustered together at &#x003E;90% similarity.</s><s>Two strains of PAGE group I clustered at 80% similarity.</s><s>Three strains that did not fit into any PAGE group did not cluster with the other strains.</s><s>These included the strains of <i>F. periodonticum</i> and <i>F. simiae</i> and a fresh isolate of <i>F. nucleatum</i>, strain FD39.</s><s>It should be noted that within-group levels of homology were all &#x003E;80%, but levels of homology between groups were, with one exception, &#x003C;80%.</s><s>The percentages of similarity of <i>F. simiae</i> to strains EM48, ATCC 25586<sup>T</sup>, and ATCC 10953<sup>T</sup> were 70, 49, and 64%, respectively.</s><s>The percentages of similarity of <i>F. periodonticum</i> to strains EM48, ATCC 25585<sup>T</sup>, and ATCC 10953<sup>T</sup> were 60, 52, and 58%, respectively. <i>F. simiae</i> and <i>F. periodonticum</i> exhibited SDS-PAGE patterns that were distinct from those of the proposed subgroups of <i>F. nucleatum</i> and from each other.</s></p><p class="description"><s>There was 100% agreement between PAGE and DNA homology data when the DNAs of 137 fresh isolates were tested against each of the three central strains.</s><s>Of the 137 isolates, 74 were classified as group I, 26 were classified as group 11, and 37 were classified as group III.</s><s>The mean percentages of similarity and ranges were as follows: group I, 84 and 73 to 98%; group II,91 and 82 to 106%; and group III, 85 and 78 to 95%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In this investigation, the difficulty in separating subgroups on the basis of phenotypic traits or SDS-PAGE patterns with conventional silver staining was confirmed.</s><s>However, the use of SDS-PAGE with a polychromatic silver stain and DNA hybridization techniques allowed a robust subgroup ing.</s><s>Because DNA hybridization is not practical for subgrouping large numbers of fresh isolates, the PAGE method provides a practical means of assigning strains to groups.</s><s>Perhaps more rapid methods will be devised for distinguishing subgroups, such as hemagglutination (7, 8, 10), enzyme markers (11), or cloned (J.</s><s>M.</s><s>DeRienzo, personal communication) or oligonucleotide DNA probes (B.</s><s>J.</s><s>Paster and F.</s><s>E.</s><s>Dewhirst, personal communication; G.</s><s>L.</s><s>F.</s><s>Smith et al., J.</s><s>Dent.</s><s>Res. 68:241, 1989).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Investigators have recognized the heterogeneity among isolates of <i>F. nucleatum</i> but have had difficulty in developing methods to identify subgroups in this species reliably.</s><s>Variations observed in numerous morphological, biochemical, and serological characteristics and in DNA relatedness have confounded the separation of this species into subgroups.</s><s>Indeed, the level of relatedness of strains within this species has been reported to be as low as 30% and as high as 100% (25; Selin and Johnson, J.</s><s>Dent.</s><s>Res. 60:415, 1981), depending upon the methodology used.</s><s>In this study, interstrain DNA-DNA hybridization values ranged from 50 to loo%, which was in good agreement with the findings of other workers.</s><s>DNA homology studies indicate that strains of the same species usually exhibit more than 70% DNA relatedness (32).</s><s>Based upon the report of Wayne et al. (31) and the fact that the levels of relatedness in the majority of hybridizations in this study and other studies were &#x003E;70%, it seems tenable to place strains identified conventionally as <i>F. nucleatum</i> into one species.</s><s>However, the detection of <i>F. nucleatum</i> subgroups in this study with 40% similarity between groups suggests the existence of subspecies.</s><s>The hybridization data also suggest that <i>F. simiae</i> and <i>F. periodonticum</i> may represent additional subspecies of <i>F. nucleatum</i>.</s><s>However, more strains of these species should be examined to confirm or refute this suggestion.</s></p></content></protolog>