<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1320_nm.7944" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7944" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7944" rank="species">Bacteroides corporis</organism><reference id="rid.1320"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Holdeman</surname><given-names>L.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacteroides intermedius comb. nov. and description of Bacteroides corporis sp. nov. and Bacteroides levii sp. nov.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>15</fpage><lpage>25</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacteroides corporis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacteroides corporis</i> (cor'po.ris. L. gen.n. <i>corporis</i> of the body; pertaining to the isolation of this organism from human clinical specimens).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells in glucose broth cultures are 0.9 to 1.6 by 1.6 to 4 μm and occur singly, in pairs, and in short chains.</s><s>In many cultures the cells are coccoid.</s><s>Occasionally, longer cells (up to 11 μm) are observed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Surface colonies on anaerobic blood agar plates are minute to 1 mm in diameter, circular, entire, convex, and (after 48 to 72 h) buff with brown edges.</s><s>Dark brown colonies developed after 4 to 7 days.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Glucose broth cultures are turbid, often with a smooth or ropy sediment that tend to adhere to the bottom of the tube, and have a final pH of 4.8 to 5.1.</s><s>Addition of 10% (vol/vol) serum enhances growth and fermentation of some strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major fermentation acids detected in cultures of the type strain grown in broth medium containing 1% peptone, 1% yeast extract, 1% glucose, vitamin K, and hemin are (in milliequivalents per 100 ml of culture): succinic, 4; acetic, 2.</s><s>Isobutyric acid (0.1 to 0.4 meq/100 ml) and isovaleric acid (0.1 to 0.4 meq/100 ml) also are detected.</s><s>No hydrogen is detected in the headspace gas.</s><s>Similar products are obtained with other strains.</s><s>Neither lactate nor pyruvate is used; threonine is not converted to propionate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Hemin and vitamin K are required for growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Of six strains tested, two are resistant to penicillin G (2 U/ml), one is resistant to tetracycline (6 μg/ml), and two is resistant to both penicillin G and tetracycline.</s><s>All six strains are susceptible to chloramphenicol (12 μg/ml) and clindamycin (1.6 μg/ml).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Other characteristics of the species are given in Table 5.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains of this species have been isolated from various types of human clinical specimens.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 43 to 46 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is ATCC 33547<sup>T</sup> (= VPI 9342 = Lambe 532-70A).</s></p></content></protolog>