<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12534_nm.21392" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21392" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21392" rank="species">Streptococcus lactarius</organism><reference id="rid.12534"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Martín</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mañes-Lázaro</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Miguel Rodríguez</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Maldonado-Barragán</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptococcus lactarius sp. nov., isolated from breast milk of healthy women</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1048</fpage><lpage>1052</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.021642-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20511454</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptococcus lactarius</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptococcus lactarius</em> (lac.ta′ri.us. L. masc. adj. <em>lactarius</em> of or belonging to milk, referring to the isolation of the first strains from human breast milk).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive after staining and are non-motile, non-spore-forming cocci, 1.0–1.3 µm in diameter, occurring as pairs or short chains.</s><s>Colonies on Columbia sheep- or horse-blood agar plates after 2 days of incubation are about 0.3–0.5 mm in diameter, circular, flat, greyish, non-pigmented and α-haemolytic.</s><s>Grows under aerobic or anaerobic conditions but, under anaerobic conditions, haemolysis is visible only when the plates have been taken out of the anaerobic chamber for more than 1 h.</s><s>Hydrolyses hippurate.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer-negative.</s><s>Exhibits the following enzyme activities: arginine dihydrolase, β-glucosidase, alkaline phosphatase, alanine phenylalanine proline arylamidase and glycyl tryptophan arylamidase.</s><s>Lacks β-glucuronidase, α-galactosidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase and β-mannosidase activities.</s><s>β-Galactosidase activity is detected using <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl β-d-galactopyranoside as the substrate, but not with 2-naphthyl β-d-galactopyranoside.</s><s>Positive for aesculin hydrolysis.</s><s>Acid is produced from lactose, maltose and sucrose, but not from ribose, mannitol, sorbitol, trehalose, raffinose, glycogen, pullulan, melibiose, tagatose, melezitose, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cyclodextrin or methyl β-d-glucopyranoside.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, MV1<sup>T</sup> ( = CECT 7613<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 23027<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from breast milk of a healthy woman.</s></p></content></protolog>