<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7305_nm.2882" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2882" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2882" rank="species">Pseudoalteromonas bacteriolytica</organism><reference id="rid.7305"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sawabe</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Makino</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tatsumi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nakano</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tajima</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Iqbal</surname><given-names>M.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yumoto</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ezura</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudoalteromonas bacteriolytica sp. nov., a marine bacterium that is the causative agent of red spot disease of Laminaria japonica.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>769</fpage><lpage>774</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-3-769</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9734030</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudoalteromonas bacteriolytica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pseudoalteromonas bacteriolytica</i> (bac.te.rio.ly'ti.ca. Gr. n. <i>baktron</i> rod or staff; Gr. adj. <i>lytica</i> dissolving; M.L. fem. adj. <i>bacteriolytica</i> bacteria-dissolving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, strictly aerobic, polarly flagellated bacterium isolated from red-spotted culture beds of <i>Laminaria japonica</i>.</s><s>Cells are rod-shaped, with rounded ends, and are 0.6-0.9 µm in diameter and 1.9-2-5 µm long when the organism is grown on CSY-3 agar medium; the cells occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>No endospores or capsules are formed.</s><s>Peritrichous flagellation is not observed when the organism is cultivated on solid media.</s><s>Colonies on CSY-3 agar medium are red (although non-pigmented colonies frequently occurred), circular, and smooth and convex with entire edges.</s><s>Mesophilic and neutrophilic chemo-organotroph which grows at temperatures ranging from 15 to 35 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 37 °C.</s><s>Positive for acid production from glucose, hydrolysis of starch, Tween 80 and casein; weakly positive for catalase; positive for oxidase; assimilates D-mannose, D-fructose, sucrose, D-glucosamine, fumarate, succinate, D-glucose, D-galactose, acetate and propionate.</s><s>Negative for luminescence, production of fluorescein and pyocyanin; hydrolysis of agar, chitin and 7c-carrageenan; nitrate reduction; growth on KCN; accumulation of poly-β-hydroxybutyrate; assimilation of D-gluconate, N-acetylglucosamine, D-sorbitol, citrate, meso-erythritol, glycerol, DL-malate, α-ketoglutarate, m-hydroxybenzoate, melibiose, lactose, D-glucronate, xylose, putrescine, δ-aminovarate, γ-aminobutyrate, L-proline, aconitate (Table 2).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 44-46mol%.</s><s>The type strain is IAM 14595<sup>T</sup> (Table 1).</s></p></content></protolog>