<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.901_nm.2784" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2784" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2784" rank="species">Alkanindiges illinoisensis</organism><reference id="rid.901"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bogan</surname><given-names>B.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sullivan</surname><given-names>W.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kayser</surname><given-names>K.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Derr</surname><given-names>K.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Aldrich</surname><given-names>H.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Paterek</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Alkanindiges illinoisensis gen. nov., sp. nov., an obligately hydrocarbonoclastic, aerobic squalane-degrading bacterium isolated from oilfield soils.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1389</fpage><lpage>1395</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02568-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">13130023</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Alkanindiges illinoisensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Alkanindiges illinoisensis</em> (il.li.nois.en′sis. N.L. gen. n. <em>illinoisensis</em> pertaining to Illinois, the state from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the properties described for the genus, cells are non-motile and catalase-positive.</s><s>Colonies formed on R2A agar in the absence of hydrocarbon are small and colourless to translucent cream-coloured.</s><s>Sugars are not hydrolysed and the isolate is non-haemolytic.</s><s>Substrates that support good growth include hexadecane, heptadecane, pristane, squalane and Tween surfactants.</s><s>Weak growth occurs on acetic acid; no other substrate in the Biolog test gave unequivocally positive growth.</s><s>Morphologically, cells occur as both spheres and short rods with dimensions of 0·9–1·6×1·5–2·5 μm.</s><s>Based on TEM observations of hydrocarbon-grown cells, plasma membrane, peptidoglycan and outer membrane structures are similar to those of Gram-negative strains, with an extensive layer of extracellular matrix often present.</s><s>During rapid growth on hydrocarbons (especially hexadecane), extensive accumulation of large intracellular inclusion bodies is observed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is GTI MVAB Hex1<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC PTA-4839<sup>T</sup>=DSM 15370<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>