<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9240_nm.14503" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14503" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14503" rank="species">Parasutterella excrementihominis</organism><reference id="rid.9240"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nagai</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Morotomi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sakon</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanaka</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Parasutterella excrementihominis gen. nov., sp. nov., a member of the family Alcaligenaceae isolated from human faeces</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1793</fpage><lpage>1797</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.002519-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19542131</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Parasutterella excrementihominis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Parasutterella excrementihominis</em> (ex.cre.men.ti.ho′mi.nis. L. n. <em>excrementum</em> excrement; L. n. <em>homo -inis</em> human being, man; N.L. gen. n. <em>excrementihominis</em> of faeces of a human).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of the species is as given for the genus above.</s><s>In addition, cells are approximately 0.4–1.1×0.9–2.6 μm in size.</s><s>After 3 days anaerobic incubation on anaerobe basal agar (pH 6.0) colonies are translucent, entire, circular, convex and pinpoint.</s><s>In the API test systems, positive for esterase (C4), arginine arylamidase and leucine arylamidase, weakly positive for acid phosphatase, alanine arylamidase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), glycine arylamidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, but negative for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, arginine dihydrolase, chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, 6-phospho-<em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, lipase (C4), <em>α</em>-mannosidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, proline arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, serine arylamidase, trypsin, tyrosine arylamidase and valine arylamidase.</s><s>The fatty acid profile of the type strain contains C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>t</em>, C<sub>18 : 0</sub> and unknown fatty acids (equivalent chain-lengths of 15.306 and 17.478).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 49.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIT 11859<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 21040<sup>T</sup> =JCM 15078<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from human faeces.</s></p></content></protolog>