<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6713_nm.5614" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5614" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5614" rank="species">Streptococcus canis</organism><reference id="rid.6713"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Devriese</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hommez</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kilpper-Bälz</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schleifer</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptococcus canis sp. nov.: a species of group G streptococci from animals.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>422</fpage><lpage>425</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-36-3-422</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptococcus canis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptococcus canis</i> (ca'nis. L.n. <i>canis</i> dog)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-positive cocci and occur in pairs or in chains.</s><s>Wide zones of β-hemolysis are produced.</s><s>CAMP factor negative.</s><s>Colonies are circular with entire edges.</s><s>A precipitate is formed in broth cultures.</s><s>Catalase negative.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Good growth occurs at 37°C.</s><s>Not resistant to 6.5% NaCl or 40% bile.</s><s>Negative for hippurate, fibrinolysin, tyrosine, starch hydrolysis, Voges-Proskauer, and pyrrolidonylarylamidase reactions.</s><s>Positive in L-aminopeptidase, alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, and arginine dehydrolase tests.</s><s>Most strains produce a β-galactosidase, but few strains are hyaluronidase and pglucuronidase positive.</s><s>Variable reactions in α-galactosidase tests.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No acid is produced from adonitol, amygdalin, L-arabhose, D-arabinose, D-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, D-fucose, L-fucose, β-gentiobiose, gluconate, 2-keto-gluconate, inositol, indin, D-lyxose, mannitol, α-methyl-D-mannoside, melezitose, melibiose, D-raffinose, rhamnose, sorbitol, L-sorbose, D-tagatose, D-turanose, xylitol, D-xylose, L-xylose, or β-methyl-xyloside.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid is produced from N-acetylglucosamine, D-fructose, galactose, D-glucose, maltose, D-mannose, ribose, salicine, starch, and sucrose.</s><s>A few strains are trehalose positive, and some weak acid reactions may occur with glycogen.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Peptidoglycan type: Lys-Thr-Gly.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA ranges from 39 to 40 mol%, as determined by the melting temperature method.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: skin, upper respiratory tracts, and genitals of dogs, cow udders, and probably also cats (22).</s><s>Strains from cats have not been studied in detail.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain DSM 20715 (= STR-T1).</s><s>This strain is hyaluronidase negative, α-galactosidase, pgalactosidase, α-methyl-glucoside, cellobiose, and lactose positive, and β-glucuronidase, 5-keto-gluconate, glycogen, and trehalose negative.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 39.5 mol%, as determined by the melting temperature method.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Other characters of the type strain are as given above.</s></p></content></protolog>