<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7186_nm.5784" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5784" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5784" rank="species">Actinomyces graevenitzii</organism><reference id="rid.7186"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Pascual Ramos</surname><given-names>C.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Alvarez</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Åkervall</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sjödén</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinomyces graevenitzii sp. nov., isolated from human clinical specimens.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>885</fpage><lpage>888</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-3-885</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9226924</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinomyces graevenitzii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinomyces graevenitzii</i> (N. L. gen. n. <i>gruevenitzii</i>, of Graevenitz, in honor of Alexander von Graevenitz, contemporary American microbiologist, for his many contributions to clinical microbiology)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight or slightly curved rods that exhibit some branching and have swollen ends.</s><s>Cells are gram positive, do not form spores, and are nonmotile.</s><s>Colonies on blood agar incubated in the presence of 5% CO<sub>2</sub> are nonpigmented, opaque, and approximately 0.2 mm in diameter after 24 h of incubation.</s><s>Colonies adhere to agar surfaces.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and catalase negative.</s><s>Lactic acid and succinic acid are the major end products of glucose metabolism.</s><s>Acid is produced from glycerol, galactose, fructose, inositol, N-acetylglucosamine, maltose, lactose, ribose, sucrose, D-tagatose, and 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Acid is not produced from erythritol, D-arabinose, D-xylose, L-xylose, β-methylxyloside, L-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, rnannitol, sorbitol, α-methyl-D-mannoside amethyl- D-glucoside, amygdalin, salicin, cellobiose, melibiose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, amidon, glycogen, xylitol, β-gentiobiose, D-fucose, L-fucose, D-arabitol, and L-arabitol.</s><s>Hippurate, esculin, and urea are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, phosphoamidase, β-galactosidase, and N-acetyl- β-glucosaminidase are produced.</s><s>Pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, lipase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, α-mannosidase, and α-fucosidase activities are not detected.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>12:0</sub> (3 to 4%), C<sub>14:0</sub> (10 to ll%), C<sub>16:0 ω9</sub> (4 to 5%), C<sub>16:0</sub> (38 to 40%), C<sub>18:0 ω9</sub> (28 to 30%), and C<sub>18:0</sub> (6 to 8%).</s><s>Isolated from human clinical specimens (mainly respiratory tract secretions).</s><s>Habitat is unknown.</s><s>The type strain is CCUG 27294.</s><s>The type strain has the characteristics of the species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nucleotide sequence accession number.</s><s>The 16s rRNA gene sequence of strain CCUG 27294<sup>T</sup> has been deposited in the GenBank database under accession no. Y09589.</s></p></content></protolog>