<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4569_nm.3845" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3845" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3845" rank="species">Helicobacter ganmani</organism><reference id="rid.4569"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Robertson</surname><given-names>B.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>O'Rourke</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>On</surname><given-names>S.L.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Helicobacter ganmani sp. nov., a urease-negative anaerobe isolated from the intestines of laboratory mice.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1881</fpage><lpage>1889</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11594622</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Helicobacter ganmani</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Helicobacter ganmani</i> (gan.man'i. N.L. gen. n. <i>ganmani</i> arbitrary name derived from <i>ganman</i> which, in the language of the Gadigal people, indigenous Australians who live in the Sydney Harbour area, means `snake finder'. Thus, `ganman' refers to the spiral or `snake-like' morphology and the fact that this organism was isolated from mice in Sydney, Australia, the home of the Gadigal people)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are curved to spiral rods (0.3x2.5 μm) with two turns per cell and have single, unsheathed flagella in a bipolar arrangement.</s><s>Single colonies are rarely seen and are &#x003C;1 mm in diameter, irregular, unpigmented and translucent, after 3-5 d growth on 5% horse blood agar.</s><s>Anaerobic; no growth obtained in microaerobic or aerobic conditions.</s><s>Pitting of the agar not observed.</s><s>All strains produce oxidase.</s><s>Weak catalase activity detected (2/7 strains).</s><s>Nitrate and triphenyltetrazolium chloride (TTC) reduced.</s><s>No urease, alkaline phosphatase, hippuricase or DNase activity detected.</s><s>Selenite not reduced.</s><s>Indoxyl acetate not hydrolysed.</s><s>Neither hydrogen sulphide nor acid from sugar fermentation produced in triple-sugar iron agar.</s><s>Non-haemolytic.</s><s>All strains grow anaerobically at 37 °C on Campylobacter charcoal-deoxycholate (CCD) agar, and on media containing 0.1% trimethylamine N-oxide (TMAO), 1.0 and 2.0%ox-bile, 0.04% TTC, 32 mg cephalothin l<sup>-1</sup>, 32 mg carbenicillin l<sup>-1</sup> (BA base), 64 mg cefoperazone l<sup>-1</sup> (BA base), 5-fluorouracil or 0.1% sodium fluoride.</s><s>No growth obtained anaerobically at room temperature (18-22 °C), 25 or 42 °C, on tyrosine or casein media, or on media containing 1.0% glycine, 2-4% NaCl, 32 mg nalidixic acid l<sup>-1</sup>, 0.0005% crystal violet, 0.1% janus green or 0.02% pyronin.</s><s>Growth on 0.032% methyl orange media (6/7 strains), minimal and 0.005% basic fuchsin media (5/7 strains) and 4 mgmetronidazole l<sup>-1</sup> (BA medium) (3/7 strains).</s><s>Strains do not always give reproducible results when tested for growth on MacConkey, 0.1% sodium deoxycholate or 0.02-0.05% safranin media.</s><s>Cells have been isolated from caeca, large bowels, small bowels and livers of mice.</s><s>The type strain is CMRI H02<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 43526<sup>T</sup>=CIP 106846<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>When a difference in phenotype was observed between strains, the description given above applies to the type strain, CMRI H02<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>