<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4256_nm.2035" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2035" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2035" rank="species">Azovibrio restrictus</organism><reference id="rid.4256"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Reinhold-Hurek</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hurek</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reassessment of the taxonomic structure of the diazotrophic genus Azoarcus sensu lato and description of three new genera and new species, Azovibrio restrictus gen. nov., sp. nov., Azospira oryzae gen. nov., sp. nov. and Azonexus fungiphilus gen. nov., sp. nov.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>649</fpage><lpage>659</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10758872</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Azovibrio restrictus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Azovibrio restrictus</i> (re'stric.tus. L. adv. <i>restrictus</i> limited, restricted, referring to the restricted spectrum of carbon sources used for growth)</s></p><p class="description"><s>On VM ethanol medium, colonies are opaque beige, smooth, convex with an entire margin; on Congo red medium, colonies are orange-red, shining with otherwise similar characteristics.</s><s>Grows weakly in presence of 2% NaCl.</s><s>Most strains grow at 40 °C.</s><s>No requirement for cobalamine.</s><s>In addition to those described for the genus, can use L-aspartate as sole carbon source, but not isovalerate or 3-hydroxybutyrate.</s><s>Source is surface-sterilized roots of gramineae such as Kallar grass [<i>Leptochloa fusca</i> (L.) Kunth] or rice (<i>Oryza sativa</i>), grown in the Punjab of Pakistan or Nepal, respectively, or resting stages (sclerotia) of a basidiomycete (Pakistan).</s><s>Type strain, S5b2<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 9099<sup>T</sup>), has a G+C content of 64.8 mol% and was isolated from Kallar grass roots.</s><s>It grows at 40 °C and on D(­+)-malate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Another strain of this genus is BS20-3.</s><s>Differs from <i>Azovibrio restrictus</i> by obligately microaerobic growth, thus colony growth is negligible.</s><s>Requires cobalamine.</s><s>L-Alanine, isovalerate, isobutyrate and 3-hydroxybutyrate, but not l-aspartate, serve as sole carbon sources in addition to those mentioned in the genus description.</s><s>Source: resting stages (sclerotia) of a basidiomycete (Pakistan).</s></p></content></protolog>