<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12752_nm.6313" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6313" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6333" rank="species">Mycobacterium abscessus</organism><reference id="rid.12752"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Leao</surname><given-names>S.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tortoli</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Euzéby</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garcia</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal that Mycobacterium massiliense and Mycobacterium bolletii be united and reclassified as Mycobacterium abscessus subsp. bolletii comb. nov., designation of Mycobacterium abscessus subsp. abscessus subsp. nov. and emended description of Mycobacterium abscessus</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2311</fpage><lpage>2313</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.023770-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21037035</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Mycobacterium abscessus</em> (Moore and Frerichs 1953) Kusunoki and Ezaki 1992</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mycobacterium abscessus</em> (abs.ces′sus. L. gen. n. <em>abscessus</em> of an abscess).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following properties are displayed in addition to those listed in the species description by Kusunoki &#x0026; Ezaki (1992): alkaline phosphatase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase and tolerance to 5 % (w/v) NaCl are present.</s><s>Colonies can be smooth and grow on 5 % sheep blood agar.</s><s>Several enzymic activities show within-species variability, such as urease, catalase at 68 °C, β-glucosidase and β-galactosidase.</s><s>More stable phenotypic characteristics are absence of growth at ≥42 °C, negative result for nitrate reduction and negative result for utilization of sodium citrate.</s><s>The mycolic acid pattern, displayed by using HPLC, is very similar to those of other related species, showing only minor differences and low discriminatory power (Leao <em>et al.</em>, 2009). <em>M. abscessus</em> has a single ribosomal operon (<em>rrn</em> operon) per genome (Domenech <em>et al.</em>, 1994; Leao <em>et al.</em>, 2009).</s><s>This species has two characteristic PRA-<em>hsp65</em> patterns: type 1, showing <em>Bst</em>EII (bp) (235, 210) and <em>Hae</em>III (bp) (145, 70, 60, 50), and type 2 with <em>Bst</em>EII (bp) (235, 210) and <em>Hae</em>III (bp) (200, 70, 60, 50).</s><s>The trait of 711 bp of the <em>rpoB</em> and the trait of 401 bp of the <em>hsp65</em> nucleotide sequences show up to 96.6 and 98.7 % within-species similarity, respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s><em>Mycobacterium abscessus</em> (Moore and Frerichs 1953) Kusunoki and Ezaki 1992 emend. Leao <em>et al.</em> (authorship reads Leao, Tortoli and Garcia) encompasses two subspecies: <em>Mycobacterium abscessus</em> subsp. <em>bolletii</em> (Adékambi <em>et al.</em> 2006a) Leao, Tortoli and Garcia, comb. nov., and <em>Mycobacterium abscessus</em> subsp. <em>abscessus</em> (Moore and Frerichs 1953) Kusunoki and Ezaki 1992, subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is Hauduroy L948<sup>T</sup> ( = TMC 1543<sup>T</sup>  = ATCC 19977<sup>T</sup>  = CCUG 20993<sup>T</sup>  = CIP 104536<sup>T</sup>  = DSM 44196<sup>T</sup>  = JCM 13569<sup>T</sup>  = NCTC 13031<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>