<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1231_nm.4172" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4172" rank="genus">Peptostreptococcus</organism><reference id="rid.1231"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ezaki</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamamoto</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ninomiya</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yabuuchi</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Peptococcus indolicus, Peptococcus asaccharolyticus, Peptococcus prevotii and Peptococcus magnus to the genus Peptostreptococcus and proposal of Peptostreptococcus tetradius sp. nov.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>683</fpage><lpage>698</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-4-683</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <i>Peptostreptococcus</i></s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Cells are spherical to ovoid and 0.3 to 1.8 μm in diameter and occur in pairs, masses, tetrads, or chains. Gram-positive. Strictly anaerobic. Usually nonhemolytic on sheep or rabbit blood agar. A few strains are hemolytic. Colonies are pinpoint to 2 mm in diameter, circular, smooth, and translucent. Peptone and amino acids can be used as major energy sources. Metabolic end products from PYG broth vary among species. Acidic products may include any of the following: acetic, butyric, isocaproic, lactic, propionic, isobutyric, and isovaleric acids. Catalase variable. Gas production in peptone-yeast extract and peptone-yeast extract-glucose media is variable. The saccharolytic activity of most species is negative or only weakly positive. Tween 80 enhances fermentation of carbohydrates by some species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from female genital tracts, feces, blood, and abscesses of various sites.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA ranges from 28 to 34 mol%, as determined by thermal denaturation (T<sub>m</sub>), except for <i>Peptostreptococcus productus</i>, whose G+C content is 45 mol% (T<sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <i>Peptostreptococcus anaerobes</i> (Natvig 1905) Kluyver and van Niel</s></p><p class="description"><s>1936.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition, the saccharolytic species <i>Peptostreptococcus parvulus</i> and <i>Peptostreptococcus products</i> have DNAs with G+C contents of 44 to 45 mol% (T<sub>m</sub>).</s><s>These G+C values are somewhat higher than the values for other species of <i>Peptostreptococcus</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Recently, <i>Peptostreptococcus parvenus</i> has been transferred to the genus <i>Streptococcus</i>, but the taxonomic position of <i>Peptostreptococcus productus</i> has not yet been evaluated in detail.</s></p></content></protolog>