<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2780_nm.5671" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5671" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5671" rank="species">Streptococcus pasteurianus</organism><reference id="rid.2780"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Poyart</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Quesne</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trieu-Cuot</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic dissection of the Streptococcus bovis group by analysis of manganese-dependent superoxide dismutase gene (sodA) sequences: reclassification of 'Streptococcus infantarius subsp. coli' as Streptococcus lutetiensis sp. nov. and of Streptococcus bovis biotype 11.2 as Streptococcus pasteurianus sp. nov.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1247</fpage><lpage>1255</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02044-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12148636</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptococcus pasteurianus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptococcus pasteurianus</i> (pas.teu'ri.an.us. N.L. n. <i>pasteurianus</i> of the Pasteur Institute, where the species was characterized)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains of this species have been characterized previously as belonging to <i>S. bovis</i> biotype II.2 (Farrow et al., 1984; Clarridge et al., 2001).</s><s>Cells are Gram-positive cocci that occur in pairs or short chains.</s><s>They are non-motile, non-sporulating, catalase-negative and facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Most strains show homogeneous growth in BHI and glucose broths after 18 h incubation at 37 °C.</s><s>Growth also occurs in MRS broth without gas production.</s><s>No growth occurs in 6.5% NaCl broth.</s><s>Colonies on blood agar or nutrient agar are circular, smooth, entire and non-pigmented.</s><s>α-Haemolytic on blood agar.</s><s>Characteristics useful in the differentiation of streptococci related to <i>S. pastereurianus</i> are listed in Table 3.</s><s>The type strain of <i>Streptococcus pasteurianus</i> (NEM 1202<sup>T</sup>=CIP 107122<sup>T</sup>) is a human isolate responsible for meningitis and was isolated from the cerebrospinal fluid of an infant.</s><s>The five other strains of this species were isolated from human specimen cultures (cerebrospinal fluid, n=; blood, n=3; urine, n=1).</s><s>Some other characteristics for <i>S. pasteurianus</i> can be found in Clarridge et al. (2001) and Schlegel et al. (2000).</s></p></content></protolog>