<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7441_nm.7782" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7782" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7782" rank="species">Parachlamydia acanthamoebae</organism><reference id="rid.7441"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Everett</surname><given-names>K.D.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bush</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Andersen</surname><given-names>A.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended description of the order Chlamydiales, proposal of Parachlamydiaceae fam. nov. and Simkaniaceae fam. nov., each containing one monotypic genus, revised taxonomy of the family Chlamydiaceae, including a new genus and five new species, and standards for the identification of organisms.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>415</fpage><lpage>440</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-2-415</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10319462</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Parachlamydia acanthamoebae</i> sp. nov. '<i>Candidatus</i> Parachlamydia acanthamoebae' Amann, Springer, Schbnhuber, Ludwig, Schmid, Muller and Michel 1997</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Parachlamydia acanthamoebae</i> (acan.tha.moe'bae. M.L. gen. sing. n. of <i>Acanthamoeba</i> taxonomic name of a genus of <i>Acanthamoebidae</i>; of (living in) members of the genus <i>Acanthamoeba</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Parachlamydia acanthamoebae</i> sp. nov. currently includes the type strain Bn<sub>9</sub><sup>T</sup> (=ATCC VR 1476<sup>T</sup>), isolate Berg<sub>17</sub>, and several unnamed isolates (Amann et al., 1997; Birtles et al., 1997; Michel et al., 1994).</s><s>The 16s rRNA and rDNA of <i>Parachlamydia acanthamoebae</i> can be specifically detected with oligonucleotide probe Bn<sub>9</sub>658: 5' TCCGTTTTCTCCGCCTAC 3'.</s><s>Trophozoites of <i>Acanthamoeba</i> hosting these strains were isolated from humans in an outbreak of humidifier fever in Vermont USA ('Hall's coccus') and also from asymptomatic women in Germany.</s><s>In Nova Scotia, four patients whose sera recognized Hall's coccus did not show serological cross-reaction with antigens from the <i>Chlamydiaceae</i> (Birtles et al., 1997).</s></p></content></protolog>