<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12127_nm.20123" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20123" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20123" rank="species">Flavobacterium glycines</organism><reference id="rid.12127"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Madhaiyan</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Poonguzhali</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sundaram</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flavobacterium glycines sp. nov., a facultative
methylotroph isolated from the rhizosphere of
soybean</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2187</fpage><lpage>2192</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.014019-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19897620</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Flavobacterium glycines</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Flavobacterium glycines</em> (gly.ci′nes. N.L. n. <em>Glycine</em> a botanical genus name; N.L. gen. n. <em>glycines</em> of <em>Glycine max</em>, from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-staining-negative rods, 0.2–0.3 μm in diameter and 0.8–1.0 μm in length (see Supplementary Fig. S1 in IJSEM Online), that are motile by gliding.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–35 °C (optimum, 28 °C), at pH 6–8 and in the presence of 0–1 % NaCl.</s><s>Grows optimally on R2A medium without the addition of NaCl; growth is severely inhibited on R2A medium containing &#x003E;1 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs on AMS, R2A, trypticase soy and nutrient agars, but not on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Colonies are yellow, convex and circular with regular margins.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Starch and casein are degraded, but gelatin, CM-cellulose, pectin, chitin, aesculin, tyrosine and egg yolk are not.</s><s>Congo red is not absorbed by colonies.</s><s>Flexirubin and carotenoid pigments are produced.</s><s>Tolerates up to 2 mM NiCl<sub>2</sub> and 0.5 mM CdCl<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Methanol, ethanol, succinate and dichloromethane are utilized as sole carbon sources, but methylamine, trimethylamine, diethanolamine, formaldehyde, dimethylamine and methane are not.</s><s>Utilizes ammonium chloride, ACC, potassium nitrate, ammonium sulfate, sodium nitrate, l-glutamine, glycine and potassium thiocyanate as sole nitrogen sources, but not l-alanine, l-glutamate, urea, l-aspartate, l-tryptophan, methylamine, diethylamine, diphenylamine or potassium cyanate.</s><s>Positive for nitrate reduction and <em>β</em>-galactosidase activity, but negative for glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase and urease activities, and aesculin and gelatin hydrolysis (API 20NE).</s><s>In the same gallery, assimilates l-arabinose, d-mannose and maltose, but not d-glucose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid, trisodium citrate or phenylacetic acid.</s><s>In the API ZYM gallery, positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase C4 (weak), esterase lipase C8 (weak), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase (weak), naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase (weak) and <em>β</em>-galactosidase activities, but negative for lipase C14, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase activities.</s><s>The type strain is highly resistant (up to 500 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) to spectinomycin, ampicillin, carbenicillin, nalidixic acid, bacitracin, cefotaxime, chloramphenicol, penicillin G, polymyxin B, novobiocin, vancomycin, doxycyclin, rifampicin, cephalosporin and trimethoprim, but sensitive to tetracycline (500 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), gentamicin (300 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>), kanamycin (300 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>) and erythromycin (500 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>).</s><s>The following substrates are utilized in the GN2 microplate system: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannose, melibiose, d-psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, dl-lactic acid and l-glutamic acid.</s><s>All other substrates in the GN2 microplate system are not utilized.</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is MK-6.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, summed feature 3 (comprising iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 3-OH and anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 35.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Gm-149<sup>T</sup> (=ICMP 17618<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 105008<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the rhizosphere of field-grown soybean in Tamilnadu, India.</s></p></content></protolog>