<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.800_nm.4600" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4600" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4600" rank="species">Halonatronum saccharophilum</organism><reference id="rid.800"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhilina</surname><given-names>T.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garnova</surname><given-names>E.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tourova</surname><given-names>T.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kostrikina</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zavarzin</surname><given-names>G.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halonatronum saccharophilum gen. nov. sp. nov.: a new haloalkaliphilic bacterium of the order Haloanaerobiales from Lake Magadi.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>70</volume><fpage>77</fpage><lpage>85</lpage><source id="130">Mikrobiologiia</source><issn>0026-3656</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11338841</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Halonatronum saccharophilum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Halonatronum saccharophilum</i> (Sac.cha.ro.philum. From Gr. n. <i>sacchar</i>, sugar and Gr. adj. <i>philus</i>, liking. A sugar-liking organism.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Slender flexible rods, 0.4–0.6 × 3.5−10 μm in young cultures; long thickened degenerate cells, spheroplasts, and spores are characteristic of aging cultures.</s><s>Spores are round, terminal, thermostable, of the plectridial type.</s><s>The cell wall is characterized by a gram-negative structural pattern.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A moderate haloalkaliphile obligatorily requiring sodium chloride and carbonate and growing within the NaCl concentration range of 3–17% with an optimum at 7–12% and at pH 7.7–10.3 with a pH optimum of 8.0–8.5.</s><s>A moderate thermophile growing at 18–60°C with an optimum within the broad temperature range of 36–55°C.</s><s>The doubling time is 2.5 h under optimum conditions.</s></p><p class="description"><s>An obligate anaerobe with the fermentative type of metabolism.</s><s>Ferments glucose, fructose, sucrose, maltose, starch, glycogen, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, and, to a slight degree, peptone and yeast extract.</s><s>A chemoorganotroph whose metabolism requires yeast extract or amino acids.</s><s>Formate, ethanol, acetate, H<sub>2</sub>, and CO<sub>2</sub> form as glucose fermentation products.</s><s>Uses sulfur as electron acceptor in a process that yields no energy.</s><s>Sulfide-tolerant.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of DNA is 34.3 mol %.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from the bottom deposits of the coastal lagoon of Lake Magadi (Kenya).</s><s>Z-7986<sup>T</sup> (=DSM13868, =Uniqem 211) is the type strain of the species.</s></p></content></protolog>