<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9565_nm.14740" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14740" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14740" rank="species">Alicyclobacillus aeris</organism><reference id="rid.9565"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Guo</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>You</surname><given-names>X.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>L.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>J.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>S.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>C.-Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Alicyclobacillus aeris sp. nov., a novel ferrous- and sulfur-oxidizing bacterium isolated from a copper mine</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2415</fpage><lpage>2420</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008870-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19622665</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Alicyclobacillus aeris</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Alicyclobacillus aeris</em> (ae′ris. L. gen. neut. n. <em>aeris</em> of ore/copper).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rods with rounded ends (0.4–0.6×1.5–2.5 μm), stain Gram-positive or are Gram-variable, and are strictly aerobic, motile and endospore-forming.</s><s>Colonies on modified Norris broth are brown-centred with yellow–orange peripheries, circular, flat and entire with diameters of 0.3–0.5 mm after incubation for 5–6 days.</s><s>Colonies on BAM plates are creamy white, circular and entire with diameters of 0.5–1.0 mm after incubation for 3–5 days.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 25–35 °C; optimum growth temperature is 30 °C.</s><s>Optimum pH for growth is 3.5; growth occurs at pH 2.0–6.0.</s><s>Cells grow well in BAM medium containing 0–2 % (w/v) NaCl, but are inhibited by 3 % NaCl.</s><s>Oxidase, catalase and Voges–Proskauer reactions are negative.</s><s>Indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced.</s><s>Reduces nitrate.</s><s>Gelatin and aesculin are hydrolysed, but casein, starch and Tween 80 are not.</s><s>Leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase are positive; alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are absent.</s><s>Grows on the carbon sources peptone, starch, raffinose, d-galactose, d-glucose, l-arabinose and adipate, but not on d-glucitol, l-rhamnose, d-sorbose, d-mannose, maltose, sucrose, d-fructose, d-xylose, cellobiose, inulin, mannitol, phenylacetate or caprate.</s><s>Acid is produced from glycerol, erythritol, l-arabinose, ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, adonitol, galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, mannitol, sorbitol, aesculin, xylitol, fucose, arabitol and 5-ketogluconate, but not from d-arabinose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, l-sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, gluconate or 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>Can grow chemoautotrophically by using ferrous iron, elemental sulfur and K<sub>2</sub>S<sub>4</sub>O<sub>6</sub> as electron donors.</s><s>Major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is MK-7.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is ZJ-6<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 1.7072<sup>T</sup>=NBRC 104953<sup>T</sup>), isolated from Zi-Jin copper mine, Inner Mongolia, China.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 51.2 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>