<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8595_nm.13702" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13702" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13702" rank="species">Cohaesibacter gelatinilyticus</organism><reference id="rid.8595"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hwang</surname><given-names>C.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>B.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Cohaesibacter gelatinilyticus gen. nov., sp. nov., a marine bacterium that forms a distinct branch in the order Rhizobiales, and proposal of Cohaesibacteraceae fam. nov.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>267</fpage><lpage>277</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65016-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18175720</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Cohaesibacter gelatinilyticus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Cohaesibacter gelatinilyticus</em> (ge.la.ti.ni.ly′ti.cus. N.L. n. <em>gelatinum</em> gelatin; Gr. adj. <em>lutikos</em> able to dissolve; N.L. adj. <em>lyticus</em> dissolving; N.L. masc. adj. <em>gelatinilyticus</em> gelatin-dissolving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the characteristics reported for the genus, cells are weakly motile by a polar flagellum and approximately 0.2–0.4 μm wide and 1.0–3.0 μm long.</s><s>Reproduce by budding or binary fission or asymmetric division.</s><s>Rosette formation occurs.</s><s>Intracellular granules of poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate are formed.</s><s>No growth occurs on TSA, fivefold-diluted TSA, Czapek–Dox agar, MacConkey agar, blood agar or the above media supplemented with either 3 % (w/v) NaCl or 3 % (w/v) sea salts.</s><s>On MA or R2A agar supplemented with 3 % (w/v) NaCl, colonies are circular, entire, convex and creamy white in colour.</s><s>After incubation for 1 week at optimal growth conditions, colonies are approximately 2 mm in diameter.</s><s>Grows at temperatures in the range 15–31 °C (optimum, 25–30 °C) and at pH 6–9 (optimum pH 8).</s><s>Growth occurs with NaCl concentrations of 2–5 % (w/v, optimum 3 %).</s><s>Casein, cellulose, xanthine and hypoxanthine are decomposed.</s><s>Hydrolyses gelatin and aesculin.</s><s>Negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, arginine dihydrolase and urease.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase and trypsin activities are present, and esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-phosphohydrolase and <em>N-</em>acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase activities are weakly present.</s><s>Lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>Acid is produced from glycerol, dl-arabinose, d-ribose, dl-xylose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-lyxose, l-fucose, potassium gluconate and potassium 5-ketogluconate, but not from erythritol, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, d-cellobiose, maltose, d-lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, turanose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, dl-arabitol or potassium 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>Growth occurs on acetate, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, citrate, d-fructose, d-glucose, mannitol, d-mannose, ribose, sorbitol, glutamic acid, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-lysine, l-ornithine, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, polyethylene glycol, l-pyruvate, sodium succinate, sucrose, thiamine, Casamino acids, l-proline, peptone, tryptone and yeast extract.</s><s>No growth occurs on acetamide, benzoate, dl-cysteine, cellobiose, d-galactose, raffinose, salicin, trehalose, l-xylose, ethanol, formic acid, glycine, 2-propanol, d-lactose, l-arabinose, ascorbate, l-rhamnose, maleic acid, oxalic acid, salicylate, tartrate or urea.</s><s>Cells are sensitive to (μg per disc) gentamicin (6), cephalexin (20), vancomycin (20), mitomycin C (0.6), kanamycin (20), penicillin (6), erythromycin (10), chloramphenicol (20), ciprofloxacin (3) and ampicillin (6), but resistant to tetracycline (20), nalidixic acid (20) and streptomycin (6).</s><s>The fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (54.3–55.1 %) and C<sub>15 : 0</sub> iso 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (summed feature 3; 19.2–20.4 %), C<sub>20 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (9.6–11.1 %), C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (3.1–3.3 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 3-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub> iso I (3.0 %), C<sub>18 : 0</sub> 3-OH (1.9–2.0 %), C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> (1.1–1.5 %) and C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (1.1 %).</s><s>Other minor fatty acids (&#x003C;1 %) are C<sub>9 : 0</sub>, C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, C<sub>19 : 0</sub>, C<sub>20 : 0</sub>, C<sub>14 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em>, C<sub>19 : 0</sub> cyclo <em>ω</em>8<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>17 : 0</sub> iso 3-OH and C<sub>19 : 0</sub> 10-methyl.</s><s>In addition to the polar lipids listed in the genus description, minor amounts of an unidentified aminolipid (AL2) and unidentified lipids (L1–4) can be detected.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CL-GR15<sup>T</sup> (=KCCM 42319<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18289<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from coastal water of the east coast of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>