<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6705_nm.5174" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5174" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5174" rank="species">Brevibacillus invocatus</organism><reference id="rid.6705"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Forsyth</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lebbe</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goris</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heyndrickx</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Balcaen</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Verhelst</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ljungh</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hansson</surname><given-names>H.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Polyphasic identification of Bacillus and Brevibacillus strains from clinical, dairy and industrial specimens and proposal of Brevibacillus invocatus sp. nov.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>953</fpage><lpage>966</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02081-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12054263</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Brevibacillus invocatus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Brevibacillus invocatus</i> (in.vo.ca'tus ; M.L. adj. <i>invocatus</i>, uninvited, referring to the isolation of strains of this organism as contaminants of an industrial fermentation)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, motile, rod-shaped cells, 0.5-1.0 lm by 2.0-6.0 lm.</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>The ellipsoidal spores are borne subterminally, occasionally terminally, and swell the sporangia (Fig. 6).</s><s>Grows on routine media such as nutrient agar and trypticase soy agar.</s><s>Growth at 30 °C is initially slow, with more rapid growth following 24 h incubation; after 3-4 days the slightly umbonate colonies are 1.8 mm in diameter, with slightly irregular margins.</s><s>Colonies are brownishyellow, some with a single whitish concentric zone at the margin, and they are butyrous and have silky surfaces; the centres are opaque and the edges translucent.</s><s>Catalase-positive.</s><s>Nitrate reduction-negative.</s><s>Casein, gelatin, starch and urea are not hydrolysed and indole is not produced.</s><s>Growth temperatures range from 15 to 35 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs between pH 6.0 and 8.5.</s><s>Few carbohydrates are assimilated and acid is produced weakly, if at all, from them; amino acids and some organic acids are used as carbon sources.</s><s>The following carbon sources are assimilated in the API Biotype 100 System: L-glutamate, DL-3-hydroxybutyrate, 2-ketoglutarate, DL-lactate, D-mannitol, phenylacetate, L-proline, quinate, D-ribose and L-tyrosine and L-alanine.</s><s>Propionate and L-serine are usually assimilated.</s><s>Assimilation varies between strains for 2- keto-D-gluconate, L-rhamnose and succinate.</s><s>Aesculin hydrolysis varies between strains.</s><s>The following carbon sources are occasionally assimilated: adonitol, 4- aminobutyrate, L-aspartate, D-fructose, fumarate, D-galacturonate, DL-glycerate, L-malate, malonate, palatinose, D-trehalose and D-xylose.</s><s>The following substrates are not assimilated: N-acetyL-D-glucosamine, <i>cis</i>- and <i>trans</i>-aconitate, D-alanine, 5-aminovalerate, L-arabinose, D- and L-arabitol, benzoate, betain, caprate, caprylate, D-cellobiose, citrate, m-coumarate, dulcitol, i-erythritol, ethanolamine, L-fucose, D-galactose, β-gentiobiose, gentisate, D-glucose, D-glucosamine, D-gluconate, D-glucuronate, glutarate, glycerol, histamine, L-histidine, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, hydroxyquinoline-β-glucuronide, <i>myo</i>-inositol, itaconate, 5-keto-D-gluconate, α-lactose, lactulose, dlyxose, D-mannose, D-melezitose, 1-O-methyl-α-galactopyranoside, 1-O-methyl-β-galactopyranoside, 1-Omethyl-α-D-glucopyranoside, 1-O-methyl-β-D-glucopyranoside, 3-O-methyl-D-glucopyranose, D-malate, maltitol, maltose, maltotriose, D-melibiose, mucate, 3-phenylpropionate, protocatechuate, putrescine, D-raffinose, D-saccharate, D-sorbitol, L-sorbose, sucrose, D-tagatose, D- and L-tartrate, <i>meso</i>-tartrate, tricarballylate, trigonelline, tryptamine, L-tryptophan, D-turanose and xylitol.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acid components (accounting for more than 1% of the total fatty acid content) are, in descending order of content: anteiso-C15:0, iso-C15:0, iso-C14: 0, C16:1<i>ω</i>7<i>c</i> alcohol, iso-C16:0 and iso-C17:1<i>ω</i>10<i>c</i>.</s><s>The G+C content ranges from 49.7 mol% for the type strain to 49.1 for LMG 18167.</s><s>The type strain is LMG 18962<sup>T</sup> (=B2156<sup>T</sup>=CIP 106911<sup>T</sup>=NCIMB 13772<sup>T</sup>) and in the variable assimilation characters listed above it is positive for L-alanine, 2-keto-D-gluconate, propionate and L-serine, and negative for L-rhamnose, succinate and aesculin.</s></p></content></protolog>