<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6989_nm.6414" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6414" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6414" rank="species">Mycobacterium vanbaalenii</organism><reference id="rid.6989"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Khan</surname><given-names>A.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Paine</surname><given-names>D.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cerniglia</surname><given-names>C.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Classification of a polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbon-metabolizing bacterium, Mycobacterium sp. strain PYR-1, as Mycobacterium vanbaalenii sp. nov.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1997</fpage><lpage>2002</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02163-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12508859</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycobacterium vanbaalenii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycobacterium vanbaalenii</i> (van.baa'len.i.i. N.L. gen. n. <i>vanbaalenii</i> of Van Baalen, in memory of Dr Chase Van Baalen, late Professor at The University of Texas Marine Science Institute, Port Aransas Marine Laboratory, Port Aransas, TX, USA)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-positive, acid-fast rods (1.4 μm long and 0.7 μm wide).</s><s>Colonies are smooth and saffron yellow.</s><s>Catalase-and urease-positive, reduces nitrate to nitrite, metabolizes salicylic acid, hydrolyses Tween 80, reduces tellurite and utilizes pyrene, anthracene, fluoranthene, naphthalene, phenanthrene, 1-nitropyrene, 6-nitrochrysene, 3-methylcholanthene and benzo[a]pyrene.</s><s>Can grow well at 24 and 37 °C, with minimal or no growth at 42 °C.</s><s>Classified as a rapidly growing <i>Mycobacterium</i> species with a generation time of 2.7-4.0 h in MBS medium.</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Does not produce niacin and does not utilize glucose, xylose, lactose, Simmons' citrate, sucrose, maltose, adonitol, arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, galactose, malonate, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, sorbose, starch, trehalose, gelatin or aesculin.</s><s>Does not produce H<sub>2</sub>S and there is no reaction for the motility assay, aesculin hydrolysis, lysine decarboxylase, arginine dihydrolase or ornithine decarboxylase.</s><s>The type strain is strain PYR-1<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 7251<sup>T</sup>= NRRL B-24157<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>