<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2753_nm.10771" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10771" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10771" rank="species">Halomonas indalinina</organism><reference id="rid.2753"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cabrera</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Aguilera</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fuentes</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Incerti</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Russell</surname><given-names>N.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ramos-Cormenzana</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Monteoliva-Sánchez</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halomonas indalinina sp. nov., a moderately halophilic bacterium isolated from a solar saltern in Cabo de Gata, Almería, southern Spain</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>376</fpage><lpage>380</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64702-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17267982</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Halomonas indalinina</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Halomonas indalinina</em> (in.da.li.ni′na. N.L. n. <em>indalo</em> -<em>inis</em> a prehistoric magical symbol; L. suff. -<em>inus</em> -<em>a</em> -<em>um</em> suffix used in the sense of ‘belonging to’; N.L. fem. adj. <em>indalinina</em> pertaining to the Indalo, the symbol of the province of Almería, Spain, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight or slightly curved short rods 1.1–1.3×0.8 μm in size.</s><s>Cells stain Gram-negative and are motile by means of polar flagella.</s><s>Non-spore-forming.</s><s>On MH complex solid medium containing 7.5 % (w/v) total salts (mixture of sea salts), the bacteria grow in orange, flat/slightly convex, smooth and circular/slightly irregular colonies.</s><s>Moderately halophilic; growth occurs in total salts concentrations of 3–25 % (w/v), with optimum growth at 7.5–10 % (w/v).</s><s>No growth in the absence of salt.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–40 °C and at pH 5–9.</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Catalase is produced and gelatin and Tween 20 are hydrolysed.</s><s>Negative in tests for oxidase and indole and in methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests.</s><s>Casein, starch, aesculin, DNA, tyrosine and Tween 80 are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Phosphatase and phenylalanine deaminase are produced, but urease is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced from l-cysteine.</s><s>Acids are produced from l-arabinose, d-galactose and d-glucose, but not from d-cellobiose, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, d-salicin, sucrose, d-trehalose or d-xylose.</s><s>The following organic compounds are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: acetate, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, citrate, formate, d-fructose, fumarate, d-galactose, gluconate, d-glucose, lactate, lactose, malate, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, pyruvate and sucrose.</s><s><em>myo</em>-Inositol, propionate, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol and d-xylose are not utilized.</s><s>The following compounds are used as sole carbon, nitrogen and energy sources: l-arginine, isoleucine, l-lysine, l-serine and l-valine.</s><s>Alanine, l-histidine, l-ornithine and l-tryptophan are not utilized.</s><s>Susceptible to cefoxitin, chloramphenicol, neomycin, polymyxin B and rifampicin.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>19 : 0</sub> cyclo <em>ω</em>8<em>c</em> when cells are grown on MH medium containing 7.5 % (w/v) total salts.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 60.9 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CG2.1<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 5902<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23625<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a water sample from a solar saltern at Cabo de Gata, Almería, Spain.</s></p></content></protolog>