<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1343_nm.9887" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9887" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9887" rank="species">Thorsellia anophelis</organism><reference id="rid.1343"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lindh</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Terenius</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Haghdoost</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Faye</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thorsellia anophelis gen. nov., sp. nov., a new member of the Gammaproteobacteria</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>335</fpage><lpage>338</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63999-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16449435</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Thorsellia anophelis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Thorsellia anophelis</em> (a.no′phe.lis. N.L. gen. n. <em>anophelis</em> from a mosquito of the genus <em>Anopheles</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exhibits the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Slow growth occurs after 24 h incubation on tryptone soy agar and nutrient agar at 37 °C.</s><s>The fatty acid profile comprises C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (32·9 %), C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (35·9 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (12·2 %), C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (1·0 %), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH (0·8 %), summed feature 2 (C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 3-OH/iso I C<sub>16 : 1</sub>, 5·4 %) and summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>/iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH, 8·0 %).</s><s>The polar lipid profile contains moderate to minor amounts of two unknown aminophospholipids, an unknown phospholipid and two unknown polar lipids; when the organism is grown under strictly aerobic conditions, the quinone system consists exclusively of ubiquinone Q-8; the polyamine pattern consists of the predominant compound 1,3-diaminopropane [94·1 μmol (g dry weight)<sup>−1</sup>], spermidine [1·5 μmol (g dry weight)<sup>−1</sup>] and traces [&#x003C;1·0 μmol (g dry weight)<sup>−1</sup>] of putrescine and <em>sym</em>-homospermidine.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed.</s><s>Positive for acid production from glucose (O/F positive after 48 h incubation), lactose, sucrose, d-mannitol, dulcitol, salicin, adonitol, inositol, rhamnose, maltose, trehalose, cellobiose, d-arabitol and d-mannose.</s><s>No acid is produced from sorbitol, l-arabinose, raffinose, d-xylose, methyl d-glucoside, erythritol or melibiose.</s><s>The following carbon sources are utilized (only after prolonged incubation, 7 days): <em>p</em>-arbutin, d-gluconate, d-glucose, sucrose, d-trehalose, d-xylose, adonitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, maltitol, d-mannitol, acetate, propionate, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, <em>trans</em>-aconitate, adipate, fumarate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, dl-lactate, l-malate, mesaconate, pyruvate, l-alanine and l-leucine.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized as carbon sources: <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, salicin, d-sorbitol, putrescine, 4-aminobutyrate, azelate, citrate, glutarate, itaconate, oxoglutarate, suberate, <em>β</em>-alanine, l-aspartate, l-histidine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine, l-tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate and phenylacetate.</s><s>Negative for hydrolysis of <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl (pNP) <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>o</em>-nitrophenyl (oNP) <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucuronide, pNP <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, bis-pNP phosphate, pNP phenylphosphonate, pNP phosphorylcholine, 2-deoxythymidine-5′-pNP phosphate, l-alanine <em>p</em>-nitroanilide (pNA), l-glutamate-<em>γ</em>-3-carboxy pna and l-proline pNA.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CCUG 49520<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 108754<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the midgut contents of the mosquito <em>Anopheles arabiensis</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>