<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4652_nm.10339" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10339" rank="genus">Ketogulonigenium</organism><reference id="rid.4652"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>List Editor</surname><given-names /></person-name></authors><article-title>Notification that new names and new combinations have appeared in volume 51, part 3, of the IJSEM.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1231</fpage><lpage>1233</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11491318</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Ketogulonigenium</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Ketogulonigenium</i> (Ke.to.gu.lo.ni.ge'ni.um. N.L. n. <i>acidum ketogulonicum</i> ketogulonic acid; N.L. neut. suff. <i>genium</i> that which produces, N.L. neut. n. <i>Ketogulonigenium</i> that which produces ketogulonic acid)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, facultatively anaerobic, motile or nonmotile, ovoid to rod-shaped cells, 0.8-1.3 μm long, 0.5-0.7 μm in diameter, with tapered ends, occurring as single cells, pairs and occasionally short chains.</s><s>Some strains form elongated cells (up to 30 lm in length) on TSB.</s><s>Flagella and fimbrae have been observed.</s><s>Colonies are tan-coloured, smooth, circular, entire, raised to convex, 1-2 mm in diameter with a diffusible brown pigment after 48 h incubation.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase reactions are positive.</s><s>Optimum temperature range is 27-31 °C, optimum pH range is 7.2-8.5 and optimum Na<sup>+</sup> concentration is 117-459 mM.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>Carbon sources utilized include arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, glucose, glycerol, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, rhamnose, sorbitol, sorbose, sucrose, trehalose, pyruvate and succinate.</s><s>Favoured carbon sources are inositol, mannitol, glycerol, sorbitol, lactose and arabinose.</s><s>All strains examined produce 2-keto-L-gulonic acid from L-sorbose.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are 16:0 and 18:1 <i>ω</i>7<i>c</i>/<i>ω</i>9<i>t</i>/<i>ω</i>7<i>t</i> and the DNA G+­C content is 52.1-54.0%.</s><s>Small subunit rDNA sequence analysis places this genus in the α-subclass of the <i>Proteobacteria</i>.</s><s>All strains isolated in the present study originated in soil.</s><s>The DNA reassociation studies divide the genus into two species, <i>K. vulgare</i> and <i>K. robustum</i>, of which <i>K. vulgare</i> is the designated type species.</s></p></content></protolog>