<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8337_nm.13734" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13734" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13734" rank="species">Kushneria aurantia</organism><reference id="rid.8337"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sánchez-Porro</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>de la Haba</surname><given-names>R.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Soto-Ramírez</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Márquez</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Montalvo-Rodríguez</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of Kushneria aurantia gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel member of the family Halomonadaceae, and a proposal for reclassification of Halomonas marisflavi as Kushneria marisflavi comb. nov., of Halomonas indalinina as Kushneria indalinina comb. nov. and of Halomonas avicenniae as Kushneria avicenniae comb. nov.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>397</fpage><lpage>405</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.001461-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19196785</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Kushneria aurantia</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Kushneria aurantia</em> (au.ran′ti.a. N.L. adj. <em>aurantius</em> orange; N.L. fem. adj. <em>aurantia</em> orange-pigmented).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exhibits the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are 1.0×2.0–5.0 μm in size and occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>Does not produce exopolysaccharide and does not accumulate poly-hydroxyalkanoate.</s><s>Colonies on SW10 medium after 2 days incubation at 37 °C are 0.5–1.0 mm in diameter, circular, smooth, regular and convex with an entire margin, with an orange pigmentation.</s><s>Moderately halophilic, requires NaCl; grows at NaCl concentrations in the range 5–17.5 % (w/v), with an optimum at 10 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures of 20–40 °C (optimally at 37 °C) and at pH 5.5–8.5 (optimally at pH 7.0–8.0).</s><s>Respiration with fumarate, nitrate and nitrite is negative.</s><s>Gelatin and aesculin are hydrolysed.</s><s>Positive for methyl red, phosphatase and Simmons' citrate tests.</s><s>Starch, casein, Tween 80, tyrosine and DNA are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Negative for H<sub>2</sub>S production, Voges–Proskauer, indole production, nitrate and nitrite reduction, urease, arginine dihydrolase, phenylalanine deaminase, lysine decarboxylase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-maltosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and l-aspartic acid arylamidase but positive for ornithine decarboxylase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-glucuronidase.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, d-galactose, d-fructose, maltose, d-mannose and xylose, but not from arabinose, glycerol, mannitol, trehalose or sorbitol.</s><s>Does not grow on MacConkey agar with 10 % (w/v) salts.</s><s>The following compounds are used as sole carbon and energy sources: d-fructose, d-glucose, dl-malate, d-ribose, d-tartrate and d-xylose.</s><s>The following compounds are not used as sole carbon and energy sources: aesculin, benzoate, ethanol, fumarate, hippurate, d-lactose, melezitose, salicin and starch.</s><s>l-Cysteine is used as sole carbon, nitrogen and energy sources.</s><s>The following compounds are not used as sole carbons, nitrogen and energy sources: l-isoleucine, dl-lysine, l-methionine, l-tryptophan and l-valine.</s><s>The following compounds are used (oxidized) as sole carbon and energy sources (Biolog): dextrin, glycogen, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-psicose, d-sorbitol, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, d-galacturonic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, l-threonine, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>The following compounds are not used (oxidized) as sole carbon and energy sources (Biolog): <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, Tween 40, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-fucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, sebacic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl-glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, d-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate and <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate.</s><s>Resistant to (μg per disc, unless specified otherwise): bacitracin (10 U), cephalothin (30), erythromycin (15), kanamycin (30), nalidixic acid (30) and streptomycin (10).</s><s>Susceptible to chloramphenicol (30), novobiocin (30), penicillin G (10 U), polymyxin B (300 U), rifampicin (5), sulfamethazole/trimethoprim (23.75/1.25) and vancomycin (30).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 61.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, A10<sup>T</sup> (=CCM 7415<sup>T</sup>=CECT 7220<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the leaf surface of <em>A. germinans</em> (black mangrove).</s></p></content></protolog>