<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7437_nm.7098" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7098" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7098" rank="species">Streptomyces labedae</organism><reference id="rid.7437"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lacey</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nomenclature of Saccharopolyspora erythraea Labeda 1987 and Streptomyces erythreus, Waksman 1923 Waksman and Henrici 1948, and proposals for the alternative epithet Streptomyces labadae sp. nov.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>458</fpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-37-4-458</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptomyces labedae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces labedae</i> (la'bed'ae.;L. gen. n. <i>labedae</i>, named after D. P. Labeda, who first recorded the difference between the type strain and second reference strain of <i>Streptomyces erythraeus</i> designated by Waksman)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description given by Labeda (2) is as follows.</s><s>Substrate mycelium olive gray to dark reddish brown.</s><s>Aerial mycelium white to pinkish, especially on glycerol-asparagine or Czapek agars.</s><s>Spores are moderate gray on most media and reddish gray on glycerol-asparagine or Czapek agars.</s><s>Spore chains are in long, open spirals (<i>Spirales</i>).</s><s>The spore surface is spiny.</s><s>Melanin pigments are not produced on Czapek agar.</s><s>Glucose, xylose, rhamnose, fructose, galactose, mannitol, and inositol are assimilated as sole carbon sources; arabinose, salicin, and sucrose are assimilated moderately well; raffinose is poorly assimilated.</s><s>Wall chemotype I, with LL-diaminopimelic acid and glycine.</s><s>Isolated from soil.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain is NRRL B-5616 (ISP 5059, IMRU 3737, Sanchez-Marroquin A-24).</s></p></content></protolog>