<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8339_nm.13344" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13344" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13344" rank="species">Haloferula harenae</organism><reference id="rid.8339"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsuo</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Katsuta</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jang</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsuda</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Adachi</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kasai</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Haloferula rosea gen. nov., sp. nov., Haloferula harenae sp. nov., Haloferula phyci sp. nov., Haloferula helveola sp. nov. and Haloferula sargassicola sp. nov., five marine representatives of the family Verrucomicrobiaceae within the phylum 'Verrucomicrobia'.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2491</fpage><lpage>2500</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.2008/000711-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18984682</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Haloferula harenae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Haloferula harenae</em> (ha.re.na′e. L. gen. n. <em>harenae</em> from sand).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exhibits the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are 0.8–1.0 μm in width and 1.5–2.0 μm in length.</s><s>Neither cellular gliding movement nor swarming growth is observed.</s><s>Colonies grown on 1/5-strength MA are circular, convex and pink in colour.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 20–37 °C.</s><s>Optimal temperature for growth is 25–30 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs at either 4 or 45 °C.</s><s>pH range for growth is 6.0–9.0.</s><s>NaCl is required for growth and can be tolerated up to 5 % (w/v).</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase are positive, but esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C4), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are negative.</s><s>Dextrin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, d-glucose, d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannose, melibiose, d-psicose, raffinose, sucrose, trehalose, furanose, d-galacturonic acid, succinic acid and glycerol are oxidized, but Tween 80, glucose 6-phosphate, l-fucose, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, inosine, glucose 1-phosphate, cyclodextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, adonitol, d-arabitol, i-erythritol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, l-rhamnose, xylitol, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-amino butyric acid, urocanic acid, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate are not oxidized.</s><s>Cell wall peptidoglycan contains muramic acid and <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>Major fatty acid components (&#x003E;1.0 %) include C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 63.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, is YM23-227<sup>T</sup> (=MBIC08299<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 22198<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from marine sediment.</s></p></content></protolog>