<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10571_nm.17817" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17817" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3240" rank="species">Tatumella terrea</organism><reference id="rid.10571"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brady</surname><given-names>C.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Venter</surname><given-names>S.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cleenwerck</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandemeulebroecke</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coutinho</surname><given-names>T.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Pantoea citrea, Pantoea punctata and Pantoea terrea to the genus Tatumella emend. as Tatumella citrea comb. nov., Tatumella punctata comb. nov. and Tatumella terrea comb. nov. and description of Tatumella morbirosei sp. nov.</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>484</fpage><lpage>494</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.012070-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19654354</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Tatumella terrea</em> (Kageyama <em>et al.</em> 1992) comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Tatumella terrea</em> (ter′re.a. L. fem. adj. <em>terrea</em> of the earth).</s></p><p class="nomenclature"><s>Basonym: <em>Panteoa terrea</em> Kageyama <em>et al.</em> 1992.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, short rods (0.8–0.9×1.2–2.0 μm) occurring singly or in pairs, motile by means of one or two lateral flagella and non-spore-forming.</s><s>Colonies are pale beige to pale orange, round, convex and smooth with entire margins.</s><s>Nicotinic acid or nicotinamide is required for growth.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic, oxidase-negative, catalase-positive and glucose dehydrogenase, gluconate dehydrogenase and 2-ketogluconate dehydrogenase are produced.</s><s>Indole, urease, phenylalanine deaminase and arginine dihydrolase are negative.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, d-mannose, sucrose and trehalose, but not from starch, d-mannitol or raffinose.</s><s>The following carbon sources are utilized at 28 °C: <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, citrate, d-fructose, formic acid, d-galactose, d-gluconic acid, d-glucose, 5-ketogluconate, d-mannose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid and trehalose.</s><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized at 28 °C: <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, d-adonitol, l-alanine, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, betaine, cellobiose, dextrin, dulcitol, erythritol, l-fucose, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, D-glucuronic acid, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, glutarate, histidine, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, lactulose, maltose, maltotriose, melibiose, l-proline, propionate, quinic acid, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, l-serine, sucrose, l-tartrate and trigonelline.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 52.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SHS 2008<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 31628<sup>T</sup>=BD 877<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 30161<sup>T</sup>=CIP 105600<sup>T</sup>=DSM 13701<sup>T</sup>=JCM 8887<sup>T</sup>=LMG 22051<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil in Japan.</s></p></content></protolog>