<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4076_nm.4834" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4834" rank="family">Anaeroplasmataceae</organism><reference id="rid.4076"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Robinson</surname><given-names>I.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Freundt</surname><given-names>E.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal for an amended classification of anaerobic mollicutes.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>78</fpage><lpage>81</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-37-1-78</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Anaeroplasmataceae</i> fam. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Anaeroplasmataceae</i> (An.ae.ro.plas.ma.ta'ce.ae. M.L. neut. n. <i>Anaeroplasma</i> type genus of the family; aceae ending to denote a family; M.L. fem. pl. n. <i>Anaeroplasmataceae</i> the <i>Anaeroplasma</i> family)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells of young (16- to 18-h-old) cultures are coccoid and may be joined by short filaments; they pass membrane filters with average pore-size designations of 200 to 450 nm; older cells have a variety of pleomorphic forms.</s><s>Gram-negative and nonmotile.</s><s>Bounded by a single membrane, with no evidence of cell wall.</s><s>Obligately anaerobic; the inhibitory effect of oxygen on growth is not alleviated during repeated subculture.</s><s>Prereduced medium maintained in a system for exclusion of oxygen is required for culturing.</s><s>Optimum temperature, 37°C; optimum pH, 6.5 to 7.0.</s><s>Subsurface colonies are golden, irregular, and often multilobed.</s><s>Surface colonies present the “fried-egg” appearance characteristic of most mycoplasmas.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>Strains vary in their ability to ferment various carbohydrates; products of carbohydrate fermentation include acids (generally acetic, formic, propionic, lactic, and succinic), ethanol, and gases (primarily CO<sub>2</sub>, although some strains also produce H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>Arginine and urea are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Some members produce an extracellular enzyme that hydrolyzes the peptidoglycan layer of the bacterial cell wall, a characteristic that has not been reported for other mycoplasmas (15, 19).</s><s>The polar lipids of some species have been shown to contain plasmalogens (alk-l'enyl-glycerol ethers) which are commonly found in various anaerobic, but not in aerobic, bacteria.</s><s>The lipid composition of these species is otherwise simlar to that of facultatively anaerobic members of the <i>Mollicutes</i> (10).</s><s>All organisms currently classified in the family are found in the rumens of cattle and sheep.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Two genera are accepted in this family: <i>Anaeroplasma</i> Robinson, Allison, and Hartman 1975<sup>AL</sup> (16) (type genus) and <i>Asteroleplasma</i>.</s><s>Members of <i>Anaeroplasma</i> are characterized by requiring sterol for growth.</s><s>The DNA base composition is within the narrow range of approximately 29 to 34 mol% G + C (Bd).</s><s>Members of <i>Asteroleplasma</i> are distinguished by not requiring sterol for growth.</s><s>The G + C ratio of the DNA is approximately 40 mol% (<i>B<sub>d</sub></i>).</s><s>The genome size of both genera is about 1,000 megadaltons (1).</s></p></content></protolog>