<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4678_nm.4946" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4946" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4946" rank="species">Bacillus mucilaginosus</organism><reference id="rid.4678"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shelobolina</surname><given-names>E.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Avakyan</surname><given-names>Z.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bulygina</surname><given-names>E.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Turova</surname><given-names>T.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lysenko</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Osipov</surname><given-names>G.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Karavaiko</surname><given-names>G.I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Description of a new species of mucilaginous bacteria, Bacillus edaphicus sp. nov., and confirmation of the taxonomic status of Bacillus mucilaginosus Avakyan et al. 1986 based on data from phenotypic and genotypic analysis.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>66</volume><fpage>813</fpage><lpage>822</lpage><source id="130">Mikrobiologiia</source><issn>0026-3656</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Bacillus mucilaginosus</i></s></p><p class="etymology"><s>On potato agar, the colonies are light gray, smooth, even-edged, wet, and shiny; they do not exceeding 0.5 cm in diameter. On Ashby medium and synthetic medium with carbohydrates and ammonium nitrogen, colonies are convex, semitransparent, mucous, even-edged, of viscous consistency, 0.5-1 cm in diameter. No growth occurs on nutrient agar, nutrient broth, and nutrient gelatin. Cells are nonmotile regular rods with rounded ends, single, and surrounded by a capsule. The cell size is 1.0-1.2 x 4-7 μm. The cells are gram-positive by their wall structure, although Gram staining may yield varying results. The complete developmental cycle, culminating in sporulation, occurs during growth on potato agar and synthetic media with carbohydrates and ammonium nitrogen; no sporulation takes place on media devoid of a nitrogen source. The spores are oval, 1.0-1.2 x 1.7-2.0 μm in size. The location of spores is central or subterminal. The spore coat has 9 ridge-like protrusions. During sporulation, the cell becomes fusiform. Anteisopentadecanoic, palmitic, and stearic acids are most frequent in the cellular lipids. Cells are strictly aerobic, incapable of fermentation. Nitrates are not reduced under anaerobic conditions. Cells are catalase- and peroxidase-positive. Starch is hydrolyzed. Tyrosine is not decomposed. Gelatin is not liquefied. The temperature range suitable for growth is 10-45°C. Cells are resistant to lysozyme. Carbohydrates, polyols, and certain organic acids are utilized as the sources of carbon and energy. The G+C content of DNA is 55.8 mol %.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from clay.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is VKM B-1480D.</s></p></content></protolog>