<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6474_nm.10571" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10571" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6082" rank="species">Agromyces cerinus</organism><reference id="rid.6474"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zgurskaya</surname><given-names>H.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Evtushenko</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Akimov</surname><given-names>V.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Voyevoda</surname><given-names>H.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dobrovolskaya</surname><given-names>T.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lysak</surname><given-names>L.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kalakoutskii</surname><given-names>L.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emended description of the genus Agromyces and description of Agromyces cerinus subsp. cerinus sp. nov., subsp. nov., Agromyces cerinus subsp. nitratus sp. nov., subsp. nov., Agromyces fucosus subsp. fucosus sp. nov., subsp. nov., and Agromyces fucosus subsp. hippuratus sp. nov., subsp. nov.</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>635</fpage><lpage>641</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-42-4-635</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Agromyces cerinus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Agromyces cerinus</i> (ce.ri'nus. M.L. adj. <i>cerinus</i>, honey yellow)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Branching hyphae (width, 0.2 to 0.6 μm) break up into diphtheroid and rodlike, irregular, nonmotile fragments.</s><s>Colonies on peptone- yeast extract medium are opaque, entire, and convex and penetrate into the agar.</s><s>Produces a yellow carotenoid pigment.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In most strains the cell wall contains galactose, rhamnose, tyvelose, and xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Ammonium ions are usually assimilated as a sole N source.</s><s>Organic nitrogen is required for good growth of only some strains.</s><s>D-Arabinose, cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, inulin, maltose, D-mannose, melezitose, methyl-α-D-glucoside, methyl-β-D-glucoside, raffinose, L-rhamnose, salicin, sucrose, and trehalose are used as sole C sources.</s><s>Does not utilize dulcitol, i-erythritol, D-mannitol, methyl-β-D-arabinopyranoside, or sorbose as a sole C source.</s><s>Acids are produced from cellobiose, D-galactose, D-mannose, and L-rhamnose, and no acids are formed from L-arabinose, <i>meso</i>-inositol, melibiose, raffinose, sucrose, and D-xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Alkaline reactions occur with citrate, fumarate, α-ketoglutarate, and succinate, but aconitate, ascorbate, gluconate, salicylate, oxalate, tartrate, and usually formate are not utilized.</s><s>Arginine, methionine, norleucine, phenylalanine, threonine, tryptophan, tyrosine, and valine are not utilized as N sources.</s><s>Deamination of phenylalanine is negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Usually nitrate reduction does not occur.</s><s>The Voges-Proskauer test is negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Esculin and arbutin are hydrolyzed; casein, elastin, guanine, hypoxanthine, pectin, testosterone, Tween 21, Tween 60, Tween 80, and xanthine are not decomposed.</s><s>Tyrosine and Tween 40 are decomposed by most strains.</s><s>No growth occurs on media supplemented with 7% NaCl, 0.01% sodium azide, or 0.0175% potassium tellurite.</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin (10 μg/ml), bacitracin (10 μg/ml), erythromycin (15 μg/ml), kanamycin (30 μg/ml), neomycin (30 μg/ml), novobiocin (30 μg/ml), rifampin (5 μg/ml), tetracycline (30 μg/ml), and vancomycin (30 μg/ml) but resistant to clindamycin (2 μg/ml), nalidixic acid (30 μg/ml), and penicillin (10 μg/ml).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following tests are variable: utilization of L-arabinose, <i>meso</i>-inositol, and melibiose as sole C sources; acid production from D-fructose, D-glucose, lactose, maltose, D-mannitol, salicin, and trehalose; utilization of formate, transaconitate, or valerate; assimilation of asparagine, lysine, and serine as N sources; hydrolysis of hippurate and starch; susceptibility to gentamicin (10 μg/ml), rifampin (50 μg/ml), and streptomycin (10 μg/ml); and growth at 37°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 72 mol% (as determined by the <i>T<sub>m</sub></i> method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from soil.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>A. cerinus</i> is strain VKM Ac-1340.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description given above was based on seven strains.</s></p></content></protolog>