<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4321_nm.1205" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1205" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1477" rank="species">Blastomonas natatoria</organism><reference id="rid.4321"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hiraishi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kuraishi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kawahara</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emendation of the description of Blastomonas natatoria (Sly 1985) Sly and Cahill 1997 as an aerobic photosynthetic bacterium and reclassification of Erythromonas ursincola Yurkov et al. 1997 as Blastomonas ursincola comb. nov.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1113</fpage><lpage>1118</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10843052</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Blastomonas natatoria</i></s></p><p class="etymology"><s>The description of the species is the same as described for the genus. Additional properties are given as follows; the chemotaxonomic information is derived from the report of Sittig &#x0026; Hirsch (1992) and this study. Cells are ovoid or rod-shaped, 0.6-0.9 by 1.0-2.5 μm and reproduce by budding or asymmetric cell division. Colonies on complex media containing peptone and beef extract or yeast extract are circular, convex, smooth and opaque and grow to 2 mm within 1 week of incubation. Colour of colonies is yellow, orange or brown, depending upon the composition of growth media. Aerobic chemo-organotrophy is the preferred mode of growth. No chemolithotrophic growth with H<sub>2</sub>, sulfide or thiosulfate is found. Optimum temperature for growth is 30-35 °C. Optimum pH is 7.0-7.5. Growth occurs in the presence of 3% NaCl. No growth factors are required. Hydrolytic activities against aesculin, starch, gelatin, Tween 80 and DNA are present. Chitin, cellulose and casein are not hydrolysed. Urease, phenylalanine deaminase, indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not produced. Good growth occurs with d-xylose, maltose, pyruvate, glutamate, peptone or yeast extract as sole carbon sources. Other usable carbon sources are L-arabinose, D-glucose, acetate, propionate, butyrate, succinate, fumarate and Casamino acids. No or little growth occurs with dfructose, D-mannose, cellobiose, lactose, mannitol, sorbitol, lactate, methanol, propanol, formate, citrate, malate, phenylacetate, benzoate, dichlorophenol, dibenzofuran, dibenzo-<i>p</i>-dioxin or naphthalene. The major phospholipids are phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidyldimethylethanolamine and phosphatidylcholine. The genomic DNA G+C content is 64.8 mol% (HPLC method). Inhabits freshwater environments. The type strain is DSM 3183<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 35951<sup>T</sup>=ACM 2507<sup>T</sup>=NCIMB 12085<sup>T</sup>=IFO 15649<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>