<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9287_nm.14573" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14573" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14573" rank="species">Vibrio hangzhouensis</organism><reference id="rid.9287"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>X.-W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>Y.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>C.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oren</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vibrio hangzhouensis sp. nov., isolated from sediment of the East China Sea</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>2099</fpage><lpage>2103</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008698-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19605706</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Vibrio hangzhouensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Vibrio hangzhouensis</em> (hang.zhou.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>hangzhouensis</em> pertaining to Hangzhou, a city in eastern China, near where the sample from which the type strain was isolated was collected).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative rods, motile by means of polar flagella.</s><s>Cells are straight to slightly curved and rod-shaped (0.5–0.8 μm in width and 1.0–2.0 μm in length) with rounded ends.</s><s>No endospores are formed.</s><s>Colonies on MA are 1–2 mm in diameter, smooth and circular, with slightly irregular borders and non-pigmented after 48 h.</s><s>Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations of 0.5–7.5 % (w/v) with optimum growth with 3.0 %.</s><s>pH and temperature ranges for growth are pH 6.0–10.0 and 20–37 °C (optimum growth at pH 7.0–8.0 and 30 °C).</s><s>No growth is detected below 15 or above 42 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs on MacConkey agar (red colonies).</s><s>No growth occurs on Cetrimide agar.</s><s>Positive for oxidase and catalase.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite but not further to N<sub>2</sub>O or N<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Aesculin, gelatin, starch, Tween 20 and tyrosine are hydrolysed.</s><s>Agar, casein, DNA and Tween 80 are not hydrolysed.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced from thiosulfate or l-cysteine.</s><s>Glucose fermentation, indole production and <em>o</em>-nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-galactopyranosidase are positive.</s><s>Negative for arginine dihydrolase, lecithinase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, urease and Voges–Proskauer reaction.</s><s>The follow constitutive enzyme activities are detected in API ZYM tests: acid and alkaline phosphatases, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8) and naphthol-AS-<em>β</em>-1-phosphohydrolase. <em>N</em>-Acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidases, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-glucosidases, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, trypsin and valine arylamidase activities are not observed.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: acetate, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-aspartate, d-cellobiose, citrate, l-cysteine, d-fructose, fumarate, d-galactose, d-gluconate, glucose, l-glutamate, glycerol, glycine, l-glutamine, l-histidine, lactate, lactose, malate, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, l-ornithine, l-proline, propionate, pyruvate, ribose, l-serine, succinate, sucrose and d-trehalose.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: adonitol, l-arabinose, ethanol, formate, inositol, l-isoleucine, l-lysine, malonate, l-methionine, l-rhamnose, ribitol, l-sorbitol, sorbose, l-valine, xylitol and xylose.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-fructose, d-galactose, glucose, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, ribose, sucrose and trehalose.</s><s>Susceptible to chloramphenicol, erythromycin, nitrofurantoin, novobiocin and the vibriostatic agent O/129; not susceptible to ampicillin, bacitracin, carbenicillin, cefotaxime, kanamycin, nalidixic acid, neomycin, nystatin, polymyxin B, streptomycin and tetracycline.</s><s>Principal fatty acids (greater than 5 %) are C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>14 : 0</sub> and C<sub>12 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 44.9 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CN83<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 1.7062<sup>T</sup>=JCM 15146<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a marine sediment sample from Zhejiang, China.</s></p></content></protolog>