<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6689_nm.8717" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8717" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8717" rank="species">Mycobacterium houstonense</organism><reference id="rid.6689"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schinsky</surname><given-names>M.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Morey</surname><given-names>R.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Douglas</surname><given-names>M.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wilson</surname><given-names>R.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Floyd</surname><given-names>M.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Butler</surname><given-names>W.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Daneshvar</surname><given-names>M.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brown-Elliott</surname><given-names>B.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wallace</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McNeil</surname><given-names>M.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brown</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic variation in the Mycobacterium fortuitum third biovariant complex: description of Mycobacterium boenickei sp. nov., Mycobacterium houstonense sp. nov., Mycobacterium neworleansense sp. nov. and Mycobacterium brisbanense sp. nov. and recognition of Mycobacterium porcinum from human clinical isolates.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1653</fpage><lpage>1667</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02743-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15388725</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Mycobacterium houstonense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mycobacterium houstonense</em> [hous′ton.en.se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>houstonense</em> pertaining to Houston, TX, USA, where the first isolate of the <em>M. fortuitum</em> third biovariant (sorbitol-positive) was identified].</s></p><p class="description"><s>The organisms are acid-fast, Gram-positive, pleomorphic bacilli.</s><s>Long filamentous forms are often observed, but the organisms have no spores or capsules.</s><s>Both isolates, under low-power stereomicroscopic examination, show white to slightly beige, small-diameter (approx. 1 mm) colonies after incubation on heart infusion agar with 5 % (v/v) rabbit blood for 2 days at 35 °C.</s><s>Colonies are mucoid, convex, round and entire-edged and do not demonstrate aerial hyphae.</s><s>Both grow on Löwenstein–Jensen medium at 35 and 42 °C in less than 7 days and grow on 5 % NaCl and on MacConkey's agar without crystal violet at 28 °C.</s><s>Semi-quantitative catalase of both isolates is weakly reactive (&#x003C;45 mm).</s><s>Both have arylsulfatase activity by 3 days, utilize acetamide, reduce nitrate, exhibit iron uptake and produce urease and thermostable catalase.</s><s>Both are unable to utilize citrate or grow in lysozyme.</s><s>d-Fructose, d-glucose, i-<em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-sorbitol and d-trehalose are utilized as sole carbon sources, but adonitol, l-arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, i-erythritol, d-galactose, glycerol, lactose, maltose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, salicin, starch, sucrose and d-xylose are not utilized.</s><s>Acid is produced oxidatively from d-fructose, d-glucose, i-<em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-sorbitol and d-trehalose, but not from adonitol, l-arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, i-erythritol, d-galactose, glycerol, lactose, maltose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, salicin, starch, sucrose or d-xylose.</s><s>Both isolates are resistant to ampicillin, cefotaxime, ceftriaxone, doxycycline, erythromycin, minocycline and vancomycin, and both isolates are susceptible to amikacin, amoxycillin/clavulanate, ciprofloxacin, imipenem, sulfamethoxazole and trimethoprim/sulfamethoxazole.</s><s>The type strain has a DNA G+C content of 64 mol%.</s><s>The nearest phylogenetic neighbours, according to 16S rRNA gene sequence similarity, are <em>M. fortuitum</em> ATCC 6841<sup>T</sup> and <em>M. senegalense</em> ATCC 35796<sup>T</sup>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, which was isolated from a face wound, is W5198<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 49403<sup>T</sup>=DSM 44676<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>DNA relatedness among the strains in the species and their relatedness to other strains of <em>M. fortuitum</em> third biovariant complex and related species are available in IJSEM Online.</s></p></content></protolog>