<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9159_nm.14355" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14355" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14355" rank="species">Psychromonas agarivorans</organism><reference id="rid.9159"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hosoya</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jang</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yasumoto-Hirose</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsuda</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kasai</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Psychromonas agarivorans sp. nov., a novel agarolytic bacterium.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1262</fpage><lpage>1266</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.003244-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19502298</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Psychromonas agarivorans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Psychromonas agarivorans</em> (a.ga.ri.vo′rans. N.L. n. <em>agarum</em> agar; L. part. adj. <em>vorans</em> devouring, destroying; N.L. part. adj. <em>agarivorans</em> agar-devouring).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, facultatively anaerobic, rod-shaped, approximately 0.8–1.2 μm long and 0.5–0.8 μm wide.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of a subpolar flagellum.</s><s>Cytochrome oxidase-positive and catalase-negative.</s><s>Optimal growth temperature is 20–25 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 2 and 30 °C; no growth occurs at 37 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6.0–9.0.</s><s>Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations of 1–4 %.</s><s>Does not grow in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>Pitting of agar plates occurs and eventually the agar is liquefied.</s><s>Positive for degradation of DNA and aesculin.</s><s>Positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase.</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate (API 20E; bioMérieux).</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose by fermentation (API 20NE).</s><s>Acid is produced by oxidation from galactose, glucose, cellobiose and maltose (API 50 CH).</s><s>Hydrolysis of and acid production from starch is variable.</s><s>Does not decompose gelatin, Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80, tyrosine or urea.</s><s>Does not produce indole.</s><s>Negative for arginine dihydrolase, esterase (C4), lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosamidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Does not produce acid from glycerol, erythritol, dl-arabinose, ribose, dl-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, fructose, mannose, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, dl-fucose, dl-arabitol, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate or 5-ketogluconate (API 50 CH).</s><s>Assimilation of the following carbon sources is positive for glucose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, maltose, gluconate, dl-malate and citrate.</s><s>Assimilation is negative for n-capric acid, adipic acid and phenyl acetate (API 20NE).</s><s>Predominant fatty acids are 16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and 16 : 0.</s><s>The respiratory quinone is Q-8.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, J42-3A<sup>T</sup> (=NBRC 104585<sup>T</sup>=KCTC 22285<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from marine sediments collected at Kori, off Nomozaki, Nagasaki in Japan.</s><s>Strain 04OZ-AS15-7A (=NBRC 104632) is a reference strain.</s><s>The DNA G+C contents of the type strain and strain 04OZ-AS15-7A are 41–42 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>