<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7175_nm.2721" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2721" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2721" rank="species">Azotobacter salinestris</organism><reference id="rid.7175"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Page</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shivprasad</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Azotobacter salinestris sp. nov., a sodium-dependent, microaerophilic, and aeroadaptive nitrogen-fixing bacterium.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>369</fpage><lpage>376</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-41-3-369</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of Azotobacter salinestris sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Azotobacter salinestris (sal. in. es' tris. N. L. adj. <i>salinus</i>, saline; L. suff. -<i>estris</i>, belonging to, living in; N. L. adj. <i>salinestris</i>, living in saline environments)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The data below are summarized from this study and previous studies (24, 25, 27, 34) which have been conducted with type strain 184.</s><s>The type strain does not form appreciable capsule polysaccharide, whereas other isolates may form considerable amounts of capsule.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Young cells (18 h old) are elongated and oval with pointed ends (2 by 3 to 4 μm) and occur singly, in pairs, or chains of six to eight cells in actively growing cultures.</s><s>Motile by means of peritrichous flagella (Fig. 5).</s><s>Each flagellar filament has a wavelength of 2.7 to 2.9 μm and an amplitude of 0.36 to 0.55 μm and is 9 to 10 μm long.</s><s>Poly-β-hydroxybutyrate is formed.</s><s>Older cells are rounder, larger (diameter, 3 to 5 μm), pleomorphic, and nonmotile and form cysts.</s><s>Encystment is induced in young cultures by incubation with 0.2% β-hydroxybutyrate as the sole carbon source.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth in all media is Na<sup>+</sup> dependent.</s><s>Optimal growth is promoted by ≥1 mM NaCl.</s><s>Cells grow well in the presence of 0.25 mM Na<sup>+</sup> and 25 mM Li<sup>+</sup> or 25 mM Mg<sup>2+</sup>; 15 to 25 mM K<sup>+</sup> or 15 to 25 mM Rb<sup>+</sup> is antagonistic to growth.</s><s>Optimal growth requires &#x003E;5 μM soluble iron.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies develop on solid media after 2 to 3 days of incubation at 30°C.</s><s>Cells are killed by 100 μM H<sub>2</sub>O,.</s><s>Colonies are not formed in numbers proportional to the dilution of a culture because of the presence of toxic oxygen products in normal media.</s><s>Capsules are absent in the type strain, but may be formed by other isolates.</s><s>Colonies are brown to brownish black because of the production of a water-insoluble, cell-associated catechol melanin.</s><s>Water-soluble catechol formation precedes melanization.</s><s>Melanization is greatest in aerated, nitrogen-free medium and is promoted by trace amounts (0.25 μg/ml) of Cu<sup>+</sup> or Cu<sup>2+</sup>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrogen fixation is optimal with molybdate, but nitrogen is fixed by molybdate-starved cells in the presence of vanadate.</s><s>Nitrogen fixation is optimal at 35°C and minimal at 28°C.</s><s>Nitrogen-fixing growth in liquid medium is initially microaerophilic, but the cells can adapt to growth in vigorously aerated medium.</s><s>Cells inoculated at a low density into nitrogen-free medium or aerated vigorously before aeroadaptation do not grow.</s><s>NO<sub>3</sub><sup>-</sup> is assimilated without NO<sub>2</sub><sup>-</sup> or N<sub>2</sub> production.</s><s>Urease is produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase negative in the H<sub>2</sub><sub>2</sub> spot test.</s><s>A single, weakly active catalase electromorph is present, which migrates on nondenaturing polyacrylamide gels with the same relative mobility as beef liver catalase.</s><s>Multiple peroxidase electromorphs are present, and a single superoxide dismutase is present.</s><s>All of the enzyme activities are dependent on iron.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Optimal growth occurs at pH 7.2 to 7.5, and growth is limited at pH 6.2 and 8.2 (nitrogen fixing) or pH 9.0 (with ammonium acetate).</s><s>Acid is produced during aerobic or microaerophilic growth in a sodium-dependent manner.</s><s>Higher available NaCl concentrations promote greater acidification of the medium until a growth-inhibiting pH is attained.</s><s>The acid released by nitrogen-fixing cultures on agar-solidified medium containing 0.5 to 1.5% (wt/vol) NaCl is sufficient to solubilize CaCO<sub>3</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>An alkaline reaction is produced in marine broth alone, and an acid reaction is produced in marine broth containing glucose under oxidative or fermentative conditions.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains are very susceptible to streptomycin and kanamycin (inhibited by ≤1 μg/ml) and resistant to chloramphenicol (40 μg/ml).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The carbon substrates used for growth are the same as those described previously for <i>Azotobacter chroococcum</i>, including 0.25% sodium benzoate, 0.5 to ≥1.0% fructose, galactose, glucose, mannitol, melibiose, starch, and sucrose.</s><s>The substrates not used for growth include 0.5 to ≥1.0% arabinose, cellobiose, glutamate, glycerol, lactose, mannose, rhamnose, and xylose.</s><s>Acid is produced during incubation with the growth-promoting substrates fructose, galactose, glucose, mannitol, melibiose, and sucrose and with the non-growth-promoting substrates arabinose, cellobiose, lactose, mannose, rhamnose, and xylose.</s><s>Strains have been isolated from slightly saline, neutral to slightly alkaline soils from the Canadian provinces Alberta (type strain 184), Saskatchewan, British Columbia, and the Yukon and from a saline soil from Egypt.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content is 65.19 to 65.98 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain 184 is the type strain; this strain has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection, Rockville, Md., as strain ATCC 49674.</s></p></content></protolog>