<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3590_nm.14675" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14675" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14675" rank="species">Mycoplasma haemolamae</organism><reference id="rid.3590"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Messick</surname><given-names>J.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Walker</surname><given-names>P.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Raphael</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Berent</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shi</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>'Candidatus mycoplasma haemodidelphidis' sp. nov., 'Candidatus mycoplasma haemolamae' sp. nov. and Mycoplasma haemocanis comb. nov., haemotrophic parasites from a naturally infected opossum (Didelphis virginiana), alpaca (Lama pacos) and dog (Canis familiaris): phylogenetic and secondary structural relatedness of their 16S rRNA genes to other mycoplasmas.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>693</fpage><lpage>698</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.01861-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12054227</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of '<i>Candidatus</i> Mycoplasma haemolamae' sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>'<i>Candidatus</i> Mycoplasma haemolamae' (hae.mo.la'mae. Gr. neut. n. <i>haema</i> blood; L. fem. gen. n. <i>lamae</i> of the alpaca; N.L. fem. gen. n. <i>haemolamae</i> of alpaca blood. [(Mollicutes) NC; NA; O, wall-less;NAS (GenBank no. AF306346)])</s></p><p class="description"><s>Coccus- and ring-shaped basophilic organisms are present on red blood cells in Wright-Giemsa-stained peripheral blood smears.</s><s>Cells are 0.4-1.0 μm in diameter, causing only slightly deformation of the red blood cell membrane by scanning and transmission electron microscopy (McLaughlin et al., 1990; Reagan et al., 1990).</s><s>Multiple clinical problems have been reported in infected llamas including poorly to nonregenerative anaemia, inflammatory disease, hypoproteinaemia, chronic weight loss and failure to thrive.</s><s>Younger animals are more susceptible to acute infection, leading to anaemia and massive parasitaemia, especially when stressed or when they have concurrent disease.</s><s>In some cases, hypoglycermia is associated with the parasitaemia and may be profound (McLaughlin et al., 1990).</s><s>Based on sequence analysis of its 16S rRNA gene, `<i>Candidatus</i> M. haemolamae' is most closely related to <i>Mycoplasma wenyonii</i>, a parasite of cattle, and other haemotrophic mycoplasmas.</s></p></content></protolog>