<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6435_nm.11706" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11706" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5236" rank="subspecies">Staphylococcus capitis ureolyticus</organism><reference id="rid.6435"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bannerman</surname><given-names>T.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kloos</surname><given-names>W.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Staphylococcus capitis subsp. ureolyticus subsp. nov. from human skin.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>144</fpage><lpage>147</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-41-1-144</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1995030</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Staphylococcus capitis</i> subsp. <i>ureolyticus</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Staphylococcus capitis</i> subsp. <i>ureolyticus</i> (ur.e.o.ly'ti.cus. N. L. n. <i>urea</i>, urea; Gr. adj. <i>lyticus</i>, dissolving; N. L. adj. <i>ureolyticus</i>, urea dissolving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of <i>S. capitis</i> subsp. <i>ureolyticus</i> below is based on studies of 15 to 26 strains.</s><s>Cells are gram-positive cocci that are 0.8 to 1.0 predominantly in singles, pairs, and clusters.</s><s>Colonies on P agar (9) are usually raised, opaque, circular, and glossy and range in diameter from 4.3 to 7.1 mm (after incubation for 3 days at 35°C and for 2 days at 25°C); 73% have some delayed yellow pigmentation.</s><s>The colony surfaces of 75% of the strains are smooth; 25% of the strains have colonies with rough surfaces or a granular texture.</s><s>The colony edges are entire to slightly irregular.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Catalase is produced.</s><s>Oxidase is not produced.</s><s>Coagulase, clumping factor, heat-stable nuclease, alkaline phosphatase, ornithine decarboxylase, β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-galactosidase, and arginine arylamidase tests are negative.</s><s>Urease positive.</s><s>Arginine is utilized.</s><s>No esculin hydrolysis.</s><s>Acid is not produced aerobically from D-trehalose, D-xylose, D-cellobiose, L-arabinose, N-acetylglucosamine, and raffinose.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-mannose.</s><s>No anaerobic acid production from D-mannitol.</s><s>The variable characteristics of <i>S. capitis</i> subsp. <i>ureolyticus</i> are shown in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The strains from skin are mostly from heads, primarily ears and foreheads.</s><s>This habitat distribution is similar to that of <i>S. capitis</i> (9).</s><s>However, unlike <i>S. capitis</i>, during antibiotic use <i>S. capitis</i> subsp. <i>ureolyticus</i> increases its range of habitats to areas other than the head (5).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Fatty acid profile.</s><s>The results of a fatty acid analysis of <i>S. capitis</i> subsp. <i>ureolyticus</i> and closely related members of the <i>S. epidermidis</i> species group are shown in Table 3.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Compared with <i>S. capitis</i>, the new subspecies has a higher percentage of iso-C<sub>15:0</sub> fatty acid and a lower percentage of C<sub>20:0</sub> fatty acid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Antibiotic susceptibilities.</s><s>As determined by agar disk diffusion tests, the strains isolated from the skin of healthy human volunteers are susceptible to novobiocin, tetracycline, erythromycin, oxacillin, kanamycin, lincomycin, streptomycin, gentamicin, and chloramphenicol; 79% of the strains are resistant to penicillin G.</s><s>Of the clinical strains, 83% are resistant to penicillin G.</s><s>All strains except strain 5717-1 are susceptible to the same antibiotics as the isolates from healthy controls.</s><s>Strain 5717-1 shows resistance to penicillin G, lincomycin, and chloramphenicol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell wall peptidoglycan.</s><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan type is similar to that of <i>S. capitis</i> and <i>S. epidermidis</i> on the basis of the molar ratio of amino acids and is of the L-Lys-Gly<sub>3.6</sub>-Ser<sub>1.4</sub> type.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>S. capitis</i> subsp. <i>ureolyticus</i> is strain ATCC 49326 (= MAW 8436).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>The type strain has all of the uniform characteristics of the subspecies.</s><s>In addition, it has the properties described below.</s><s>Cells are spherical (diameter, 0.8 to 1.0 μm) and occur predominately in singles, pairs, and clusters.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Agar colonies are circular, raised, entire, 5.5 mm in diameter (after 5 days), smooth with glossy surfaces, and yellow pigmented.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrates are reduced to nitrites.</s><s>Acetylmethylcarbinol is produced.</s><s>Weak pyrrolidonyl arylamidase is produced.</s><s>Weak hemolysins are detected.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid is produced aerobically from D-mannitol, α-lactose, maltose, and sucrose.</s><s>Weak acid is produced aerobically from D-turanose.</s><s>No acid is produced aerobically from D-melezitose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Resistant to penicillin G.</s><s>There is variability within the strain with respect to resistance to tetracycline, lincomycin, and erythromycin; this variability is related to the presence or absence of specific plasmids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 38.8 mol%</s></p><p class="description"><s>Distinguishing characteristics.</s><s>According to the <i>International Code of Nomenclature of Bacteria</i> (13), <i>S. capitis</i> as described by Kloos and Schleifer (9) should be designated <i>S. capitis</i> subsp. cupitis.</s><s>The type strain is strain ATCC 27840<sup>T</sup>. <i>S. capitis</i> subsp. <i>ureolyticus</i> can be distinguished from <i>S. capitis</i> subsp. <i>capitis</i> primarily by its positive urease activity, its ability to produce acid aerobically from maltose, its fatty acid profile, its larger colony size, and its DNA relationship with <i>S. capitis</i> subsp. <i>capitis</i>.</s><s>The major features useful in distinguishing <i>S. capitis</i> subsp. <i>ureolyticus</i> from the closely related members of the <i>S. epidermidis</i> species group (2, 4, 9, 17) are summarized in Table 4.</s></p></content></protolog>