<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6851_nm.6705" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6705" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6705" rank="species">Amycolatopsis alba</organism><reference id="rid.6851"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mertz</surname><given-names>F.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yao</surname><given-names>R.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Amycolatopsis alba sp. nov., isolated from soil.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>715</fpage><lpage>720</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-4-715</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8240953</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Amycolatopsis alba</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Amycolatopsis alba</i> (A.my.co.la.top'sis. M.L. fem. n.; al'ba. L. fem. adj. <i>alba</i>, white, referring to the white aerial hyphae)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, nonmotile, not acid fast, gram positive, filamentous, and differentiated into substrate and aerial hyphae with a diameter of 1.0 μm.</s><s>The vegetative hyphae have a tendency to fragment when the organism is grown in liquid culture.</s><s>The aerial hyphae are white, and the vegetative mycelium is yellowish brown.</s><s>A faint soluble pigment is produced on some media.</s><s>Cylindrical, smooth spores are formed with a typical cobweb morphology.</s><s>Acid is produced from the following carbohydrates: D-arabinose, D-fructose, D-glucose, glycerol, D-mannose, D-ribose, and trehalose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from cellulose, dulcitol, ethanol, glycogen, inulin, melezitose, D-sorbitol, L-sorbose, and xylitol.</s><s>The following carbohydrates are utilized when ISP medium 9 is the basal medium: D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, inositol, D-mannitol, raffinose, salicin, and D-xylose.</s><s>L-Arabinose, L-rhamnose, and sucrose are not utilized.</s><s>Assimilates acetate, butyrate, formate, lactate, malate, propionate, pyruvate, and succinate, but not oxalate, mucate, and tartrate.</s><s>Strain A83850<sup>T</sup> utilizes allantoin, calcium malate, casein, elastin, hippurate, and L-tyrosine, but is not able to degrade adenine and guanine.</s><s>Skim milk is hydrolyzed but not peptonized.</s><s>Testosterone is very weakly hydrolyzed.</s><s>Catalase, esculinase, gelatinase, and H,S are produced.</s><s>Strain A83850<sup>T</sup> does not produce melanoid pigments and is not able to survive at 50°C for 8 h.</s><s>A83850<sup>T</sup> grows at temperatures between 15 and 37°C.</s><s>Strain A83850<sup>T</sup> conzhytains <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid and has a type A whole-cell sugar pattern and a type PII phospholipid pattern.</s><s>Mycolic acids are not present.</s><s>The major menaquinone detected is MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>); there is also a minor amount of MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>Strain A83850<sup>T</sup> differs from the other <i>Amycolatopsis</i> species in fatty acid composition (Table 4) and in morphological, cultural, and physiological characteristics (Table 2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>The type strain is A83850 (= NRRL 18532).</s><s>This strain was isolated from soil.</s><s>The species description is based on a single strain and thus serves as the type strain description.</s></p></content></protolog>