<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9591_nm.14782" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14782" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14782" rank="species">Flectobacillus roseus</organism><reference id="rid.9591"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sheu</surname><given-names>S.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chiu</surname><given-names>T.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>N.-T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>J.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sheu</surname><given-names>D.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>C.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>J.-T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.-M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flectobacillus roseus sp. nov., isolated from freshwater in Taiwan</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2546</fpage><lpage>2551</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.009738-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19622645</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Flectobacillus roseus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Flectobacillus roseus</em> (ro.se′us. L. masc. adj. <em>roseus</em> rose-coloured, pink).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, non-motile, straight rods (0.3–0.5 μm in diameter and 1.5–2.5 μm in length).</s><s>Accumulation of poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate granules is not observed.</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar are pale pink to rose coloured, circular (1.5–2.5 mm in diameter), convex and smooth with entire margins.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–40 °C and pH 7–8; optimal temperature and pH for growth are 30 °C and pH 7.</s><s>Good growth is observed on R2A and nutrient agar without NaCl or with 0.5 % (w/v) NaCl; no growth is seen in the presence of 2.0 % (w/v) NaCl or on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are not detected.</s><s>Positive for catalase and oxidase.</s><s>Negative for DNase and lipase (corn oil), and hydrolysis of Tweens 20, 40, 60, 80 and skimmed milk.</s><s>Hydrolysis of starch is strain specific.</s><s>Positive reactions (API 20NE) are seen for <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase, but negative reactions for nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose acidification, arginine dihydrolase, urease, protease, and assimilation of glucose, arabinose, mannose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, gluconate, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate and phenyl acetate.</s><s>Positive enzyme reactions (API ZYM) are seen for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase; negative enzyme reactions are seen for lipase (C14) and <em>β</em>-glucuronidase.</s><s>Enzyme reactions for <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are strain specific.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized in the API 50 CH test system: d-arabinose, d-xylose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, arbutin, aesculin, d-salicin, cellobiose, maltose, d-lactose, <em>α</em>-melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, <em>α</em>-melezitose, <em>α</em>-raffinose, starch, glycogen, gentiobiose, turanose and 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Negative for assimilation of glycerol, erythritol, d-ribose, l-xylose, adonitol, l-sorbose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, xylitol, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, gluconate and 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>Utilization of the remaining substrates (l-fucose, l-arabinose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and amygdalin) is strain specific.</s><s>The following compounds are oxidized in the Biolog GN II test system: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannose, melibiose, d-psicose, raffinose, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, dl-lactic acid, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-glutamic acid, uridine and <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate.</s><s>The following compounds are not oxidized: Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, i-erythritol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, xylitol, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, d-alanine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>Sensitive to tetracycline, rifampicin, gentamicin, penicillin G, chloramphenicol, nalidixic acid, novobiocin, streptomycin, ampicillin, and sulfamethoxazole plus trimethoprim.</s><s>Resistant to kanamycin.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 39.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, GFA-11<sup>T</sup> (=BCRC 17834<sup>T</sup>=LMG 24501<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a fish culture pond, Taoyuan County, northern Taiwan.</s><s>RG-4, isolated from a freshwater spring, Pingtung County, southern Taiwan, is a second strain of the species.</s></p></content></protolog>