<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.333_nm.2492" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2492" rank="family">Halomonadaceae</organism><reference id="rid.333"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dobson</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Franzmann</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Unification of the genera Deleya (Baumann et al. 1983), Halomonas (Vreeland et al. 1980), and Halovibrio (Fendrich 1988) and the species Paracoccus halodenitrificans (Robinson and Gibbons 1952) into a single genus, Halomonas, and placement of the genus Zymobacter in the family Halomonadaceae.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>550</fpage><lpage>558</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-2-550</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emendation of the description of the family <i>Halomonadaceae</i></s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Gram-negative, straight or curved, rod-shaped cells. Members are either slight or moderate halophiles or osmotolerant, growing in the presence of high concentrations of sugars. Aerobic or facultatively anaerobic. The major respiratory lipoquinone is ubiquinone 9, and the major fatty acids are 18:1 plus 19:Ocyc and 16:O. The family is a member of the gamma subclass of the <i>Proteobacteria</i>, and its members have 15 signature characteristics in their 16s rRNA sequences, including a very rare cytosine residue at position 486. The 15 signature characteristics are as follows: a 6-bp stem at positions 76 to 93, A at position 484, C at position 486, G at position 640, A at position 660, A at position 668, A at position 669, U at position 737, U at position 738, U at position 745, U at position 776, U at position 1124, U at position 1297, C at position 1298, and A at position 1423 (<i>E. coli</i> numbering). The family comprises three genera, <i>Halomonas</i>, <i>Chromohalobacter</i>, and <i>Zymobacter</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>