<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2770_nm.835" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.835" rank="genus">Phaeospirillum</organism><reference id="rid.2770"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Petri</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Süling</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of species of the spiral-shaped phototrophic purple non-sulfur bacteria of the alpha-Proteobacteria: description of the new genera Phaeospirillum gen. nov., Rhodovibrio gen. nov., Rhodothalassium gen. nov. and Roseospira gen. nov. as well as transfer of Rhodospirillum fulvum to Phaeospirillum fulvum comb. nov., of Rhodospirillum molischianum to Phaeospirillum molischianum comb. nov., of Rhodospirillum salinarum to Rhodovibrio salexigens.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>793</fpage><lpage>798</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-3-793</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9734033</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Phaeospirillum</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Phaeospirillum</i> (Phae.o.spi.ril'lum. Gr. adj. <i>phaeos</i> brown; M.L. neut. n. <i>Spirillum</i> a bacterial genus; M.L. neut. n. <i>Phaeospirillum</i> brown <i>Spirillum</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The name <i>Phaeospirillum</i> was proposed by Kluyver &#x0026; van Niel (1936) for brown-coloured phototrophic spiral-shaped bacteria.</s><s>It is not included in the Approved Lists of Bacterial Names and therefore has no standing in nomenclature.</s><s>It is proposed to revive this name for the brown-coloured spiral-shaped phototrophic purple non-sulfur bacteria of the α-<i>Proteobacteria</i> that do not belong to the genus <i>Rhodospirillum</i>.</s><s>Cells are vibrioid- to spiral-shaped, 0.5-1.0 μm wide, motile by means of polar flagella, multiply by binary fission and are Gram-negative.</s><s>They belong to the α-<i>Proteobacteria</i> and have a G+C content between 60 and 66 mol%.</s><s>Intracytoplasmic photosynthetic membranes are present as lamellar stacks, contain bacteriochlorophyll a and various carotenoids as photosynthetic pigments.</s><s>Contain ubiquinones and menaquinones Q-9 and MK-9 as major components.</s><s>Freshwater bacteria without a requirement for NaCl or sea salt for growth.</s><s>Growth occurs preferably photo-organotrophically under anoxic conditions in the light, but is also possible in the dark at very low oxygen tensions.</s><s>Growth factors are required.</s><s>Known species of the genus are <i>Phaeospirillum fulvum</i> and <i>Phaeospirillum molischianum</i>.</s><s>The type species is <i>Phaeospirillum fulvum</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>