<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3459_nm.7232" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7232" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7232" rank="species">Streptomyces reticuliscabiei</organism><reference id="rid.3459"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bouchek-Mechiche</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gardan</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Normand</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jouan</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>DNA relatedness among strains of Streptomyces pathogenic to potato in France: description of three new species, S. europaeiscabiei sp. nov. and S. stelliscabiei sp. nov. associated with common scab, and S. reticuliscabiei sp. nov. associated with netted scab</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>91</fpage><lpage>99</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10826791</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptomyces reticuliscabiei</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces reticuliscabiei</i> (re.ti.cu.li.sca'bi.ei. L. n. <i>reticulum</i> reticulum; L. n. <i>scabies</i> mange; M.L. n. <i>reticuliscabiei</i> referring to the reticulum aspect of the symptoms of the disease)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Spores are light grey, and are borne in mature flexuous chains.</s><s>Melanin is not produced on tyrosine agar.</s><s>They do not grow in the presence of 0.5 μg crystal violet ml<sup>-1</sup>, 20 μg streptomycin ml<sup>-1</sup>, 100 μg oleandomycin ml<sup>-1</sup> or 5% (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>They are not susceptible to 10 IU penicillin G ml<sup>-1</sup> and some (about 60%) of the strains are not susceptible to 25 μg oleandomycin ml<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>All ISP sugars (fructose, D-glucose D-mannitol, inositol, raffinose, rhamnose, sucrose, D-xylose) are used as carbon sources.</s><s>These strains utilize α-D(+­)melibiose, mucate, D-saccharate, D(+­)trehalose, 5-keto-D-gluconate.</s><s>They do not assimilate <i>trans</i>-aconitate or OMPG.</s><s>Most (about 80%) of the strains utilize DL-lactate and turanose.</s><s>Some strains use betain.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 69.8 mol%.</s><s>These strains were isolated from netted scab lesions on potato cv. Bintje and have been confirmed to be pathogenic only on potato cv. Bintje.</s><s>The type strain is CFBP 4531<sup>T</sup> (=ICMP 13716<sup>T</sup>=NCPPB 4041<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>It was isolated from lesions of netted scab on potato tubers in France.</s></p></content></protolog>