<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3850_nm.3058" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3058" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3058" rank="species">Aeromonas jandaei</organism><reference id="rid.3850"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Esteve</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Valera</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gutiérrez</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic study of sucrose-positive Aeromonas jandaei-like isolates from faeces, water and eels: emendation of A. jandaei Carnahan et al. 1992.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1411</fpage><lpage>1419</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02504-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">13130026</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Aeromonas jandaei</em> Carnahan <em>et al.</em> 1992</s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, straight rods that are motile by a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies develop within 24 h at 28 °C on TSA (Oxoid) and are not pigmented.</s><s>No brown water-soluble pigment is produced.</s><s>Growth occurs on MacConkey agar and on TCBS agar (Oxoid).</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic, with both oxidative and fermentative metabolism.</s><s>Acid and gas are produced from glucose.</s><s>Kovacs' cytochrome oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Does not swarm on solid media (1·5 % agar, w/v) and is resistant to vibriostatic agent O/129 (150 μg).</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–3 % (w/v) NaCl, at temperatures between 4 and 42 °C and under alkaline (pH 8·5) conditions.</s><s>All strains produce H<sub>2</sub>S from l-cysteine.</s><s>Positive for indole, Moeller's arginine dihydrolase, Thornley's arginine, gluconate oxidation and Voges–Proskauer test but negative for Moeller's ornithine and glutamine decarboxylases.</s><s>All strains produce acid from fructose, d-galactose, glycerol, d-mannose, d-mannitol, d-ribose and d-trehalose.</s><s>None of the strains produces acid from adonitol, d-amygdalin, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, arbutin, dulcitol, 2-deoxy-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, d-melibiose, d-raffinose, d-rhamnose, salicin, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, xylitol or xylose.</s><s>All strains use the following substrates as sole carbon and energy sources: <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, fumarate, d-gluconate, l-glutamate, l-glutamine, malate (alkalinization), l-proline and succinate.</s><s>None of the strains uses <em>trans</em>-aconitate, adenine, l-alanine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyrate, l-arabinose, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-aspartate, benzoate, l-carnosine, l-citrulline, l-cysteine, d-galacturonate, d-glucuronate, glutarate, glutathione, glycine, guanine, l-isoleucine, l-lactate, l-leucine, l-lysine, maleate (alkalinization), malonate (alkalinization), l-methionine, mucate, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, propionate, putrescine, sarcosine, l-tartrate, l-threonine, l-tryptophan, l-tyrosine, l-valine or xanthine.</s><s>Strains hydrolyse casein and gelatin but not alginate, arbutin or aesculin.</s><s>All strains display amylase and lecithinase activities and excrete <em>β</em>-haemolysins against human red blood cells.</s><s>All strains are resistant to ampicillin and penicillin but sensitive to amikacin, gentamicin, tetracycline and tobramycin (Carnahan <em>et al.</em>, 1991a; Esteve 1995).</s><s>Additional characteristics that vary among strains are shown in Table 2.</s><s>The DNA G+C content ranges from 58·1 to 61·1 mol%, as determined by the <em>T</em><sub>m</sub> method.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from clinical samples, fresh water, prawns and eels (<em>Anguilla anguilla</em>).</s><s>Mostly virulent for eels and mice; the latter animal model is currently used to assess pathogenic significance for humans.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is ATCC 49568<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 4228<sup>T</sup>); it presents all of the properties given above for the species.</s><s>In addition, it is positive for Moeller's lysine decarboxylase, produces acid from maltose, hydrolyses elastin, SDS and Tween 80 and uses acetate, citrate and l-serine (Table 2).</s><s>However, it is negative for acid production from sucrose and d-cellobiose, does not grow at pH 4·5 and does not use dl-glycerate, l-histidine or d-glucosamine.</s><s>Isolated from faeces.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 58·8 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>