<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8_nm.8359" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8359" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8359" rank="subspecies">Fusobacterium necrophorum necrophorum</organism><reference id="rid.8"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shinjo</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fujisawa</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mitsuoka</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of two subspecies of Fusobacterium necrophorum, (Flügge) Moore and Holdeman: Fusobacterium necrophorum subsp. necrophorum subsp. nov., nom. rev. (ex Flugge 1886), and Fusobacterium necrophorum subsp. funduliforme (ex Hallé 1898).</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>395</fpage><lpage>397</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-41-3-395</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1883714</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Fusobacterium necrophorum necrophorum</i> subsp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Cells grown in liquid medium are 0.5 to 0.6 by 3 to 70 μm. Filamentous forms often occur. Surface colonies on GAM agar supplemented with 5% defibrinated horse blood are about 2 mm in diameter and circular with scalloped to erose edges; they are grayish to whitish and flat (sometimes umbonate) and often have a bumpy surface. BTY broth (24) cultures produce moderate to abundant growth with homogeneous turbidity throughout the medium. Strain VPI 2891<sup>T</sup> is positive for H<sub>2</sub>S production and gelatin liquefaction and ferments maltose weakly. The hemolytic activity of these organisms is stronger than that of biovar B strains. Agglutination of chicken erythrocytes as determined by the glass slide method (2, 22) is positive, and the hemagglutination titer is more than 1:8 as determined by the test tube method (22, 24). Mice injected intraperitoneally or intraportally with strains of this subspecies die with diffuse abscesses in their livers (24).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content is 28 to 31 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>F. necrophorum</i> subsp. <i>necrophorum</i> subsp. nov., nom. rev. (ex Flügge 1886), is strain VPI 2891 (= JCM 3718 = ATCC 25286).</s></p></content></protolog>