<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4810_nm.1614" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1614" rank="genus">Parvularcula</organism><reference id="rid.4810"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Giovannoni</surname><given-names>S.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Parvularcula bermudensis gen. nov., sp. nov., a marine bacterium that forms a deep branch in the alpha-Proteobacteria.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1031</fpage><lpage>1036</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02566-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12892122</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Parvularcula</em> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Parvularcula</em> (Par.vu.lar′cu.la. L. adj. <em>parvulus</em> very small; L. fem. n. <em>arcula</em> a jewel-casket; N.L. fem. n. <em>Parvularcula</em> a very small jewel-casket).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, strictly aerobic short rods that occur singly, are sometimes coccoid, multiply by binary fission and are slightly motile with a single flagellum.</s><s>Endospores and poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate granules are not formed.</s><s>Colonies on marine agar are very small (0·3–0·8 mm in diameter), yellowish-brown, circular, dry and very hard.</s><s>Produces carotenoid pigments, but not bacteriochlorophyll <em>a</em>.</s><s>Catalase-negative and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Urea and gelatin are hydrolysed, but aesculin is not.</s><s>Chemoheterotrophic and moderately halophilic, requires NaCl for growth.</s><s>Cellular fatty acids are even-numbered monounsaturated or saturated fatty acids.</s><s>The major fatty acid is <em>cis</em>-7-octadecenoic acid (73·3 %).</s><s>Based on the 16S rRNA sequence, the genus belongs to the <em>α</em>-<em>Proteobacteria</em>.</s><s>Phylogenetically, the genus forms a novel seventh order of the <em>α</em>-<em>Proteobacteria</em>.</s><s>The type species of the genus is <em>Parvularcula bermudensis</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>