<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9244_nm.14509" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14509" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14509" rank="species">Pedobacter nyackensis</organism><reference id="rid.9244"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gordon</surname><given-names>N.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Valenzuela</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Adams</surname><given-names>S.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ramsey</surname><given-names>P.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pollock</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Holben</surname><given-names>W.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gannon</surname><given-names>J.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pedobacter nyackensis sp. nov., Pedobacter alluvionis sp. nov. and Pedobacter borealis sp. nov., isolated from Montana flood-plain sediment and forest soil</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1720</fpage><lpage>1726</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.000158-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19542109</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pedobacter nyackensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pedobacter nyackensis</em> (ny.ack.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>nyackensis</em> from Nyack, a region of north-western Montana, USA).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies grown on TSA for 48 h at 20 °C are 0.5–5.0 mm in diameter, round, convex, opaque and beige, darkening with age.</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative, oxidase- and catalase-positive, non-motile, non-spore-forming rods (0.2–0.7×1.0–4.0 μm), with an oxidative metabolism.</s><s>Good growth is observed after 96 h at 10 and 30 °C on TSA, NA and R2A.</s><s>Growth does not occur at 37 °C or on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 5–10 (optimal pH 7–8).</s><s>It can be differentiated from other <em>Pedobacter</em> species with validly published names by its ability to assimilate l-sorbose; it can be differentiated from its closest phylogenetic relatives, <em>P. caeni</em>, <em>P. heparinus</em> and <em>P. africanus</em>, by its ability to assimilate glycogen and 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>The fatty acid profile is composed of C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em>.</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is MK-7.</s><s>Additional phenotypic properties are shown in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Differential characteristics of strains NWGII14<sup>T</sup>, NWERII11<sup>T</sup> and G-1<sup>T</sup> and phylogenetically related species of the genus <em>Pedobacter</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Taxa: 1, strain NWGII14<sup>T</sup>; 2, strain NWERII11<sup>T</sup>; 3, strain G-1<sup>T</sup>; 4, <em>P. heparinus</em>; 5, <em>P. africanus</em>; 6, <em>P. piscium</em>; 7, <em>P. cryoconitis</em>; 8, <em>P. himalayensis</em>; 9, <em>P. caeni</em>; 10, <em>P. sandarakinus</em>; 11, <em>P. roseus</em>; 12, <em>P. aquatilis</em>; 13, <em>P. ginsengisoli</em>; 14, <em>P. suwonensis</em>; 15, <em>P. steynii</em>.</s><s>Unless otherwise indicated, data were compiled from Steyn <em>et al.</em> (1998), Margesin <em>et al.</em> (2003), Shivaji <em>et al.</em> (2005), Vanparys <em>et al.</em> (2005), Yoon <em>et al.</em> (2006), Hwang <em>et al.</em> (2006), Gallego <em>et al.</em> (2006), Ten <em>et al.</em> (2006), Muurholm <em>et al.</em> (2007), Kwon <em>et al.</em> (2007) and the present study. +, Positive; (+), weak reaction; −, negative; v, variable; na, data not available.</s><s>All taxa are positive for the following features: aerobic growth, presence of catalase, oxidase and alkaline phosphatase (na for <em>P. ginsengisoli</em>) and assimilation of d-glucose, d-mannose, d-lactose, cellobiose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin (na for <em>P. himalayensis</em> and <em>P. roseus</em>), salicin (v for <em>P. africanus</em>), melibiose (v for <em>P. saltans</em>; na for <em>P. roseus</em>), sucrose (v for <em>P. saltans</em>) and trehalose (v for <em>P. saltans</em>).</s><s>All taxa are negative for the following features: Gram-staining, sporulation, indole production, nitrate reduction, urease activity and assimilation of d-lyxose (na for <em>P. himalayensis</em> and <em>P. roseus</em>), d-fucose (na for <em>P. himalayensis</em> and <em>P. roseus</em>), erythritol (na for <em>P. roseus</em> and <em>P. ginsengisoli</em>), inositol and dulcitol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is NWG-II14<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 19625<sup>T</sup> =LMG 24260<sup>T</sup>), isolated from hyporheic sediments of the Nyack flood plain in north-western Montana, USA.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 36.1 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>