<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1352_nm.6505" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6505" rank="genus">Tsukamurella</organism><reference id="rid.1352"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Smida</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dorsch</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Tsukamurella gen. nov. harboring Corynebacterium paurometabolum and Rhodococcus aurantiacus.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>385</fpage><lpage>391</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-4-385</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Tsukamurella</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Tsukamurella</i> (Tsuk.am.ur.el'la. M.L. dim. ending <i>ella</i>; M.L. fem. n. <i>Tsukamurella</i>, honoring Michio Tsukamura, a Japanese microbiologist)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, weakly acid-fast (some strains are strongly acid fast), non-sporeforming, rod-shaped cells.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Obligately aerobic.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>Acid is produced from some sugars.</s><s>Catalase is produced.</s><s>Pyrazinamidase positive.</s><s>The diagnostic amino acid of peptidoglycan is <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid (variation A1<sub>γ</sub>; the glycan moiety of cell walls contains N-glycolyl residues.</s><s>The major cell wall sugars are arabinose and galactose.</s><s>Longchain mycolic acids are present (overall size, 62 to 78 carbon atoms) and contain one to six double bonds.</s><s>The fatty acid esters released on pyrolysis of mycolic acids have 20 to 22 carbon atoms.</s><s>The long-chain cellular fatty acids are predominantly of the straight-chain saturated, monounsaturated, and 10-methyl branched types.</s><s>The major polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylinositol, and mono- and diacylated phosphatidylinositol dimannosides.</s><s>Some strains produce glycolipids.</s><s>Menaquinones are the sole respiratory quinones, with MK-9 predominating.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 67 to 68 mol%.</s><s>The type species of <i>Tsukamurella</i> is <i>Tsukamurella paurometabolum</i>.</s><s>The genus <i>Tsukamurella</i> can be readily distinguished from other mycolic acid-containing taxa by using the criteria shown in Table 5.</s></p></content></protolog>