<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6400_nm.4057" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4057" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4057" rank="species">Acetivibrio cellulosolvens</organism><reference id="rid.6400"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Khan</surname><given-names>A.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Meek</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sowden</surname><given-names>L.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Colvin</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emendation of the genus Acetivibrio and description of Acetivibrio cellulosolvens sp. nov., a nonmotile cellulolytic mesophile.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>419</fpage><lpage>422</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-4-419</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Acetivibrio cellulosolvens</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Acetivibrio cellulosolvens</i> (cel. lu. lo. sol. vens. L. verb <i>solvere</i> to dissolve; N.L. adj . <i>cellulosolvens</i> cellulose dissolving, indicating the ability of this organism to ferment cellulosic substrates)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are obligately anaerobic, gram negative, rod shaped, and straight and occur singly, in pairs, or in chains of three or more cells (Fig. 1).</s><s>Single cells are about 0.3 to 0.7 by 2 to 3 μm.</s><s>No spores have been detected, and 72-h- and 2-week-old cultures grown on cellobiose or cellulose medium fail to survive heating at 80°C for 10 min or exposure to 50% ethanol (9).</s><s>The cells are nonmotile with no flagella visible in electron micrographs of young cells grown without shaking in broth containing cellobiose (Fig. 2).</s><s>Electron micrographs show that one end of each cell is round and uniform and the other end is rough and uneven.</s><s>This characteristic is observed in both young and old cells.</s><s>The cells have an outer membrane (Fig, 3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on cellulose agar are visible after 4 to 7 days of incubation.</s><s>They are about 2 to 3 mm in diameter, entire, raised, and cream colored, showing no clear zones surrounding the colonies.</s><s>Growth in cellulose-containing broth under an N<sub>2</sub>-CO<sub>2</sub> gas phase has little or no color.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimum growth temperature is between 35 and 37°C, and there is no growth at 20 or 45°C.</s><s>The optimum pH is between 6.5 and 7.5, and there is no growth at pH 6.0 or 8.0.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Only cellulose, cellobiose, esculin, and salicin support growth.</s><s>Yeast extract or rumen fluid is not required for growth on these carbon sources.</s><s>Bile (2% Oxgall; Difco) inhibits growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No growth is produced in medium supplemented with adonitol, amygdalin, arabinose, Casamino Acids, casein, chopped meat broth, dulcitol, erythritol, fructose, galactose, glucose, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, lactate, lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, melezitose, melibiose, milk, peptone, pyruvate, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, sorbitol, sorbose, starch, sucrose, trehalose, urea, xylose, or yeast extract.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Esculin is hydrolyzed to give a positive reaction with ferric ammonium citrate.</s><s>Sulfate is not reduced to sulfite, gelatin is not hydrolyzed, and catalase is not produced.</s><s>Indole and nitrate reduction tests are negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The metabolic products of cultures in basal medium containing cellobiose incubated for 4 to 8 days under 100% N2 or 80% Nr20% CO<sub>2</sub> are acetic acid (18 mM), ethanol (3 mM), CO<sub>2</sub>, and H<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Trace amounts of lactic acid also are produced.</s><s>In cellulose-containing medium, glucose (8 mM) also is produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The deoxyribonucleic acid base composition of the type strain is 41 ± 1.4 mol% guanine plus cytosine (n=4).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>A . cellulosolvens</i> is strain BAS, which has been deposited in the Wational Research Council of Canada culture collection as strain NRC 2936.</s></p></content></protolog>