<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1339_nm.10788" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10788" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6734" rank="species">Kibdelosporangium aridum</organism><reference id="rid.1339"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shearer</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Colman</surname><given-names>P.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ferrin</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nisbet</surname><given-names>L.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nash</surname><given-names>C.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>New genus of the Actinomycetales: Kibdelosporangium aridum gen. nov., sp. nov.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>47</fpage><lpage>54</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Kibdelosporangium aridum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Kibdelosporangium aridum</i> (ar' id. um. Lat. adj. <i>aridum</i> dry, arid)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Substrate mycelium. <i>K. aridum</i> substrate mycelium is well developed, with moderately branching, septate hyphae that are approximately 0.4 to 1.0 μm in diameter.</s><s>The vegetative hyphae do not fragment into rods and cocci during smear preparation.</s><s>However, fragmentation without hyphal displacement occurs in plate cultures (Fig. l).</s><s>Fragmentation in fermentors and shake flasks also occurs occasionally.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Present on the vegetative hyphae are specialized structures which consist of dichotomously branched, septate hyphae radiating from a common stalk (Fig. 2).</s><s>These specialized structures may be produced either deep in the agar or just below the surface of the agar and appear to be “naked” sporangiumlike structures analogous to the conidial structures which Couch (4) observed on the substrate mycelium of members of the <i>Actinoplanaceae</i>.</s><s>On many media <i>K. aridum</i> produces characteristic crystals in</s></p><p class="description"><s>the agar (Fig. 3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>(ii) Aerial mycelium.</s><s>The aerial mycelium is white and tends to be thin.</s><s>When viewed perpendicularly with a light microscope, the surface of a sporulating colony is covered with straight to irregularly curved chains of rod-shaped spores.</s><s>These spore chains are usually very long, with more than 50 spores per chain, but chains of 10 spores or less are also present.</s><s>The spore chains are usually borne terminally on branched or unbranched hyphae; occasionally they are borne terminally on lateral branches of the main hyphal threads.</s><s>The spores are smooth walled (Fig. 4) and irregular in length (approximately 0.4 μm wide by 0.8 to 2.8 μm long).</s><s>When placed on agar, these spores germinate, producing one or more germ tubes.</s></p><p class="description"><s>When a microscope is focused on the surface of the agar, sporangiumlike structures are observed beneath the long spore chains (Fig. 5).</s><s>These sporangiumlike structures are borne apically on branched or unbranched hyphae, as well as terminally on short lateral branches of the main hyphal threads (Fig. 6).</s><s>Sporangiumlike structures and chains of spores are frequently produced on the same aerial hyphae.</s><s>These sporangiumlike structures begin as small round swellings at the tips of the hyphae.</s><s>These swellings continue to enlarge, often going through a stage where they appear irregular in shape.</s><s>At maturity, these sporangiumlike structures are usually round (approximately 9 to 22 μm in diameter).</s><s>However, sporangiumlike structures slightly flattened along one axis are also present.</s><s>Very irregular, sausage-shaped sporangiumlike structures are rarely observed.</s><s>Mature sporangiumlike structures are surrounded by well defined walls and contain septate, branched hyphae embedded in an amorphous matrix (Fig. 7 through 10).</s><s>Despite extensive experimentation and observation of these sporangium-like structures, the development or release of any type of spore has not been observed.</s><s>When placed on a nutrient medium, these sporangiumlike structures germinate directly, producing one or more germ tubes (Fig. 11).</s></p><p class="description"><s>(iii) Chemotaxonomy.</s><s>Purified cell wall preparations of <i>K. aridum</i> contain <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, D-glutamic acid, DL-alanine, muramic acid, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, D-galactose, and a minor amount of arabinose.</s><s>Whole-cell hydrolysates contain D-galactose, D-glucose, D-mannose, D-ribose, L-rhamnose, and arabinose; traces of madurose are also usually present.</s><s>The phospholipids present are phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylmethylethanolamine, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol, and phosphatidylinositol mannosides.</s><s>Thus, <i>K. aridum</i> has type IV cell walls (30), a type A sugar pattern (30) with traces of madurose, and a type PII phospholipid composition (28).</s><s>No mycolic acids of any type are found in the cell extracts.</s><s>The DNA guanine-plus-cytosine content is 66 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(iv) Appearance on various media.</s><s>All plates were incubated at 28°C in closed Petri dish cans and observed at intervals for up to 21 days.</s><s>The common names for the colors were chosen after comparison with color chips from either the ISCC-NBS Centroid Color Charts (19, 37) or A Dictionary of Color (35).</s></p><p class="description"><s>On oatmeal agar growth is good, the substrate mycelium is off-white to yellowish brown, the aerial mycelium is sparse and white, spore chains and sporangium-like structures are present, no soluble pigment is produced, and crystals are present in the agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On inorganic salts-starch agar growth is good, the substrate mycelium is off-white to yellowish brown, the aerial mycelium is sparse and white, spore chains and sporangium-like structures are present, no soluble pigment is produced, and crystals are present in the agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On peptone-yeast extract-iron agar growth is good, the substrate mycelium is gray to bronzish brown, there is no aerial mycelium, a dark brownish black soluble pigment is produced, and no crystals are detected in the agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On thin potato-carrot agar growth is fair, the substrate mycelium is off-white to pale yellowish brown, the aerial mycelium is sparse to moderate and white, numerous spore chains and sporangiumlike structures are present , no soluble pigment is produced, and no crystals are detected in the agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On starch-casein-nitrate agar growth is good, the substrate mycelium is off-white to yellowish brown, the aerial mycelium is sparse and white, spore chains and sporangium-like structures are present, a pale yellowish brown soluble pigment is variably present, and crystals are present in the agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On soil extract agar growth is fair, the substrate mycelium is pale yellowish brown, the aerial mycelium is sparse and white, spore chains and sporangium-like structures are present, no soluble pigment is produced, and crystals are variably present in the agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On water agar growth is poor, the substrate mycelium is translucent to pale yellowish brown, the aerial mycelium is sparse to moderate and white, spore chains and sporangium-like structures are present, no soluble pigment is produced, and no crystals are detected in the agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(v) Physiological and biochemical characteristics.</s><s>No growth occurs under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 15 to 42°C, with a trace of growth at 45°C.</s><s>Growth at 10°C is inconsistent.</s><s>Freshly inoculated slants survive exposure to 50°C for 8 h.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide and melanin are produced.</s><s>Milk is peptonized.</s><s>Gelatin is both hydrolyzed and liquefied.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Casein, L-tyrosine, hypoxanthine, guanine, elastin, and testosterone are hydrolyzed, but starch, adenine, xanthine, and cellulose (Avicel) are not.</s><s>Catalase and phosphatase are produced.</s><s>Urea, esculin, and hippurate are decomposed; tests for allantoin decomposition are weakly positive.</s><s>No growth occurs in lysozyme broth.</s><s>Growth in the presence of 4% NaCl is consistent; growth in the presence of 5 to 7% NaCl is inconsistent, and no growth occurs in the presence of 8% NaCl.</s><s>Acid is produced from L-arabinose, D-cellobiose, dextrin, dextrose, D-fructose, glycerol, glycogen, D-galactose, i-inositol, lactose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, α-methyl- D-glucoside, α-methyl-D-mannoside, maltose, melbiose, D-melezitose, raffnose, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, sucrose, trehalose, and D-xylose.</s><s>Acid production from salicin is variable.</s><s>No acid is produced from adonitol, dulcitol, i-erythritol, inulin, D-sorbitol, or L-sorbose.</s><s>Citrate, L-malate, succinate, oxalate, DL-lactate, acetate, pyruvate, propionate, and formate are utilized; benzoate and L-tartrate are not utilized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(vi) Susceptibility to antibiotics and antimicrobial agents. <i>K. aridum</i> is resistant to gentamicin (10 μg), penicillin (10 U), ampicillin (2 μg), bacitracin (2 U), lincomycin (2 μg), clindamycin (2 μg), cephalothin (30 μg), tobramycin (10 μg), polymixin B (300 U), nalidixic acid (5 μg), and vancomycin (30 μg).</s><s>Chlortetracycline (5 μg) produces 18-mm zones of inhibition; tetracycline (5 μg) produces 11- to 12-mm zones; rifampin (5 μg) produces 11- to 15-mm zones; neomycin (30 μg) produces 12- to 13-mm zones; novobiocin (5 μg) produces 27- to 28-mm zones; chloramphenicol (30 μg) produces 15- to 21-mm hazy zones; and sulfathiazole (0.25 mg) produces 70- to 75-mm hazy zones.</s><s>All zones of inhibition contain at least a few resistant colonies.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(vii) Type strain.</s><s>The type strain is strain SK&#x0026;F-AAD-216 (= ATCC 39323).</s><s>The species description given above is based on a single strain, the type strain.</s><s>Therefore, this description also serves as the description of the type strain.</s></p></content></protolog>