<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8567_nm.13242" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13242" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13242" rank="species">Bifidobacterium tsurumiense</organism><reference id="rid.8567"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Okamoto</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Benno</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Leung</surname><given-names>K.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Maeda</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bifidobacterium tsurumiense sp. nov., from hamster dental plaque.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>144</fpage><lpage>148</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65296-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18175700</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bifidobacterium tsurumiense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bifidobacterium tsurumiense</em> (tsu.ru.mi.en′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>tsurumiense</em> pertaining to Tsurumi University, Yokohama, Japan).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on Brucella HK blood agar plates are white, rough and slightly convex.</s><s>Cells are short rods or coccoid when grown on Brucella HK blood agar under anaerobic conditions for 24 h.</s><s>Cells are Gram-positive, F6PPK-positive, catalase- and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Growth occurs at 25 and 45 °C; optimal temperature for growth is 37 °C.</s><s>Growth also occurs on LBS and CFAT agars.</s><s>End products of glucose fermentation are acetic and lactic acids at a molar ratio of 3 : 2.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 53 mol%.</s><s>l-Arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, d-lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, gentiobiose, turanose, gluconate and 2-ketogluconate are fermented.</s><s>Glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, inulin, melezitose, xylitol, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol and 5-ketogluconate are not fermented.</s><s>Positive for aesculin hydrolysis, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, arginine arylamidase, proline arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, tyrosine arylamidase, alanine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, serine arylamidase, esterase, esterase lipase, lipase, valine arylamidase, cysteine arylamidase and acid phosphatase.</s><s>Negative for catalase, urease, arginine dihydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase-6-phosphate, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, nitrate reduction, indole production, alkaline phosphatase, pyroglutamate arylamidase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, phosphoamidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>The cell-wall amino acids consist of Glu–Lys–Asp–(Ala)<sub>2</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, OMB115<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 13495<sup>T</sup> =DSM 17777<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from dental plaque from hamsters fed with a high-carbohydrate diet.</s></p></content></protolog>