<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1048_nm.12206" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.12206" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5432" rank="species">Lactobacillus sanfrancisco</organism><reference id="rid.1048"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schillinger</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lactobacillus sanfrancisco sp. nov., nom. rev.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>5</volume><fpage>230</fpage><lpage>232</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Lactobacillus sanfrancisco</i> sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Lactobacillus sanfrancisco</i> (san . fran . cis' co. M.L. n. <i>sanfrancisco</i> San Francisco, named after the city where the sourdoughs from which the organism was first isolated have been propagated for more than 100 years)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, non spore-forming rods with rounded ends, generally 0.6 to 0.8 by 2 to 4 μm, occurring singly and in pairs.</s><s>Non motile.</s><s>Requires the addition of freshly prepared yeast extractives to media for good growth.</s><s>Microaerophilic; growth is enhanced by reduced O<sub>2</sub> pressure and CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Slightly acidophilic; favourable initial pH for growth is around 5.5.</s><s>Growth occurs between 13 and 40°C with an optimum at 30°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Obligately saccharoclastic.</s><s>Heterofermentative; CO<sub>2</sub>, acetic acid (ethanol), and DL-lactic acid are formed from hexoses and gluconate.</s><s>Only glucose, galactose, maltose, and gluconate are fermented, arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, lactose, mannitol, mannose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, and xylose not fermented.</s><s>Ammonia not produced from arginine.</s><s>Katalase and benzidin reaction negative.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite; indole and H<sub>2</sub> negate.</s><s>Electrophoretic mobility of L-LDH and D-LDH are 1.05 and 1.18, respectively.</s><s>Cell walls contain murrain of the Lys-Ala type and no teichoic acid.</s><s>The G + C content of the DNA is 36 to 38 mol%. (T<sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat: Isolated from sourdough.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: NRRL B-3934 (L-12, ATCC 27651, DSM 20451)</s></p></content></protolog>