<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4332_nm.5903" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5903" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5903" rank="species">Rothia nasimurium</organism><reference id="rid.4332"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hutson</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Båverud</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characterization of a Rothia-like organism from a mouse: description of Rothia nasimurium sp. nov. and reclassification of Stomatococcus mucilaginosus as Rothia mucilaginosa comb. nov.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1247</fpage><lpage>1251</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10843069</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rothia nasimurium</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rothia nasimurium</i> (na.si.mu'ri.um. M.L. pl. gen. n. <i>nasimurium</i> of the nose of mice)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-motile cocci.</s><s>Produce a weak α-haemolysis on blood agar.</s><s>Non-pigmented.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and catalase-positive.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, lactose, maltose, methyl β-D-glucopyranoside, sucrose and trehalose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from L-arabinose, D-arabitol, cyclodextrin, glycogen, mannitol, melibiose, melezitose, N-acetylglucosamine, pullulan, raffinose, ribose, sorbitol, tagatose or D-xylose.</s><s>Alanine phenylalanine proline arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, ester lipase C-8, bgalacturonidase, α-glucosidase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, pyrazinamidase and trypsin are produced.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, arginine dihydrolase, esterase C-4, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, lipase C14, α-mannosidase, β-mannosidase, pyrrolydonyl arylamidase and urease are not produced.</s><s>Acid phosphatase, chymotrypsin, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, β-galactosidase, glycine tryptophan arylamidase may or may not be produced.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed but not hippurate.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer-negative.</s><s>Cellular fatty acids are mainly of the methyl-branched types with ai-C15 predominating.</s><s>Isolated from the nose of a healthy mouse.</s><s>Habitat unknown.</s><s>The G+­C content of the DNA is 56 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is CCUG 35957<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>