<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9022_nm.9757" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9757" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9757" rank="species">Spiroplasma leucomae</organism><reference id="rid.9022"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Whitcomb</surname><given-names>R.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Evolution and devolution of minimal standards for descriptions of species of the class Mollicutes: analysis of two Spiroplasma descriptions.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>201</fpage><lpage>206</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17267949</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>‘Fulfilment of the minimal standards' in the description of <em>S. leucomae</em></s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Given the above circumstances, the claim that the minimal standards have been fulfilled for <em>S. leucomae</em> is unwarranted, and the paper should be retracted. Failing retraction, the problems revealed in the above analysis must be clarified. Clarification can be achieved only by presentation of the missing data, which could be published as an electronic erratum in IJSEM Online. A list of suggested points that should be addressed is presented in Supplement B in IJSEM Online. By revealing what they actually did (or did not do), the authors would satisfy a general need in species descriptions identified by Stackebrandt <em>et al</em>. (2002). In the words of these authors, providing full details of procedures used in taxonomic papers ‘would be neither onerous nor expensive’, given the opportunity to publish supplementary material in IJSEM Online. If it is not possible to resolve these problems, a Request for an Opinion may be placed with the Judicial Commission of the ICSP contesting the validity of the name <em>S. leucomae</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>