<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4363_nm.10714" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10714" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10714" rank="species">Exiguobacterium indicum</organism><reference id="rid.4363"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chaturvedi</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shivaji</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Exiguobacterium indicum sp. nov., a psychrophilic bacterium from the Hamta glacier of the Himalayan mountain ranges of India.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2765</fpage><lpage>2770</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64508-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17158975</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Exiguobacterium indicum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Exiguobacterium indicum</em> (in′di.cum. L. neut. adj. <em>indicum</em> Indian, pertaining to India).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-positive, motile and rod-shaped (2.3 μm long and 0.52 μm wide).</s><s>Stationary-phase cells are coccobacilli.</s><s>Colonies (2–4 mm) on nutrient agar are round, shiny, irregular, elevated and orange-coloured after 24 h at 22 °C.</s><s>No spores are observed.</s><s>Grows at 5–30 °C and at pH 6–10.</s><s>The optimum temperature and pH for growth are 25 °C and pH 7.0.</s><s>Tolerates 5.8 % NaCl and also grows in the absence of salt.</s><s>Colonies are yellowish orange in colour.</s><s>The pigment is soluble in chloroform and exhibits multiple absorption maxima at 408, 434, 460 and 495 nm.</s><s>Positive for catalase, oxidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, phosphatase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, arginine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, malonate utilization, in the Voges–Proskauer test and for reduction of nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Negative for urease, lipase, gelatinase, DNase, caseinase, tryptophan deamination, indole production, in the methyl red test, for H<sub>2</sub>S production and for hydrolysis of aesculin and starch hydrolysis.</s><s>Utilizes d-glucose, d-galactose, d-rhamnose, l-melibiose, d-cellobiose, sucrose, d-xylose, L-xylose, d-raffinose, glycerol, lactic acid, fumaric acid, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-sorbitol, dulcitol, polyethylene glycol, citric acid, sodium acetate, potassium acetate, inulin, dextrin, <em>myo</em>-inositol, glycogen, sodium thioglycolate, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, arbutin, malic acid, erythritol, sodium gluconate, sodium fumarate, sodium formate, sodium succinate, <em>γ</em>-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, valeric acid, 5-ketogluconate, l-glycine, l-ornithine, l-alanine, l-valine, l-leucine, l-isoleucine, l-serine, l-threonine, l-lysine, l-arginine, l-glutamic acid, l-aspartic acid, glutamine, l-asparagine, l-methionine, l-tyrosine, l-tryptophan, l-proline, l-histidine and l-creatinine, but not l-sorbose, l- or d-arabinose, d-fructose, d-mannose, d-trehalose, d-mannitol, d-ribose, d-lactose, d-adonitol, maltose, d-melezitose, hydroxybutyric acid, dextran, sodium propionate, cellulose, starch, pyruvate, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, salicin, amygdalin, xylitol, l-fucose, l-cysteine or l-phenylalanine.</s><s>Negative for acid production from inulin, d-glucose, sucrose, d-fructose, d-sorbitol, l-melibiose, d-lactose, d-trehalose, maltose, l-rhamnose, d-mannose, l-arabinose, l-xylose, d-ribose, d-cellobiose and adonitol.</s><s>Resistant to discs containing the following antibiotics (μg): norfloxacin (10), cotrimoxazole (25), clindamycin (25), doxycycline (25), sulfamethoxazole (50), amoxicillin (30), amikacin (30), nalidixic acid (30), nitrofurantoin (300) and colistin (10).</s><s>Sensitive to the following antibiotics (μg): tobramycin (15), lomefloxacin (30), roxithromycin (30), ciprofloxacin (30), penicillin (10), cefoperazone (75), vancomycin (30), cefuroxime (30), lincomycin (15), cefotaxime (30), cefazolin (30), kanamycin (30), novobiocin (30), chloramphenicol (30), ampicillin (25), tetracycline (30), streptomycin (25), erythromycin (15), bacitracin (10), gentamicin G (30), polymyxin B (50), oleandomycin (15), spectinomycin (100), rifampicin (25) and carbenicillin (100).</s><s>Major respiratory quinones are MK-7 and MK-8.</s><s>Peptidoglycan is of the Lys–Gly type.</s><s>Phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol are the main phospholipids; minute amounts of phosphatidylethanolamine are also present.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 48.0 mol%.</s><s>The fatty acids present are iso-C<sub>13 : 0</sub> (0.2 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (48.7 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (3.0 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub> (0.3 %), iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (43.0 %), anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (0.3 %) and C<sub>18 : 1</sub> (2.0 %).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, HHS 31<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 23471<sup>T</sup>=IAM 15368<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from melt water from the Hamta glacier located at a height of 4279 m above sea level in the Himalayan mountain ranges of India.</s></p></content></protolog>