<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10793_nm.13770" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13770" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13770" rank="species">Salinicola socius</organism><reference id="rid.10793"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>de la Haba</surname><given-names>R.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sánchez-Porro</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Márquez</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic study of the genus Salinicola: transfer of Halomonas salaria and Chromohalobacter salarius  to the genus Salinicola as Salinicola salarius comb. nov. and Salinicola halophilus nom. nov., respectively</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>963</fpage><lpage>971</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.014480-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19661506</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Salinicola socius</em> Anan'ina <em>et al.</em> 2008</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Salinicola socius</em> (so′ci.us, L. masc. adj. <em>socius</em> associated, referring to membership in a microbial association).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The characteristics of this species are as described by Anan'ina <em>et al.</em> (2007), with the addition of the following features.</s><s>Grows in the range 15 to 40 °C.</s><s>Exopolysaccharide is not produced.</s><s>Poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxyalkanoate is produced.</s><s>Respiration on fumarate, nitrate and nitrite is negative.</s><s>Tween 20 is hydrolysed.</s><s>Casein, DNA, tyrosine and aesculin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Methyl red and phosphatase tests are positive.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer test is negative.</s><s>Lysine- and ornithine-decarboxylase-negative.</s><s>Gluconate is not oxidized.</s><s>Selenite is not reduced.</s><s>The following compounds are used as sole carbon and energy sources: aesculin, d-arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, sucrose, salicin, starch, d-xylose, butanol, dulcitol, ethanol, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, methanol, propanol, d-sorbitol, xylitol, acetate, benzoate, citrate, fumarate, hippurate and propionate.</s><s>The following compounds are not used as sole carbon and energy sources: d-fucose, lactose, ribose, trehalose, formate, malate, succinate, tartrate and valerate.</s><s>The following compounds are used as sole carbon, nitrogen and energy sources: l-alanine, glutamine, isoleucine, l-lysine, l-ornithine, l-serine, l-threonine and tryptophan.</s><s>The following compounds are not used as sole carbon, nitrogen and energy sources: l-arginine, aspartate, l-cysteine, l-methionine, phenylalanine and valine.</s><s>Resistant to cephalothin (30 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), neomycin (10 μg), rifampicin (30 μg) and bacitracin (10 units).</s><s>Sensitive to sulfamethoxazole/trimethoprim (23.75/1.25 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg) and novobiocin (30 μg).</s><s>The polar lipids comprise phospholipids, aminolipids and phosphoglycolipids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is SMB35<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 19940<sup>T</sup> =VKM B-2397<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>