<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3311_nm.5776" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5776" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5776" rank="species">Actinomyces cardiffensis</organism><reference id="rid.3311"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hall</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hutson</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Duerden</surname><given-names>B.I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinomyces cardiffensis sp. nov. from human clinical sources</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>3427</fpage><lpage>3431</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1128/JCM.40.9.3427-3431.2002</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12202588</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinomyces cardiffensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinomyces cardiffensis</i> (car.dif.fen'sis, L. adj. <i>cardiffensis</i>, pertaining to Cardiff, a city in Wales)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are pleomorphic, slender, straight-to-curved rods; beaded branching filaments occur.</s><s>Cells stain gram positive, are non-acid-fast and nonmotile.</s><s>On Fastidious Anaerobic Agar with 5% horse blood after 48 h of incubation, colonies are pinpoint, convex, smooth surfaced, entire-edged, and opaque cream to pinkish.</s><s>Nonhemolytic.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and catalase negative.</s><s>Using conventional testing, acid is formed from glucose and sucrose but not from amygdalin, L-arabinose, cellobiose, lactose, mannitol, mannose, D-raffinose, salicin, trehalose, or D-xylose.</s><s>Acid production from D-ribose variable.</s><s>Principal end products of glucose metabolism are lactic and succinic acids, together with small amounts of acetic acid.</s><s>Hydrolysis of esculin and starch is negative.</s><s>Lipase and lecithinase are not produced.</s><s>Using API systems, acid is produced from D-glucose but not from L-arabinose, D-arabitol, cyclodextrin, glycogen, lactose, mannitol, melibiose, melezitose, methyl-β-D-glucopyranoside, N-acetyl-β-glucosamine, pullulan, sorbitol, tagatose, trehalose, or D-xylose.</s><s>Acid may or may not be formed from maltose, mannose, D-raffinose, D-ribose, and sucrose.</s><s>Gelatin, esculin, and hippurate are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Alanine phenylalanine proline arylamidase, alanine arylamidase, arginine arylamidase, α-glucosidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, leucylglycine arylamidase, proline arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, serine arylamidase, and tyrosine arylamidase are detected.</s><s>No activity is detected for α-arabinosidase, arginine dihydrolase, alkaline phosphatase, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-galactosidase 6-phosphate, β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, glycyl tryptophan arylamidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, glutamylglutamic acid arylamidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, pyrazinamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, β-mannosidase, pyrolydonyl arylamidase, or urease.</s><s>Acetoin is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate may or may not be reduced.</s><s>Indole negative.</s><s>The type strain is CCUG 44997<sup>T</sup>= CIP 107323<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>Isolated from human clinical sources, including pleural fluid, brain, jaw, pericolic and ear abscesses, antrum, and IUCDs.</s><s>Habitat is not known.</s></p></content></protolog>