<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1872_nm.9602" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9602" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9602" rank="species">Bacillus herbersteinensis</organism><reference id="rid.1872"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wieser</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Worliczek</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus herbersteinensis sp. nov.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>2119</fpage><lpage>2123</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63660-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16166719</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus herbersteinensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus herbersteinensis</em> (her.ber.stein′en.sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>herbersteinensis</em> pertaining to Castle Herberstein in Styria, in which the chapel with the medieval wall painting is located from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are motile, rod-shaped, Gram-positive in the KOH and aminopeptidase tests, rod-shaped and produce oval spores in terminal, unswollen sporangia.</s><s>Colonies on PYES agar are 2–3 mm in diameter, slightly raised, irregular and cream-coloured to beige.</s><s>Older colonies are more translucent.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4 and 28 °C, in the presence of 0, 1, 3 and 5 % NaCl (w/v) but not at 7 or 10 % NaCl (w/v).</s><s>On buffered medium, growth is observed at pH 7 (weakly), 8 and 9.</s><s>On unbuffered medium, growth is observed at pH 7 (weakly), 8, 9, 10, 11 and 12 but not at pH 6.</s><s>Negative for nitrate reduction and haemolysis.</s><s>Starch, <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl (pNP) <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, pNP <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside and bis-pNP phosphate are hydrolysed. pNP <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, pNP phenylphosphonate, pNP phosphorylcholine, 2-deoxythymidine-5′-pNP phosphate, l-alanine pNA (pNA, <em>p</em>-nitroanilide), l-glutamate <em>γ</em>-3-carboxy-pNA, l-proline pna and pnp <em>β</em>-d-glucoronide are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Acid is not produced from adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, glucose, inositol, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl d-glucoside, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose or d-xylose. <em>N</em>-Acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose (weakly), <em>p</em>-arbutin (weakly), d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gluconic acid, d-glucose, d-maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, <em>α</em>-d-melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, d-sorbitol, d-sucrose, d-trehalose, d-xylose, acetate (weakly), <em>cis</em>-aconitate (weakly), l-aspartate, citrate, fumarate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, dl-lactate, l-malate, l-ornithine (weakly), 2-oxoglutarate (weakly), pyruvate and l-proline are assimilated.</s><s>Adonitol, <em>i</em>-inositol, maltitol, putrescine, azelate, glutarate, itaconate, <em>trans</em>-aconitate, adipate, propionate, 4-aminobutyric acid, 4-hydroxybenzoic acid, mesaconate, suberate, l-alanine, <em>β</em>-alanine, l-serine, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-phenylalanine, l-tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoic acid and phenylacetate are not assimilated.</s><s>The fatty acid profile consists of C<sub>14 : 0</sub> iso (8·7–14·2 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (0–0·5 %), C<sub>15 : 0</sub> iso (17·7–27·4 %), C<sub>15 : 0</sub> anteiso (17·0–23·4 %), C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (1·9–3·2 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (2·9–5·1 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>11<em>c</em> (1·9–2·4 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> iso (8·4–15·8 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (4·8–5·9 %), C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>10<em>c</em> iso (2·4–2·5 %), C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em> iso (1·0 %), C<sub>17 : 0</sub> iso (3·7–5·1 %), C<sub>17 : 0</sub> anteiso (1·1–1·2 %) and C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (1·1–1·6 %).</s><s>The diamino acid in the cell wall is <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The predominant polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and an unidentified glycolipid.</s><s>Additionally, moderate to minor amounts of a second unknown glycolipid, two phospholipids and four polar lipids are present.</s><s>The major respiratory quinone is MK-7.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 36·2–36·9 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain D-1,5a<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 16534<sup>T</sup>=CCM 7228<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Strains D-1,5a<sup>T</sup> and D-1,5b were both isolated from a damaged wall painting in the chapel of Castle Herberstein, Styria (Austria).</s></p></content></protolog>