<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11560_nm.18594" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.18594" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.18594" rank="species">Ancylobacter dichloromethanicus</organism><reference id="rid.11560"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Firsova</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Doronina</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lang</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Spröer</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vuilleumier</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trotsenko</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ancylobacter dichloromethanicus sp. nov. – a new aerobic facultatively methylotrophic bacterium utilizing dichloromethane</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>32</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>227</fpage><lpage>232</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2009.02.002</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Ancylobacter dichloromethanicus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>A. dichloromethanicus</em> (<em>di.chlo.ro.me.tha.ni.cus</em>. N.L. n. <em>dichloromethanum</em>, dichloromethane; L. suff. – icus – a – um, suffix used with various meanings; N.L. masc. adj. <em>dichloromethanicus</em>, dichloromethane utilizing).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-sporulating, colorless, non-motile curved rods having no capsule and multiplying by binary fission.</s><s>Colonies on methanol agar are round, low convex, smooth, with entire edge, of homogeneous consistency, semitransparent and colorless, up to 0.6 mm in diameter.</s><s>Obligate aerobe.</s><s>Unable to produce H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>Indole is produced from tryptophan on a medium with nitrate as nitrogen source.</s><s>It does not reduce nitrates to nitrites.</s><s>The bacterium hydrolyzed aesculin but not starch, gelatin, or casein milk.</s><s>Facultative methylotroph and chemolithoautotroph using thiosulfate as an energy source.</s><s>Assimilates C<sub>1</sub> compounds via the RuBP pathway.</s><s>Autotrophic growth occurs on mineral salt medium with gas mixture of H<sub>2</sub>/O<sub>2</sub>/CO<sub>2</sub>, dichloromethane, methanol, formate and formaldehyde.</s><s>Utilizes a variety of polycarbon compounds.</s><s>Ammonium salts, nitrates, glutamate and urea serve as nitrogen sources.</s><s>Urease, catalase, oxidase and β-galactosidase positive.</s><s>Neutrophilic and mesophilic.</s><s>Grows at pH 6.0–9.0 and temperatures 4–37 °C.</s><s>Optimal growth at pH 7.0–7.5 and temperatures 28–30 °C.</s><s>No growth in the presence of 2% NaCl (w/v).</s><s>Contains ubiquinone Q-10.</s><s>Dominant phospholipids are phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol (cardiolipin).</s><s>The prevailing cellular fatty acids are 18:1ω7c (58.6%), cyclo-19:0ω8c (34.8%) and 16:0 (3.2%).</s><s>The major polyamines are putrescine, homospermidine and spermine.</s><s>Utilizable carbon sources are dichloromethane, methanol, formate, formaldehyde, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-maltose, d-raffinose, d-xylose, l-arabinose, d-melibiose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-mannitol, d-adonitol, d-arabitol, xylitol, α-ketoglutarate, succinate, propionate, gluconate, 5-ketogluconate, l-alanine, l-arginine, serine, inositol, sorbitol, glycerol, salicin and sarcosine.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized: sucrose, d-lactose, trehalose, cellobiose, l-rhamnose, malate, fumarate, glutamate, pyruvate, citrate, acetate, dulcitol, ethanol, l-valine, glycine, tryptophan, acetone, dimethylsulfoxide, mono-, di- and trimethylamines and acetamide.</s><s>Biotin and pantothenate are required for good growth on most substrates.</s><s>Resistant to linkomycin, novobiocin, oxacillin and nalidixic acid, but sensitive to ampicillin, neomycin, streptomycin and gentamycin.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 64.5 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s><s>The type strain is DM16<sup>T</sup> (DSM 21507<sup>T</sup>=VKM B-2484<sup>T</sup>) isolated from contaminated soil sampled at Volgograd chemical plant (Russia).</s><s>The GenBank accession number for the 16S rRNA gene sequence is <a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=search&#x0026;db=nucleotide&#x0026;doptcmdl=genbank&#x0026;term=EU589386[accn]" target="externObjLink">EU589386</a>.</s></p></content></protolog>