<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6738_nm.461" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.461" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.461" rank="species">Thermotoga elfii</organism><reference id="rid.6738"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ravot</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Magot</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fardeau</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prensier</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Egan</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garcia</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ollivier</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Thermotoga elfii sp. nov., a novel thermophilic bacterium from an African oil-producing well.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>308</fpage><lpage>314</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-2-308</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7537064</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thermotoga elfii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thermotoga elfii</i> (el.fi'i. L. gen. n. <i>elfii</i>, named after Elf-Aquitaine)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Round colonies (diameter, 1 mm) are present after 7 days of incubation at 60°C.</s><s>Cells are rods (0.5 to 1 by 2 to 3 μm), and each cell has an outer sheath-like structure (toga).</s><s>The cells occur singly or in pairs and have peritrichous flagella.</s><s>The cell wall is gram negative, as determined by electron microscopy or Gram staining.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic and obligately anaerobic members of the domain <i>Bacteria</i>.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 66°C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 45 or 75°C.</s><s>The optimum pH is 7.5; growth occurs at pH 5.5 but not at pH 9.1.</s><s>The optimum sodium chloride concentration for growth is around 1%; only marginal growth occurs in the absence of sodium chloride, and no growth occurs in the presence of 2.8% NaCl.</s><s>Oxidizes D-glucose, D-arabinose, D-fructose, lactose, maltose, D-mannose, D-ribose, sucrose, and D-xylose in the presence of thiosulfate but not L-arabitol, D-mannitol, L-rhamnose, L-sorbose, L-xylose, acetate, butyrate, lactate, or propionate.</s><s>Requires yeast extract and bio-Trypticase for growth.</s><s>Yeast extract cannot be replaced by Casamino Acids, a vitamin solution, or a mixture of Casamino Acids and vitamins.</s><s>Bio- Trypticase can be fermented in the presence of yeast extract.</s><s>The end products of glucose fermentation in the presence of yeast extract and bio-Trypticase are acetate, CO<sub>2</sub>, and hydrogen.</s><s>Uses thiosulfate as an electron acceptor during glucose fermentation, and under these conditions the cell density is greater than the cell density when the organism is grown with no added electron acceptor.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced from thiosulfate reduction.</s><s>Elemental sulfur cannot be used as an electron acceptor, and growth is inhibited by elemental sulfur.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 39.6 mol% (as determined by HPLC).</s><s>Isolated from an oil-producing well.</s><s>The type strain is SEBR 6459 (= DSM 9442).</s></p></content></protolog>