<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2648_nm.5232" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5232" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5232" rank="subspecies">Staphylococcus aureus anaerobius</organism><reference id="rid.2648"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>De la Fuente</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suarez</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schleifer</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Staphylococcus aureus subsp. anaerobius subsp. nov., the causal agent of abscess disease of sheep.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>99</fpage><lpage>102</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-35-1-99</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Staphylococcus aureus</i> subsp. <i>anaerobius</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Staphylococcus aureus</i> subsp. <i>anaerobius</i> (ain.ae.ro'bi. us. Gr. pref. <i>an</i> not; Gr. n. <i>aer</i> air; Gr. n. <i>bios</i> life; M.L. adj. <i>anaerobius</i> not living in air)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are cocci that are 0.8 to 1.0 μm in diameter and occur singly, in pairs, and predominantly in irregular clusters.</s><s>Gram positive.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Nonsporeforming.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On the primary isolation medium, growth is obtained only in media that are supplemented with blood, serum, or egg yolk and incubated microaerobically or anaerobically.</s><s>Colonies on blood agar (Oxoid Ltd., London, England) after 2 days of incubation are very small (1 to 3 mm in diameter), low convex, circular, entire, smooth, glistening, and opaque.</s><s>Pigment is not produced.</s><s>Luxuriant growth is obtained on Dorset egg medium, with colony diameters of 4 to 6 mm.</s><s>The strains produce unevenly disseminated growth on brain heart infusion agar (Difco Laboratories, Detroit, Mich.) after 3 days of microaerophilic incubation.</s><s>They grow as dwarf colonies, among which a few colonies of normal size are observed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In broth cultures (3 days), a white granular deposit without turbidity is formed.</s><s>When broth media are supplemented with 5% serum, the typical deposit appears after 24 h.</s></p><p class="description"><s>After several subcultures, the strains are able to grow aerobically on solid media, but aerobic growth is much worse than anaerobic growth.</s><s>Growth is weak to moderate in the anaerobic portion of a semisolid thioglycolate medium after 4 to 5 days.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Analysis for volatile and nonvolatile fatty acids as end products of anaerobic glucose metabolism indicates production of acetic, lactic, and succinic acids by all strains.</s><s>The five strains studied in detail produce L-lactic acid from glucose under anaerobic conditions, but not D-lactic acid.</s><s>Most <i>S. aureus</i> strains produce D- and L-lactic acids, and only rare strains (about 5%) produce solely L-lactic acid.</s><s>All strains grow well at NaCl concentrations up to 10%; 70% of the strains grow at a NaCl concentration of 12.5%, and 85% do not grow in the presence of 15% NaCl.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature range is 30 to 40°C.</s><s>No strain grows at 20 or 45°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains are catalase, benzidine, and oxidase negative.</s><s>Catalase and cytochrome synthesis cannot be induced by adding small amounts of H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> or hemin to the culture media.</s><s>Catalase-negative staphylococci have been described occasionally (17, 28, 36, 38, 39), but the strains on which the benzidine test was performed (36, 38, 39) contained the cytochrome system; since catalase is ubiquitously present in aerobic bacteria containing a cytochrome system (13), the absence of catalase activity in these strains could be interpreted as a mutation affecting the synthesis or function of this enzyme.</s><s>On the other hand, Kilpper-Balz and Schleifer (27) reported that the amount of cytochromes is markedly reduced in the anaerobic species <i>Staphylococcus saccharolyticus</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Like most staphylococci, the <i>S. aureus</i> subsp. <i>anaerobius</i> strains contain class I fructose-1,6-bisphosphate aldolase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The strains produce coagulase (tube test positive between 3 and 8 h) and heat-stable and heat-labile nucleases and are clumping-factor negative.</s><s>They produce hemolysis in sheep, bovine, rabbit, and human blood agar media.</s><s>On sheep or bovine blood agar, a wide zone of β-hemolysis (sphingomyelinase) is observed.</s><s>This hemolytic effect is a characteristic of many coagulase-positive staphylococci of animal origin (20).</s><s>They do not ferment mannitol, reduce nitrates, or produce acetylmethylcarbinol.</s><s>Phosphatase activity is positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>They produce acid from glucose, fructose, maltose, and sucrose.</s><s>No acid is produced from galactose, mannose, rhamnose, xylose, arabinose, ribose, lactose, trehalose, cellobiose, melibiose, gentiobiose, melezitose, raffinose, glycerol, inositol, xylitol, sorbitol, salicin, galactitol, inulin, or amygdalin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The strains show strong caseinolytic and gelatinase activities and produce egg yolk factor, but lipolytic activity on Tween 80 is negative.</s><s>They are hyaluronidase positive and staphylokinase negative.</s><s>They reduce tellurite.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The strains of <i>S. aureus</i> subsp. <i>anaerobius</i> are pathogenic for sheep, in which they produce the abscess disease, and experimentally for goats (3-3, but not for mice, guinea pigs, or rabbits (2-5,7-11, 37; De la Fuente and Suarez, in press).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cultural characteristics, the pathogenicity, and some biochemical properties of <i>S. mireus</i> subsp. <i>anaerobius</i> are similar to those of the organism studied by Aynaud (2-5) and Carre (9-11) and subsequently named “<i>M. pyogenes ovis</i>” (7) and “<i>M. abscedens ovis</i>” (25).</s><s>Contrary to the description of “<i>M. pyogenes ovis</i>” by Benito and Borrel and the results of the present study, Joubert found that “<i>M. abscedens ovis</i>” did not produce hemolysins, coagulase, or proteases.</s><s>The organism studied by Shirlaw and Ashford (37) closely resembles <i>S. aureus</i> subsp. <i>anaerobius</i>, but it did not produce coagulase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>None of the strains studied showed production of enterotoxins A through E by the methods used.</s></p><p class="description"><s>When we used the API-ZYM tests, all <i>S. aureus</i> subsp. <i>anaerobius</i> strains exhibited strong esterase-lipase and acid phosphatase activities and moderate phosphoamidase and alkaline phosphatase activities.</s><s>All strains were negative for lipase, leucine aminopeptidase, valine aminopeptidase, cystine aminopeptidase, trypsin-like protease, chymotrypsin-like protease, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase, and α-fucosidase activities.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The strains were very susceptible to lysostaphin (minimal inhibitory concentration, 12.5 μg/ml) and resistant to lysozyme (minimal inhibitory concentration, 1,000 μg/ml).</s><s>Agar disk diffusion tests indicated that all of the strains were susceptible to novobiocin, penicillin G, methicillin, cephalothin, gentamicin, tetracycline, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, and vancomycin.</s><s>Growth was inhibited in a medium supplemented with 25 μg of furazolidone per ml.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains studied exhibited the same cell wall composition as <i>S. aureus</i> (i.e., peptidoglycan type L-LysGly<sub>5-6</sub> and ribitol teichoic acid substituted with N-acetylglucosamine).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Protein A was not detected by a passive hemagglutination method (40), using the commercial reagent AUREA-KIT (bio-Merieux).</s></p><p class="description"><s>None of the 20 selected strains tested was susceptible to phages of the human <i>S. aureus</i> typing set.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine contents of the DNAs, as determined by melting temperature in five strains (strains MVF-7<sup>T</sup>, MVF-25, MVF-39, MVF-41, and MVF-43) ranged from 31.5 to 32.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>S. aureus</i> subsp. <i>anaerobius</i> can be distinguished from all other staphylococci primarily by its weak or negative aerobic growth, negative catalase activity, and negative benzidine test. <i>S. aureus</i> subsp. <i>anaerobius</i> is easily differentiated from the anaerobic species <i>S. succharolyticus</i> by colonial morphology, catalase activity, the benzidine test, coagulase and thermonuclease production, and hemolytic activity.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Simple characters that are useful in identification of <i>S. aureus</i> subsp. <i>anaerobius</i> and separation of this taxon from other coagulase-psotive staphylococcal species and subspecies are listed in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The characteristics of type strain MVF 7 are the same as those described above for the subspecies; the guanine-plus-cytosine content of its DNA is 31.7 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>