<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3716_nm.907" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.907" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.907" rank="species">Asaia krungthepensis</organism><reference id="rid.3716"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yukphan</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Potacharoen</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanasupawat</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanticharoen</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamada</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Asaia krungthepensis sp. nov., an acetic acid bacterium in the alpha-Proteobacteria</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>313</fpage><lpage>316</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02734-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15023938</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Asaia krungthepensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Asaia krungthepensis</em> (krung.thep.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>krungthepensis</em> of or pertaining to Krungthep, the Thai name of Bangkok, Thailand, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative rods, measuring 0·6–1·0×1·0–2·5 μm on GECA medium.</s><s>Motile with peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Colonies are pink, shiny, smooth and raised with an entire margin on GECA medium.</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Grows at pH 3·0 and 3·5 at 30 °C on CaCO<sub>3</sub>- and agar-free GECA medium.</s><s>Oxidizes acetate and lactate to carbon dioxide and water, but the activity is not intense.</s><s>No production of acetic acid from ethanol.</s><s>No growth on methanol.</s><s>Produces 2-keto-d-gluconate and 5-keto-d-gluconate from d-glucose, but not 2,5-diketo-d-gluconate.</s><s>Grows on glutamate agar and mannitol agar.</s><s>Vigorous growth on a vitamin-free glucose/(NH<sub>4</sub>)<sub>2</sub>SO<sub>4</sub> medium, but not on a vitamin-free ethanol/(NH<sub>4</sub>)<sub>2</sub>SO<sub>4</sub> medium.</s><s>Produces dihydroxyacetone.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, d-mannose, d-galactose, d-fructose, l-sorbose, d-xylose, l-arabinose, l-rhamnose, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, dulcitol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, glycerol, melibiose and sucrose.</s><s>Acid production is weak from d-arabinose, maltose and raffinose and acid is not produced from lactose or ethanol.</s><s>Grows on d-glucose, d-galactose, d-fructose, l-sorbose, d-xylose, l-arabinose, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, dulcitol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, glycerol and sucrose, but grows hardly at all on d-mannose, d-arabinose, l-rhamnose, melibiose and raffinose.</s><s>No growth is shown on lactose and ethanol.</s><s>Grows on maltose, but the growth is not intense.</s><s>The major ubiquinone is Q<sub>10</sub>.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 60·2–60·5 mol%, with a range of 0·3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, isolate AA08<sup>T</sup>, has a DNA G+C content of 60·3 mol% and was isolated from a heliconia flower collected in Bangkok, Thailand.</s><s>The type strain has been deposited in the BIOTEC Culture Collection, BIOTEC Central Research Unit, National Centre for Genetic Engineering and Biotechnology, National Science and Technology Development Agency, Pathumthani, Thailand, as BCC 12978<sup>T</sup>, in the culture collection of the National Biological Resource Centre, Department of Biotechnology, National Institute of Technology and Evaluation, Kisarazu, Chiba-ken, Japan, as NBRC 100057<sup>T</sup>, in the NODAI Culture Collection, Tokyo University of Agriculture, Setagaya-ku, Tokyo, Japan, as NRIC 0535<sup>T</sup> and in the culture collection of the Thailand Institute of Scientific and Technological Research, Bangkok, Thailand, as TISTR 1524<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>