<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2656_nm.962" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.962" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.962" rank="species">Rickettsia helvetica</organism><reference id="rid.2656"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Beati</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Péter</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Burgdorfer</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Aeschlimann</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Raoult</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Confirmation that Rickettsia helvetica sp. nov. is a distinct species of the spotted fever group of rickettsiae.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>521</fpage><lpage>526</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-3-521</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8102245</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rickettsia helvetica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rickettsia helvetica</i> (hel.ve'ti.ca. N.L. adj. <i>helvetica</i>, pertaining to Helvetia, the Latin name of Switzerland, where the <i>I. ricinus</i> ticks providing the first isolates were collected)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Rickettsia helvetica</i> is an obligately intracellular bacterium which grows in several organs of the tick <i>I. ricinus</i> and in Vero, L929, and chicken embryo fibroblasts cells, as well as in yolk sacs.</s><s>It can be cultured in Earle’s minimum essential medium supplemented with 4% fetal calf serum and 2 mM L-glutamine at 32°C.</s><s>Infected cells stained by the Gimenez method are diplococci or rod shaped (4).</s><s>As determined by electron microscopy (4, 8), <i>R. helvetica</i> is free in the cytoplasm and has a trilaminar cell wall, a microcapsular layer, a prominent plasma membrane, and occasionally a slime layer.</s><s>The cytoplasm contains ribosomes, and the nuclear material may appear to be reticulated.</s><s>The presence of the organism can be demonstrated by an indirect MIF assay performed with polyclonal mouse sera.</s><s>Mouse antisera against <i>R. helvetica</i> show little or no (4) cross-reactivity with other SFG rickettsiae.</s><s>The SDS-PAGE proteins profiles are distinct from those of other SFG rickettsiae, and Western blots also exhibit unique profiles.</s><s>The organism is pathogenic for some rodents, including <i>Microtus pennsylvanicus</i>, <i>Microtus awalis</i>, and <i>Apodernus flavicollis</i> (12).</s><s>No information is available about the possible pathogenicity of this organism for other animals or humans.</s><s>Although high seroprevalence (9.5 to 32.5%) of antibodies to SFG rickettsiae has been observed among wild and domestic animals in Switzerland, there is no information about possible mammalian reservoirs (13).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain C3 (Reference Center for Rickettsioses, Marseille, France).</s><s>It is one of the first strains of this species isolated at the Rocky Mountain Laboratories from <i>I. ricinus</i> ticks collected in the Staatswald, Bern, Switzerland.</s></p></content></protolog>