<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4420_nm.4328" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4328" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4328" rank="species">Desulfosporosinus meridiei</organism><reference id="rid.4420"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Robertson</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Franzmann</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mee</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Desulfosporosinus meridiei sp. nov., a spore-forming sulfate-reducing bacterium isolated from gasolene-contaminated groundwater.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>133</fpage><lpage>140</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11211250</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Desulfosporosinus meridiei</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Desulfosporosinus meridiei</i> (me.ri'die.i. M.L. n. <i>meridies</i> south; L. fem. gen. n. <i>meridiei</i> of the south, referring to its isolation in the Southern Hemisphere)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative/Gram-variable curved rods with multilayered cell wall.</s><s>Cells are 0.7-1.1 μm in width and generally 2.3-4.2 μm in length, cells of some strains reaching up to 13 μm in length.</s><s>Cells occur singly or in chains of two or more cells, are motile and have a single lateral flagellum.</s><s>Endospores are produced; they are oval and subterminal and sometimes cause the cells to swell.</s><s>Sulfate, sulfite, thiosulfate, elemental sulfur, DMSO and Fe(III) serve as electron acceptors in the presence of lactate.</s><s>Nitrate reduction is variable (3 out of 7 strains, type strain negative).</s><s>Manganese (IV) and arsenic (V) are not used as electron acceptors.</s><s>In the presence of sulfate and thiosulfate, the following compounds are used as carbon sources and electron donors: H<sub>2</sub>/CO<sub>2</sub>­1 mM acetate, pyruvate, lactate, ethanol, formate (3 out of 7 strains, type strain positive), caproate (1 out of 7 strains, type strain negative), caprylate (4 out of 7 strains, type strain negative), methanol (2 out of 7 strains, type strain positive), syringic acid (3 out of 7 strains, type strain positive), H<sub>2</sub>/CO<sub>2</sub> (only type strain tested), butyrate (2 out of 2 strains, including type strain), caprate (2 out of 2 strains, including type strain) and laurate (2 out of 2 strains, including type strain).</s><s>The following compounds are not used as carbon sources and electron donors in the presence of sulfate and thiosulfate: acetate, propionate, fumarate, malate, benzoate, valerate (2 strains tested, including type strain), fructose (2 strains tested, including type strain) and 3,4,5-trimethylbenzoic acid (2 strains tested, including type strain).</s><s>The following compounds are used as carbon and energy sources in the absence of an electron acceptor (2 strains tested, including type strain): lactate, pyruvate, ethanol, methanol (1 out of 2 strains, type strain positive).</s><s>Perchloroethene is reduced in the presence of sulfate and pyruvate.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is between 10 and 37 °C.</s><s>The upper limit of salt tolerance is 4% NaCl.</s><s>The predominant whole-cell fatty acids are 16:1<i />9, 16:0, 14:0 and 18:1<i>cis</i>11.</s><s>Both iso- and anteiso-branched-chain fatty acids are present, as well as trace amounts of cyclopropane fatty acids in most strains (cyclo17:0, 6 out of 7 strains, type strain positive; cyclo19:0, 3 out of 7 strains, type strain negative).</s><s>The G+­C content of the DNA is 46.8-46.9 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is strain S10<sup>T</sup>, and it has been deposited with the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen (accession no. DSM 13257<sup>T</sup>) and the National Collection of Industrial and Marine Bacteria (accession no. NCIMB 13706<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>