<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1889_nm.11094" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11094" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11094" rank="species">Syntrophomonas zehnderi</organism><reference id="rid.1889"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sousa</surname><given-names>D.Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Smidt</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Alves</surname><given-names>M.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stams</surname><given-names>A.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Syntrophomonas zehnderi sp. nov., an anaerobe that degrades long-chain fatty acids in co-culture with Methanobacterium formicicum.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>609</fpage><lpage>615</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64734-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17329794</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Syntrophomonas zehnderi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Syntrophomonas zehnderi</em> (zehn′de.ri. N.L. masc. gen. n. <em>zehnderi</em> of Zehnder, named after Alexander J. B. Zehnder, who contributed to our present knowledge of the microbiology of microbial processes in methanogenic bioreactors).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are slightly curved rods (approximately 0.4–0.7 μm in width and 2.0–4.0 μm in length) and show a variable response to Gram staining.</s><s>Cells have a slight twitching motility and spore formation is observed during growth on oleate in co-culture with a methanogen that utilizes hydrogen and formate.</s><s>In addition to oleate, a mono-unsaturated fatty acid (C<sub>18 : 1</sub>), straight-chain fatty acids with C<sub>4 : 0</sub> to C<sub>18 : 0</sub> carbon atoms can be used as sole carbon and energy sources, in co-culture with <em>Methanobacterium formicicum</em> DSM 1535<sup>NT</sup>.</s><s>Grows at pH 7.0 and 25–40 °C in co-culture with hydrogenophilic archaea.</s><s>Organic supplements are not required for growth.</s><s>Even-numbered fatty acids are degraded to acetate and (presumably) hydrogen, whereas degradation of odd-numbered fatty acids also yields propionate.</s><s>Acetate, propionate and branched-chain fatty acids, such as isobutyrate, isovalerate and isocaproate, do not support growth of the co-culture.</s><s>Yeast extract, tryptone, peptone, glucose, lactate, pyruvate, fumarate, malate, succinate, acetate, propionate, crotonate, glucose, fructose, lactose, xylose, ribose, methanol, ethanol, glutamate, glycine plus alanine and proline plus alanine do not support growth.</s><s>Sulfate, thiosulfate, sulfite, nitrate, Fe(III) EDTA, fumarate and crotonate do not act as electron acceptors for oleate or butyrate oxidation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is OL-4<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 17840<sup>T</sup>=JCM 13948<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated in co-culture with <em>Methanobacterium formicicum</em> DSM 1535<sup>NT</sup>, in Wageningen, The Netherlands, from an oleate-degrading culture enriched from anaerobic sludge sampled from an EGSB reactor used to treat oleate-based effluent (University of Minho, Braga, Portugal).</s></p></content></protolog>