<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7354_nm.1323" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1323" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1307" rank="species">Allorhizobium undicola</organism><reference id="rid.7354"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>de Lajudie</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Laurent-Fulele</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Willems</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Torck</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coopman</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dreyfus</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillis</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Allorhizobium undicola gen. nov., sp. nov., nitrogen-fixing bacteria that efficiently nodulate Neptunia natans in Senegal.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>1277</fpage><lpage>1290</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-4-1277</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9828428</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Allorhizobium undicola</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Allorhizobium undicola</i> (un.di'co.la. L. n. <i>unda</i> water; L. suff. <i>cola</i> dweller; L. n. <i>undicola</i> water-dweller, referring to the isolation of these strains from nodules of the aquatic plant <i>Neptunia natans</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains have all the characteristics of the genus <i>Allorhizobium</i>.</s><s>They grow fast and form colonies of 0.5-3 mm diameter within 1-2 d on YMA.</s><s>Colonies are round, creamy, convex to drop-like, beige-coloured; margin and surface have a smooth aspect.</s><s>Aerobic, Gram-negative, non-spore-forming rods that are 0.5-0.7 μm wide by 2-4 μm long.</s><s>Motile in liquid medium.</s><s>A wide range of carbohydrates, organic acids and amino acids are utilized as sole carbon sources for growth (Table 3).</s><s>Discriminating features from related species are given in Table 3.</s><s>Strains are 3-ketolactosenegative.</s><s>Strains can induce nitrogen-fixing nodules on their original host <i>N. natans</i> and can also nodulate <i>Medicago sativa</i>, <i>Acacia senegal</i>, <i>Acacia seyal</i>, <i>Acacia tortilis</i> subsp. <i>raddiana</i>, <i>Lotus arabicus</i> and <i>Faidherbia albida</i>, but nodules do not always fix nitrogen.</s><s>No strain was found to nodulate <i>Sesbania rostrata</i>, <i>Sesbania pubescens</i>, <i>Sesbania grandiflora</i>, <i>Vigna unguiculuta</i> or <i>Macroptilium atropurpureum</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>They can be differentiated by SDS-PAGE of their total cellular proteins, and at the molecular level by PCRRFLP profiles of the ITS and the sequence of their 16s rRNA gene.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The well-studied strain ORS 992<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 11875), isolated from <i>N. nutans</i> in Senegal, is designated as the type strain and its features are given in Tables 2 and 3.</s><s>The G + C content of ORS 992<sup>T</sup> is 60.1 mol %.</s><s>All <i>Allorhizobium undicola</i> strains have been deposited in the Culture Collection of the Laboratorium voor Microbiologie, University of Gent, in the Culture Collection of the Laboratory of Soil Microbiology, ORSTOM, Dakar, Senegal, and in the Culture Collection of LSTM, CIRAD-ORSTOM, Baillarguet, France.</s></p></content></protolog>