<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3634_nm.792" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.792" rank="genus">Chlorobaculum</organism><reference id="rid.3634"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic taxonomy of the family Chlorobiaceae on the basis of 16S rRNA and fmo (Fenna-Matthews-Olson protein) gene sequences.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>941</fpage><lpage>951</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02403-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12892110</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chlorobaculum</em> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chlorobaculum</em> (Chlo.ro.ba′cu.lum. Gr. adj. <em>chloros</em> green; L. n. <em>baculum</em> rod; N.L. neut. n. <em>Chlorobaculum</em> the green rod).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The genus <em>Chlorobaculum</em> comprises green sulfur bacteria with vibrioid or rod-shaped cells that develop singly.</s><s>Some species and strains may contain gas vesicles.</s><s>The cell size ranges from 0·3 to 1·1 μm in width.</s><s>Photosynthetic pigments are BChl <em>c</em> and <em>d</em> or BChl <em>e</em>, with carotenoids of the chlorobactene series in green strains and of the isorenieratene series in brown strains.</s><s>Sodium chloride may be required for growth.</s><s>Vitamin B<sub>12</sub> is required as a growth factor by most species.</s><s>The fatty acid composition is characterized by approximately 21–25 % C<sub>14 : 0</sub> and approximately 43 % C<sub>16 : 1</sub>.</s><s>The genus comprises those strains and species that previously belonged to the genus <em>Chlorobium</em>, but form phylogenetic group 4 of the green sulfur bacteria, according to Alexander <em>et al.</em> (2002).</s><s>Photolithoautotrophic growth occurs under anoxic conditions in the light, with reduced sulfur compounds such as sulfide, elemental sulfur and thiosulfate as electron donors.</s><s>During oxidation of sulfide, elemental sulfur is transiently deposited outside cells.</s><s>Final oxidation product is sulfate.</s><s>In the presence of sulfide and bicarbonate, simple organic substrates are photoassimilated.</s><s>Obligately phototrophic and strictly anaerobic.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 54·0–58·1 mol% (Bd).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <em>Chlorobaculum tepidum</em> comb. nov. (<em>Chlorobium tepidum</em> Wahlund <em>et al.</em> 1996, 1189).</s></p></content></protolog>