<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4194_nm.317" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.317" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.317" rank="species">Halorhabdus utahensis</organism><reference id="rid.4194"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wainø</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ingvorsen</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halorhabdus utahensis gen. nov., sp. nov., an aerobic, extremely halophilic member of the Archaea from Great Salt Lake, Utah.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>183</fpage><lpage>190</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10826803</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Halorhabdus utahensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Halorhabdus utahensis</i> (u'tah.ensis. M.L. n. pertaining to the state of Utah, USA, where the strain was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of <i>Halorhabdus utahensis</i> is identical to that given above for the genus, with the following additions.</s><s>The following substrates (0.2%, w/v) are utilized for growth: glucose, xylose and fructose.</s><s>No growth on amylose, arginine, D-arabinose, D-galactose, lactose, maltose, sucrose, Na-acetate, Na-citrate, Na-formiate, Na-D-glucuronate, Na-lactate, Na-pyruvate, N-acetyl-glucosamine, L-alanine, betaine, L-lysine, phenylalanine, L-proline, L-serine, acetamide, ethanol, glycerol, methanol, D-sorbitol, glycogen, peptone, yeast extract, starch, casein, gelatin or Tween 80.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed.</s><s>No hydrolysis of gelatin or starch.</s><s>Does not produce protease or urease.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Does not produce arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase or tryptophan deaminase.</s><s>The G+­C content of the DNA of the only strain known in the species is 64 mol%.</s><s>The type strain, strain AX-2<sup>T</sup>, isolated from Great Salt Lake, UT, USA, has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen GmbH (Braunschweig, Germany) as strain DSM 12940<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>