<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6482_nm.7965" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7965" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7965" rank="species">Bacteroides merdae</organism><reference id="rid.6482"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>W.E.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>L.V.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacteroides caccae sp. nov., Bacteroides merdae sp. nov., and Bacteroides stercoris sp. nov. isolated from human feces.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>499</fpage><lpage>501</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacteroides merdae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacteroides merdae</i> (mer'dae, L. gen. n. <i>merdae</i> of feces, referring to source of isolate)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Previously referred to as "T4-1" DNA homology group (3, 4).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells of the type strain from peptone-yeast extract broth cultures are 1.6 by 3.1 to 12 μm and occur singly or in pairs or short chains.</s><s>Surface colonies on supplemented brain heart infusion blood agar plates (1) are 0.5 to 1.0 mm in diameter, circular to slightly irregular, entire, convex, white, shiny, and smooth.</s><s>Rabbit blood is slightly hemolyzed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Glucose broth cultures are turbid with a smooth sediment and have a final pH of 5.3.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 37°C.</s><s>The type strain reduces neutral red and resazurin and produces hydrogen sulfide after incubation for 5 days.</s></p><p class="description"><s>From peptone-yeast extract-glucose broth cultures, major a.mounts of succinate and acetate, often with trace amounts of propionate, isobutyrate, or isovalerate, are detected; no hydrogen, or only a trace amount, is detected in headspace gas.</s><s>Pyruvate is converted to acetate and propionate.</s><s>Lactate, threonine, and gluconate are not utilized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Other characteristics of the species are given in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Characteristics by which <i>B. merdae</i> can be differentiated from phenotypically similar <i>Bacteroides</i> species are given in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: ATCC 43184 (VPI T4-1).</s><s>The G + C content of the DNA is 44 mol% for the type strain and 43 to 46 mol% for the nine other strains examined (3).</s></p></content></protolog>