<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6800_nm.8232" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8232" rank="genus">Pedobacter</organism><reference id="rid.6800"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Steyn</surname><given-names>P.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Segers</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sandra</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Joubert</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Classification of heparinolytic bacteria into a new genus, Pedobacter, comprising four species: Pedobacter heparinus comb. nov., Pedobacter piscium comb. nov., Pedobacter africanus sp. nov. and Pedobacter saltans sp. nov. proposal of the family Sphingobacteriaceae fam. nov.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>165</fpage><lpage>177</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-1-165</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9542086</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pedobacter</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pedobacter</i> (Pe'do.bac.ter. Gr. n. <i>pedon</i> soil; M.L. n. <i>bacter</i> from the Gr. n. baktron rod or staff; M.L. masc. n. <i>Pedobacter</i> rod or staff from soil)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on data from this study, as well as on previous descriptions.</s><s>Most strains are heparinase-producing, obligately aerobic, Gram-negative rods, varying in form and length from 0.7 to 6 μm and about 0.5 μm wide with rounded or slightly tapering ends.</s><s>No flagella or pili have been observed.</s><s>Gliding motility has been observed in strains of some species.</s><s>The colour of the colonies on modified Trypticase soy agar (TSA) and on nutrient agar varies from dirty yellow to creamy white.</s><s>Pigments do not give the typical flexirubin reaction with 20% KOH.</s><s>Sizes of the colonies vary from 1 to 5 mm in diameter on both media indicated above.</s><s>On modified TSA, colonies are round, convex or slightly umbonate with entire margins.</s><s>On nutrient agar, colonies are round to slightly irregular and spreading, convex to umbonate to flat with entire to scalloped margins.</s><s>All members (except <i>P. piscium</i>) grow on heparin, which is degraded by inducible enzymes.</s><s>Good growth occurs on nutrient agar or regular and modified TSA, but random isolates may inexplicably loose viability.</s><s>All or most strains contain cytochrome-c oxidase, catalase, acid and alkaline phosphatases, esterase lipase (C8), leucine-arylamidase, α-glucosidase, β-galactosidase, N-acetyl β-glucosaminidase, lysine decarboxylase and phosphoamidase.</s><s>They produce acetoin from pyruvate, degrade chondroitin sulfate, hydrolyse aesculin, and assimilate D-glucose, D-mannose, amygdalin and glucosamine.</s><s>None or almost none of the strains produce H<sub>2</sub>S from thiosulfate and indole from tryptophan.</s><s>Urease, lipase, β-glucuronidase, α-fucosidase, lysine deaminase, arginine dihydrolase, phenylalanine deaminase and tryptophan deaminase are absent.</s><s>No reduction of nitrate, growth on MacConkey agar, or gelatin liquefaction occurs.</s><s>No assimilation or acid production is detected for a large number of substrates tested (Table 5).</s><s>Particular taxa assimilate or produce acid from some carbohydrates, which can be used as differentiating features (Table 5).</s><s>Organic acids, except pyruvate, and a few amino acids and amines are utilized by only some strains.</s><s>Sensitivity to antibiotics is described in Table 6.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All the strains contain iso-15:0, iso-15:0(2-OH), iso-15:0(3-OH), 16:0, 16:1ω5c, C16:1ω7c 16:0(3-OH), iso-17:0 (3-OH) and iso-17:1ω9c as major cellular fatty acids.</s><s>All strains tested contain sphingolipids and the MK-7 menaquinone system.</s><s>The G+ C content is 36-45 mol% (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i>).</s><s>Temperature range is normally between 5 and 30°C but some strains may grow at 37 °C.</s><s>The habitat is soil, activated sludge, or fish.</s><s>The type species is <i>Pedobacter heparinus</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>