<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8233_nm.14193" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14193" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14193" rank="species">Gallibacterium salpingitidis</organism><reference id="rid.8233"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bisgaard</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Korczak</surname><given-names>B.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kuhnert</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bojesen</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christensen</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Classification of the taxon 2 and taxon 3 complex of Bisgaard within Gallibacterium and description of Gallibacterium melopsittaci sp. nov., Gallibacterium trehalosifermentans sp. nov. and Gallibacterium salpingitidis sp. nov.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>735</fpage><lpage>744</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.005694-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19329598</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Gallibacterium salpingitidis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Gallibacterium salpingitidis</em> (sal.pin.gi′ti.dis. N.L. fem. gen. n. <em>salpingitidis</em> from an inflammation of the ovarial tube).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colony morphology is similar to that observed for other species of <em>Gallibacterium</em> and members of the <em>Pasteurellaceae</em> in general.</s><s>Haemolysis and adherence to the agar are not observed.</s><s>The type strain is urease-positive and negative for acid production from (−)-d-sorbitol.</s><s>Five phenotypic characters separate the species from <em>Gallibacterium</em> group V (Table 3).</s><s>Differences that separate the species from the other species reported in this study are stated in the descriptions of those species.</s><s>Finally, differences in acid production from (+)-l-arabinose, trehalose and dulcitol in addition to <em>α</em>-glucosidase activity and haemolysis separate the species from <em>Gallibacterium anatis</em> (Christensen <em>et al.</em>, 2003a).</s><s>Strains have been obtained from reproductive tract lesions in web-footed birds and pericarditis in a cat.</s><s>To avoid confusion with regard to the name, the names ‘<em>Pasteurella salpingitis</em>’ and ‘<em>Actinobacillus salpingitidis</em>’, not included on the Approved Lists of Bacterial Names (Skerman <em>et al.</em>, 1980), refer to <em>Gallibacterium</em> genomospecies 1 and 2 described by Christensen <em>et al.</em> (2003a), whereas <em>Gallibacterium salpingitidis</em> refers to taxon 2 of Bisgaard (1982).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, F150<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 15564<sup>T</sup> =CCUG 36325<sup>T</sup> =NCTC 11414<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from salpingitis in a duck.</s></p></content></protolog>