<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1440_nm.4874" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4874" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4874" rank="species">Bacillus atrophaeus</organism><reference id="rid.1440"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nakamura</surname><given-names>L.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic relationship of black-pigmented Bacillus subtilis strains and a proposal for Bacillus atrophaeus sp. nov.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>295</fpage><lpage>300</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-3-295</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus atrophaeus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus atrophaeus</i> (a.tro.phae´.us L. adj. <i>ater</i>, black; Gr. adj. <i>phaeus</i>, brown; M.L. adj. <i>atrophaeus</i>, dark brown)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Vegetative cells are rods that are 0.5 to 1.0 μm wide by 2.0 to 4.0 μm long (as determined by phase microscopy) and occur singly and in short chains.</s><s>Motile.</s><s>Gram positive.</s><s>Produces ellipsoidal spores centrally or paracentrally in unswollen sporangia.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Agar colonies are opaque, smooth, circular, entire, and 1.0 to 2.0 mm in diameter after 2 days at 28°C.</s><s>A dark brown pigment is formed in 2 to 6 days in media containing an organic nitrogen source.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase is produced.</s><s>Oxidase is not produced.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Acetylmethylcarbinol (Voges-Pros kauer test) is produced.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide, indole, and dihydroxyacetone are not produced.</s><s>The pH in Voges-Proskauer broth ranges from 5.3 to 5.7.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Starch and casein are hydrolyzed.</s><s>Citrate but not propionate is utilized.</s><s>Egg yolk lecithin, Tween 80, and urea are not decomposed.</s><s>The pH in litmus milk is alkaline; casein is digested.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Arginine, lysine, ornithine, phenylalanine, and tyrosine are not decomposed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimum growth temperature ranges from 28 to 30°C, the maximum growth temperature ranges from 50 to 55°C, and the minimum growth temperature ranges from 5 to 10°C.</s><s>Grows at pH 5.6 or 5.7 and in the presence of 7% NaCl.</s><s>Growth is usually inhibited by 0.001% lysozyme.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid but no gas is produced from L-arabinose, D-fructose, D-glucose, mannitol, salicin, sucrose, trehalose, and D-xylose.</s><s>Acid production from cellobiose, D-galactose, maltose, D-mannose, D-ribose, L-rhamnose, and sorbitol is variable.</s><s>Lactose and melibiose are not fermented.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA buoyant density ranges from 1.6946 to 1.6966 g/cm<sup>3</sup>, and the G+C contents determined from these values</s></p><p class="description"><s>are 41 to 43 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description above is virtually identical to that of <i>B. subtilis</i>.</s><s>The new species is differentiated from <i>B. subtilis</i> on the basis of DNA relatedness and multilocus enzyme electrophoresis analyses, as well as pigment production.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated mainly from soil.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain NRS-213, which has been deposited as NRRL NRS-213 in the Agricultural Research Service Culture Collection, Peoria, Ill.</s></p></content></protolog>