<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8270_nm.5826" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5826" rank="suborder">Micrococcineae</organism><reference id="rid.8270"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhi</surname><given-names>X.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>An update of the structure and 16S rRNA gene sequence-based definition of higher ranks of the class Actinobacteria, with the proposal of two new suborders and four new families and emended descriptions of the existing higher taxa.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>589</fpage><lpage>608</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65780-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19244447</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the suborder <em>Micrococcineae</em> Stackebrandt <em>et al.</em> 1997</s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>The pattern of 16S rRNA signatures consists of nucleotides at positions 127 : 234 (A–U), 598 : 640 (U–G), 657 : 749 (U–A), 953 : 1228 (G–C), 986 : 1219 (A–U), 987 : 1218 (A–U) and 1362 (A).</s><s>The suborder contains the families <em>Micrococcaceae</em>, <em>Dermatophilaceae</em>, <em>Beutenbergiaceae</em>, <em>Bogoriellaceae</em>, <em>Brevibacteriaceae</em>, <em>Cellulomonadaceae</em>, <em>Dermabacteraceae</em>, <em>Dermacoccaceae</em>, <em>Intrasporangiaceae</em>, <em>Jonesiaceae</em>, <em>Microbacteriaceae</em>, <em>Promicromonosporaceae</em>, <em>Rarobacteraceae</em>, <em>Sanguibacteraceae</em> and <em>Yaniellaceae</em>.</s><s>The nomenclatural type is the genus <em>Micrococcus</em> Cohn 1872.</s><s>Patterns of 16S rRNA signature nucleotides that define families of the suborder <em>Micrococcineae</em> are shown in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Patterns of 16S rRNA signature nucleotides that define families of the suborder <em>Micrococcineae</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Families: 1, <em>Beutenbergiaceae</em>; 2, <em>Bogoriellaceae</em>; 3, <em>Brevibacteriaceae</em>; 4, <em>Cellulomonadaceae</em>; 5, <em>Dermabacteraceae</em>; 6, <em>Dermacoccaceae</em>; 7, <em>Dermatophilaceae</em>; 8, <em>Intrasporangiaceae</em>; 9, <em>Jonesiaceae</em>; 10, <em>Microbacteriaceae</em>; 11, <em>Micrococcaceae</em>; 12, <em>Promicromonosporaceae</em>; 13, <em>Rarobacteraceae</em>; 14, <em>Sanguibacteraceae</em>; 15, <em>Yaniellaceae</em>.</s><s>Residues in lower-case letters are present in some but not all strains.</s></p></content></protolog>