<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4667_nm.930" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.930" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.930" rank="species">Gluconobacter frateurii</organism><reference id="rid.4667"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mason</surname><given-names>L.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Claus</surname><given-names>G.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phenotypic characteristics correlated with deoxyribonucleic acid sequence similarities for three species of Gluconobacter: G. oxydans, Henneberg 1897 De Ley 1961, G. frateurii sp. nov., emend G. asaii sp. nov.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>174</fpage><lpage>184</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-2-174</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Gluconobacter frateurii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Gluconobacter frateurii</i> (fra.teur'i.i. M.L. n. <i>frateurii</i>, of Joseph Frateur [1903-19741, eminent Belgian microbiologist, who is well known for his classic study of the acetic acid bacteria [8])</s></p><p class="description"><s>The characteristics are as given previously for the genus (7).</s><s>In addition, all strains in this species form a DNA-DNA homology group when strain IFO 3264<sup>T</sup> is used as the reference strain (14).</s><s>When our methods are used, all strains grow to an OD of 1.0 U or more after 24 h of incubation and three passages (24 h of incubation each) in nicotinate-deficient media (except strain IFO 3272, which seems to have unusual nutritional requirements [Table 4]), and all strains grow to an OD of 1.0 U or more after 24 h when either ribitiol or arabitol is the primary carbon source (Table 4).</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 53 to 55 mol% (14).</s><s>Representative strains are ATCC 12302, ATCC 15178, ATCC 15180, IFO 3251, IFO 3254, IFO 3268, IFO 3270, and IFO 3286.</s><s>The type strain is strain ATCC 49207 (= IFO 3264).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Further description of the type strain.</s><s>When grown as described in Materials and Methods, strain ATCC 49207T (=IFO 3264<sup>T</sup>) forms cream-colored colonies that have convex elevations, glistening surfaces, a granular internal appearance, slightly undulating edges, and diameters of 1 mm.</s><s>In addition to having the characteristics described previously for the genus (7), strain ATCC 49207<sup>T</sup> has the following Characteristics: (i) 21% DNA-DNA homology with the type strain of the genus, strain ATCC 19357 (Micales, M.S. thesis); (ii) 30% DNA-DNA homology with group III reference strain, IFO 3276a (14); and (iii) 70% DNA-DNA homology with strain ATCC 12302 (14), another group II strain (<i>G. frateurii</i>).</s><s>When strain ATCC 49207<sup>T</sup> is grown according to our methods, it has the following characteristics: grows to an OD of 1.5 U or more after three passages (24 h of incubation each) in nicotinate-deficient media (Table 5); and grows to an OD of 2.5 u or more after 24 h of incubation in media containing ribitol or arabitol as the primary carbon source (Table 3).</s><s>In addition to the five differential characteristics noted above, when strain IFO 3264<sup>T</sup> is grown according to our methods, it has the following additional properties (L.</s><s>M.</s><s>Jones-Mason, M.S. thesis, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, 1987): grows to an OD of more than 1.0 U within 24 h in media containing glucose or <i>myo</i>-inositol as the primary carbon source; grows to an OD of more than 3.0 U within 24 h in media containing xylitol but fails to grow to an OD of more than 0.40 U within 24 h in media containing sucrose as the primary carbon source; grows to an OD of 0.90 ± 0.17 U after 48 h of incubation in media containing 17% glucose; and grows to an OD of 1.85 ± 0.17 U after 48 h of incubation in medium (1% mannitol, 1% yeast extract, 1% peptone) containing 1.0% NaCl.</s></p></content></protolog>