<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1352_nm.11681" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11681" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6252" rank="species">Tsukamurella paurometabolum</organism><reference id="rid.1352"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Smida</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dorsch</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Tsukamurella gen. nov. harboring Corynebacterium paurometabolum and Rhodococcus aurantiacus.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>385</fpage><lpage>391</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-4-385</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Tsukamurella paurometabolum</i> (Steinhaus 1941) comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Tsukamurella paurometabolum</i> (pau.ro. me.ta´bo.lum. Gr.adj. <i>pairs</i>, little; Gr.adj. <i>metabolus</i>, changeable; M.L. neut.adj, <i>paurometabolum</i> little changeable)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on data from references 1, 8, 13, 21, 25, and 26.</s><s>In addition to the characteristics of the genus the salient characteristics are given below.</s><s>Cells are straight to slightly curved rods (0.5 to 0.8 by 1.0 to 5 μm) and occur singly, in pairs, or in masses.</s><s>Coccobacillary forms occur.</s><s>Colonies are small (diameter, 0.5 to 2.0 mm) and convex, have entire edges (sometimes rhizoidal), are dryish but easily emulsified and are white to creamy to orange in color.</s><s>Metachromic granules may be formed.</s><s>Growth at 10 and 35°C, but not at 45°C.</s><s>Some strains do not grow at 37°C.</s><s>Does not survive heating at 60°C for 15 min.</s><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Some strains produce acid from fructose, galactose, glucose, glycerol, inositol, mannitol, mannose, sorbitol, sucrose, and trehalose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from L-arabinose, L-rhamnose, or D-xylose.</s><s>Some strains grow on ethanol, fructose, galactose, glucose, inositol, mannitol, mannose, melizitose, sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, xylose, <i>n</i>-butanol, isobutanol, 2,3-butylene glycol, propanol, propylene glycol, citrate, fumarate, malate, pyruvate, and succinate.</s><s>Does not grow on adonitol, arabinose, inulin, lactose, raffinose, or rhamnose.</s><s>Uses acetamide and nicatinamide as sole nitrogen sources but not benzamide.</s><s>Acetamide, glutamate, glucosamine, monoethanolamine, and serine are used as sole sources of carbon and nitrogen.</s><s>Degrades Tween 20, Tween 40, Tween 60, and Tween 80, but not adenine, casein, or elastin.</s><s>Some strains degrade xanthine and tyrosine.</s><s>β-Galactosidase and urease are produced, but arylsulfatase and alpha-esterase are not.</s><s>Pyrazinamidase positive.</s><s>Nitrite is utilized by some strains.</s><s>Resistant to ethambutol (5 μg/ml), 5-fluorouracil (20 μg/ml), mitomycin C (10 μg/ml), and picric acid (0.2%, wt/vol).</s><s>Susceptible to bleomycin (5 μg/ml).</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of DNA is 67 to 68 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from human sputum and the mycetomes and ovaries of bed bugs (<i>Cimex lectularius</i>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain ATCC 8368 (= DSM 20162).</s><s>The type strain does not grow at 37°C, and colonies are creamy white in color.</s><s>Acid is not produced from inositol, mannitol, mannose, sorbitol, or trehalose.</s><s>Tyrosine and xanthine are not degraded.</s></p></content></protolog>