<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6429_nm.4068" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4068" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4068" rank="species">Anaerotruncus colihominis</organism><reference id="rid.6429"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Song</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Molitoris</surname><given-names>D.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vaisanen</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Finegold</surname><given-names>S.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Anaerotruncus colihominis gen. nov., sp. nov., from human faeces.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>413</fpage><lpage>417</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02653-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15023953</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Anaerotruncus colihominis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Anaerotruncus colihominis</em> (co.li.ho′mi.nis. L. n. <em>colum</em> colon; L. gen. n. <em>hominis</em> of man; N.L. gen. n. <em>colihominis</em> of the gut of man).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-spore-forming, thin rods, approximately 0·5×2–5 μm.</s><s>After 48 h anaerobic incubation at 37 °C under an N<sub>2</sub>/CO<sub>2</sub> (80 : 20, v/v) gas phase, colonies are 2–3 mm in diameter, grey, entire-edged, irregularly shaped, low pyramidal in profile and translucent.</s><s>pH range for growth is 5·5–11 and growth temperature range is 36–40 °C.</s><s>Catalase-negative; nitrate is not reduced to nitrite, but indole is produced.</s><s>End products of metabolism from peptone/yeast broth are acetic and butyric acids.</s><s>Aesculin, gelatin and urea are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Able to grow in peptone/yeast broth supplemented with 1 % glucose, fructose, mannose or cellobiose, but there is no growth in peptone/yeast broth alone or supplemented with arabinose, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, starch or xylose.</s><s>By using the Biolog system, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-mannosamine, arbutin, d-cellobiose, dextrin, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-galacturonic acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannose, methyl 3-d-glucose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, palatinose, d-trehalose and turanose are utilized.</s><s><em>α</em>-Ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, l-malic acid, pyruvic acid and pyruvic acid methyl ester are also utilized.</s><s>Serine, l-valine, 2′-deoxyadenosine, inosine, thymidine and uridine are also utilized for growth.</s><s>By using the API ZYM and Rapid ID 32A systems, acid phosphatase and indole activities are detected, but <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, alanine arylamidase, alkaline phosphatase, arginine arylamidase, arginine dehydrolase, <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, ester lipase C8, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, chymotrypsin, alanine arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, phosphoamidase, trypsin, cystine arylamidase, esterase C4, <em>β</em>-galactosidase-6-phosphate, glutamic acid decarboxylase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, lipase C14, leucine arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, proline arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, serine arylamidase, tyrosine arylamidase and valine arylamidase activities are not detected.</s><s>Sensitive to vancomycin (5 μg) and kanamycin (1000 μg), but resistant to colistin sulphate (10 μg) identification discs.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 54 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is WAL 14565<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 45055<sup>T</sup>=CIP 107754<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>Isolated from human faecal material.</s><s>Habitat is not known, but is probably the human gut.</s></p></content></protolog>