<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4599_nm.6047" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6047" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6047" rank="species">Microbacterium gubbeenense</organism><reference id="rid.4599"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brennan</surname><given-names>N.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brown</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ward</surname><given-names>A.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beresford</surname><given-names>T.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cogan</surname><given-names>T.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fox</surname><given-names>P.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Microbacterium gubbeenense sp. nov., from the surface of a smear-ripened cheese</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1969</fpage><lpage>1976</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11760936</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Microbacterium gubbeenense</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Microbacterium gubbeenense</i> (gub.been.en'se. N.L. neut. adj. <i>gubbeenense</i> of Gubbeen House, Ireland, where the cheese containing the organism is produced)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of the biochemical and morphological characteristics is based on the results of the study of 11 isolates.</s><s>Colonies on PYA are irregular, cream, matt, slightly raised, 1-5 mm in diameter.</s><s>Gram-positive, catalase-positive, facultative anaerobes, oxidase-negative, small, slender, motile rods, 0.5-2.0 lm in length.</s><s>Many cells are arranged at angles to form V-shapes; no primary branching is observed and a rod/coccus transformation does not occur.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 5, 7, 10 or 12% (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Strains do not grow at 37°C.</s><s>Gluconate, mannose, malate, citrate, propionate and fumarate are assimilated but adipate, caprate, phenylacetate, acetate and lactate are not.</s><s>Acid is produced from arabinose, mannose, glucose, galactose, trehalose, lactose and sucrose but not from rhamnose, melezitose, xylose, inulin, raffinose or ribose.</s><s>Gelatin, Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80 and starch are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Methyl-red and Voges-Proskauer tests are negative and hydrogen sulphide is not produced.</s><s>All isolates are positive for nitrate reductase and β-galactosidase activities but negative for indole production and urease activity.</s><s>The organism produces alkaline phosphatase, esterase (2-naphthyl butyrate as substrate), esterase lipase (2-naphthyl caprylate as substrate), leucine arylamidase (L-leucine 2-naphthylamide as substrate), acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-β-1-phosphohydrolase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase and N-acetylglucosaminidase.</s><s>The organism does not produce lipase (2-naphthyl myristate as substrate), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, β-glucuronidase, chymotrypsin, α-mannosidase, afucosidase or arginine dihydrolase activity.</s><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan is of the B1 type, containing a glycolyl acyl group and L-lysine as the diamino acid.</s><s>The cell wall sugars are rhamnose and galactose and the menaquinones are unsaturated MK-11 and MK- 12.</s><s>The polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol and phosphatidylglycerol mannosides and the major fatty acids are 15:0 anteiso, 17: 0 anteiso and 16:0 iso.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content is 69-75 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is LMGS-19263<sup>T</sup> (=NCIMB30129<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>