<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6299_nm.1760" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1760" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1760" rank="species">Kerstersia gyiorum</organism><reference id="rid.6299"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Coenye</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cnockaert</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Kerstersia gyiorum gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel Alcaligenes faecalis-like organism isolated from human clinical samples, and reclassification of Alcaligenes denitrificans Rüger and Tan 1983 as Achromobacter denitrificans comb. nov.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1825</fpage><lpage>1831</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02609-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14657111</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Kerstersia gyiorum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Kerstersia gyiorum</em> (gy.i.o′rum. Gr. n. <em>gyion</em> limb; N.L. gen. n. <em>gyiorum</em> from the limbs, referring to the fact that the majority of strains were isolated from human leg wounds).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is the same as for the genus.</s><s>Additional characteristics are the assimilation of caprylate and the absence of assimilation of isobutyrate, isovalerate, glutarate, adipate, pimelate, suberate, azelate, sebacate, levulinate, 2-ketoglutarate, citraconate, itaconate, mesaconate, aconitate, l-leucine, l-isoleucine, l-valine, dl-norvaline, l-threonine, l-cysteine and l-methionine.</s><s>The G+C content is 62·7–62·9 mol%.</s><s>The type strain, LMG 5906<sup>T</sup> (=API 184-2-84<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 47000<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a human ankle wound.</s><s>Characteristics for the type strain are the same as described above for the species.</s><s>In addition, the type strain can use l-norleucine.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 62·9 mol%.</s><s>All <em>K. gyiorum</em> strains reported in this study have been deposited in the BCCM/LMG Bacteria Collection (Laboratorium voor Microbiologie, Gent, Belgium) and the CCUG (Department of Clinical Bacteriology, Göteborg, Sweden).</s></p></content></protolog>