<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6102_nm.10247" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10247" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10247" rank="species">Aeromonas sharmana</organism><reference id="rid.6102"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Saha</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chakrabarti</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Aeromonas sharmana sp. nov., isolated from a warm spring</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1905</fpage><lpage>1909</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63972-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16902029</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Aeromonas sharmana</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Aeromonas sharmana</em> (shar.ma′na. N.L. fem. adj. <em>sharmana</em> named after Dr Manju Sharma, a biologist and a great proponent of research on microbial diversity in India).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, facultatively anaerobic, mesophilic, motile, short rods occurring in singly or in pairs.</s><s>Single polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies on TSBA after 36 h growth are round, convex with slightly irregular margins, opaque and whitish in colour without the production of any diffusible pigment.</s><s>Cells are 1–2 μm long and 0.4–0.5 μm wide.</s><s>Oxidase-positive and very weakly positive for catalase.</s><s>Grows at temperatures between 15 and 42 °C, at pH 5.7–8.0 and can tolerate 2 % NaCl.</s><s>Does not produce indole, gas from glucose, H<sub>2</sub>S, gelatinase, phenylalanine deaminase, DNase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase or ornithine decarboxylase.</s><s>Hydrolyses starch, aesculin and ONPG but not casein, urea, fat or Tweens 20, 40 and 80.</s><s>Does not reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Produces acid from arbutin, d-amygdalin, cellobiose, fructose, d-glucose, d-galactose, inulin, d-maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, salicin, sucrose and trehalose but not from adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabinose, l-arabitol, dulcitol, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-melibiose, d-melezitose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, xylitol, d-xylose and l-xylose.</s><s>Utilizes l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-glucose, d-galactose, d-lactose, d-mannose, d-maltose, sucrose and d-xylose (weakly) but not d-arabinose, l-arabitol, arbutin, d-amygdalin, adonitol, dulcitol, glycerol, melezitose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, acetate, citrate, fumarate, glutarate, malate, propionate or succinate as sole carbon sources.</s><s>The type strain is resistant to the vibriostatic compound O/129, lincomycin and methicillin but is susceptible to ampicillin, bacitracin, cephalothin, chloramphenicol, colistin, erythromycin, gentamicin, kanamycin, neomycin, nitrofurantoin, novobiocin, polymyxin B, penicillin G, rifampicin, streptomycin, sulfasomidine and tetracycline.</s><s>The major whole-cell fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (29.0 %), summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or C<sub>15 : 0</sub> iso 2-OH; 29.3 %), C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (24.0 %), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> (6.1 %), summed feature 2 (C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 3-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub> iso I; 5.6 %) and C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (4.7 %).</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content is 60.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, GPTSA-6<sup>T</sup> (=MTCC 7090<sup>T</sup>=DSM 17445<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a water sample from a warm spring in Assam, India.</s></p></content></protolog>