<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12587_nm.21845" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21845" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21845" rank="species">Chryseobacterium yonginense</organism><reference id="rid.12587"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Joung</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Joh</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chryseobacterium yonginense sp. nov., isolated from a mesotrophic artificial lake</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1413</fpage><lpage>1417</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.022590-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20601485</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chryseobacterium yonginense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chryseobacterium yon.gi.nen′se.</em> (yon.gi.nen′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>yonginense</em> of or belonging to Yongin, Korea, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-staining-negative, non-motile, strictly aerobic rods (approximately 0.5–0.6 µm in diameter and 0.8–1.0 µm in length).</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar are circular with entire margins, smooth, pale yellow, transparent and slimy (approximately 5 mm in diameter after 2 days at 30 °C).</s><s>Good growth occurs on MA, TSA and R2A agar.</s><s>No growth occurs on cetrimide agar, DNase test agar or MacConkey agar.</s><s>Growth occurs with 0–2 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 0.5 % NaCl), at pH 7–8 (optimum pH 7) and at 4–30 °C (optimum 30 °C).</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Positive for indole production and gelatin and aesculin hydrolysis, but negative for nitrate reduction, glucose fermentation and arginine dihydrolase, urease and β-galactosidase (API 20 NE).</s><s>Non-diffusible flexirubin and carotenoid pigments are produced.</s><s>With API ZYM, positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, α-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and α-glucosidase, but negative for lipase (C14), trypsin, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase.</s><s>With GN2 MicroPlates, utilizes dextrin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, d-fructose, gentiobiose, α-d-glucose, maltose, melibiose, methyl β-d-glucoside, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucuronic acid, d-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, dl-carnitine, γ-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, α-d-glucose-1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate as sole carbon sources, but does not utilize α-cyclodextrin, glycogen, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, i-erythritol, l-fucose, d-galactose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, lactulose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, turanose, xylitol, succinic acid monomethyl ester, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, α-, β- and γ-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, α-ketobutyric acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol or dl-α-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>The major fatty acids (&#x003E;5 %) are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, summed feature 9 (comprising iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub>ω9<em>c</em> and/or 10-methyl C<sub>16 : 0</sub>) and iso-C<sub>13 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 31.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, HMD1043<sup>T</sup> ( = KCTC 22744<sup>T</sup>  = CECT 7547<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a mesotrophic artificial lake in Wangsan, Yongin, Gyeonggi, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>