<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3343_nm.11675" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11675" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7048" rank="species">Kitasatosporia griseola</organism><reference id="rid.3343"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Takahashi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Iwai</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ōmura</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Two new species of the genus Kitasatosporia, Kitasatosporia phosalacinea sp. nov. and Kitasatosporia griseola sp. nov.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>30</volume><fpage>377</fpage><lpage>387</lpage><source id="120">The Journal of General and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Gen Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-1260</issn><essn>1349-8037</essn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Kitasatosporia griseola</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Kitasatosporia griseola</i> (gri se'o la. M. L. fem. adj. <i>griseola</i> gray)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Species-level classification</s></p><p class="description"><s>The species-level taxonomic studies of the two strains were carried out by comparing them with <i>K. setalba</i>, the type species of <i>Kitasatosporia</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology of aerial mycelia.</s><s>Figure 3 shows scanning electron-micrographs of aerial mycelia of three <i>Kitasatosporia</i> strains grown on glycerol-asparagine agar.</s><s>The morphology of the three strains was almost identical in that the sporophore is Rectiflexibiles and the spore shape is cylindrical.</s><s>However, compared with strain KA-338 and <i>K. setalba</i>, the aerial spores of strain AM-9660 were immature in septation and the spore surface was somewhat wrinkled as shown in Figs. 2a and 3b.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultural characteristics.</s><s>Table 2 shows the cultural characteristics of the three strains.</s><s>Abundant aerial mycelia were observed in these strains grown on yeast extract-malt extract agar, oatmeal agar and inorganic salts-starch agar.</s><s>The aerial mycelia of strain KA-338 and <i>K. setalba</i> was white on most media, and gray in strain AM-9660.</s><s>The three <i>Kitasatosporia</i> strains were different from each other in soluble-pigment production.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Physiological properties and carbon utilization.</s><s>Table 3 shows the physiological properties of three <i>Kitasatosporia</i> strains.</s><s>The strains are mesophiles and grew at pH 5.5-9.0.</s><s>The physiological properties of strain AM-9660 and <i>K. setalba</i> are similar to each other but different from those of strain KA-338 in nitrate reduction; coagulation of milk and antibiotic produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Table 4 shows the carbon utilization by <i>Kitasatosporia</i> strains.</s><s>In addition to carbon sources utilized by <i>K. setalba</i>, strain AM-9660 utilized raffinose, and strain KA-338 utilized raffinose, D-fructose, L-rhamnose and sucrose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>GC contents.</s><s>The GC contents (%) of strains KA-338 and AM-9660, and <i>K. setalba</i> were 66.6, 66.0 and 73.1, respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The taxonomic comparison of the three <i>Kitasatosporia</i> strains is summarized in Table 5.</s><s>They are different from each other in some taxonomic properties.</s><s>Strains KA-338 and AM-9660 differ clearly from <i>K. setalba</i> in GC content, vegetative- mass color, soluble-pigment production and carbon utilization.</s><s>Strain KAFig 338 is different from strain AM-9660 in spore shape, color of aerial mycelium, nitrate reduction, coagulation of milk, utilizable carbons and antibiotics produced.</s><s>It is reasonable to conclude from the above data that strains KA-338 and AM- 9660 are new species of the genus <i>Kitasatosporia</i>, and they are named Kitasatosporia phosalacinea and Kitasatosporia griseola, respectively.</s></p></content></protolog>