<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2125_nm.7859" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7859" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7859" rank="species">Treponema amylovorum</organism><reference id="rid.2125"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wyss</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>B.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schüpbach</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Guggenheim</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Göbel</surname><given-names>U.B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Treponema amylovorum sp. nov., a saccharolytic spirochete of medium size isolated from an advanced human periodontal lesion.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>842</fpage><lpage>845</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-3-842</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9226916</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Treponema amylovorum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Treponema amylovorum</i> (a.my.lo.vo'rum. Gr. n. <i>amylum</i>, starch; L. V. <i>voro</i>, to devour; M. L. adj. <i>amylovorum</i>, starch devouring)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Treponema amylovorum</i> is an intermediate-size, obligately anaerobic, helically coiled, motile treponeme.</s><s>Strain HA2P<sup>T</sup>, which was isolated from subgingival plaque of a deep human periodontal lesion, is designated the type strain and has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection (Rockville, Md.) under accession number ATCC 700288.</s></p><p class="description"><s>As shown in Fig. 1, the cells are ca. 0.25 μm in diameter and approximately 7 μm long, with a wavelength of ca. 1.2 μm and an amplitude of ca. 0.3 μm.</s><s>They have six periplasmic flagella; three flagella originate at each cell end, and the flagella overlap in the central region of the cell (i.e., flagellation type 3:6:3).</s><s>In liquid media of low viscosity cells exhibit active cellular rotation and jerky flexing but no directional motility.</s><s>Translational movement, however, is seen in media of higher viscosity or when cells creep along a surface.</s><s>Cells can be stored at temperatures below - 70°C in medium supplemented with 10 to 20% glycerol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(i) Colonies.</s><s>When streaked onto OMIZ-Pat/HuS agarose plates, <i>T. amylovorum</i> forms dense, off-white, subsurface colonies up to 3 mm in diameter within 5 days of inoculation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(ii) Cultural characteristics. <i>T. amylovorum</i> does not grow in chemically defined OMIZ-W1 medium and requires the addition of yeast extract and/or Neopeptone (or fractions thereof).</s><s>Addition of 1% human serum is highly stimulatory, whereas FBS or higher concentrations of human serum are inhibitory.</s><s>Growth of strain HA2P<sup>T</sup> is accompanied by acid production, as judged by phenol red indicator in the medium, and strictly depends on the presence of at least one of the following carbohydrates: glucose, maltose, starch, or glycogen.</s><s>Acid is produced from these carbohydrates.</s><s>None of the other carbohydrates tested (at a concentration of 2 g/liter) support growth; these carbohydrates include D-arabinose, D-cellobiose, D-fructose, D-fucose, D-galactose, D-galacturonic acid, D-glucuronic acid, D-lactose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, D-melibiose, D-ribose, D-sucrose, D-trehalose, D-xylose, L-arabinose, L-fucose, L-rhamnose, L-sorbose, and L-xylose.</s><s>Following the exponential growth phase, with an estimated doubling time of less than 4 h, cells of HA2P<sup>T</sup> rapidly loose viability and disintegrate into small vesicles.</s><s>Catalase activity is not observed.</s><s>With API ZYM strips the only (weak) enzyme activities detected in cells grown on glucose are alkaline and acid phosphatases, naphtholphosphohydrolase, C4 esterase, and α-fucosidase.</s><s>In cells grown on either maltose, starch, or glycogen weak α-glucosidase activity is also detected.</s><s>Strain HA2P<sup>T</sup> is resistant to 1 mg of rifampin per liter and 100 mg of fosfomycin per liter.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(iii) Distinguishing characteristics.</s><s>On the basis of a phylogenetic comparison of 16s rRNA sequences, <i>T. amylovorum</i> is a species that is genetically distinct from previously described treponemes.</s><s>Its SDS-PAGE protein and antigen profiles and its Western blot profile are readily distinguished from those of the other five cultivable, oral Treponema species (Fig. 2).</s><s>Furthermore, size and flagellation, as well as rapid flexing motility, clearly distinguish <i>T. amylovorum</i> from other treponeme species, such as <i>T. denticola</i>, <i>T. maltophilum</i>, <i>T. pectinovorum</i>, and <i>T. socranskii</i>.</s><s>In contrast to the two asaccharolytic oral species, <i>T. denticola</i> and <i>T. vincentii</i>, growth of strain HA2P<sup>T</sup> is strictly carbohydrate dependent, and the range of carbohydrates utilized is clearly distinct from the range of carbohydrates utilized by <i>T. maltophilum</i>, <i>T. pectinovorum</i>, and <i>T. socranskii</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>