<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10760_nm.17855" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17855" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.17855" rank="species">Cryobacterium roopkundense</organism><reference id="rid.10760"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Reddy</surname><given-names>G.S.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pradhan</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Manorama</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shivaji</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Cryobacterium roopkundense  sp. nov., a psychrophilic bacterium isolated from glacial soil</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>866</fpage><lpage>870</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.011775-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19661491</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Cryobacterium roopkundense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Cryobacterium roopkundense</em> (ro.op.kun.den′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>roopkundense</em> pertaining to Lake Roopkund, the area from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies of RuGl7<sup>T</sup> on LB agar plates are convex, shiny, 2–3 mm in diameter and are pink in colour.</s><s>Cells are Gram-positive, aerobic, rod-shaped, motile and occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>The cells are approximately 0.8 μm in width and 2.5 μm in length (Fig. 1).</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is between 15 and 18 °C and the optimum pH is 7.0.</s><s>Cells of strain RuGl7<sup>T</sup> are positive for catalase and lipase activities, but negative for hydrolysis of casein and starch, for H<sub>2</sub>S production, and for activities of lysine, arginine- and ornithine decarboxylase, oxidase, urease, phosphatase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and DNase.</s><s>Gives a negative result in the methyl red test, the Voges–Proskauer test and in tests for indole production and phenylalanine deamination.</s><s>Does not produce acid from erythritol, <em>myo-</em>inositol, inulin, d-melibiose, ribose, d-sorbitol, sorbose, trehalose or d-xylose.</s><s>Cells of strain RuGl7<sup>T</sup> can utilize citrate and malonate, but not acetate, adonitol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, d-fructose, galactose, gluconate, d-glucose, glucosamine, glycerol, <em>myo-</em>inositol, inulin, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, melezitose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, raffinose, d-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, sorbitol, l-sorbose, sucrose, trehalose, xylitol or d-xylose.</s><s>Cells are sensitive to the following antibiotics (μg per disc): bacitracin (10), carbenicillin (100), cefotaxime (30), chloramphenicol (30), erythromycin (15), gentamicin-G (30), oleandomycin (15), penicillin-G (10), rifampicin (30), spectinomycin (100), streptomycin (10), tetracycline (30) and colistin (10).</s><s>Additional characteristics of the species are listed in Table 1.</s><s>The major fatty acid is anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The absorption maxima (nm) of the pink pigment are 360, 470 and 490.</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan of strain RuGl7<sup>T</sup> contains 2,4-diaminobutyric acid as the diagnostic diamino acid.</s><s>The major menaquinones are MK-10, MK-11 and MK-12 and the polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglycerol and one unidentified glycolipid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, RuGl7<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 21065<sup>T</sup>=JCM 15131<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil sample from the banks of Lake Roopkund, Himalayan region, India.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of strain RuGl7<sup>T</sup> is 64.7 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>