<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12180_nm.20178" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20178" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20178" rank="species">Chryseobacterium culicis</organism><reference id="rid.12180"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chandel</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prasad</surname><given-names>G.B.K.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shouche</surname><given-names>Y.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Veer</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chryseobacterium culicis sp. nov., isolated from
the midgut of the mosquito Culex quinquefasciatus</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2387</fpage><lpage>2391</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.019794-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19933582</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chryseobacterium culicis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chryseobacterium culicis</em> [cu.li′cis. L. n. <em>culex</em> -<em>icis</em> a gnat, a midge, and also a genus of mosquito (<em>Culex</em>, family Culicidae); N.L. gen. n. <em>culicis</em> of <em>Culex</em>, referring to the isolation of the type strain from <em>Culex quinquefasciatus</em>].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-staining-negative, non-motile, non-spore-forming rods, approx. 1 μm wide and 2 μm long.</s><s>Aerobic, oxidase-positive and catalase-positive.</s><s>Good growth occurs at 11–36 °C after 48 h on NA, brain heart infusion agar and TSA (all Oxoid).</s><s>No growth on MacConkey agar (Oxoid) at 28 °C.</s><s>The type strain is unable to grow at 4 or 45 °C.</s><s>Grows in the presence of 0.5–3.0 % NaCl.</s><s>Colonies on NA are smooth, yellowish, circular, translucent and shiny with entire edges.</s><s>Colonies become mucoid and cannot be identified as single entities after prolonged incubation.</s><s>The yellow pigment of the flexirubin type is non-diffusible and non-fluorescent.</s><s>Produces acid weakly from d-glucose, trehalose and d-mannitol.</s><s>No acid is produced from adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, maltose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, raffinose, l-rhamnose, salicin, d-sorbitol, sucrose or d-xylose.</s><s>Urease activity, indole production and hydrolysis of casein, gelatin, starch, DNA and tyrosine are positive, while hydrogen sulphide production and activities of arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase (ONPG) are negative.</s><s>d-Glucose, maltose, d-mannose, d-fructose and trehalose are utilized as sole sources of carbon.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole sources of carbon: acetate, propionate, <em>N</em>-acetylgalactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, l-arabinose, l-arbutin, cellobiose, d-galactose, gluconate, glycerol, d-mannitol, maltitol, melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, salicin, d-xylose, adonitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-sorbitol, putrescine, <em>cis</em>- and <em>trans</em>-aconitate, 4-aminobutyrate, adipate, azelate, fumarate, glutarate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, itaconate, dl-lactate, 2-oxoglutarate, pyruvate, suberate, citrate, mesaconate, l-alanine, <em>β</em>-alanine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-aspartate, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-proline, l-tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate and phenylacetate.</s><s>The chromogenic substrates <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl (pNP) <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside (weak), pNP <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, bis-pNP phosphate, bis-pNP phenylphosphonate, bis-pNP phosphorylcholine, 2-deoxythymidine-2′-pNP phosphate, l-alanine <em>p</em>-nitroanilide (pNA), <em>γ</em>-l-glutamate pNA and l-proline pNA are hydrolysed. pNP <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside and pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucuronide are not hydrolysed.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids (≥10 %) are iso-15 : 0, summed feature 4 (iso-15 : 0 2-OH and/or 16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>), iso-17 : 1<em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> and iso-17 : 0 3-OH.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is R4-1A<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 25442<sup>T</sup> =CCM 7716<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the midgut of the mosquito <em>Culex quinquefasciatus</em> (a vector of lymphatic filariasis) collected from the filarial endemic region of Raipur (Chattishgarh province), India.</s></p></content></protolog>