<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7231_nm.8062" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8062" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8062" rank="species">Prevotella pallens</organism><reference id="rid.7231"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Könönen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Eerola</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frandsen</surname><given-names>E.V.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jalava</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mättö</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Salmenlinna</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jousimies-Somer</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic characterization and proposal of a new pigmented species to the genus Prevotella: Prevotella pallens sp. nov.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>47</fpage><lpage>51</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-1-47</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9542075</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Prevotella pallens</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Prevotella pallens</i> (pal'lens. L. v. part. <i>pallere</i> to pale, referring to the weak pigmentation of colonies on blood agar plates)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following description is based partly on the results presented in the accompanying paper (6).</s><s>Cells are obligatory anaerobic, non-sporing, non-motile, Gram-negative rods or coccobacilli.</s><s>Cells grown in broth cultures are 0.5-0.8 x 1.2-2 μm.</s><s>Surface colonies on supplemented Brucella sheep blood agar plates after 3 d are 0.8-1.4 mm in diameter, circular, entire, raised convex, smooth and glistening.</s><s>A distinct halo of metallic sheen is seen around the colonies.</s><s>After 3-5 d incubation, colonies are weakly pigmented (cream); on rabbit laked blood agar colonies are tan to light brown exhibiting red fluorescence under long-wave UV light (365 nm).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid is produced from glucose, maltose and sucrose in prereduced anaerobically sterilized peptone-yeast extract broth (PYG).</s><s>Carbohydrate fermentation is not demonstrated from arabinose, cellobiose, aesculin, lactose (except one strain) and xylose.</s><s>Gelatin is liquefied.</s><s>Strains are indole-positive but lipase-negative.</s><s>The major end-products of glucose fermentation are acetic and succinic acids; isovaleric acid is also frequently produced.</s><s>Alkaline and acid phosphatases, phosphohydrolase, α-glucosidase, and α-fucosidase are positive, whereas α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase (except for one strain), β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase and α-mannosidase are negative.</s><s>Table 2 summarizes distinctive biochemical and enzymic key reactions of <i>P. pallens</i> and biochemically and phylogenetically closely related <i>Prevotella</i> species.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15:0</sub>, iso-3-OH C<sub>17:0</sub>, and an unknown cellular fatty acid with equivalent chain-length at 13.570, presented in descending quantitative order.</s><s>The strains are resistant to vancomycin but susceptible to colistin as determined by the special-potency antimicrobial disk profiles.</s><s>Susceptibility to kanamycin, sodium polyanethol sulfonate and penicillin varies.</s><s>Strains with decreased susceptibility to penicillin (&#x003E;40% of strains, including the type strain) produced β-lactamase.</s><s>The type strain of <i>P. pullens</i> is NCTC 13042 (= AHN 10371).</s></p></content></protolog>