<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5741_nm.7845" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7845" rank="genus">Brevinema</organism><reference id="rid.5741"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Defosse</surname><given-names>D.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>R.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Paster</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dewhirst</surname><given-names>F.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fraser</surname><given-names>G.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Brevinema andersonii gen. nov., sp. nov., an infectious spirochete isolated from the short-tailed shrew (Blarina brevicauda) and the white-footed mouse (Peromyscus leucopus).</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>78</fpage><lpage>84</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-45-1-78</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7857811</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Brevinema</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Brevinema</i> (Brev. i. ne' ma. L. adj. <i>brevis</i>, short; Gr. n. <i>nema</i>, thread; N.L. neut. n. <i>Brevinema</i>, a short thread.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following description is based on our data and data obtained from previous studies (1, 5, 12, 13, 17).</s><s>Cells are flexible and helical; they are 0.2 to 0.3 μm in diameter and 4 to 5 μm long.</s><s>One to two waves occur, and the irregular wavelengths of the spirochete cells range from 2 to 3 μm.</s><s>Ultrastructurally, the cells possess traits that are typical of spirochetes.</s><s>They possess an outer envelope, a protoplasmic cylinder, and sheathed periplasmic flagella in a 1-2-1 arrangement.</s><s>Cytoplasmic tubules have not been observed.</s><s>Cells are motile and exhibit flexing, rotational, and translational movements at 30°C.</s><s>Cells stain negatively by Gram reaction.</s><s>While cells are visible by dark-field or phase-contrast microscopy, they cannot be seen when bright-field microscopy is used.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Brevinema</i> strains have unique single-base nucleotide signatures at positions 52 359 (G⋄C) and 783⋄799 (U⋄A) which differentiate them from other major spirochete phylogenetic groups. <i>Brevinema andersonii</i> CT11616<sup>T</sup>, FS47, and MV116 have a distinguishing 16s rRNA sequence corresponding to positions 724 to 750 in <i>E. coli</i> (5'-GGCAGCUACCUAUGCUAAGAUUGACGC-3‘).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Brevinema andersonii</i> is host associated.</s><s>Strains have been isolated from blood and other tissues of short-tailed shrews (<i>Blarina brevicauda</i>) and white-footed mice (<i>Peromyscus leucopus</i>) and are infectious for laboratory mice and Syrian hamsters.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <i>Brevinema andersonii</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>