<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5804_nm.5791" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5791" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5791" rank="species">Actinomyces marimammalium</organism><reference id="rid.5804"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hoyles</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pascual</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Foster</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grainger</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinomyces marimammalium sp. nov., from marine mammals</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>151</fpage><lpage>156</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11211252</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of Actinomyces marimammalium sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Actinomyces marimammalium (ma.ri.mam.ma«li.um. L. neut. n. <i>mare</i> the sea; M.L. neut. gen. pl. n. <i>mammalium</i> of mammals; M.L. <i>marimammalium</i> of marine mammals)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight to slightly curved rods, some of which exhibit branching.</s><s>Cells stain Gram-positive, are non-aciD-fast and non-motile.</s><s>Colonies are grey, entire, circular, convex and pin-point to 0±5 mm in diameter at 48 h.</s><s>Non-haemolytic.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and catalase-negative.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-glucose, maltose, lactose and N-acetyL-β-glucosamine.</s><s>Acid is not produced from L-arabinose, darabitol, cyclodextrin, mannitol, melibiose, melezitose, methyL-β-D-glucopyranoside, pullulan, raffinose, dribose, sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, tagatose or dxylose.</s><s>Acid may or may not be produced from glycogen.</s><s>Aesculin, gelatin and hippurate are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Alanine phenylalanine proline arylamidase, β-galactosidase, β-galacturonidase, leucine arylamidase and glycyl tryptophan arylamidase are produced.</s><s>α-Galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, arginine dihydrolase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, pyrazinamidase, urease, β-mannosidase and pyrolydonyl arylamidase are not produced.</s><s>Activity for alkaline phosphatase may or may not be detected.</s><s>Acetoin is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>The end products of glucose metabolism are acetic, lactic and succinic acids.</s><s>The G+C content of DNA is 66 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from sea mammals (hooded seal, grey seal and harbour porpoise).</s><s>Habitat is not known.</s><s>The type strain is CCUG 41710<sup>T</sup> (CIP 106509<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The type strain exhibits the characteristics of the species and produces acid from glycogen.</s></p></content></protolog>