<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1195_nm.2695" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2695" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2695" rank="species">Pseudomonas taeniospiralis</organism><reference id="rid.1195"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lalucat</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pares</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schlegel</surname><given-names>H.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas taeniospiralis sp. nov., an R-body-containing hydrogen bacterium.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>332</fpage><lpage>338</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-32-3-332</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pseudomonas taeniospiralis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Pseudomonas taeniospiralis sp. nov. (tae.ni.o.spi.ra'lis. Gr. noun <i>taenia</i> ribbon: L. adj. <i>spirals</i> coiled; M.L. adj. <i>taeniospiralis</i> ribbon coiled; named after <i>Caedibacter taeniospiralis</i>, an organism with which it has characters in common).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rod-shaped cells 0.5 by 1.0 to 3.0 μm, with a tendency to pleomorphism.</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Motile by means of a single polar or subpolar flagellum.</s><s>Variable proportions of cells in the stationary growth phase contain typical characteristic inclusions referred to as R bodies; these are convoluted, proteinaceous ribbons.</s><s>The R bodies have an average diameter of 0.25 μm and an average height of 0.21 μm.</s><s>Poly-β-hydroxybutyric acid and polyphosphate inclusions are present.</s><s>Colonies are yellow.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Temperature for optimal growth: 37°C.</s><s>Either chemolithoautotrophic, using H<sub>2</sub> as the electron donor and C0<sub>2</sub> as the carbon source, or chemoorganoheterotrophic; strictly respiratory in metabolism, with oxygen as the terminal electron acceptor, or (only heterotrophically) with denitrification of nitrate.</s><s>The hydrogenase is membrane bound and is not nicotinamide adenine dinucleotide specific.</s><s>CO<sub>2</sub> is fixed autotrophically via the ribulose bisphosphate cycle.</s><s>Among the hydrogen-oxidizing bacteria, this organism is outstanding because of its ability to utilize nine sugars; many organic acids and amino acids are also used.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase are produced.</s><s>Gelatin is hydrolyzed, but casein, starch, esculin, and poly-β-hydroxybutyric acid are not hydrolyzed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exerts a toxic effect against strains of paramecia.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Source: isolated from a soil sample collected near Barcelona, Spain.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain 2K1 is designated as the type strain for the species.</s><s>A culture of this strain has been deposited with the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen under the number DSM 2082.</s><s>The description of the type strain is the same as that given above for the species, with the following addition: the G+C content of the DNA is 60.2 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>