<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9583_nm.14771" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14771" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14771" rank="species">Marinobacter szutsaonensis</organism><reference id="rid.9583"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>C.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ng</surname><given-names>C.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tzeng</surname><given-names>W.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shyu</surname><given-names>Y.-T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Marinobacter szutsaonensis sp. nov., isolated from a solar saltern</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2605</fpage><lpage>2609</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008896-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19622658</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Marinobacter szutsaonensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Marinobacter szutsaonensis</em> (szu.tsao.nen′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>szutsaonensis</em> of szutsao, a former salt field located in southern Taiwan).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, rod-shaped (0.3–0.6×1.3–2.2 μm) and motile with a single flagellum.</s><s>Colonies are irregular to regular, flat and light translucent and milky cream colour after 48 h at 37 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations of 0–20 % (w/v), with optimum growth at 5 % NaCl.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is 35–40 °C; growth is observed at 10–50 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 6–8.5, with an optimum at pH 7.5–8.0.</s><s>Growth occurs under aerobic conditions.</s><s>Nitrate reduction is positive, H<sub>2</sub>S production is negative.</s><s>Aesculin, acetate, casein, pyruvate, urea and gelatin are hydrolysed, but starch, l-tyrosine, Tween 20, Tween 80, DNA and xanthine are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-glucose, d-mannose, maltose, d-mannitol, sucrose and d-galactose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from cellobiose, d-fructose, melibiose, d-ribose, l-arabinose, melezitose, d-sorbitol, raffinose, trehalose or d-xylose.</s><s>The following substrates are used as sole carbon sources: l-alanine, fumarate, d-glucose, malate, succinate, d-mannose, maltose and sucrose.</s><s>Melezitose, trehalose, d-salicin, d-sorbitol, d-xylose, benzoate, sorbose, lactose, d-fructose, l-tryptophan, formate, l-rhamnose, l-glutamate, glycerol, gluconate, glutamate, succinate and citrate are not used.</s><s>When assayed with the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase are present, but esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-B1-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, cystine arylamidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are absent.</s><s>The type strain is susceptible to ampicillin, bacitracin, carbenicillin, cefotaxime, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, kanamycin, nalidixic acid, nitrofurantoin, nystatin, penicillin, polymyxin B and tetracycline, but is resistant to neomycin, novobiocin, rifampicin and streptomycin.</s><s>The predominant isoprenoid quinone is Q-9.</s><s>Phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylethanolamine are the predominant polar lipids.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH and C<sub>12 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, NTU-104<sup>T</sup> (=BCRC 17809<sup>T</sup>=CGMCC 1.7011<sup>T</sup>=JCM 15751<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from Szutsao, a discarded salt field located in southern Taiwan.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 56.5 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>