<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2675_nm.4463" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4463" rank="genus">Syntrophomonas</organism><reference id="rid.2675"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>McInerney</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bryant</surname><given-names>M.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hespell</surname><given-names>R.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Costerton</surname><given-names>J.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Syntrophomonas wolfei gen. nov. sp. nov., an Anaerobic, Syntrophic, Fatty Acid-Oxidizing Bacterium.</article-title><year>1981</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>1029</fpage><lpage>1039</lpage><source id="228">Applied and Environmental Microbiology</source><abbrev>Appl Environ Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0099-2240</issn><essn>1098-5336</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16345745</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Syntrophomonas</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Syntrophomonas</i> (syn.tro.pho.mon.'as, Gr. adj., <i>syn</i> together with; Gr. n., <i>trophos</i> one who feeds; Gr. n., <i>monas</i> a unit, monad; M.L. fem.n. <i>Syntrophomonas</i>, monad which feeds together with (another species))</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nonsporing, gram-negative, slightly helical rods, 0.5 to 1.0 by 2.0 to 7.0 μm with slightly tapered rounded ends.</s><s>Most cells occur singly or in pairs with helical chains of three or more often observed.</s><s>Multiplication by binary fission.</s><s>Cells possess two to eight flagella with a diameter of about 20 nm that are laterally inserted in a linear fashion on the concave side of the cell about 130 nm or more apart.</s><s>Under most conditions, cells usually exhibit only a sluggish twitching motility.</s><s>Cells have an unusual multilayered gram-negative wall.</s><s>Muramic and <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acids are present, and the organism is sensitive to penicillin.</s><s>PHB is present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Surface colonies in roll tubes of <i>S. wolfei</i> cocultured with methanogens are smooth, convex, and circular, with entire edges and black in color when the <i>Desulfovibrio</i> species is the H<sub>2</sub>-utilizing bacterium.</s><s>Colonies form in 3 to 20 weeks and may reach 2 to 3 mm in diameter.</s><s>Subsurface colonies are lenticular.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>S. wolfei</i> is chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>It anaerobically β-oxidizes fatty acids with protons serving as the electron acceptor.</s><s>Butyrate, caproate, and caprylate are degraded to acetate and H<sub>2</sub>; valerate and heptanoate are degraded to acetate, propionate, and H<sub>2</sub>; and isoheptanoate is degraded to acetate, isovalerate, and H<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Carbohydrates, proteinaceous materials, alcohols, or other organic compounds do not support growth.</s><s>Common electron acceptors such as fumarate, malate, nitrate, oxygen, sulfate, sulfite, sulfur, thiosulfate, or others are not utilized with butyrate as the electron donor.</s><s>Growth and degradation of fatty acids occur only in syntrophic association with H<sub>2</sub>-utilizing bacteria and are stimulated by factors in rumen fluid and/or B vitamin mixture.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from anaerobic environments, such as aquatic sediments, sewage digestor sludge, and rumen digesta, where organic matter is degraded with CO<sub>2</sub> and CH<sub>4</sub> as major products.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The Göttingen strain is the type strain of the genus and species.</s></p></content></protolog>