<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4055_nm.5670" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5670" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4186" rank="species">Streptococcus parvulus</organism><reference id="rid.4055"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cato</surname><given-names>E.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Peptostreptococcus parvulus, Weinberg, Nativelle, and Prévot 1937 Smith 1957 to the genus Streptococcus: Streptococcus parvulus, Weinberg, Nativelle, and Prévot 1937 comb. nov., nom. rev., emend.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>82</fpage><lpage>84</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-1-82</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Streptococcus parvulus</i> (ex Weinberg, Nativelle, and Prevot 1937) Cato 1983, 83<sup>VP</sup>.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptococcus parvulus</i> (par'vu.lus. L. dim. adj. <i>parvulus</i>, somewhat small)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Obligately anaerobic, nonmotile, nonsporeforming, gram-positive cocci (diameter, approximately 0.3 to 0.6 μm) that occur singly, in pairs, in clumps, and in short chains.</s><s>Occasional elongate cells, some with central swelling, may occur in stained preparations obtained from growth in media without Tween-80.</s><s>Colonies on brain heart blood agar are pinpoint to 1 mm in diameter, raised or low convex, circular, entire, translucent to transparent, and colorless to grey after 2 to 5 days of anaerobic incubation at 37°C.</s><s>Growth is stimulated (30 of 30 strains tested) by 0.02% (vol/vol) Tween 80 and by 10% (vol/vol) rabbit serum added to culture media.</s><s>Of 72 strains tested, 58 grow at 45°C; 6 of 67 strains tested grow in the presence of 6.5% (wt/vol) NaCl.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The fermentation products from glucose are lactic acid (0.7 to 6.3 meq/100 ml of culture; mean for 40 strains, 4.2 meq/100 ml), acetic acid (0.1 to 0.6 meq/100 ml; mean for 40 strains, 0.3 meq/100 ml), formic acid (0 to 0.3 meq/100 ml), and occasionally trace amounts of succinic acid.</s><s>Little or no</s></p><p class="description"><s>gas is detected in agar deeps.</s><s>Hydrogen is not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The terminal pH in PYG-Tween 80 broth cultures ranges from 4.0 to 5.1; the mean terminal pH for 32 strains is 4.4.</s><s>A total of 11 of 82 strains tested ferment esculin, 1 of 68 strains ferments glycerol, 1 of 82 strains ferments melibiose, and 16 of 82 strains ferment xylose.</s><s>Amygdalin, erythritol, glycogen, inositol, mannitol, melezitose, raffinose, rhamnose, sorbitol, and starch are not fermented.</s><s>Starch is not hydrolyzed in the absence of added serum (which contains amylase).</s><s>Additional characteristics are shown in Table 3.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gelatin is not liquefied, meat is not digested, indole is not produced, and nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Reactions usually are negative for bile-esculin (none of 68 strains tested is positive), DNase (1 of 68 strains is positive), and hippurate hydrolysis (none of 68 strains is positive).</s><s>Catalase activity is not detected.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Susceptibility to antibiotics varies among strains; 1 of 82 strains tested is resistant to 12 μg of chloramphenicol per ml, 10 of 82 strains are resistant to 1.6 μg of clindamycin per ml, 5 of 82 strains are resistant to 3 μg of erythromycin per ml, 6 of 82 strains are resistant to 2 U of penicillin G per ml, and 1 of 82 strains is resistant to 6 μg of tetracycline per ml.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major cellular fatty acid derivatives are C<sub>18:1</sub> <i>cis</i>-9 fatty acid methyl ester and C<sub>18:1</sub> dimethylacetyl (Table 2).</s><s>Isolated from human gingival crevices and, according to Prévot et al. (16), from patients with pulmonary gangrene, tonsillitis, sinusitis, otitis, and dental and thoracic abscesses.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain IPP 1246 (= VPI 0546 = ATCC 33793).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 39 mol%.</s><s>The original source of this strain is unknown.</s></p></content></protolog>