<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7364_nm.5892" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5892" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5892" rank="species">Kocuria rhizophila</organism><reference id="rid.7364"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kovács</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Burghardt</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pradella</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Màrialigeti</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Kocuria palustris sp. nov. and Kocuria rhizophila sp. nov., isolated from the rhizoplane of the narrow-leaved cattail (Typha angustifolia).</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>167</fpage><lpage>173</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10028258</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Kocuria rhizophila</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Kocuria rhizophila</i> (rhi.z'’phi.la. Gr. n. <i>rhiza</i> a root; Gr. adj. <i>philos</i> loving; M.L. adj. <i>rhizophila</i> root-loving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are spherical, occurring in pairs, tetrads and packets, 1.0-1.5 μm in diameter, Gram-positive and non-motile.</s><s>Endospores not produced.</s><s>Not acid-fast.</s><s>The colonies are 1.5-2.5 mm in diameter, opaque, smooth with irregular edges with yellow pigmentation.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic.</s><s>No growth above 40°C.</s><s>Good growth between pH 5.7-7.7.</s><s>Catalase, benzidine and growth on inorganic nitrogen positive.</s><s>Gelatinase, phosphatase, Tween 80 hydrolysis, growth on Simmons' citrate are positive.</s><s>Oxidase, starch hydrolysis, indol, urease, aesculin hydrolysis, arginine dihydrolase and phenylalanine deaminase reaction are negative.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S reaction weak.</s><s>Nitrate not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Acid production from D-glucose, D-fructose, D-mannose and saccharose.</s><s>No acid production from glycerol, mannitol, sorbitol, ribose, D-xylose, L-arabinose, galactose, lactose, maltose, β-gentiobiose, D-turanose, arbutin, salicin, trehalose, melezitose or amidon.</s><s>Utilization of adonitol, L-arabinose, D-fructose, L-fucose, D-glucose, turanose, xylitol, methylpyruvate, glucuronamide, dextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, Tween 80 and N-acetyl-D-glucosamine.</s><s>No utilization of cellobiose, D-trehalose, N-acetyh-galactosamine, <i>meso</i>-inositol, maltose, D-mannitol, D-melibiose, sorbitol, inosine, glycerol, L-glutamic acid and L-alanine.</s><s>Good growth at 10% NaCl.</s><s>Peptidoglycan contains L-lysine as the diagnostic diamino acid.</s><s>The interpeptide bridge consists of three alanine residues (variation A3α).</s><s>The major menaquinones are MK-7(H<sub>2</sub>) and MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>The major fatty acids are ai-C<sub>17:0</sub>, ai-C<sub>15:0</sub> and i-C<sub>15:0</sub>.</s><s>Predominant polar lipids are phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 69.4 mol% G+C.</s><s>Isolated from the rhizosphere of <i>Typha angustifolia</i> from a floating mat on the Soroksar tributary of the river Danube, Hungary.</s><s>The type strain is strain TA68<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>It has been deposited at the DSMZ as strain DSM 11926<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>