<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6863_nm.6307" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6307" rank="genus">Skermania</organism><reference id="rid.6863"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chun</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Blackall</surname><given-names>L.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>S.-O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hah</surname><given-names>Y.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A proposal to reclassify Nocardia pinensis Blackall et al. as Skermania piniformis gen. nov., comb. nov.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>127</fpage><lpage>131</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-1-127</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8995814</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Skermania</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Skermania</i> (Sker.man'i.a. M. L. n. <i>Skemania</i>, named after Victor Skerman, an Australian taxonomist)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on data derived from the present study and the study of Blackall et al. (1).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, non-acid-fast, nonmotile actinomycetes which form a mycelium that does not fragment in undisturbed cultures; secondary branching is rare or absent.</s><s>Aerial hyphae are not visible to the naked eye, but short branched and unbranched aerial hyphae can be seen microscopically.</s><s>Strains have an oxidative metabolism and are catalase, oxidase, and urease positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall contains major amounts of <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, arabinose, galactose, glucose, ribose, and N-glycolated muramic acid.</s><s>The peptidoglycan is of the Aly type.</s><s>The organism contains diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylinositol, and phosphatidylinositol mannosides as predominant polar lipids, major amounts of straight-chain saturated, unsaturated, and tuberculostearic fatty acids, mycolic acids with 58 to 64 carbons and monounsaturated side chains, and hexahydrogenated menaquinones with eight isoprene units in which the two end units are cyclized.</s><s>The organism has DNA that is rich in guanine and cytosine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species of the genus <i>Skemania</i> is <i>Skermania piniformis</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>