<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8600_nm.13439" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13439" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13439" rank="species">Microbacterium luticocti</organism><reference id="rid.8600"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Vaz-Moreira</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lopes</surname><given-names>A.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nunes</surname><given-names>O.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Manaia</surname><given-names>C.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Microbacterium luticocti sp. nov., isolated from sewage sludge compost.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1700</fpage><lpage>1704</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65494-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18599719</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Microbacterium luticocti</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Microbacterium luticocti</em> (L. neut. n. <em>lutum</em> mud, sludge; L. part. adj. <em>coctus</em> -<em>a</em> -<em>um</em> digested; N.L. gen. n. <em>luticocti</em> of digested sludge).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are white, opaque and circular (1–2 mm diameter) on BHI agar.</s><s>Cells are Gram-positive, short rods (1.6±0.3 μm long and 0.5±0.1 μm wide) that are non-spore-forming and motile.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Growth occurs between 27 and 45 °C, between pH 5.5 and 9.7 and in the presence of up to 10 % NaCl, with optimum growth around 36 °C, 1–3 % NaCl and pH 8.</s><s>Growth does not occur at 25 °C or 47 °C, at pH 5 or pH 10, or in 12 % NaCl.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite, but does not support anaerobic growth.</s><s>Starch, gelatin and aesculin are hydrolysed.</s><s>Urease and <em>β</em>-galactosidase are produced.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-arabitol, d-fructose, d-mannitol, l-rhamnose, sucrose and trehalose and produced weakly from cellobiose, l-fucose, d-galactose, maltose, d-mannose, potassium 5-ketogluconate and turanose.</s><s>The following sole carbon sources are assimilated: <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, d-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, d-lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, potassium gluconate, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin and trehalose.</s><s>Poor growth is observed when glucose is the single carbon source.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of ciprofloxacin (5 μg), meropenem (10 μg), ceftazidime (30 μg), colistin sulfate (50 μg) and sulfamethoxazole (25 μg).</s><s>Unable to assimilate l-arabinose, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate, phenylacetate, glycerol, erythritol, l-arabinose, d-xylose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, l-sorbose, dulcitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, arbutin, melibiose, sucrose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, potassium 2-ketogluconate or potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Does not produce acid from glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-glucose, l-sorbose, dulcitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, d-lactose, melibiose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-arabitol, potassium gluconate or potassium 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>Cannot ferment or oxidize (API 20E) d-glucose, d-mannitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, sucrose, melibiose, amygdalin or l-arabinose.</s><s>Negative for Tweenase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine and ornithine decarboxylases, citrate utilization, and indole and acetoin production.</s><s>Unable to grow in the presence of amoxicillin (25 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), tetracycline (30 μg), SXT (sulfamethoxazole/trimethoprim, 23.5/1.25 μg), cephalothin (30 μg), streptomycin (10 μg) or ticarcillin (75 μg).</s><s>The fatty acids anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> comprise more than 70 % of the total.</s><s>The peptidoglycan is of the B2<em>β</em> type and contains glycolyl residues.</s><s>Mannose is the cell-wall sugar.</s><s>MK-12 is the major respiratory quinone.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is SC-087B<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 19459<sup>T</sup>=CCUG 54537<sup>T</sup>), isolated from sewage sludge compost.</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content of the type strain is 72±0.3 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>