<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1374_nm.6758" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6758" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6981" rank="species">Saccharopolyspora erythraea</organism><reference id="rid.1374"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Labeda</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of the type strain of Streptomyces erythraeus (Waksman 1923) Waksman and Henrici 1948 to genus Saccharopolyspora Lacey and Goodfellow 1975 as Saccharopolyspora erythraea sp. nov., and designation of a neotype strain for Streptomyces erythraeus.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>19</fpage><lpage>22</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-37-1-19</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Saccharopolyspora erythraea</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Saccharopolyspora erythraea</i> (e. ryth´ rae. a. L. adj. <i>erythraea</i> from Gr. n. erythros red)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Spore chains usually short so that imperfect spirals and short straight to flexuous chains are common.</s><s>The spore surface is spiny.</s><s>Substrate mycelium ranges from pale orangish yellow to reddish brown, depending on the medium; pale pink to moderately brownish gray aerial hyphae are produced on many media (e.g., glycerolasparagine agar).</s><s>White aerial mycelia are also seen.</s><s>A faint yellow to pinkish orangish brown soluble pigment is produced on most media.</s><s>No melanin pigments are produced.</s><s>Adenine, casein, esculin, gelatin, hypoxanthine, starch, tyrosine, urea, and xanthine are hydrolyzed or degraded; allantoin is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Nitrate reduced.</s><s>Phosphatase not produced.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 5% NaCl; no growth occurs in the presence of salicylate; poor growth occurs in the presence of lysozyme.</s><s>Assimilates acetate, citrate, lactate, malate, propionate, pyruvate, and succinate; does not assimilate benzoate, mucate, oxalate, or tartrate.</s><s>Acid produced from adonitol, arabinose, cellobiose, dextrin, erythritol, fructose, galactose, glucose, glycerol, inositol, maltose, mannose, mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, salicin, sucrose, and xylose; no acid produced from dulcitol, lactose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, β-methyl-D-xyloside, or sorbitol.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 20 to 42°C.</s><s>Many strains produce erythromycins A and B.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 76.9 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from soil.</s><s>The type strain is strain NRRL 2338 (= ATCC 11635 = ISP 5517)</s></p></content></protolog>