<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4488_nm.8031" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8031" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8031" rank="species">Porphyromonas gulae</organism><reference id="rid.4488"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Fournier</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mouton</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lapierre</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kato</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Okuda</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ménard</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Porphyromonas gulae sp. nov., an anaerobic, gram-negative coccobacillus from the gingival sulcus of various animal hosts.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1179</fpage><lpage>1189</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11411686</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Porphyromonas gulae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Porphyromonas gulae</i> (gu'lae. L. n. <i>gula</i> [animal] mouth; N.L. gen. n. <i>gulae</i> from the animal mouth, referring to its isolation from subgingival plaque of various animal hosts)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are obligately anaerobic, non-spore-forming, non-motile, Gram-negative rods or coccoid forms.</s><s>From Todd-Hewitt broth cultures or blood agar plates, the following cellular morphologies can be observed.</s><s>The size of cells ranges from 0.5 to 0.9 μm by 1.0 to 4.0 μm.</s><s>Cells are arranged singly, in short chains or in groups; some filaments up to 10 μm are occasionally seen.</s><s>After 48 h growth on solid media, colonies are 0.5-3.5 mm in diameter, with a circular form, an entire margin, a convex elevation and a mucoid aspect.</s><s>A brown to black pigment is produced on ageing of the cultures.</s><s>Moreover, colonies do not fluoresce under UV light (λ=366 nm).</s><s>Vitamin K<sub>1</sub> and haemin are required for growth.</s><s>Mannose and raffinose are not fermented.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major metabolic end products in Todd-Hewitt broth are butyric acid, isovaleric acid, succinic acid and phenylacetic acid.</s><s>Strains are all catalase-positive and indole is produced.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, trypsinlike and β-NAG activities are strong.</s><s>β-GAL and glutamylglutamic acid arylamidase activities are present.</s><s>Urea is not used and nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Cells significantly haemagglutinate sheep erythrocytes and are resistant to kanamycin (50 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>All isolates came from subgingival plaque samples of various mammals, including cat, dog, coyote, wolf, bear and non-human primate from the NewWorld i.e. squirrel monkey and black spider monkey.</s><s>The sites were mainly healthy, or with a minor presence of calculus.</s><s>The G­C content of the DNA is 51 mol%.</s><s>The average level of intraspecies DNA-DNA homology is 80%and higher.</s><s>The DNA-DNA relatedness with related species is <i>P. gingivalis</i> (C60%), <i>P. endodontalis</i> (14%), <i>P. levii</i> (13%), <i>P. asaccharolytica</i> (10%) and <i>P. macacae</i> (9%).</s><s>The type strain of <i>P. gulae</i> sp. nov. is Loup 1<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 51700<sup>T</sup>=NCTC 13180<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>