<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12540_nm.21399" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21399" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21399" rank="species">Rheinheimera nanhaiensis</organism><reference id="rid.12540"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>H.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>X.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>M.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gao</surname><given-names>Z.-M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>X.-L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dang</surname><given-names>H.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.-Z.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rheinheimera nanhaiensis sp. nov., isolated from marine sediments, and emended description of the genus Rheinheimera Brettar et al. 2002 emend. Merchant et al. 2007</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1016</fpage><lpage>1022</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.019281-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20511463</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rheinheimera nanhaiensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rheinheimera nanhaiensis</em> (nan.hai.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>nanhaiensis</em> pertaining to NanHai, the Chinese name for the South China Sea, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, straight or curved rods (1.0–2.0 µm long and 0.3–0.5 µm wide).</s><s>Motile by a single polar flagellum.</s><s>Able to form prosthecae.</s><s>Facultatively aerobic.</s><s>Colonies on marine agar are slightly yellow, circular (1.5–2.0 mm in diameter) and convex with smooth surfaces after incubation for 48 h at 30 °C.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Grows at 10–48 °C (optimum, 37 °C), but not at 50 °C.</s><s>Grows in 0–8 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum, 0.5–2.5 %) and at pH 5.5–10.0 (optimum, pH 7.5–8.5).</s><s>Hydrolyses starch, gelatin, casein, DNA and Tweens 40 and 80.</s><s>Able to utilize d-glucose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, sucrose, trehalose, cellobiose and maltose as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>In API 20NE tests, positive for reduction of nitrate to nitrite, gelatinase, assimilation of d-glucose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and maltose and hydrolysis of aesculin and negative for indole production, arginine dihydrolase, urease, β-galactosidase, acid production from glucose and assimilation of arabinose, mannose, mannitol, gluconate, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate and phenylacetate.</s><s>In API 20E tests, positive for gelatinase, weakly positive for acid production from sucrose and negative for β-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, utilization of citrate, H<sub>2</sub>S production, urease, tryptophan deaminase, indole production, the Voges–Proskauer test and acid production from glucose, mannitol, inositol, sorbitol, rhamnose, melibiose, amygdalin and arabinose.</s><s>With API ZYM strips, the following enzyme activities are detected: <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-chymotrypsin, trypsin, alkaline and acid phosphatases, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase; activities of α- and β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α- and β-glucosidase, α-mannosidase, β-fucosidase, lipase (C14) and cystine arylamidase are not detected.</s><s>Susceptible to (µg per disc) chloramphenicol (30), erythromycin (15), gentamicin (10), kanamycin (30) and streptomycin (10), but resistant to ampicillin (10), penicillin G (10), vancomycin (30), lincomycin (2) and tetracycline (30).</s><s>The respiratory lipoquinones are Q-8 (98 %) and Q-7 (2 %).</s><s>The major fatty acids (&#x003E;5 %) are summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH), C<sub>17 : 1</sub>ω8<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 51.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is E407-8<sup>T</sup> ( = CCTCC AB 209089<sup>T</sup>  = KACC 14030<sup>T</sup>), isolated from marine sediments of the South China Sea.</s></p></content></protolog>