<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2654_nm.4650" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4650" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4650" rank="species">Mycoplasma cottewii</organism><reference id="rid.2654"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>DaMassa</surname><given-names>A.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tully</surname><given-names>J.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rose</surname><given-names>D.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pitcher</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Leach</surname><given-names>R.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cottew</surname><given-names>G.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycoplasma auris sp. nov., Mycoplasma cottewii sp. nov., and Mycoplasma yeatsii sp. nov., new sterol-requiring mollicutes from the external ear canals of goats.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>479</fpage><lpage>484</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-3-479</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8068541</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycoplasma cottewii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycoplasma cottewii</i> (cot.tew'i.i. M. L. gen. n. <i>cottewii</i>, of Cottew, named, as proposed by R. H. Leach, after G. S. Cottew, one of the coisolators of the organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>M. cottewii</i> is serologically distinct from all of the other <i>Acholeplasma</i>, <i>Entomoplasma</i>, <i>Mesoplasma</i>, and <i>Mycoplasma</i> species evaluated in this study.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on agar have the fried-egg appearance characteristic of most mycoplasmas.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>M. cottewii</i> catabolizes glucose and mannose.</s><s>Arginine and urea are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Tetrazolium is reduced aerobically.</s><s>Phosphatase is not produced.</s><s>Sterol is required for growth.</s><s>Serum and casein are not digested, and film and spots are not produced on equine or porcine serum-containing media.</s><s>Chicken and guinea pig erythrocytes are not hemadsorbed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic growth is greater than growth under anaerobic (GasPak) conditions when the two methods are compared.</s><s>Colonies on ovine blood agar that are incubated aerobically produce zones of viridans type hemolysis, which changes to a beta-hemolysis after additional incubation.</s><s>Brown to black pigmentation, which is often intense, occurs in young, well-separated colonies on thallium acetate-containing agar medium; this characteristic can be used for presumptive diagnostic identification of <i>M. cottewii</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Filterable through 220-nm-pore-size filters with some loss of viability.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 27.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is VIS (= ATCC 51347 = NCTC 11732).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Serologic types similar to strain VIS<sup>T</sup> are common in the ears of goats in Australia and have been recovered occasionally from the ears of goats in the United States.</s><s>One isolation of a strain VIS<sup>T</sup> serotype has been reported from the nasal sinuses of goats (6).</s><s>Pathogenicity is unknown.</s></p></content></protolog>