<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6678_nm.6152" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6152" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6152" rank="species">Rathayibacter festucae</organism><reference id="rid.6678"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dorofeeva</surname><given-names>L.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Evtushenko</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Krausova</surname><given-names>V.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Karpov</surname><given-names>A.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Subbotin</surname><given-names>S.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tiedje</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rathayibacter caricis sp. nov. and Rathayibacter festucae sp. nov., isolated from the phyllosphere of Carex sp. and the leaf gall induced by the nematode Anguina graminis on Festuca rubra L., respectively</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1917</fpage><lpage>1923</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12508848</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rathayibacter festucae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rathayibacter festucae</i> (fes'tu.ca.e. M.L. adj. <i>festucae</i> from Festuca, generic name of fescue, a host plant of this species)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The colonies on corynebacterium agar are circular, convex and orange to rose-orange.</s><s>The cells are nonspore- forming, non-motile, irregular rods, sometimes curved.</s><s>Rod-coccoid life cycle may be observed.</s><s>Obligately aerobic.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Optimum growth temperature is 24-26°C; no growth observed at 7 or 37°C.</s><s>D-Glucose, D-galactose, adonitol, L-arabinose, cellobiose, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, fructose, inositol, inulin, maltose, mannose, mannitol, melibiose, raffinose, L-rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, trehalose, turanose and D-xylose are used as carbon sources for growth in salt medium supplemented with 0.1% (w/v) yeast extract and 0.1% (w/v) casitone.</s><s>Dextran, lyxose, ribose and sorbose are not utilized.</s><s>Asparagine, glycine, methionine, proline, tyrosine are used as nitrogen sources for growth.</s><s>Acetate, citrate, fumarate, gluconate, α-ketoglutarate, malate, malonate, succinate, tartrate are utilized (alkaline reaction), but not formate or propionate.</s><s>Tween 40, Tween 60 and Tween 80 are hydrolysed, but starch, aesculin, hypoxanthine and xanthine are not.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced.</s><s>Methyl red and Voges-Proskauer tests are positive.</s><s>No growth with 5% (w/v) NaCl, 0.03% (w/v) tellurium acetate and 0.03% (w/v) potassium tellurite.</s><s>Resistant to the following antibiotics (10 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>): ampicillin, gentamicin, oxacillin and rubomicin.</s><s>Susceptible to doxycycline, levomicetin, metacycline, rifampicin and streptomycin at the same concentration.</s><s>DNA G+C content is approximately 68 mol%.Cell-wall sugars consist of glucose, mannose and rhamnose and minor amounts of xylose.</s><s>Other chemotaxonomic characteristics are as given previously (Zgurskaya et al., 1993; Sasaki et al., 1998).</s><s>The type strain of the species, VKM Ac-1390<sup>T</sup> (=UCMAc-619<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the leaf gall induced by the fescue leaf gall nematode <i>Anguina graminis</i> on <i>Festuca rubra</i> L. (Moscow region, Russia).</s></p></content></protolog>