<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12522_nm.21376" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21376" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21376" rank="species">Pseudonocardia artemisiae</organism><reference id="rid.12522"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>G.-Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>H.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>W.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>L.-X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudonocardia artemisiae sp. nov., isolated from surface-sterilized Artemisia annua L.</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1061</fpage><lpage>1065</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.021931-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20511456</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudonocardia artemisiae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudonocardia artemisiae</em> (ar.te.mi′si.ae. L. n. <em>artemisia</em> mugwort, also a plant genus; L. gen. n. <em>artemisiae</em> of <em>Artemisia</em>, isolated from <em>Artemisia annua</em> L.).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, non-motile, non-endospore-forming, Gram-positive-staining actinomycete that forms extensively branched substrate mycelium and aerial mycelium, which carry smooth-surfaced rod-shaped spores.</s><s>Forms white aerial mycelia and orange–yellow or brown substrate mycelia on the media tested.</s><s>No pigment is produced.</s><s>Grows at 10–37 °C (optimum 20–28 °C), at pH 5–9 (optimum pH 6–8) and with 0–3 % NaCl (optimum 1 % NaCl).</s><s>Positive for catalase, milk coagulation and milk peptonization, but negative for nitrate reduction, oxidase, urease, gelatin liquefaction, cellulose and starch hydrolysis and H<sub>2</sub>S production.</s><s>As sole carbon sources, utilizes cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose and l-rhamnose, but not glucose, glycerol, raffinose, sodium acetate, d-sorbitol or sucrose.</s><s>As sole nitrogen sources, utilizes l-alanine, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-hydroxyproline, hypoxanthine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-tyrosine, l-valine and xanthine, but not glycine or l-lysine.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-fructose, lactose, mannitol and maltose.</s><s>The cell wall of strain YIM 63587<sup>T</sup> contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid and the whole-cell sugars are arabinose, galactose, mannose and ribose (cell wall type IV).</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The phospholipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylmethylethanolamine, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylinositol mannosides, phosphatidylinositol and an unknown phospholipid (phospholipid type PIII).</s><s>The major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 1</sub> H, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 10-methyl and C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM 63587<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 45313<sup>T</sup> = CCTCC AA 208081<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from surface-sterilized roots of <em>Artemisia annua</em> L., collected from Yunnan province, south-west China.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 68.2 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>