<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.252_nm.5001" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5001" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5001" rank="species">Bacillus tusciae</organism><reference id="rid.252"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bonjour</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Aragno</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus tusciae, a new species of thermoacidophilic, facultatively chemolithoautotrophic, hydrogen oxidizing sporeformer from a geothermal area.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>139</volume><fpage>397</fpage><lpage>401</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00408386</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus tusciae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus tusciae</i> (<i>Tus.cia.e</i> L. gen.n. <i>tusciae</i> from Tuscia; named after Tuscia, a name used by Romans for the region of central Italy where the Etruscan people (Tuscii) lived and where the organism was found)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Straight, rod-shaped cells 0.8 x 4 to 5 μm, with one lateral flagellum forming broad oval, subterminal endospores, 1.2 x 1.8 μm, distending distinctly the sporangium.</s><s>Grampositive in young cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies spreading, cream-white, chalky.</s><s>Liquid cultures form a surface pellicle.</s><s>A yellow, water soluble pigment with an absorption peak at 410 nm is produced in heavy, autotrophic cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell wall of Gram-positive type, without a protein coat.</s><s>Poly-β-hydroxybutyric acid formed.</s><s>No growth factors required.</s><s>Strictly respiratory metabolism, with oxygen as the final electron acceptor.</s><s>Cannot grow anaerobically with nitrate.</s><s>Nitrate reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Either chemolithoautotrophic, using H<sub>2</sub> as the electron donor and CO<sub>2</sub> as the carbon source, or chemoorganoheterotrophic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A few organic acids, amino acids and alcohols can serve as sole carbon sources, with ammonium ions as the nitrogen source.</s><s>Sugars not metabolized.</s><s>Ammonium ions, urea and asparagine utilized as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>Dinitrogen not fixed under microaerophilic conditions.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Hydrogenase inducible, soluble; does not reduce pyridine nucleotides.</s><s>CO<sub>2</sub> fixed via ribulose-bisphosphate cycle.</s><s>Catalase weakly positive; oxidase positive.</s><s>Starch not hydrolysed.</s><s>No growth in the presence of 1% NaCl.</s><s>Growth in the presence of 1% glycine.</s><s>Inhibitions of growth by penicillin G (0.04 U⋄ml<sup>-1</sup>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Temperature optimum for growth about 55°C no growth at 35 or 65°C.</s><s>pH for optimum growth: 4.2 to 4.8.</s><s>Weak growth at pH 3.5 or at pH 6.0.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G + C content of the DNA is 57- 58 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from an acidic pond in a solfatara near Lago, province of Grosseto, Italy.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: strain T2 is designated as the type strain for the species.</s><s>It has been deposited at the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen, Göttingen, FRG, under the accession number 2912.</s><s>The description of the type strain is the same as the one given for the species, with the following additions: growth under air with acetate, malonate, butyrate, succinate, malate, oxaloacetate, 2-oxoglutarate, L-isoleucine, L-valine, ethanol, propanol, as sole C-sources.</s><s>The G + C content of the DNA is 57.7 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>