<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4338_nm.9758" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9758" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9758" rank="species">Gramella portivictoriae</organism><reference id="rid.4338"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lau</surname><given-names>S.C.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tsoi</surname><given-names>M.M.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Plakhotnikova</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dobretsov</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wong</surname><given-names>P.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Qian</surname><given-names>P.Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Gramella portivictoriae sp. nov., a novel member of the family Flavobacteriaceae isolated from marine sediment.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2497</fpage><lpage>2500</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63824-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16280516</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Gramella portivictoriae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Gramella portivictoriae</em> (por′ti.vic.to′ri.ae. L. n. <em>portus</em> harbour; L. gen. fem. n. <em>victoriae</em> of Victoria; N.L. gen. fem. n. <em>portivictoriae</em> from/of Victoria Harbour, Hong Kong, the source of isolation of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, rod-shaped (0·6–3·6 μm), glide slowly and do not form spores.</s><s>Colonies on marine agar are yellow in colour without diffusible pigment, circular, 2·0–4·0 mm in diameter and convex with smooth surfaces and entire translucent margins after 48 h at 30·0 °C.</s><s>Growth is strictly aerobic and occurs between 4·0 and 36·0 °C (28·0–30·0 °C optimum), at pH 6·0–10·0 (pH 7·0–8·0 optimum) and at 1·0–6·0 % NaCl.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 39·9 mol%.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are a15 : 0, i15 : 0, i15 : 0 3-OH, i17 : 1<em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>, i17 : 0 3-OH and summed feature 3, comprising i15 : 0 2-OH and/or 16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (altogether representing 76·2 % of the total).</s><s>The major quinone is MK-6.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are not produced.</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, penicillin and tetracycline, but not to kanamycin or streptomycin.</s><s>Acetoin is produced, but indole and H<sub>2</sub>S are not.</s><s>Citrate is not utilized.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Aesculin ferric citrate, gelatin, starch and Tweens 20, 40 and 80 are hydrolysed, but agar, casein, carboxymethylcellulose, chitin and DNA are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Positive for acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, catalase, cystine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), oxidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, trypsin and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase activities.</s><s>Negative for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, arginine dihydrolase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase and urease activities.</s><s>Utilization of d-arabinose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, d-mannitol, d-melibiose, d-sorbitol, starch and sucrose as sole carbon sources is observed on agar medium supplemented with 4 % (w/v) carbon source.</s><s>Utilization of <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid is observed with the MicroLog 3 system.</s><s>However, no growth or acid production is observed from the carbon sources in the API 50 CH, API 20E and API 20NE test systems (lists of carbon sources included in the API and MicroLog 3 test systems are available in Supplementary Tables S2 and S3, respectively, in IJSEM Online.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is UST040801-001<sup>T</sup> (=NRRL 41137<sup>T</sup>=JCM 13192<sup>T</sup>), isolated from sediment in Victoria Harbour, Hong Kong.</s></p></content></protolog>