<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7513_nm.6394" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6394" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6394" rank="species">Mycobacterium poriferae</organism><reference id="rid.7513"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Padgitt</surname><given-names>P.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moshier</surname><given-names>S.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium porifera sp. nov., a scotochromogenic, rapidly growing species isolated from a marine sponge</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>186</fpage><lpage>191</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-37-3-186</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycobacterium poriferae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycobacterium poriferae</i> (po.rif.'er.ae, L. gen., of the Porifera, the phylum of sponges)</s></p><p class="description"><s>(no. 47 = ATCC 35087<sup>T</sup>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>This species, isolated from cell suspensions of a marine sponge, consists of rapidly growing, strongly acid-fast, gram-positive rods which frequently appear coccoid.</s><s>No branching or Y-shaped cells occur, but cells may become enlarged on one end and display an ovoid, non-acid-fast body.</s><s>Cells are 0.7 to 2.5 μm wide and 1.1 to 4.9 μm long.</s><s>Nondividing cells in cultures are typically 2.2 to 2.3 μm wide by 2.7 to 3.1 μm long.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 28 to 30°C on various media including Middlebrook 7-H-11 and tryptic soy agar with 5% (vol/vol) glycerol.</s><s>A pH range from 5.0 through 8.5 is tolerated.</s><s>Growth on Middlebrook 7-H-11 agar after 4 days produces smooth, moist, shiny, dome-shaped colonies with a nearly translucent apron which disappears on continued growth. <i>M. poriferae</i> is a strongly orange scotochromogen.</s><s>High-molecular-weight mycolic acids precipitate with ether-ethanol in the range of 4.1 to 4.6 mg/50 mg of cells, LCN-A is absent, and two-dimensional thin-layer chromatography gives a mycolic acid pattern of the <i>M. avium</i> type, which has α-mycolates, ketomycolates, and wax ester derivatives, although some strains may have α'-mycolates present also.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>M. poriferae</i> produces catalase but is negative for arylsulfatase (3 days) and nitrate reductase.</s><s>Urease, pyrazinamidase , and nicotinamidase are present, while acetamidase, allantoinase, benzamidase, isonicotinamidase, and succinamidase are absent.</s><s>Sodium chloride (5%), salicylate, picric acid, PAS, and TCH are tolerated; neither salicylate nor PAS is degraded.</s><s>Hydroxylamine is tolerated to 0.0125%.</s><s>Iron uptake and Tween hydrolysis (7 days) are positive.</s><s>Carbon sources utilized include acetate, pyruvate, citrate, succinate, malate, benzoate, malonate, fumarate, glucose, galactose, trehalose, mannose, D-xylose, mannitol, sorbitol, fructose, sucrose, ethanol, 1-propanol, propylene glycol, 1-butanol, 2,3-butylene glycol, and glycerol but not 1,3-butylene glycol, 1,4-butylene glycol, isobutanol, inositol, L-arabinose, or L-rhamnose.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, mannitol, sucrose, D-xylose, and mannose but not from trehalose, inositol, L-arabinose, galactose, lactose, L-rhamnose or sorbitol.</s><s>Sole nitrogen sources include L-glutamate, L-serine, acetamide, pyrazinamide, succinamide, nitrate, nicotinamide and urea but not benzamide or nitrite.</s><s>Dual nitrogen and carbon sources are glucosamine, L-glutamate, L-serine, monoethanolamine and trimethylenediamine but not nicotinamide, acetamide, or benzamide.</s></p></content></protolog>