<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4628_nm.4863" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4863" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4863" rank="species">Bacillus agaradhaerens</organism><reference id="rid.4628"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nielsen</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fritze</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Priest</surname><given-names>F.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phenetic diversity of alkaliphilic Bacillus strains: proposal for nine new species.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>141</volume><fpage>1745</fpage><lpage>1761</lpage><source id="144">Microbiology</source><issn>0026-2617</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus agaradhaerens</i> sp. noy.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus agaradhaerens</i> (a.gar.ad.hae.rens, Malayan n. <i>agar</i> gelling polysaccharide from brown algae; L adj. <i>adhaerens</i> adherent; ML adj. <i>agaradhaerens</i> adhering to the agar which is characteristic of these colonies)</s></p><p class="description"><s>This description is taken from this paper for DNA hybridization group 2 and unpublished results of H.</s><s>Outtrup.</s><s>Colonies are white and rhizoid with a filamentous margin.</s><s>Cells are rod-shaped (0.5-0.6 x 2-5 μmμm) and produce ellipsoidal spores (0.6-1.0 x 1.0-1.6 μm) subterminally positioned within a sporangium, which is clearly swollen.</s><s>Strains of this species are characterized by hydrolysis of Tween 40 and 60 (PN-105 is negative for the former) casein, gelatin, starch, cellulose and xylan.</s><s>Hippurate, MUG and Tween 20 are not hydrolysed and phenylalanine is not deaminated.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Strains of this species are strictly alkaliphilic: no growth is observed at pH 7.0 and optimal growth is observed at pH 10.0 or above.</s><s>Growth occurs within a temperature range of 10-45 °C.</s><s>Tolerance to 16 % NaCl is observed (strain PN-I07 grows only weakly at this NaCl concentration).</s><s>Carbohydrate utilization profiles show growth on L-arabinose, galactose, mannose, N-acetylglucosamine or 2-ketogluconate and most strains grow on tagatose but no growth on methyl β-D-xyloside, inositol or xylitol is observed.</s><s>The chromosomal DNA  composition is between 39.3 and 39.5 mol % G +C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Source: soil.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain of this species is PN-105 (= DSM 8721).</s></p></content></protolog>