<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6734_nm.5042" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5042" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5042" rank="species">Halobacillus trueperi</organism><reference id="rid.6734"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Spring</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ludwig</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Marquez</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schleifer</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halobacillus gen. nov., with descriptions of Halobacillus litoralis sp. nov. and Halobacillus trueperi sp. nov., and transfer of Sporosarcina halophila to Halobacillus halophilus comb. nov.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>492</fpage><lpage>496</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-2-492</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Halobacillus trueperi</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Halobacillus trueperi</i> (true'per.i. M.L. gen. n. <i>trueperi</i>, of Trueper, in honor of Hans G. Triiper, who has made important contributions to our knowledge of the ecophysiology and taxonomy of halophilic bacteria)</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the characteristics given above in the description of the genus, H. trueperi has the following characteristics.</s><s>Rod-shaped cells are 0.7 to 1.4 by 2.0 to 4.5 μm and occur singly, in pairs, or in short chains.</s><s>Sometimes cells up to 20 μm long are present.</s><s>Motile by means of several flagella, which are inserted at both poles of each cell or laterally.</s><s>EnEndospores are ellipsoidal or sometimes spherical and 0.7 to 1.5 μm in diameter; they are located at a central to subterminal position.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-fructose, D-galactose, maltose, sucrose, D-glucose, and D-trehalose, but not from D-xylose and D-mannitol.</s><s>Gelatin and pullulan are hydrolyzed, but casein, starch, Tween 80, and tyrosine are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Phosphatase is not produced.</s><s>Growth occurs in media containing 0.5 to 30% (wt/vol) salt, and the optimum salt concentration is around 10%.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 10 to 44°C, and the optimum temperature is 35°C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is pH 6.0 to 9.5; the optimum pH is 7.5.</s><s>The doubling time is 0.42 h under optimal conditions.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 43 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from sediment obtained from the southern part of the Great Salt Lake in Utah.</s><s>The type strain is strain SL-5, which has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen GmbH, Braunschweig, Germany, as strain DSM 10404.</s></p></content></protolog>