<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2564_nm.3152" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3152" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3152" rank="species">Enterobacter amnigenus</organism><reference id="rid.2564"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Izard</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gavini</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trinel</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Leclerc</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Deoxyribonucleic acid relatedness between Enterobacter cloacae and Enterobacter amnigenus sp. nov.</article-title><year>1981</year><volume>31</volume><fpage>35</fpage><lpage>42</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-31-1-35</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Enterobacter amnigenus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Enterobacter amnigenus</i> (L. adj: <i>amnigenus</i>: coming from water),</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following description of <i>E. amnigenus</i> is based on the data obtained by Gavini et al. (11) and Izard et al. (15) from studies of 28 strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, peritrichous, nonsporeforming, straight rods (0.5 by 30μm) resembling those of the other members of <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i>.</s><s>Never encapsulated.</s><s>Growth on nutrient agar occurs at 30 and 37°C but not at 41°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following biochemical reactions are positive: acetoin production, citrate (Simmons), mucate and malonate utilization, reduction of nitrates to nitrites, ornithine decarboxylase and arginine dihydrolase production, production of β-galactosidase and β-xylosidase, and fermentation of the following carbohydrates within 24 to 48 h (for 80 to 100% of the strains): glucose (with gas production), arabinose, xylose, ribose, maltose, galactose, rhamnose, mannose, fructose, raffinose, melibiose, cellobiose, mannitol, salicin, and esculin.</s><s>The following reactions are negative: indole production, methyl red test, tartrate utilization (Jordan), H<sub>2</sub>S production, phenylalanine deaminase production, lysine decarboxylase, gelatinase, Tween esterase, tetrathionate reductase, deoxyribonuclease, and fermentation of the following carbohydrates within 30 days (for 80 to 100% of the strains): lactose, sorbose, melezitose, dulcitol, inositol, glycerol, adonitol, erythritol, inulin, dextrin, starch, pectin, and chitin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following are utilized (by 80 to 100% of the strains) as sole carbon sources: D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, D-mannose, D-maltose, D-trehalose, D-cellobiose, D-ribose, D-xylose, L-arabinose, L-rhamnose, starch, salicin, gluconate, D-mannitol, m-glycerate, citrate, fumarate, DL-lactate, L-malate, pyruvate, L-α-alanine, D-α-alanine, and L-glutamate.</s><s>The following are not utilized (by 80 to 100% of the strains within 5 days) as sole carbon sources: D-fucose, inulin, ethanol, methanol, n-propanol, <i>iso</i>-propanol, geraniol, 2,3-butylene glycol, ethylene glycol, propylene glycol, erythritol, adonitol, D-dulcitol, <i>meso</i>-inositol, propionate, D-tartrate, L-tartrate, <i>meso</i>-tartrate, levulinate, citraconate, itaconate, mesaconate, glycolate, aconitate, D-malate, 2-ketoglutarate, oxalate, acetate, DL-3-hydroxybutyrate, maleate, pimelate, suberate, azelate, glutarate, sebacate, salicylate, butyrate, <i>iso</i>-butyrate, <i>n</i>-valerate, <i>iso</i>-valerate, <i>n</i>-caproate, heptanoate, adipate, caprate, pelargonate, caprylate, phenol, phthalate, <i>iso</i>-phthalate, <i>tere</i>-phthalate, benzylformate, D- and L-mandelate, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, phenyl acetate, benzoate, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate, D-quinate, glycine, β-alanine, L-leucine, L-isoleucine, L-valine, L-lysine, L-citrulline, L-methionine, DL-2-aminobutyrate, DL-3-aminobutyrate, DL-4-aminobutyrate, DL-4-aminobutyrarate, L-aspertate, L-arginine, L-ornithine, L-threonine, L-cysteine, 5-aminovalerate, L-phenylalanine, L-tyrosine, 2-amino benzoate, 3-aminobenzoate , 4-aminobenzoate, L-tryptophan, histamine, putrescine, spennine, tryptamine, amylamine, ethanolamine, butylamine, benzylamine, diphenylamine, urea, urate, sarcosine, betaine, creatine, hippurate, pantothenate, nicotinate, trigonelline, asparagine, acetamide, potassium nitrate, naphthalene, dodecane, and hexadecane.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Mean guanine plus cytosine content of DNA: 54.2 mol% (5 strains analyzed [15)).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Genetic relatedness (DNA-DNA hybridization) with the most related species or genus: <i>E. cloacae</i> (49-66%; 17 strains analyzed); <i>Levinea</i> (46-54%; 7 strains analyzed).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Found in water (drinking water and surface water) and unpolluted soils.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: CUETM 77-118 (ATCC 33072).</s></p></content></protolog>