<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.51_nm.2216" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2216" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2216" rank="species">Xanthomonas citri</organism><reference id="rid.51"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gabriel</surname><given-names>D.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kingsley</surname><given-names>M.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hunter</surname><given-names>J.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gottwald</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reinstatement of Xanthomonas citri (ex Hasse) and X. phaseoli (ex Smith) to species and reclassification of all X. campestris pv. citri strains</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>14</fpage><lpage>22</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-1-14</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Xanthomonas citri</i> (ex Hasse) nom. rev.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of <i>X. citri</i> is the same as for the genus. The following description is based on previously published data concerning the genus (1) and on our own work with seven strains from four countries; all studies included the type strain. Cells are straight rods, usually within the range of 0.4 to 0.7 μm wide by 0.7 to 1.8 μm long. Gram negative. Motile by a single polar flagellum. Obligately aerobic. Optimum growth temperature is 30°C, with no growth above 38°C. On agar plates, colonies are circular, raised, semitranslucent, and yellow and the margins are entire. The pigments are brominated aryl polyenes or xanthomonadins, and crude methanol extractions of the pigments exhibit a major absorption peak between 443 and 446 nm. Able to use a variety of carbohydrates and salts of organic acids as sole carbon sources. No amino acids required for growth. Growth on minimal media greatly stimulated by addition of glutamic acid. Starch and casein hydrolysis positive; lipolysis of Tween 80. Strong pectinase activity in culture, particularly evident on Hildebrandt minimal sodium polypectate medium (10). Distinguished from <i>X. campestris</i> and <i>X . phaseoli</i> by distinct pattern of hybridizing DNA bands by RFLP analyses (cf. Fig. 2). Isolated from various genera within the family <i>Rutaceae</i>, including <i>P. trifoliata</i>,  <i>Citrus sinensis</i>, <i>C. paradisi</i>,  <i>C. limon</i> (lemon), <i>C. reticulata</i>, and  <i>C. aurantifolia</i>, causing a canker disease on twigs, leaf spotting and defoliation, fruit spotting and premature fruit drop, and a general decline of both nursery stock and mature trees. The type strain is 3213, deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as ATCC 49118.</s></p></content></protolog>