<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12224_nm.20223" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20223" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20223" rank="species">Cupriavidus pampae</organism><reference id="rid.12224"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cuadrado</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gomila</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Merini</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Giulietti</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>E.R.B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Cupriavidus pampae sp. nov., a novel herbicide-degrading bacterium isolated from agricultural soil</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2606</fpage><lpage>2612</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.018341-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20023053</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Cupriavidus pampae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Cupriavidus pampae</em> [pam′pa.e. N.L. n. <em>pampa</em> (from Quechuan noun <em>pampa</em>) pampa; N.L. gen. n. <em>pampae</em> of pampa, the grassland plains of temperate South America, especially Argentina, where the soil samples were obtained from which the type strain of the species was isolated].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on R2A agar are 3–4 mm in diameter, non-pigmented, circular and darker in the centre, with a translucent and undulating margin.</s><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-negative, non-fermenting, non-sporulating, motile rods.</s><s>Growth on R2A agar medium occurs at 10–30 °C.</s><s>On blood agar medium, good growth is observed at 30 °C; weak growth is observed at 37 °C.</s><s>Reactions for oxidase and catalase are positive, whereas urease, esterase (C4), lipase, acid phosphatase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase are negative.</s><s>No nitrate reduction, indole formation, glucose fermentation or aesculin and arginine dihydrolase activities are observed.</s><s>d-Glucose, d-gluconate, caprate, adipate, l-malate, citrate and lactate are assimilated.</s><s>Trehalose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, sucrose and phenylacetate are not assimilated.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CPDB6<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 55948<sup>T</sup>=CCM-A-29:1289<sup>T</sup>), isolated from soils chronically exposed to phenoxy herbicides in the AHP region, Argentina.</s></p></content></protolog>