<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3924_nm.8054" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8054" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8054" rank="species">Prevotella enoeca</organism><reference id="rid.3924"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>L.V.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>W.E.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Descriptions of Prevotella tannerae sp. nov. and Prevotella enoeca sp. nov. from the human gingival crevice and emendation of the description of Prevotella zoogleoformans.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>599</fpage><lpage>602</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-4-599</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7981091</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Prevotella enoeca</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Prevotella enoeca</i> (e.noe'ca. Gr. adj. <i>enoikos</i>, inhabiting; N.L. fem. adj. <i>enoeca</i>, inhabiting, because the organism is an inhabitant of the gingival crevice)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on studies of the type strain and seven other isolates obtained from six other people.</s><s>Cells of the type strain are 0.5 μm wide by 2.2 to 4.6 μm long; filaments up to 7.7 μm long are observed.</s><s>Cells are not motile and occur in pairs and short chains.</s><s>Surface colonies on rabbit blood agar plates incubated for 2 days are 1 to 2 mm in diameter, circular, entire, convex, transparent to translucent, and not hemolytic.</s><s>No pigment develops on either hemolyzed or whole rabbit blood agar plates or streak tubes incubated for 10 days, and there are no hemolytic zones around colonies on blood agar plates.</s><s>Broth cultures are turbid with a smooth sediment.</s><s>The terminal pH values of glucose broth cultures incubated for 5 days are 4.8 to 5.4.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The fermentation acids are succinic acid (3.2 ± 0.72 meq/100 ml of culture [mean ± standard error of the mean]) and acetic acid (1.4 ± 0.19 meq/100 ml); sometimes a trace of formic acid is present.</s><s>No hydrogen is detected in the headspace gas of glucose broth cultures.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Additional characteristics of the species are shown in Tables 2 and 4.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from the gingival crevices of humans with healthy gingiva and periodontitis (Table 5).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is, ATCC 51261<sup>T</sup> (= VPI D194A-25A).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 47 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The lack of sucrose fermentation and the inability of <i>P. enoeca</i> to digest gelatin differentiate this species from many <i>Prevotella</i> species (Table 3).</s><s>It can be differentiated from <i>P. tannerae</i> by its cellular fatty acid profile (iso-C<sub>15:0</sub> fatty acid content) (Table 4).</s></p></content></protolog>