<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4428_nm.6759" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6759" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6759" rank="species">Saccharopolyspora flava</organism><reference id="rid.4428"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lu</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Qi</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Saccharopolyspora flava sp. nov. and Saccharopolyspora thermophila sp.nov., novel actinomycetes from soil.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>319</fpage><lpage>325</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11321076</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Saccharopolyspora flava</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Saccharopolyspora flava</i> (<i>fla</i>'<i>va</i>. L. adj. <i>flaveus</i> yellow, referring to the colour of the substrate mycelium)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, non-acid-alcohol-fast, nonmotile actinomycete which forms an extensively branched, yellow substrate mycelium which fragments into rod-shaped elements after 3-4 d at 28 °C.</s><s>Aerial hyphae are produced upon prolonged cultivation on oatmeal agar.</s><s>The organism also grows well on glucose-asparagine, ISP medium 2 and modi®ed Sauton's agars.</s><s>The aerial mycelium carries abundant chains of 3-5 smooth-surfaced spores (0.4x0.5-0.6 lm).</s><s>Diffusible pigments are not produced.</s><s>Adenine, cellulose, hypoxanthine, starch, xanthine and xylan are degraded, but casein, chitin, elastin, guanine and tyrosine are not degraded.</s><s>Aesculin and urea are hydrolysed and nitrate is reduced.</s><s>Uses adonitol, cellobiose, erythritol, fructose, galactose, glucose, glycerol, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, methyl α-D-glucoside, raffinose, salicin, sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, xylose, acetate, adipate, benzoate, butyrate, citrate, fumarate, H-malate, propionate, pyruvate and succinate as sole carbon sources for energy and growth but does not use L-arabinose, melezitose, sebacic acid or tartrate.</s><s>Weak growth occurs in the presence of 7% (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth is inhibited by lyzozyme, gentamicin sulphate (discs soaked in 100 μg antibiotic ml<sup>-1</sup>), streptomycin sulphate (100 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>) and rifampicin (50 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>).</s><s>The temperature growth range is between 28 and 37 °C.</s><s>The G­C content of the DNA is 67 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from garden soil collected from Xishan Mountain, Beijing, China.</s><s>The type strain is strain 07<sup>T</sup> [=AS4.1520<sup>T</sup> (Chinese Culture Collection of Microorganisms)=IFO 16345<sup>T</sup>=JCM 10665<sup>T</sup>].</s></p></content></protolog>