<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3725_nm.10937" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10937" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10937" rank="species">Pedobacter ginsengisoli</organism><reference id="rid.3725"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ten</surname><given-names>L.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Q.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>D.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pedobacter ginsengisoli sp. nov., a DNase-producing bacterium isolated from soil of a ginseng field in South Korea</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2565</fpage><lpage>2570</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64414-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17082391</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pedobacter ginsengisoli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pedobacter ginsengisoli</em> (gin.sen.gi.so′li. N.L. n. <em>ginsengum</em> ginseng; L. n. <em>solum</em> soil; N.L. gen. n. <em>ginsengisoli</em> of soil from a ginseng field, the source of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, non-spore-forming, non-motile and rod-shaped (0.5–1.0×2.5–4.5 μm).</s><s>After 6 days incubation at 25 °C on R2A, colonies are 2–5 mm in diameter, smooth, convex, round, glossy and white.</s><s>Grows at 4–30 °C; the optimum temperature for growth is 25 °C.</s><s>The minimum pH for growth lies between 4.5 and 5.0, the optimum pH is 6.5–7.5 and the maximum pH lies between 8.5 and 9.0.</s><s>Tolerates 1 % (w/v) NaCl, but not 2 %.</s><s>Growth occurs on trypticase soy agar, but not on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Positive for catalase and oxidase, but negative for lipase.</s><s>Negative for hydrolysis of chitin, starch, cellulose, xylan, casein and aesculin and positive for hydrolysis of DNA.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized for growth: d-glucose, d-galactose, d-mannose, d-fructose, d-xylose, l-xylose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, salicin, d-cellobiose, d-lactose, d-maltose, d-melibiose, sucrose, d-trehalose, d-raffinose, amygdalin, glycerol, inulin and dextran.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized for growth: d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-fucose, ethanol, l-rhamnose, l-sorbose, d-lyxose, d-ribose, pyruvate, formate, acetate, propionate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, valerate, caprate, maleate, fumarate, phenylacetate, benzoate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, citrate, lactate, malate, malonate, succinate, glutarate, tartrate, itaconate, adipate, suberate, oxalate, gluconate, dulcitol, inositol, d-adonitol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, xylitol, methanol, glycogen, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-cysteine, l-glutamic acid, l-glutamine, l-histidine, glycine, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, l-tryptophan, l-tyrosine and l-valine.</s><s>In API 20E tests, the Voges–Proskauer test is positive and tests for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, urease, gelatinase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and production of hydrogen sulphide and indole are all negative.</s><s>Acid is not produced from d-glucose, d-melibiose, amygdalin, l-arabinose, d-mannitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, l-rhamnose or sucrose.</s><s>The major fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA is 43.6 mol%.</s><s>The predominant respiratory quinone is MK-7.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Gsoil 104<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12576<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23399<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil sample from a ginseng field in Pocheon Province (South Korea).</s></p></content></protolog>