<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9479_nm.14622" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14622" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14622" rank="species">Rhodoplanes pokkaliisoli</organism><reference id="rid.9479"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lakshmi</surname><given-names>K.V.N.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sasikala</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ramana</surname><given-names>C.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhodoplanes pokkaliisoli sp. nov., a phototrophic alphaproteobacterium isolated from a waterlogged brackish paddy soil</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2153</fpage><lpage>2157</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.008185-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19605702</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rhodoplanes pokkaliisoli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rhodoplanes pokkaliisoli</em> (pok.ka.li.i.so′li. N.L. n. <em>pokkalium</em> pokkali (a variety of rice); L. n. <em>solum</em> soil; N.L. gen. n. <em>pokkaliisoli</em> of/from the soil of a pokkali field, from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped, 1.0–1.2 μm wide and 3.0–5.0 μm long.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of a single polar flagellum and multiply by budding and asymmetrical cell division without forming prosthecae.</s><s>Cells form chains, but are also capable of associating with each other such that they form characteristic T, Y and V shapes and rosettes.</s><s>Internal photosynthetic membranes are present as lamellar stacks parallel to the cytoplasmic membrane.</s><s>Phototrophically grown cultures are yellowish brown, whereas aerobic cultures are white.</s><s>The <em>in vivo</em> absorption spectrum of intact cells in sucrose exhibits maxima at 380, 464, 491, 527, 596, 800 and 866 nm.</s><s>Bacteriochlorophyll <em>a</em> and carotenoids of the spirilloxanthin series (rhodopin, methyl rhodopin, lycopene and a few unidentified spirilloxanthins) are present.</s><s>The type strain is mesophilic (range 25–30 °C) and grows at an optimum salinity (NaCl) of 1.5 % (range 0–2.5 %, w/v) and pH 7 (range pH 6.0–7.5).</s><s>Growth occurs under anaerobic conditions in the light (photo-organoheterotrophy) or under aerobic conditions in the dark (chemo-organoheterotrophy).</s><s>The preferred mode of growth is photo-organoheterotrophy with a few organic compounds.</s><s>Acetate, butyrate, lactate, pyruvate, malate, fumarate, succinate, glycerol and crotonate are good carbon sources.</s><s>2-Oxoglutarate, valerate, caproate, ethanol, butanol, propanol, formate, caprylate, propionate, citrate, glycolate, benzoate, glucose, fructose, gluconate, mannitol, tartrate, aspartate, sucrose, methanol, sorbitol, leucine, alanine, peptone, Casamino acids and yeast extract are not utilized.</s><s>Photoautotrophic and chemoautotrophic growth do not occur with thiosulfate, H<sub>2</sub>, sulfide, sulfur, sulfite or thioglycolate as the electron donor.</s><s>Chemotrophic growth by denitrification under anoxic conditions in the dark in the presence of nitrate is observed.</s><s>Fermentative growth does not take place in the presence of glucose, fructose or pyruvate as fermentable carbon source.</s><s>Ammonium salts and glutamate are used as good nitrogen sources.</s><s>Sulfate, sulfite, thiosulfate and methionine are used as sulfur sources.</s><s>Niacin, pantothenate and <em>p</em>-aminobenzoate are required as growth factors.</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acid component is C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>.</s><s>Ubiquinone-10 and rhodoquinone-10 are present as major quinones.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is JA415<sup>T</sup> (=NBRC 104972<sup>T</sup> =KCTC 5711<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from a soil sample from a pokkali rice field located on Vypeen Island, Ernakulam, Kerala, on the west coast of India.</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content of the type strain is 67.2 mol% (HPLC).</s></p></content></protolog>