<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6407_nm.7983" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7983" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7983" rank="species">Bacteroides salivosus</organism><reference id="rid.6407"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Love</surname><given-names>D.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>R.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Calverley</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacteroides salivosus sp. nov., an asaccharolytic, black-pigmented species from cats.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>307</fpage><lpage>309</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacteroides salivosus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacteroides salivosus</i> (L. adj. <i>salivosus</i>, of saliva, slimy)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are obligately anaerobic, nonsporeforming, nonmotile, gram-negative rods or coccoid forms.</s><s>In cooked-meat carbohydrate (3) and on sheep blood agar plates, cells are 0.3 to 0.6 μm by 0.8 to 1.5 μm and arranged singly and in groups; occasional filaments up to 10 μm are seen.</s><s>On sheep blood agar plates, surface colonies at 72 h are 0.5 to 1.5 mm in diameter, circular, entire, dome shaped, opaque, and brown-black.</s><s>Colonies may show an orange fluorescence (265 nm) at 24 h, but fluorescence is absent by 3 days.</s><s>Colonies from some strains do not fluoresce.</s><s>After incubation at 37°C for 24 h in prereduced broth media, cultures show a uniform turbidity with a small ropy deposit.</s><s>Vitamin K and hemin are required for growth.</s><s>After incubation for 5 days, the pH in media containing a fermentable carbohydrate generally ranges from 6.5 to 6.8 in all media tested.</s><s>Carbohydrate fermentation is not detected in adonitol, cellobiose, fructose, glucose, glycogen, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, rhamnose, salicin, starch, sucrose, trehalose, and xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major fermentation products from cooked-meat carbohydrate are acetic acid (average 21.9 μmol/ml) and butyric acid (average, 10.4 μmol/ml).</s><s>Smaller quantities of isobutyric acid (average, 0.4 μmol/ml) and isovaleric acid (average, 3.6 μmol/ml) are produced.</s><s>Large amounts of phenylacetic acid (average, 350 μg/ml) are produced.</s><s>Neither lactate nor pyruvate is utilized, and threonine is not converted to propionate.</s><s>Strains are catalase positive, liquefy gelatin, and have trypsin-like activity.</s><s>However, cells neither agglutinate sheep erythrocytes nor exhibit α-glucosidase activity, reduce nitrate, split urea, or hydrolyze esculin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains are susceptible to penicillin (2 U/ml), amoxycillin (2.5 μg/ml), carbenicillin (100 μg/ml), and erythromycin (3 μg/ml).</s></p><p class="description"><s>This species was isolated from soft-tissue infections (abscesses and empyemas) and normal gingival margins from cats.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA was 42 to 44 mol% by <i>T<sub>m</sub></i> (5).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is NCTC 11632<sup>T</sup> (VPB 157).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Phenotypic characteristics helpful in differentiating <i>B. salivosus</i> sp. nov. from other species are as follows. <i>B. salivosus</i> produces catalase which distinguishes it from the asaccharolytic pigmented <i>Bacteroides</i> spp. from humans.</s><s>Its combined characteristics of fluorescent colonies, trypsin-like activity, production of large amounts of phenylacetic acid, and lack of hemagglutinating activity for sheep erythrocytes easily distinguished it from <i>B. gingivalis</i> ATCC 33277<sup>T</sup>, <i>B. asaccharolyticus</i> ATCC 25260<sup>T</sup>, and <i>B. endodontalis</i> ATCC 35405<sup>T</sup> (although the description of the latter species does not mention fluorescence of colonies at 265 nm).</s></p></content></protolog>