<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3926_nm.12233" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.12233" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5622" rank="species">Streptococcus crista</organism><reference id="rid.3926"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Handley</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coykendall</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beighton</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hardie</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Whiley</surname><given-names>R.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptococcus crista sp. nov., a viridans streptococcus with tufted fibrils, isolated from the human oral cavity and throat.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>543</fpage><lpage>547</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-41-4-543</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1742199</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptococcus crista</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptococcus crista</i> (cris'ta. L. n. crista, crest)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following description is based on the results of our study together with data from the studies of Beighton et al. (2), Handley et al. (8), and Douglas et al. (7).</s><s>Cells are gram-positive, catalase-negative cocci that are approximately 1 μm in diameter and grow in chains.</s><s>Colonies grown at 37°C for 2 days on blood agar are greyish white, glossy, entire, alpha-hemolytic, and 1 to 2 mm in diameter.</s><s>Glucan production on sucrose-containing medium is a variable characteristic.</s><s>Acid is produced from arbutin, maltose, trehalose, and N-acetylglucosamine, but not from amygdalin, arabinose, inulin, mannitol, melibiose, melezitose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, sorbose, sorbitol, tagatose, turanose, and xylitol.</s><s>The majority of strains produce acid from galactose and lactose but not from lactulose or pullulan and hydrolyze arginine but not esculin or urea. β-N-acetylgalactosaminidase, β-N-acetylglucosaminidase, and α-L-fucosidase are produced, but α-arabinosidase, β-D-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, sialidase (neuraminidase), and alkaline phosphatase are not produced.</s><s>Some strains produce β-galactosidase.</s><s>All strains produce hydrogen peroxide but not acetymethylcarbinol (Voges-Proskauer test).</s><s>Salivary α-amylase is bound.</s><s>Cells have tufts of fibrils in a lateral position.</s><s>The G +C contents of the DNAs range from 42.6 to 43.2 mol%.</s><s>Source: human throats and oral cavities.</s><s>The type strain is strain CR311 (= NCTC 12479).</s></p></content></protolog>