<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5625_nm.9889" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9889" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9889" rank="species">Methylobacterium adhaesivum</organism><reference id="rid.5625"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gallego</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>García</surname><given-names>M.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Methylobacterium adhaesivum sp. nov., a methylotrophic bacterium isolated from drinking water</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>339</fpage><lpage>342</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63966-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16449436</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Methylobacterium adhaesivum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Methylobacterium adhaesivum</em> (ad.hae′si.vum. L. neut. adj. <em>adhaesivum</em> adhering, forming aggregates).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative rods, 1·0–1·2×1·5–5·0 μm, occurring singly or forming aggregates (when grown in liquid R2A medium at 28 °C after 24 h).</s><s>Cells are motile, non-spore-forming and strictly aerobic.</s><s>Growth in liquid media is flocculant whereas growth on solid media produces colonies that usually adhere to the agar surface.</s><s>Colonies are pink and circular, 0·5–0·8 mm in diameter after 7 days at 28 °C on R2A agar.</s><s>Growth is slow, doubling typically requiring 48–72 h under optimal conditions.</s><s>No growth in the presence of ≥1·0 % NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–35 °C (optimum 28 °C) and at pH 5·0–9·0 (optimum pH 6·5).</s><s>Catalase- and urease-positive.</s><s>Oxidase activity is weak.</s><s>Indole, methyl red and Voges–Proskauer reactions are negative.</s><s>Tween, starch, gelatin, casein and DNA are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide is not produced.</s><s>Simmons' citrate test is positive.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Acid is produced oxidatively from d-arabinose, d-glucose, d-galactose, d-mannose, fructose and maltose.</s><s>Methanol, formate and formaldehyde are utilized as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Ammonium sulfate, nitrate, aspartate and glutamate are utilized as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources (Biolog): d-fructose, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, l-lactic acid, d- and l-malic acid, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, propionic acid, pyruvic acid, succinamic acid, succinic acid, l-glutamic acid and glycerol.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole carbon and energy sources (Biolog): Tweens 40 and 80, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, inulin, mannan, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-mannosamine, amygdalin, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, l-fucose, d-galactose, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melezitose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, 3-methyl glucose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, palatinose, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, sedoheptulosan, d-sorbitol, stachyose, sucrose, d-tagatose, d-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, d-xylose, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, lactamide, d-lactic acid methyl ester, <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, adenosine, 2′-deoxyadenosine, inosine, thymidine, uridine, adenosine 5′-monophosphate, thymidine 5′-monophosphate, uridine 5′-monophosphate, fructose 6-phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate, glucose 6-phosphate and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, AR27<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 7069<sup>T</sup>=CCM 7305<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from drinking water.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 63·6 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p></content></protolog>