<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2617_nm.4245" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4245" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4245" rank="species">Eubacterium desmolans</organism><reference id="rid.2617"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Morris</surname><given-names>G.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Winter</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cato</surname><given-names>E.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ritchie</surname><given-names>A.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bokkenheuser</surname><given-names>V.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Eubacterium desmolans sp. nov., a steroid desmolase-producing species from cat fecal flora</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>183</fpage><lpage>186</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-36-2-183</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Eubacterium desmolans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Eubacterium desmolans</i> (des'mo.lans. Gr. n. <i>desmos</i> a bond; mod. chem. term desmolase, an enzyme splitting a carbon-carbon bond; N.L. part. adj. <i>desmolans</i> making desmolase)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-positive plump rods that are 0.8 to 1.1 μm wide by 1.7 to 2.3 μm long (Fig. 2) and occur singly or in short chains.</s><s>Some cells are capsulated.</s><s>The tumbling motility of the peritrichous cells is due to four to six long flagella.</s><s>Internal mesosomes are present, especially in dividing cells.</s><s>Spores are not formed, and the organism does not survive exposure to 80°C for 10 min or treatment with absolute alcohol for 30 min.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth characteristics.</s><s>Primary colonies on BAP incubated at 37°C are invisible to the unaided eye.</s><s>Subcultures on the same medium yield circular to slightly irregular, convex, shiny, entire, semiopaque, white to colorless colonies with a diameter of 0.6 to 0.8 mm.</s><s>Neither sheep nor rabbit erythrocytes are hemolysed.</s><s>Growth in SPB is light and slightly turbid, with a fine precipitate after 3 to 4 days.</s><s>Addition of 1% inositol enhances growth; 20% bile (2% oxgall) is tolerated but has no effect on multiplication.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerotolerance. <i>E. desmolans</i> does not form colonies on BAP incubated in atmospheric air or in air supplemented with 10 or 30% CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>However, organisms seeded on BAP tolerate 4 but not 8 h of exposure to atmospheric air at 22°C, as evidenced by colony formation on plates incubated anaerobically after exposure.</s><s>Subcultures of such organisms synthesize desmolase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Phenotypic reactions.</s><s>Inositol is fermented to a final pH of 5.1.</s><s>Indole is produced.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced on sulfideindole motility medium.</s><s>Gelatin, milk, and meat are not digested.</s><s>As noted above, inositol is utilized, resulting in the formation of acetate and butyrate and trace amounts of succinate and lactate.</s><s>Hydrogen gas is not produced.</s><s>Amygdalin, arabinose, cellobiose, erythritol, esculin, glycogen, fructose, glucose, lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose,</s></p><p class="description"><s>melezitose, melibiose, pectin, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, and xylose are not fermented.</s><s>Starch is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Lipase, lecithinase, oxidase, and catalase are not produced.</s><s>Nitrate and resazurin are not reduced.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>E. desmolans</i> is susceptible to chloramphenicol (12 μg/ml), erythromycin (3 μg/ml), and clindamycin (1.6 μg/ml) but resistant to penicillin G (2 U/ml) and tetracycline (6 μg/ml).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Steroid metabolism. <i>E. desmolans</i> synthesizes at least two enzymes with activity on corticoids, a desmolase which cleaves the side chain of 17α-hydroxysteroids between C-17 and C-20 and a 20β-hydroxysteroid dehydrogenase which reduces the 20-keto group of both 17α-hydroxy- and 17-deoxysteroids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Demolase requires a C-21 hydroxy group and a keto or β-hydroxy group at C-20, but functions independently of the structure of the rest of the molecule.</s><s>The metabolite formed is invariably a C-17 ketosteroid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The organism also reduces many C<sub>20</sub> keto steroids.</s><s>The need for hydroxy groups at C-21 or C-17 or both is not clear.</s><s>For example, 17α-hydroxyprogesterone, deoxycorticosterone, and cortisol are all reduced to the 20β-hydroxy compounds.</s><s>In contrast, progesterone, aldosterone, and corticosterone are not reduced at C-20.</s><s>Gas-liquid chromatography of the metabolites isolated compared with authentic standards of 20α- and 20β-hydroxy structures demonstrated conclusively the β orientation of the hydroxy group.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Kinetic experiments revealed that 20β-hydroxysteroid dehydrogenase is measurable in the late lag phase and the early log phase (7 to 12 h of incubation).</s><s>Desmolase is demonstrable from the beginning of the log phase (9 to 10 h of incubation) and reaches a maximum within 2 to 3 h, approximately 3 h before the beginning of the stationary phase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Natural habitat.</s><s>Although <i>E. desmolans</i> was isolated from the feces of an apparently normal cat, its host range is unknown.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the type strain, <i>E. desmolans</i> ATCC 43058, is 35 mol%, as determined</s></p><p class="description"><s>by the thermal denaturation method (8, 11).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Diagnostic characteristics.</s><s>Among the numerous carbohydrates tested, only inositol is fermented by <i>E. desmolans</i>, a feature shared by an undescribed strain of <i>Fusobacterium</i> and a strain of <i>Clostridium</i> isolated from human feces (L.</s><s>V.</s><s>Holdeman and W.</s><s>E.</s><s>C.</s><s>Moore, personal communication).</s><s>Erroneous classification of <i>E. desmolans</i> is easily avoided by microscopic examination of a culture.</s><s>However, it must be recognized that until information on the deoxyribonucleic acid composition of <i>Eubacterium</i> species becomes available, the classification of these organisms is incomplete.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Synthesis of steroid-metabolizing enzymes by <i>Eubacterium</i> sp. Many bacterial enzymes with action on corticoids are synthesized by <i>Eubacterium lentum</i> and phenotypically related organisms (2).</s><s>These intestinal organisms are known to manufacture 21-dehydroxylase (3), l6α-dehydroxylase (2), 7β-hydroxysteroid dehydrogenase (10), and 7α-hydroxysteroid dehydrogenase (16), as well as bile acid 3α- and 12α-hydroxysteroid dehydrogenases (9).</s><s>Steroid desmolase and 20β-hydroxysteroid dehydrogenase may now be added to the list of steroid enzymes that are synthesized by members of the genus Eubacterium.</s><s>Why these organisms produce such an array of highly specialized constitutive enzymes is unknown.</s><s>We have been unable to demonstrate a need for or an enhanced effect of these compounds in growth media.</s></p></content></protolog>