<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10555_nm.17793" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17793" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.17793" rank="species">Citricoccus zhacaiensis</organism><reference id="rid.10555"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Meng</surname><given-names>F.-X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>X.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>P.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pan</surname><given-names>J.-M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>C.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>X.-W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Citricoccus zhacaiensis sp. nov., isolated from a bioreactor for saline wastewater treatment</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>495</fpage><lpage>499</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.011635-0</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Citricoccus zhacaiensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Citricoccus zhacaiensis</em> (zha.ca.i.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>zhacaiensis</em> pertaining to zhacai, the Chinese name for preserved vegetables).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, non-spore-forming and aerobic.</s><s>Cells are non-motile and ellipsoidal, approximately 0.6×0.5 μm in size.</s><s>Colonies are yellow-greenish, smooth, circular, convex, opaque and 1–2 mm in diameter.</s><s>The temperature and pH range for growth are 10–37 °C (optimum 25–35 °C) and pH 6.0–9.0 (optimum pH 7.0).</s><s>Grows in the presence of 0–15 % (w/v) NaCl, optimum at 1 % (w/v) below 25 °C or 5 % (w/v) below 37 °C.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Casein, starch, Tweens 20 and 80 and urea are not decomposed.</s><s>Nitrate reduction, H<sub>2</sub>S production, phenylalanine deamination, indole production and tyrosinase activity are negative.</s><s>The following constitutive enzyme activities are detected in API ZYM tests: acid and alkaline phosphatases, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), <em>α</em>-glucosidase, lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, trypsin and valine arylamidase.</s><s><em>β</em>-Fucosidase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidases, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase are not observed.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon sources: acetate, citrate, l-glutamate, gluconate, l-glutamine, isoleucine, malate, malonate, maltose, propionate, pyruvate, salicin, l-serine, succinate, sucrose, trehalose and l-valine.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole carbon sources: adonitol, l-alanine, l-arabinose, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-aspartate, cellobiose, l-cysteine, ethanol, formate, d-fructose, fumarate, d-galactose, glucose, glycerol, glycine, l-histidine, inositol, lactate, lactose, lysine, mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, l-methionine, l-proline, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, l-sorbitol, sorbose, starch, xylitol or xylose.</s><s>Acid production was not observed.</s><s>Susceptible to cefotaxime, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, neomycin, novobiocin, polymyxin B and tetracycline, but not to kanamycin, nalidixic acid, nitrofurantoin, nystatin, rifampicin or streptomycin.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>The major cellular polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol, four unknown glycolipids, two unknown phospholipids and an unknown lipid.</s><s>The major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The cell wall amino acids are alanine, glycine, glutamic acid and lysine.</s><s>Spermidine is predominant in the polyamine pattern.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 66.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, FS24<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 1.7064<sup>T</sup> =JCM 15136<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a bioreactor treating wastewater generated from preserved vegetable production.</s></p></content></protolog>