<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1781_nm.9563" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9563" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9563" rank="species">Treponema berlinense</organism><reference id="rid.1781"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nordhoff</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Taras</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Macha</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tedin</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wieler</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Treponema berlinense sp. nov. and Treponema porcinum sp. nov., novel spirochaetes isolated from porcine faeces.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1675</fpage><lpage>1680</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63388-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16014500</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Treponema berlinense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Treponema berlinense</em> (ber.li.nen′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>berlinense</em> pertaining to Berlin, Germany, where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells show typical spirochaete morphology exhibiting two to three windings with two periplasmic, subterminally inserted flagella.</s><s>Cells are approximately 6 μm in length and 0·3 μm in width.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic.</s><s>Good growth is observed in liquid OMIZ-Pat medium at 37 °C supplemented with 10 % (v/v) BHI and 10 % (v/v) TSYE.</s><s>On OMIZ-Pat agar plates (1·3 % w/v) supplemented with 5 % (v/v) sheep blood, 10 % (v/v) BHI and 10 % (v/v) TSYE, species forms small, irregular, greyish swarms up to 1–2 mm in diameter, visible after 3–4 days.</s><s>Addition of galacturonic or glucuronic acid promotes growth, which is enhanced further by addition of any of the following carbohydrates: d-glucose, d-fructose, d-maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-arabinose, l-fucose, d-trehalose, d-sucrose and l-rhamnose.</s><s>No visible growth is observed with pectin as the sole carbon source.</s><s>Using the API ZYM and Rapid ID 32A systems, positive enzyme reactions are obtained only for acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>Negative in tests for alkaline phosphatase, esterase C4, esterase lipase C8, leucine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, urease, arginine dihydrolase, <em>α</em>-arabinosidase, mannose and raffinose fermentation, glutamic acid decarboxylase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, arginine arylamidase, proline arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, tyrosine arylamidase, alanine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase and serine arylamidase.</s><s>Reduction of nitrates and indole production are not detected.</s><s>The polar lipid profile contains diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, an unknown aminophospholipid and an unknown highly hydrophobic compound as major components.</s><s>Moderate or minor amounts of phosphatidylglycerol, several unknown aminophospholipids, phospholipids, amino lipids, polar lipids and a glycolipid are also present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 7CPL208<sup>T</sup> (ATCC BAA-909<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108244<sup>T</sup>=JCM 12341<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from swine faeces in Berlin, Germany.</s></p></content></protolog>