<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1341_nm.239" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.239" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.239" rank="species">Methanosarcina vacuolata</organism><reference id="rid.1341"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhilina</surname><given-names>T.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zavarzin</surname><given-names>G.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Methanosarcina vacuolata sp. nov., a vacuolated methanosarcina.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>37</volume><fpage>281</fpage><lpage>283</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-37-3-281</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Methanosarcina vacuolata</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Methanosarcina vacuolata</i> (<i>vacuolum</i>, M.L. diminutive of <i>vacuum</i>, an empty place; N.L. f. pl. <i>vacuolata</i>, referring to methanosarcinae with gas vesicles)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells spherical or compressed, 1 to 2 μm in rounded aggregates arranged into sarcinalike packets.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Gram positive.</s><s>Not lysed by 0.07% sodium dodecyl sulfate at 23°C.</s><s>Differentiating cytological characteristic: the presence of large vacuoles containing gas vesicles.</s><s>Multiplication by uneven fission in different planes; septation may not be visible by phase-contrast microscopy.</s><s>Rounded pseudococci observed in a light microscope are aggregates of polygonal cells with a common microcapsule.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Forms 0.5- to 1.0-mm-deep colonies in agar; light yellow, angular, fine granulation.</s><s>Grows in liquid medium as a yellow sediment, easily dispersed.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic.</s><s>Methanogenic catabolism: methanol, mono-, di-, and trimethylamines, H<sub>2</sub>-CO<sub>2</sub> are utilized with formation of methane.</s><s>Formate is not utilized.</s><s>Autotrophic anabolism.</s><s>Organic compounds with growth factors enhance growth of some strains but are not obligately needed.</s><s>Ammonium is the source of nitrogen and sulfide is the source of sulfur.</s><s>Optimal temperature, 37 to 40°C; temperature range, 18 to 42°C.</s><s>Optimal pH, 7.5; range, 6 to 8.</s><s>Squalenes are major component of lipids.</s><s>Cytochromes and factor III are present in the cells, while B<i>12</i> is absent.</s><s>Guanosine plus cytosine content of DNA is 36.3 mol%.</s><s>Habitat: soils of wetlands, swamps, freshwater sediments, anaerobic digestors.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain is Z-761 (DSM 1232) isolated from an anaerobic digestor in Moscow, USSR.</s><s>Deposited in the Institute of Microbiology of the Academy of Sciences of the USSR and in Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen, Gottingen, Federal Republic of Germany.</s></p></content></protolog>