<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3906_nm.11364" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11364" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11364" rank="species">Bacillus acidiceler</organism><reference id="rid.3906"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Peak</surname><given-names>K.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Duncan</surname><given-names>K.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Veguilla</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Luna</surname><given-names>V.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>King</surname><given-names>D.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heller</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heberlein-Larson</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Reeves</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cannons</surname><given-names>A.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Amuso</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cattani</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus acidiceler sp. nov., isolated from a forensic specimen, containing Bacillus anthracis pX02 genes.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2031</fpage><lpage>2036</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64993-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17766868</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus acidiceler</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus acidiceler</em> (a.ci.di.ce′ler. L. neut. n. <em>acidum</em> acid, L. masc. adj. <em>celer</em> fast, N.L. masc. adj. <em>acidiceler</em> fast growing in acid.).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies grown at 30 °C for 24 h on TSA with 5 % sheep blood are approximately 3 mm in diameter, cream to pearly grey, non-haemolytic, like sintered glass in opacity, smooth, shiny, becoming dull with a fine crepe texture with age, round, entire, raised to low convex and becoming crater form with age.</s><s>Cells grown in NB, pH 5.8, 30 °C, aerated, are non-motile, round-ended rods (0.8–1×2–12 μm) with rudimentary branching and pronounced chaining; are initially long and flexed (3 h), becoming grossly pleomorphic with distended forms in torturous whorls flanked by ghost cells (23 h); stain Gram-positive to Gram-variable at 6 h.</s><s>Cells in TSB, pH 5.9, 30 °C, aerated, at 6 h are pairs or short chains of bifurcating rods (1–1.2×7–15 μm) with branches of 2–15 μm in length (Fig. 2a, b); branches originate at one or less often, both poles and occasionally from the sidewalls.</s><s>Colonies grown at 30 °C for 24 h on NA, pH 6.8, and TSA, pH 6.0 and 7.2, produced only rare rudimentary branching.</s><s>Endospores are ellipsoidal and usually subterminal in unswollen to overtly swollen cells (Fig. 2c).</s><s>No parasporal bodies or crystals were observed.</s><s>Thin, omnipresent capsule is produced; genes (<em>acp</em>A, <em>cap</em>A, <em>cap</em>B, <em>cap</em>C, <em>cap</em>R, <em>cap</em>D, IS<em>1627</em>, ORF 48, ORF 61 and <em>rep</em>A) and capsule promoter with ≥99.7 % sequence similarity to the capsule operon of <em>B. anthracis</em> are carried on a large plasmid.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive, does not grow anaerobically in the presence of glucose.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite, weakly Voges–Proskauer positive.</s><s><em>β</em>-Galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, indole, ornithine, lysine decarboxylase and citrate are not utilized.</s><s>Hydrolyses casein, gelatin and aesculin, but not starch or urea.</s><s>Optimum pH is near 6; grows well on Sabouraud's agar at pH 5.6 but not at 4.5; alkaline range is to 8.5.</s><s>Respective doubling times (optical density against time) and generation times at 30 °C in aerated, buffered TSB are 30 and 32 min at pH 5.9, 46 and 38–49 min at pH 7.1, and 52 and 48 min at pH 7.5.</s><s>Autolysis is incipient as early as 4 h and extensive at 24 h in TSB at pH 7.1 and 7.5.</s><s>Does not grow with 5 % NaCl or at 45 °C.</s><s>Fatty acids anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (46.66 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (28.11 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (8.21 %) and iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (4.47 %) predominate.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 37.3 mol%.</s><s>Acid produced in API 50CH panels from amygdalin, arbutin, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, gentiobiose, gluconate, d-glucose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, glycerol, glycogen, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, salicin, starch, sucrose, trehalose.</s><s>Acid not produced from adonitol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-galactose, 2- or 5-keto-d-gluconate, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, inositol, inulin, lactose, l-lyxose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, d-melezitose, melibiose, d-raffinose, l-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, sorbose, d-tagatose, d-turanose, xylitol, d-xylose, l-xylose or <em>β</em>-methyl-xyloside.</s><s>Resistant to penicillin, oxacillin, ampicillin, amoxicillin and ceftriaxone; susceptible to chloramphenicol, ciprofloxacin, clarithromycin, clindamycin, erythromycin, gatifloxicin, gentamicin, levofloxacin, moxifloxacin, quinopristin/dalfopristin, rifampicin, streptomycin, tetracycline and vancomycin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Photomicrographs of vegetative cells and sporangia of proposed <em>Bacillus acidiceler</em> sp. nov.</s><s>CBD 119<sup>T</sup> viewed by phase-contrast microscopy. (a, b) Branched vegetative cells grown at 30 °C for 6 h in aerated TSB, pH 5.9. (c) Ellipsoidal endospores lie subterminally in unswollen or swollen sporangia.</s><s>Bars, 2 μm.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain CBD 119<sup>T</sup> (=NRRL B-41736<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18954<sup>T</sup>) was isolated in Tampa, FL from a white powder collected on a window sill and suspected of harbouring <em>B. anthracis</em> during the aftermath of the anthrax bioterrorism attacks of October 2001.</s></p></content></protolog>