<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12782_nm.22566" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22566" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22566" rank="species">Halomonas stenophila</organism><reference id="rid.12782"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Llamas</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Béjar</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martínez-Checa</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martínez-Cánovas</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Molina</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Quesada</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halomonas stenophila sp. nov., a halophilic bacterium that produces sulphate exopolysaccharides with biological activity</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2508</fpage><lpage>2514</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.026369-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21112990</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Halomonas stenophila</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Halomonas stenophila</em> [ste.no′phi.la. Gr. adj. <em>stenos</em> narrow, restricted; N.L. adj. <em>philus</em> -<em>a</em> -<em>um</em> from Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>stenophila</em> referring to the species’ preference for a narrow range of growth conditions (salt concentration, pH and temperature) compared with other <em>Halomonas</em> species, i.e. having an affinity for restricted environmental conditions].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight, Gram-negative rods, 2.5–3.0×0.7–0.75 µm, appearing either singly or in pairs.</s><s>They are non-motile and do not form endospores.</s><s>Exopolysaccharides are produced.</s><s>Colonies on MY medium are circular, convex, cream-coloured and noticeably mucoid after 72 h at 32 °C.</s><s>The growth pattern is uniform in a liquid medium.</s><s>Moderately halophilic; capable of growing in NaCl concentrations of 3–15 % (w/v), with optimum growth occurring between 5 and 10 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–37 °C, with optimum growth at 20–32 °C, and at pH 6–8, with optimum growth at pH 7–8.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic.</s><s>Metabolism is respiratory with oxygen as terminal electron acceptor.</s><s>No growth occurs anaerobically in the presence of nitrate, nitrite or fumarate.</s><s>Under aerobic conditions, nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase are produced.</s><s>Acid is not produced from adonitol, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melezitose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, d-salicin, d-sorbitol, sorbose or trehalose.</s><s>Indole, methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests are negative.</s><s>Tween 20 is hydrolysed, but starch, casein, gelatin, Tween 80, urea and blood are not.</s><s>Phosphatase is produced, but not phenylalanine deaminase or lecithinase.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced from l-cysteine.</s><s>Gluconate is oxidized.</s><s>Pyocyanin, fluorescein and pigment are not produced in tyrosine medium.</s><s>No growth occurs on MacConkey agar or cetrimide agar.</s><s>ONPG is negative.</s><s>The following compounds are acceptable as sole carbon and energy sources: acetate, citrate, ethanol, d-glucose, d-galactose, dl-glycerol, d-mannose, mannitol, trehalose, sorbitol and succinate, but lactose and adonitol are not.</s><s>The following compounds are used as sole carbon, nitrogen and energy sources: l-alanine and l-serine, but not l-cysteine, l-lysine, l-methionine or l-valine.</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin (10 µg), amoxicillin (25 µg), kanamycin (30 µg), nalidixic acid (30 µg), nitrofurantoin (300 µg), polymyxin B (300 IU), rifampicin (30 µg), sulphamide (250 µg), trimethoprim/sulphamethoxazole (1.25–23.75 µg) and tobramycin (100 µg).</s><s>Resistant to erythromycin (15 µg).</s><s>The type strain does not accumulate PHA.</s><s>DNA and tyrosine are hydrolysed, but tyrosine pigment is not produced.</s><s>Aesculin is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-gluconate, isoleucine, lactate, maltose, propionate, d-salicin, starch and l-histidine are not used as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>Principal fatty acids are C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>15 : 0</sub> iso 2-OH/C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>.</s><s>DNA G+C content of the type strain is 61.9 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub> method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, N12<sup>T</sup> ( = CECT 7744<sup>T</sup>  = LMG 25812<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a sample of soil taken from the San Pedro del Pinatar saline wetland in Murcia (Spain).</s><s>Reference strain is B-100.</s></p></content></protolog>