<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7062_nm.1597" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1597" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1597" rank="species">Microvirga subterranea</organism><reference id="rid.7062"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kanso</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Microvirga subterranea gen. nov., sp. nov., a moderate thermophile from a deep subsurface Australian thermal aquifer.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>401</fpage><lpage>406</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02348-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12710604</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Microvirga subterranea</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Microvirga subterranea</em> (sub.ter.ra′ne.a. L. fem. adj. <em>subterranea</em> underground, subterranean).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the properties described for the genus, the following properties apply.</s><s>After 48 h, colonies (diameter 0·5–2 mm) are light pink, convex, smooth and circular with entire margins.</s><s>Cells are rod-shaped (1×1·5–4 μm), stain Gram-negative and possess a typical Gram-negative type cell wall ultrastructure, are motile by a single polar flagellum and do not form spores.</s><s>Cells from old cultures are pleomorphic and contained large intracellular granules.</s><s>Does not grow at 50 °C; optimum pH is 7·0 (pH range for growth 6–9).</s><s>Grows on yeast extract, which is absolutely required for growth.</s><s>Grows on casein hydrolysate, tryptone, xylose and acetate as sole carbon and energy sources but not on other carbohydrates, organic acids, alcohols, methane, glycine, aesculin, NTA, DMF or formamide.</s><s>Gelatin, but not starch or casein, is hydrolysed.</s><s>Very weak acid production is detected from glucose and arabinose.</s><s>Catalase is produced but not oxidase, urease, indole or acetoin.</s><s>Nitrite is produced from nitrate.</s><s>Sensitive to penicillin, ampicillin, chloramphenicol, tetracycline, streptomycin and neomycin but resistant to vancomycin and spectinomycin.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 63·5±0·5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain FaiI4<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-295<sup>T</sup> =DSM 14364<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the geothermal waters of a bore (bore register no. 3768) tapping the GAB of Australia.</s></p></content></protolog>