<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1301_nm.5898" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5898" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5898" rank="species">Renibacterium salmoninarum</organism><reference id="rid.1301"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sanders</surname><given-names>J.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fryer</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Renibacterium salmoninarum gen. nov., sp. nov., the causative agent of bacterial kidney disease in salmonid fishes.</article-title><year>1980</year><volume>30</volume><fpage>496</fpage><lpage>502</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Renibacterium salmoninarum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Renibacterium salmoninarum</i> (sal.mo.ni.na'rum. M.L. <i>Salmoninae</i> subfamily of the <i>Salmonidae</i>; M.L. gen. n. <i>salmoninarum</i>, of the <i>Salmoninae</i>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Short rods, 0.3 to 1.0 by 1.0 to 1.5 μm, often occurring in pairs.</s><s>Strongly gram positive.</s><s>Not acid fast.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Nonencapsulated.</s><s>Endospores are absent.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Smith described the colony characteristics on several media.</s><s>On cysteine serum agar the colonies are circular and convex, white to creamy yellow, and of varying sizes.</s><s>On Loeffler coagulated serum a creamy growth with a matt surface is produced.</s><s>With Dorset egg medium, growth appears as a raised, smooth, shiny yellow layer.</s><s>On cysteine serum broth, creamy-yellow growth occurs only at the surface of the medium.</s><s>Growth on all media is slow, often requiring several weeks of incubation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Grows very slowly at 5 and 22°C; no growth occurs at 37°C.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 15 to 18°C.</s><s>Maximum cell yields are obtained after 20 to 30 days of incubation at 15 to 18°C at pH 6.5 to 7.5.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic.</s><s>There is no apparent acid production from sugars.</s><s>All strains require cysteine for growth.</s><s>The majority of strains also require serum or whole blood for growth.</s><s>Catalase pospositive (activity inhibited by 0.01 M sodium azide).</s><s>Cytochrome-oxidase negative.</s><s>Does not liquefy gelatin.</s><s>Proteolysis without any pH change is produced in litmus milk.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 53.0 mol%</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan contains glutamic acid, lysine, alanine, and glycine.</s><s>The principal cell wall sugar is glucose; arabinose, rhamnose, and mannose are also present.</s><s>Mycolic acids are not present in at least one strain.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Serological tests with 10 strains of this bacterium isolated from various locations in the United States and Canada showed all to be antigenically homologous.</s><s>Does not crossreact to Lancefield group G streptococcal antisera.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Produces a slowly developing chronic infection characterized by gray-white, enlarged necrotic abscesses in the kidney.</s><s>Young and Chapman indicated that the pathological changes in the fine structure of both the glomerulus and renal tubules resemble those observed in mammalian glomerulonephritis and nephrotic syndrome.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Susceptible to chloramphenicol, erythromycin, and sulfonamides.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Occurs among populations of salmonid fishes in North America, Europe, and Asia.</s><s>This bacterium has only been isolated from members of <i>Salmoninae</i>, the salmon, trout, and char, of the family <i>Salmonidae</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: Lea-1-74 (= ATCC 33209).</s><s>The description of the type strain is as follows.</s><s>Short rods, 0.3 to 1.0 by 1.0 to 1.5 μm, often occurring in pairs.</s><s>Strongly gram positive.</s><s>Not acid fast.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Nonencapsulated.</s><s>Endospores are absent.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On cysteine serum agar the colonies are circular and convex, white, and of varying sizes.</s><s>Growth is slow, often requiring several weeks of incubation.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 15 to 18°C.</s><s>Maximum cell yields are obtained after 20 to 30 days of incubation at 15 to 18°C at pH 6.5 to 7.5.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic.</s><s>There is no apparent acid production from glucose.</s><s>Cysteine is required for growth.</s><s>The majority of strains also require serum for growth.</s><s>Catalase positive.</s><s>Cytochrome-oxidase negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 53.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan contains glutamic acid, lysine, alanine, and glycine.</s><s>The principal cell wall sugar is glucose; arabinose, rhamnose, and mannose are also present.</s></p></content></protolog>