<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3876_nm.9492" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9492" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9492" rank="species">Arthrobacter tumbae</organism><reference id="rid.3876"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Heyrman</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Verbeeren</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Swings</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Six novel Arthrobacter species isolated from deteriorated mural paintings.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1457</fpage><lpage>1464</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63358-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16014466</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Arthrobacter tumbae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Arthrobacter tumbae</em> (tum′bae. L. gen. n. <em>tumbae</em> of the tomb).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, short rods and cocci (diameter 0·8–1 μm) occurring singly, in pairs or in clusters.</s><s>They are non-motile and do not form endospores.</s><s>Colonies on NA after 48 h are small (&#x003C;1 mm), yellow–orange, round with entire margins, of low convexity, opaque and smooth.</s><s>No growth in an anaerobic chamber on NA.</s><s>Optimum temperature for growth is 22–30 °C.</s><s>Weak growth at 37 °C, and no growth at 52 °C.</s><s>Growth at 4 °C after 1 week of incubation.</s><s>Growth on medium with 10 % NaCl, but not with 15 % NaCl.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Alkaliphilic; pH range for growth of 7–10 with an optimum of 8–9.</s><s>Using the API CORYNE system, positive reactions are observed for pyrazinamidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>Most strains, including the type strain, test positive for gelatinase.</s><s>Negative reactions are obtained for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and fermentation of ribose, xylose, mannitol and glycogen.</s><s>Variable reactions are obtained for nitrate reduction, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, alkaline phosphatase, aesculin (<em>β</em>-glucosidase), urease, and fermentation of glucose, maltose, lactose and sucrose.</s><s>Using the API ZYM system, activity is detected for esterase C<sub>4</sub>, leucine arylamidase and phosphoamidase (weak).</s><s>Most strains, including the type strain, test positive for esterase lipase C<sub>8</sub> and negative for alkaline phosphatase, valine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase.</s><s>No activity is detected for lipase C<sub>14</sub>, cystine arylamidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Variable reactions are obtained for trypsin, chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>α</em>-mannosidase.</s><s>Predominant fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (approximately 57 and 17 %, respectively).</s><s>Peptidoglycan type, menaquinone content and cell wall sugars are given in Table 1.</s><s>Polar lipids of the type strain are phosphatidylinositol, phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol and one unknown phospholipid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA, determined for the type strain LMG 19501<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 16406<sup>T</sup>), is 64·7 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is negative for all variable characters listed above, except for trypsin in the API ZYM system.</s><s>Isolated from a biofilm overgrowing a mural painting in the Servilia tomb (Roman necropolis of Carmona, Spain).</s></p></content></protolog>