<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8413_nm.13562" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13562" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13562" rank="species">Rheinheimera soli</organism><reference id="rid.8413"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ryu</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>B.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>C.O.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rheinheimera soli sp. nov., a gammaproteobacterium isolated from soil in Korea.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2271</fpage><lpage>2274</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65489-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18842839</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rheinheimera soli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rheinheimera soli</em> (so′li. L. fem. gen. n. <em>soli</em> of soil, the source of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are white, raised and circular with entire margins after 3 days on R2A agar.</s><s>Cells are facultatively aerobic, Gram-negative, straight or curved rods that are motile by means of a polar flagellum.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 25–30 °C and pH 7.0–7.5.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite, but nitrogen gas is not produced.</s><s>Casein, urea, tyrosine, Tweens 80 and 20, aesculin, starch and gelatin are hydrolysed.</s><s>Produces acid from raffinose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, l-arabinose, melibiose, d-fructose, salicin and arbutin, but not from d-mannose, d-galactose or d-mannitol.</s><s>Negative for indole production, glucose fermentation and arginine dihydrolase activity.</s><s>Positive for assimilation of d-glucose, l-arabinose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and maltose, but negative for assimilation of d-mannose, d-mannitol, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid, trisodium citrate and phenylacetic acid (API 20NE).</s><s>Produces alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, but not lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Weak enzyme activities are observed for acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase.</s><s>Contains large amounts of phosphatidylethanolamine and phosphatidylglycerol, and small amounts of an unknown polar lipid and three unknown polar lipids containing amino groups.</s><s>The isoprenoid quinones are Q-8 (75 %) and MK-7 (25 %).</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 49.2 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, BD-d46<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22077<sup>T</sup> =DSM 19413<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from playground soil in Jinju, South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>