<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1191_nm.9816" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9816" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9816" rank="species">Stappia alba</organism><reference id="rid.1191"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Pujalte</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Macián</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arahal</surname><given-names>D.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garay</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Stappia alba sp. nov., isolated from Mediterranean oysters</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>28</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>672</fpage><lpage>678</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.syapm.2005.05.010</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16261856</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Stappia alba</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Stappia alba</em> (al’.ba. L. fem. adj. alba white)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram negative, straight rods, 2–4 μm length by 1 μm width, motile by a subpolar flagellum.</s><s>They divide by binary fission and do not form rosettes.</s><s>Colonies on MA after 6 days incubation are not pigmented, opaque and mucous, indicating production of extracellular capsular material.</s><s>Oxidase and catalase positive.</s><s>Slightly halophilic, with specific requirements of Na<sup>+</sup> and divalent cations (Ca<sup>2+</sup> or Mg<sup>2+</sup>).</s><s>Salinity range for growth is 1–8% (w/v) total salt.</s><s>Temperature range for growth includes 13–28 °C but neither 4 nor 37 °C or above.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemoorganotrophic aerobe.</s><s>Fermentation or acid production from carbohydrates are absent.</s><s>In anaerobic conditions nitrate is reduced to gas.</s><s>Gelatine, casein, starch, agar, alginate and lecithin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Medium for Tween 80 hydrolysis either does not support growth or shows no hydrolytic activity.</s><s>Strains hydrolysed DNA on DNAse medium prepared with half-strength ASW.</s><s>The following activities are negative: indole production from tryptophan, sulphide production from thiosulphate, ADH, LDC and ODC.</s><s>Able to grow with l-arabinose, d-xylose, d-mannose, d-cellobiose, sucrose, propionate, pyruvate, citrate, aconitate, 2-ketoglutarate, succinate, fumarate, malate, acetate, lactate, <a href="content/mmlsi7.ml"><em>β</em></a>-hydroxybutyrate, l-threonine, l-glutamate and <a href="content/mmlsi8.ml"><em>γ</em></a>-aminobutyrate.</s><s>Growth is weak or variable on d-glucose, d-fructose, d-raffinose, d-melibiose, d-gluconate, d-glucuronate, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, glycerate and l-alanine.</s><s>Not able to grow on d-ribose, d-galactose, d-trehalose, l-rhamnose, maltose, lactose, salicin, amygdalin, d-galacturonate, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, glycerol, <em>m</em>-inositol, saccharate, glycine, l-leucine, l-serine, l-ornithine, l-aspartate, l-lysine, sarcosine or methanol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains 5OM6<sup>T</sup>, 5OM9 and 5OM30 were isolated from oysters cultured at the Spanish Mediterranean coast, near Vinaroz.</s><s>They have been deposited at the CECT (Colección Española de Cultivos Tipo) under the numbers CECT 5095<sup>T</sup>, CECT 5094 and CECT 5096, respectively.</s><s>The type strain has also been deposited at CIP (Collection de l’Institut Pasteur) under the number CIP 108402<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>