<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2500_nm.11435" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11435" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11435" rank="species">Mucilaginibacter gracilis</organism><reference id="rid.2500"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Pankratov</surname><given-names>T.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liesack</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dedysh</surname><given-names>S.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mucilaginibacter paludis gen. nov., sp. nov. and Mucilaginibacter gracilis sp. nov., pectin-, xylan- and laminarin-degrading members of the family Sphingobacteriaceae from acidic Sphagnum peat bog</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2349</fpage><lpage>2354</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65100-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17911309</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Mucilaginibacter gracilis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Mucilaginibacter gracilis</em> (gra′ci.lis. L. masc. adj. <em>gracilis</em> slender or thin).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is as for the genus with the following additional traits.</s><s>Cells are 0.4–0.5 μm wide.</s><s>Colony colour varies from creamy to yellowish or light orange.</s><s>Utilizes d-arabinose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-xylose, d-lactose, maltose, d-rhamnose, d-raffinose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose, d-fructose, d-cellobiose and pyruvate but not <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-melibiose, d-melezitose, l-sorbose, acetate, butyrate, valerate, gluconate, capronate, malate, propionate, succinate, fumarate, citrate, adonitol, arabitol, arbutin, dulcitol, inulin, mannitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, sorbitol, mannose or sodium d-galacturonate.</s><s>Capable of fermenting glucose and sucrose.</s><s>Hydrolyses chondroitin 6-sulfate, gellan gum, laminarin, pectin, pullulan, starch and xylan but not alginate, CM-cellulose, cellulose, chitin, aesculin, fucoidan, heparin or lichenan.</s><s>Produces acid from d-galactose, d-glucose, d-xylose, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, d-fructose, d-cellobiose, laminarin and xylan but not from mannose.</s><s>Optimal growth at 18–22 °C and at pH 5.8–6.2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain TPT18<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-1391<sup>T</sup> =VKM B-2447<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from the <em>Sphagnum</em> peat bog Bakchar in the Tomsk region of western Siberia.</s></p></content></protolog>