<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5789_nm.4752" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4752" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4752" rank="species">Ureaplasma parvum</organism><reference id="rid.5789"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Robertson</surname><given-names>J.A</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stemke</surname><given-names>G.W</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Davis</surname><given-names>J.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Harasawa</surname><given-names>R</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thirkell</surname><given-names>D</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kong</surname><given-names>F</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shepard</surname><given-names>M.C</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ford</surname><given-names>D.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of Ureaplasma parvum sp. nov. and emended description of Ureaplasma urealyticum (Shepard et al. 1974) Robertson et al. 2001.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>587</fpage><lpage>597</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.01965-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11931172</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Ureaplasma parvum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Ureaplasma parvum</i> (par'vum. L. neut. adj. <i>parvum</i> small, referring to the fact that its genome is significantly smaller than that of <i><i>U. urealyticum</i></i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Phenotypic characteristics.</s><s>Growth inhibition of cells by (or colony reaction with) polyclonal antisera to one or more of the specific antigenic determinants associated with the present parvo biovar of the human ureaplasmas (serovars 1, 3, 6 or 14) but not to any antigenic determinants associated with the emended <i>U. urealyticum</i> (T960<sup>T</sup> biovar of the human ureaplasmas or its serovars 2, 4, 5, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12 or 13).</s><s>Parvo biovarspeci fic polypeptide patterns obtained by PAGE: these may be enhanced through reaction with polyclonal antiserum or monoclonal antibodies to the antigenic specificities associated with the species.</s><s>Growth is inhibited temporarily in the presence of 1 mM Mn<sup>2+</sup>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Genotypic characteristics.</s><s>Genomes of ~760 kbp demonstrate" 70% hybridization patterns with the DNA of other strains of the present parvo biovar of ureaplasmas.</s><s>RFLP patterns which are similar to those characteristic of other serovars of the parvo biovar but differ from those characteristic of the emended <i>U. urealyticum</i>; amplification by PCRs for parvo biovar-specific nucleotide sequences for the urease-associated genes, the 16S rRNA genes, the 16S-23S rRNA intergenic regions, and the 5' end of the genes of the multiple-banded antigens, and the parvo biovar-specific RAPD PCR.</s><s>The type strain of <i>U. parvum</i> will be the serovar 3 standard (strain 27<sup>T</sup>) represented by ATCC 27815<sup>T</sup> and NCTC 11736<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>The G+­C content of the DNA is 26 mol%; its genome size is 751719 kbp.</s><s>The most recent GenBank accession numbers for the sequences of its 16S rRNA and 16S-23S rRNA intergenic spacer region are AF073456 and AF059323, respectively.</s><s>The genome sequence carries US patent number 5728522 (the annotated sequence may be found at http://genome.microbio.uab.edu/uu/uugen.htm)</s></p></content></protolog>