<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5221_nm.1653" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1653" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1653" rank="species">Burkholderia vandii</organism><reference id="rid.5221"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Urakami</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ito-Yoshida</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Araki</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kijima</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>K.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Komagata</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Pseudomonas plantarii and Pseudomonas glumae to Burkholderia as Burkholderia spp. and description of Burkholderia vandii sp. nov.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>235</fpage><lpage>245</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-2-235</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Burkholderia vandii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Burkholderia vandii</i> (vand' i. i. M.L. adj. <i>vandii</i>, coming from Hindi Vanda.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Non-spore-forming, gram-negative, rod-shaped organisms.</s><s>The cells are 0.5 to 1.0 by 1.5 to 3.0 μm and have rounded ends.</s><s>The cells occur singly, rarely in pairs, and are motile by means of one or several polar flagella.</s><s>Granules of poly-β-hydroxybutyrate accumulate in the cells.</s><s>Colonies are white to light yellow.</s><s>No water-soluble fluorescent pigment is produced.</s><s>Abundant growth occurs in nutrient broth, PYG broth, and peptone water.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>The methyl red test and the Voges-Proskauer reaction are negative.</s><s>Indole and hydrogen sulfide are not produced.</s><s>Starch is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Ammonia is produced.</s><s>Litmus milk is not changed.</s><s>Positive for dentrification and hydrolysis of gelatin.</s><s>Acids are weakly produced from inositol and glycerol oxidatively, but are not produced from L-arabinose, D-xylose, D-glucose, D-mannose, D-fructose, D-galactose, maltose, sucrose, lactose, trehalose, D-sorbitol, D-mannitol, and soluble starch.</s><s>Acid is not produced from sugars fermentatively.</s><s>L-Arabinose, D-xylose, Dglucose, D-fructose, D-mannose, D-galactose, lactose, trehalose, D-sorbitol, D-mannitol, inositol, glycerol, L-leucine, L-isoleucine, L-threonine, ornithine, sarcosine, ethanol, <i>n</i>-propanol, propylene glycol, succinic acid, acetic acid, sebacic acid, adipic acid, mesaconic acid, D-tartaric acid, citraconic acid, caprylic acid, nicotinic acid, 4-hydroxy-2-quinoline carboxylic acid, <i>n</i>-capric acid, <i>n</i>-heptanoic acid, and <i>n</i>-nonanoic acid are utilized, but sucrose, L-rhamnose, maltose, soluble starch, adonitol, glycine, DL-norleucine, DL-citrulline, methanol, <i>n</i>-butanol, isobutanol, 2,3-butanediol, monoethanolamine, <i>n</i>-amylamine, tryptamine, benzylamine, acetoamide, formic acid, citric acid, suberic acid, levulinic acid, L-tartaric acid, itaconic acid, pimelic acid, benzoylformic acid, L-mandelic acid, glutaric acid, DL-2-aminobutyric acid, <i>n</i>-caproic acid, benzoic acid, <i>p</i>-aminobenzoic acid, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoic acid, salicylic acid, azelaic acid, glycolic acid, monomethylamine, dimethylamine, trimethylamine, N,N-dimethylformamide, methane, and hydrogen are not utilized.</s><s>Growth factors are not required.</s><s>Ammonia, urea, and peptone are utilized as nitrogen sources, but nitrate is not utilized.</s><s>Oxidase, catalase, and urease are produced.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Metabolism is strictly respiratory and not fermentative.</s><s>Good growth occurs between pH 5.0 and 7.5, and weak growth occurs at pH 4.0 and 8.0.</s><s>Growth does not occur at pH values above 9.0 and below 3.0.</s><s>Good growth occurs at 30 and 37°C, but does not occur at 42°C.</s><s>Growth does not occur in the presence of 3% sodium chloride.</s><s>Susceptible to cefotaxime, cefmetanoxim, ceftizoxime, gentamicin, amikacin, minocycline, cefotiam, cefmetazole, lotamoxysefu, and arninobenzylpenicillin.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0.1% (wt/vol) fusaric acid.</s><s>Growing cells inhibit the growth of the phytopathogenic microorganisms <i>C. michiganensis</i> and <i>F. oxysporum</i>.</s><s>The cellular fatty acids include large amounts of straight-chain saturated <i>n</i>-C<sub>16:0</sub> acid and unsaturated <i>n</i>-C<sub>16:1</sub> and C<sub>18:1</sub> acids.</s><s>The hydroxy acids include large amounts of 3-OH C<sub>14:0</sub> and 2-OH C<sub>16:0</sub> acids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The ubiquinone system is Q-8.</s><s>The type strain is strain VA-1316.</s><s>Strain VA-1316<sup>T</sup> has all of the characteristics described above for the species.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 68.5 mol% G+C.</s><s>This strain was isolated from <i>Vanda</i> species by Urakami et al. as a antibiotic-producing bacterium active against <i>C. michiganensis</i> subsp. <i>michiganensis</i>.</s><s>The type strain has been deposited in the Japan Collection of Microorganisms, Institute of Physical and Chemical Research, under accession number JCM 7957.</s></p></content></protolog>