<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.287_nm.3672" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3672" rank="genus">Desulfomonile</organism><reference id="rid.287"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>DeWeerd</surname><given-names>K.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mandelco</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanner</surname><given-names>R.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Woese</surname><given-names>C.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suflita</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Desulfomonile tiedjei gen. nov. and sp. nov., a novel anaerobic, dehalogenating, sulfate-reducing bacterium.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>154</volume><fpage>23</fpage><lpage>30</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00249173</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Desulfomonile</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Desulfomonile</i> (De-sul-fo-mo-ni-le, L. pref. <i>de</i> from; L.n. <i>sulfur</i> sulfur; L.n. <i>monile</i> collar; M.L. neut. n. <i>Desulfomonile</i> a "collared" sulfate-reducer)</s></p><p class="description"><s>We propose that the anaerobic, dehalogenating, sulfate-reducing bacterium strain DCB-I be placed in a new genus <i>Desulfomonile</i>.</s><s>The type species for this genus is <i>D. tiedjei</i> sp. nov., named to recognize the contributions of James M.</s><s>Tiedje and his laboratory to the field of microbial ecology.</s><s>A combined generic and specific description follows.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rod-shaped cells 0.8-1 by 5-10 μm, with rounded ends, an invagination of the cell wall (collar) likely involved in binary fission, single.</s><s>Non-motile and no spore formation.</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Esculin negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strict anaerobic chemoorganotroph or autotroph, which can grow in mineral medium with 1 mM Na<sub>2</sub>S⋄9 H<sub>2</sub>O or 0.5 mM Na<sub>2</sub>S<sub>2</sub>O<sub>4</sub> as reductants.</s><s>Thiamine, nicotinamide and 1,4-naphthoquinone are required as growth factors.</s><s>Pyruvate is used as a carbon source and an electron donor and is converted to acetate and lactate.</s><s>Sulfate, sulfite, thiosulfate, and <i>meta</i>-halobenzoates can serve as electron acceptors and are reduced to H<sub>2</sub>S and benzoates, respectively.</s></p><p class="description"><s>L-Lactate, butyrate or acetate are poor substrates for growth with thiosulfate as the electron acceptor.</s><s>Benzoate, formate or H<sub>2</sub> and CO<sub>2</sub> can serve as carbon source and electron donors with sulfate or thiosulfate as the electron acceptor.</s><s>3-Anisate, 4-anisate, vanillate, isovanillate can serve as carbon sources with a slight stimulation of growth occurring if sulfate or thiosulfate are also present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The pH range for growth is 6.5-7.8 and optimum at 6.8 - 7.0.</s><s>Temperature range is 30-38°C and optimum is 37°C.</s><s>Cells contain 97 μg⋄g<sup>-1</sup> wet weight of PHB and also contain desulfoviridin and cytochrome c<sub>3</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G + C content of the DNA is 49.0 mol% (Stevens et al. 1988).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain <i>Desulfomonile tiedjei</i> strain DCB-1, ATCC 49306, was isolated from a sewage sludge bacterial consortium enriched on 3-chlorobenzoate as the sole carbon and energy source.</s></p></content></protolog>