<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6703_nm.5858" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5858" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5858" rank="species">Arthrobacter methylotrophus</organism><reference id="rid.6703"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Borodina</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kelly</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ward-Rainey</surname><given-names>N.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wood</surname><given-names>A.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Enzymes of dimethylsulfone metabolism and the phylogenetic characterization of the facultative methylotrophs Arthrobacter sulfonivorans sp. nov., Arthrobacter methylotrophus sp. nov., and Hyphomicrobium sulfonivorans sp. nov.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>177</volume><fpage>173</fpage><lpage>183</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00203-001-0373-3</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11807567</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Arthrobacter methylotrophus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Arthrobacter methylotrophus</i> (me.thy.lo.tro'phus. M.L. [from Gr.] prefix <i>methylo</i>-pertaining to the [chemical] methyl group, Gr. v. <i>trephein</i> to feed, M.L. adj. <i>methylotrophus</i> feeding on methyl groups)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are spherical or rod-shaped, showing a rod-coccus growth cycle, 0.6 μm in diameter and 1.3 μm in length.</s><s>Gram-positive, forming clumps and chains in liquid culture, and are non-motile; spores or capsules not seen; catalase-and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Grows heterotrophically and aerobically on glucose, fructose, sucrose, galactose, acetate, ethanol, pyruvate, malate, succinate, citrate, serine, alanine, taurine and yeast extract, and on alkanesulfonates (propane-, butane-, pentane- and hexane-sulfonate) and diethylsulfone.</s><s>Grows aerobically on methylated sulfur compounds (dimethylsulfone, dimethylsulfoxide, dimethylsulfide), methanol, methylamine, trimethylamine and formaldehyde.</s><s>Methylotrophic growth with dimethylsulfone uses the ribulose monophosphate cycle for formaldehyde assimilation.</s><s>Methylotrophic growth with methanol uses the serine pathway for C<sub>1</sub>-assimilation.</s><s>Does not grow with methanesulfonate or autotrophically on inorganic sulfur compounds.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Growth on dimethylsulfone occurs optimally at pH 7.2–7.5 and at 25°C.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 4–30°C with no growth at 37 or 44°C.</s><s>Ammonium chloride, nitrate, methylamine and EDTA are used as nitrogen sources for growth.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 1.5% (w/v) NaCl, weakly with 2.5% (w/v) NaCl, but not with 5% (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>On dimethylsulfone-agar medium they produce creamy-yellow, circular-convex colonies, 1.0–1.3 mm in diameter.</s><s>MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>) is the principal isoprenoid quinone with smaller amounts of MK-10(H<sub>2</sub>), MK-8(H<sub>2</sub>), MK-9, MK-7(H<sub>2</sub>) and MK-11(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>The principal cellular fatty acid is 13-methylpentadecanoic acid, with 14-methylpentadecanoic acid, 15-methylhexadecanoic acid and 15-methylheptadecanoic acid also present.</s><s>Peptidoglycan contains lysine as the diagnostic diamino acid, as well as alanine and glutamic acid; provisional peptidoglycan type (L-Lys–L-Ala<sub>2-4</sub>) is an A11.5, A11.6 or A11.7 structure.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 61 mol%.</s><s>As determined by 16S rRNA gene sequence analysis the organism is closely related to other members of the genus.</s><s>The type strain is strain TGA, which was isolated from soil from the root system of <i>Tagetes minuta</i>, and is deposited at the American Type Culture Collection under the accession number ATCC BAA-111, and at the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen, Braunschweig, Germany, as DSM 14008.</s><s>The GenBank accession number for its 16S rRNA gene sequence is AF235090.</s></p></content></protolog>