<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6712_nm.5528" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5528" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5528" rank="species">Enterococcus avium</organism><reference id="rid.6712"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Farrow</surname><given-names>J.A.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kilpper-Bälz</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schleifer</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Enterococcus avium nom. rev., comb. nov.; E. casseliflavus nom. rev., comb. nov.; E. durans nom. rev., comb. nov.; E. gallinarum comb. nov.; and E. malodoratus sp. nov.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>220</fpage><lpage>223</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-2-220</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Enterococcus avium</i> sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Enterococcus avium</i> (av.i'um. L.n. <i>avis</i> bird; L.gen. pl. <i>avium</i> of birds)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following description of <i>Enterococcus avium</i> (ex Nowlan and Deibel 1967) nom. rev., comb. nov. is based on previous descriptions (6, 9, 10, 13, 18, 20, 21).</s><s>Ovoid cells elongated in the direction of the chain, mostly in pairs or short chains.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Surface colonies on blood agar or nutrient agar are circular, smooth, and entire.</s><s>Nonpigmented.</s><s>Most strains produce an alphα-reaction on blood agar.</s><s>No requirement for riboflavin or pyridoxal in casein hydrolysate medium.</s><s>Folinic acid (or folic acid plus thymine) is required for growth.</s><s>Amino acid requirements not known.</s><s>Arginine and starch are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>H2S produced.</s><s>Acetylmethylcarbinol not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Does not grow in the presence of 0.04% tellurite or in 0.1% methylene blue milk.</s><s>Other biochemical characteristics are given in Table 1.</s><s>Reacts with Lancefield group D antisera and also usually, but not always, with Lancefield group Q antisera.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Group A peptidoglycan based upon lysine (type, Lys-D-Asp).</s><s>Respiratory quinones absent.</s><s>The major non-hydroxylated long-chain fatty acids are tetradecanoic (C<sub>14:0</sub>) and hexadecanoic (C<sub>16:0</sub>) acids; octadecenoic (C<sub>18:1</sub>) and <i>cis</i>-11,12-methylenoctadecanoic (ΔC<sub>19:0</sub>) acids are present in only small amounts (less than 5%).</s><s>Isolated from human, animal, and chicken feces.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA ranges from 39 to 40 mol%, as determined by melting temperature.</s><s>The strains form a distinct homology group, as determined by DNA-DNA hybridization (10).</s><s>The type strain is NCDO 2369 (=Guthof E6844=ATCC 14025).</s><s>This strain was isolated from human feces (11).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>In most respects the description of the type strain resembles the description of the species.</s><s>Positive reactions are obtained with Lancefield group Q and group D antisera.</s><s>Acid is produced from gluconate and from α-methyl-D-mannoside.</s><s>Strain NCDO 2369<sup>T</sup> (T = type strain) produces β-galactosidase and hydrolyzes hippurate (Table 1).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>E. avium</i> strains form a distinct species on the basis of genomic (10) and biochemical criteria (10, 18) (Table 1). <i>E. avium</i> and <i>E. malodoratus</i> are the only species of the genus <i>Enterococcus</i> that are known to produce H<sub>2</sub>S (detected by lead acetate paper inserted into slopes of cultures on blood agar base no. 2 [Oxoid] medium supplemented with 0.05% [wt/vol] cysteine hydrochloride).</s><s>However, in contrast to <i>E. malodoratus</i>, <i>E. avium</i> strains grow well at 45°C and survive heating at 60°C for 30 min.</s><s>In addition, they may be distinguished by their fermentation patterns and by the production of α-galactosidase ( <i>E. malodoratus</i> produces this compound but <i>E. avium</i> does not). <i>E. malodoratus</i> never reacts with Lancefield group Q antisera.</s></p></content></protolog>