<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2344_nm.1282" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1282" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1282" rank="species">Rhizobium etli</organism><reference id="rid.2344"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Segovia</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Martínez-Romero</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of American Rhizobium leguminosarum biovar phaseoli type I strains as Rhizobium etli sp. nov.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>374</fpage><lpage>377</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-43-2-374</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8494746</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhizobium etli</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhizobium etli</i> (et'li. Nahuatl n. <i>etl</i>, Bean; N. L. gen. n. <i>etli</i>, from bean)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, gram-negative, nonsporeforming flagellated rods that are 0.5 to 1 by 2 to 3 μm.</s><s>Colonies are circular, convex, opaque, and usually 2 to 4 mm in diameter within 2 to 4 days when they are grown on PY agar medium.</s><s>They are wet and translucent when they are grown on YM medium.</s><s>These bacteria are unable to grow on Luria broth medium, on PY medium lacking calcium, or in the presence of carbenicillin, spectinomycin, chloramphenicol, or rifampin.</s><s>They are able to grow on minimal medium containing malate as a carbon source, but not with arginine, hypoxanthine, or sorbitol as a carbon source.</s><s>The maximum growth temperature is 35°C.</s><s>All strains are nalidixic acid resistant.</s><s>They are distinguished from other species at the molecular level by the results of whole-DNA hybridization tests, their multilocus enzyme electrophoresis profiles, and their ribosomal gene sequences.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>R. etli</i> biovar phaseoli strains nodulate and fix nitrogen on <i>Phaseolus vulgaris</i> L. exclusively.</s><s>They are distinguished from other species at the molecular level by the presence of nitrogenase reductase gene reiterations and the separation of the <i>nodA</i> and <i>nodBC</i> genes, which form two separate transcriptional units.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Well-studied <i>R. etli</i> biovar phaseoli CFN 42 is designated the type strain; it has the characteristics described above for <i>R. etli</i> sp. nov.</s><s>This strain belongs to <i>R. etli</i> biovar phaseoli because it is capable of nodulating beans effectively and has the molecular traits described above.</s></p></content></protolog>