<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1366_nm.1581" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1581" rank="genus">Methylobacterium</organism><reference id="rid.1366"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Green</surname><given-names>P.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bousfield</surname><given-names>I.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Emendation of Methylobacterium Patt, Cole and Hanson 1976; Methylobacterium rhodinum (Heumann 1962) comb. nov. corrig.; Methylobacterium radiotolerans, (Ito and Iizuka 1971) comb. nov. corrig.; and Methylobacterium mesophilicum, (Austin and Goodfellow 1979) comb. nov.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>875</fpage><lpage>877</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emendation of <i>Methylohacterium</i> Patt, Cole, and Hanson 1976 (Approved Lists 1980)</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Rods 0.8 to 1.0 by 1.0 to 8.0 μm, occurring singly or occasionally in rosettes (8,15); occasionally branched and pleomorphic (11). Motile by single polar, subpolar or lateral flagella, although some strains are not vigorously motile. Cells often contain large sudanophilic inclusions and sometimes volutin granules. Gram negative, although many strains are gram variable; representative strains have the multilayered cell wall structure and the type of citrate synthase (6) characteristic of gram-negative bacteria. Most strains grow slowly and some do not grow at all on nutrient agar. Colonies on glycerol-peptone agar are ≤1 to 3 mm in diameter and pale pink to bright orange red; colonies on methanol-salts agar are a more uniform pale pink. The pigment is insoluble and probably carotenoid (4, 9). In static liquid media strains grow as a pink surface ring or pellicle. Strictly aerobic; catalase and oxidase (often weakly) positive. Chemoorganotrophs, facultative methylotrophs, and occasionally facultative methanotrophs (15). The ability of some strains to utilize methane as a sole source of carbon and energy is easily lost if strains are not maintained on an inorganic medium in a methane atmosphere (Hanson, personal communication). Representative strains have been reported to assimilate 1-C compounds via the homoisocitrate pathway (10) (icl<sup>-</sup> pathway [2, 18]) and to have a complete tricarboxylic acid cycle when they are grown on complex organic substrates (3, 15).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Members of the genus have been isolated from soil, dust, freshwater, lake sediments, leaf surfaces and nodules, rice grains, air, and hospital environments.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimum growth temperature is in the range from 25 to 30°C, and the deoxyribonucleic acid base composition is in the range from 60 to 70 mol% guanine plus cytosine.</s><s>The type species is <i>M . organophilum</i> Patt, Cole, and Hanson 1976 (Approved Lists 1980)</s></p></content></protolog>