<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12711_nm.9450" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9450" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9450" rank="species">Paenibacillus anaericanus</organism><reference id="rid.12711"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>K.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.-S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Paenibacillus ginsengisoli as a later heterotypic synonym of Paenibacillus anaericanus</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2101</fpage><lpage>2106</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.025650-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20870883</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Paenibacillus anaericanus</em> Horn <em>et al.</em> 2005</s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>The description is as given by Horn <em>et al.</em> (2005) with the following additions and modifications.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of up to 3 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced.</s><s>The methyl red test is negative, but the Voges–Proskauer test is positive.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed, but casein, DNA and Tweens 20 and 80 are not.</s><s>Lecithinase and ornithine decarboxylase are not produced.</s><s>On the basis of the method of Kim <em>et al.</em> (2010), amygdalin, l-arabinose, d-galactose, glycogen, melibiose, d-ribose, d-salicin, trehalose, turanose and d-xylose are utilized as sole sources of carbon and energy, but l-alanine, l-arabitol, l-fucose, gentiobiose, gluconate, glycerol, l-histidine, malate, malonate, d-mannitol, melezitose, l-proline, raffinose, l-rhamnose and l-serine are not.</s><s>In the API 50CH gallery, acid is produced from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, aesculin, amygdalin, l-arabinose, arbutin, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, d-glucose, glycerol, glycogen, inulin, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl α-d-glucoside, methyl β-d-xyloside, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, d-salicin, starch, sucrose, trehalose, turanose and d-xylose, but not from d-adonitol, d-arabinose, d- or l-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, d- or l-fucose, gluconate, inositol, 2- or 5-ketogluconate, d-lyxose, d-mannitol, melezitose, methyl α-d-mannoside, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, d-tagatose, xylitol or l-xylose.</s><s>According to the results of the API ZYM test, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase and β-galactosidase are present, but alkaline phosphatase, lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase are absent.</s><s>Susceptible to amikacin, ampicillin, bacitracin, ceftazidime, ceftriaxone, cephalothin, ciprofloxacin, doxycycline, gentamicin, imipenem, norfloxacin, novobiocin, polymyxin B and tobramycin.</s><s>Resistant to colistin and oxacillin.</s><s>The major fatty acid is antesio-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 42.2–43.2 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>