<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.341_nm.6395" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6395" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6395" rank="species">Mycobacterium pulveris</organism><reference id="rid.341"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tsukamura</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mizuno</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Toyama</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycobacterium pulveris sp. nov., a nonphotochromogenic mycobacterium with an intermediate growth rate.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>811</fpage><lpage>815</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-4-811</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycobacterium pulveris</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycobacterium pulveris</i> (pul'ver.is. L. gen. n. <i>pulvis</i> dust referring to the source, house dusts)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on eight strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are acid-fast short rods or coccoid forms less than 2 μm long and about 0.5 μm wide.</s><s>Mycelia or branching forms are not produced in initial growth on Ogawa egg medium (6).</s><s>Aryl sulfatase activity is positive after 14 days.</s><s>These characteristics indicate that the strains belong to the genus <i>Mycobacterium</i> (3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>With one loopful (0.1 mg, wet weight) of inoculum, all strains show abundant growth on Ogawa egg medium after incubation at 37°C for 5 days.</s><s>One strain grows after 3 days.</s><s>Thus, the growth rate is faster than that of slowly growing mycobacteria and slower than that of rapidly growing mycobacteria.</s><s>When plated onto Ogawa egg medium as single cells, the organisms grow as colonies after 7 to 8 days.</s><s>When they are isolated, the strains are susceptible to 0.2% picric acid in modified Sauton agar medium (pH 7.0) (6), but after a few transfers on Ogawa egg medium, they grow on this medium.</s><s>Strains do not utilize succinate, malate, or fumarate as a sole source of carbon in the presence of ammoniacal nitrogen.</s><s>The characteristics given above are similar to those of slowly growing mycobacteria (4, 5, 8, 9, 11).</s><s>However, our isolates are resistant to 0.2% sodium nitrite in modified Sauton agar medium and to 5% NaCl in Ogawa egg medium.</s><s>These characteristics are similar to those of rapidly growing mycobacteria (4, 5, 8, 9, 11).</s><s>Thus, we consider our isolates to be intermediate between slowly growing and rapidly growing mycobacteria.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth is produced on Ogawa egg medium or Lowenstein-Jensen medium at 28, 37, and 42°C, but only three of eight strains grow at 45°C.</s><s>Colonies on Ogawa egg medium are wet, smooth, creamy, and nonphotochromogenic.</s><s>Colonies on modified Sauton agar medium (with glutamate substituted for asparagine) are wet, smooth, and creamy or slightly yellowish.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains are resistant to hydroxylamine hydrochloride (125 μg/ml), ethambutol (5 μg/ml), rifampin (25 μg/ml), isoniazid (10 μg/ml), sodium chloride (5%), <i>p</i>-nitrobenzoic acid (0.5 mg/ml), sodium salicylate (0.5 mg/ml), and thiophene-2-carboxylic acid hydrazide (1 μg/ml) in Ogawa egg medium; all strains are susceptible to hydroxylamine hydrochloride (250 μg/ml), mitomycin C (5 μg/ml), and 5-fluorouracil (20 μg/ml) in Ogawa egg medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Niacin is not produced; <i>p</i>-aminosalicylate and salicylate are not degraded to catechol; arylsulfatase activity is negative after 3 days but positive after 14 days; catalase activity (semiquantitative) is negative (foam height, less than 45 mm); β-esterase is produced; nicotinamidase and pyrazinamidase tests are positive.</s><s>Urease activity is positive in two of eight strains.</s><s>Acetamidase, benzamidase, isonicotinamidase, salicylamidase , allantoinase , and succinamidase activities are negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Glutamate is utilized, but serine, glucosamine, acetamide, benzamide, monoethanolamine, and trimethyelene diamine are not utilized as simultaneous nitrogen and carbon sources.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acetate and pyruvate are utilized, but citrate, succinate, malate, malonate, benzoate, and fumarate are not utilized as sole carbon sources in the presence of ammoniacal nitrogen.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Glucose and <i>n</i>-propanol are utilized, but fructose, sucrose, mannose, galactose, arabinose, xylose, rhamnose, trehalose, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, ethanol, propylene glycol, 1,3-butylene glycol, 1,4-butylene glycol, 2,3-butylene glycol, <i>n</i>-butanol, and isobutanol are not utilized as sole carbon sources in the presence of ammoniacal nitrogen.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Serine, acetamide, urea, pyrazinamide, nicotinamide, and nitrate are utilized, but benzamide and nitrite are not utilized as sole sources of nitrogen in the presence of glycerol carbon.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Additional characteristics are shown in Tables 3 and 4.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Of characteristics that are variable among strains within the species, the type strain produces no growth at 45°C, is tolerant to 0.1% sodium salicylate in modified Sauton agar medium, produces g-galactosidase and urease activities, does not utilize mannose as a sole source of carbon, and grows at 37°C after 5 days.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain NCH (National Chubu Hospital) 33505 (= ATCC 35154).</s></p></content></protolog>