<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3592_nm.307" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.307" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.307" rank="species">Haloferax alexandrinus</organism><reference id="rid.3592"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Asker</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ohta</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Haloferax alexandrinus sp. nov., an extremely halophilic canthaxanthin-producing archaeon from a solar saltern in Alexandria (Egypt).</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>729</fpage><lpage>738</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.01999-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12054232</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Haloferax alexandrinus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Haloferax alexandrinus</i> (al.ex.and.ri'nus. L. masc. adj. <i>alexandrinus</i> pertaining to Alexandria, a city in Egypt, where the strain was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells stain Gram-negative, and are chemo-organotrophic, strictly aerobic, non-motile and pleomorphic (1.1-1.5x1.6-2.0 μm; rod-shaped cells 1.1-1.5x3.5-4 μm).</s><s>Cells occur mostly singly and exhibit a range of morphological types, including triangular forms, square forms, irregular cocci and rod-shaped cells.</s><s>Gas vacuoles are not formed.</s><s>Colonies on standard agar growth medium are 0.5-1 mm in diameter, circular, convex, entire, translucent, smooth and red.</s><s>Incapable of anaerobic growth with nitrate, DMSO or L-arginine.</s><s>Extremely halophilic, growth occurring at NaCl concentrations between 100 g l<sup>-1</sup> and saturation.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 250 g NaCl l<sup>-1</sup> with a high requirement of MgSO<sub>4</sub> g l<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>Tolerates the elevated concentrations of MgSO<sub>4</sub> up to 409 g l<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>Cells lyse in water.</s><s>The temperature range is 20-55 °C in the presence of 250 g NaCl l<sup>-1</sup>.</s><s>The pH range is 5.5-7.5, the optimum being pH 7.2 (at 37 °C).</s><s>Cells grow aerobically in a chemically defined medium containing ammonium chloride and a single carbon source such as glucose, glycerol or succinate.</s><s>Acidification of the unbuffered medium occurs when growth occurs in the presence of sugars or glycerol.</s><s>Reduction of nitrate occurs under aerobic conditions.</s><s>Aerobic reduction of nitrate and nitrite without gas production was detected.</s><s>Tween 80 and gelatin are hydrolysed, and sulfide is produced from thiosulfate.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse urea, starch or casein.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase tests are positive.</s><s>Arginine dihydroxylase and urease tests are negative.</s><s>Tests for β-galactosidase and phosphatase are positive.</s><s>Lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase tests are negative.</s><s>The strain can utilize various complex carbon and nitrogen sources such as amino acids and yeast extract.</s><s>The strain is unable to utilize peptone, casein or starch.</s><s>The major isoprenoid neutral lipids are the carotenoids (bacterioruberins, β-carotene and 3-hydroxy echinenone), including a large amount of canthaxanthin [700 μg (g dry cells)<sup>-1</sup>].</s><s>Acid hydrolysis of whole cells releases a single diether component identical to 2,3-di-O-phytanyl-<i>sn</i>-glycerol.</s><s>The major polar lipids are the diether analogues of phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerolphosphate- methyl ester, a diglycosyl glycerol diether and sulfate diglycosyl diether.</s><s>The G­+C content of the DNA is 59.5±0.3 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is TM<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 10717<sup>T</sup>=IFO 16590<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>