<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6789_nm.8904" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8904" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4918" rank="species">Virgibacillus halodenitrificans</organism><reference id="rid.6789"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>T.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>Y.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Bacillus halodenitrificans Denariaz et al. 1989 to the genus Virgibacillus as Virgibacillus halodenitrificans comb. nov.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2163</fpage><lpage>2167</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63196-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15545452</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Virgibacillus halodenitrificans</em> (Denariaz <em>et al.</em> 1989) comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Virgibacillus halodenitrificans</em> [ha.lo.de.ni.tri′fi.cans. Gr. n. <em>hals</em> salt; L. v. <em>denitrifico</em> to denitrify; N.L. part. adj. <em>halodenitrificans</em> salt (-requiring) denitrifying].</s></p><p class="nomenclature"><s>Basonym: <em>Bacillus halodenitrificans</em> Denariaz <em>et al.</em> 1989.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rods, 0·6–0·8×2·5–4·0 μm.</s><s>Gram variable.</s><s>Motile by means of single or peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Terminal or subterminal ellipsoidal spores are observed in swollen sporangia (observed only in strain SF-121).</s><s>Colonies are circular to slightly irregular, raised, translucent, cream coloured and 2–3 mm after incubation for 3 days on MA.</s><s>Growth occurs between 10 and 45 °C with an optimum of 35–40 °C (38 °C for the type strain).</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is around pH 7·4–7·5.</s><s>The pH range for growth is between 5·8 and 9·6 (for the type strain).</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 2–23 % NaCl (2–25 % for the type strain); optimal growth occurs in the presence of 3–7 % NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs under anaerobic conditions on MA only in the presence of nitrate.</s><s>Oxidase positive.</s><s>Urease negative.</s><s>Starch, Tween 80 and tyrosine are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer and methyl red reactions are negative.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase are absent.</s><s>When assayed with the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C<sub>4</sub>), esterase lipase (C<sub>8</sub>), naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase are present, but lipase (C<sub>14</sub>), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are absent.</s><s><em>β</em>-Galactosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase are variable (positive for the type strain).</s><s>Acid is produced from maltose, d-ribose and sucrose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, d-melezitose, d-raffinose, d-xylose, adonitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol or d-sorbitol.</s><s>Acid production from lactose is variable.</s><s>The cell wall peptidoglycan contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-7.</s><s>The major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The G+C content is 38–39 mol% (38 mol% for the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, ATCC 49067<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 10037<sup>T</sup>=LMG 9818<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a solar evaporation pond (saltern) in France.</s><s>Further descriptive information for the type strain is given by Denariaz <em>et al.</em> (1989) and in Table 1.</s></p></content></protolog>