<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.80_nm.1556" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1556" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1556" rank="species">Pedomicrobium americanum</organism><reference id="rid.80"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gebers</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beese</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pedomicrobium americanum sp. nov. and Pedomicrobium australicum sp. nov. from aquatic habitats, Pedomicrobium gen. emend., and Pedomicrobium ferrugineum sp. emend.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>303</fpage><lpage>315</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pedomicrobium americanum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Cells are oval (Fig. 3), tetrahedral (Fig. 4), or short rod, bean, or spindle shaped and are up to 1.3 by 1.8 μm. Up to three hyphae of various lengths originate laterally or polarly with similar frequency (Fig. 5). True branching of the hyphae occurs (Fig. 4). Multiplication is by budding at the hyphal tips (Fig. 3 and 5). Occasionally, intercalary buds are observed. Mature buds separate from the hyphae as motile swarmers with one subpolar flagellum (Fig. 6). Direct budding or division of single mother cells has not been observed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells have gram-negative cell walls (Fig. 7).</s><s>Extracellular structures appear primarily on cell surfaces opposite the lateral hyphae (Fig. 3 and 7).</s><s>These structures have been identified as polyanionic, ruthenium red- and Alcian blue- staining polymers which form fine filaments or arrays of particles (7, 14, 15) and provide the matrix for incrustations of iron oxides and manganese oxides.</s><s>Deposition of iron compounds occurs when cells are grown on fulvic acid iron sesquioxide complexes or on PSM agar containing 5 mg of FeSO<sub>4</sub>. 7H<sub>2</sub>O per liter.</s><s>Deposition of manganese(IV) oxides occurs on PSM agar containing 1.54 mg of MnSO<sub>4</sub>.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>O per liter.</s><s>Intracytoplasmic membranes are present.</s><s>Granules of poly-β-hydroxybutyric acid appear frequently in the cytoplasm (Fig. 7).</s><s>Polyphosphate granules are present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimal growth temperature is 32 to 38°C; the temperature range is 15 to 41°C.</s><s>The pH range for optimal growth in unbuffered media is 6.6 to 7.5; during growth, the pH increases (Table 4).</s><s>The optimal pH of buffered media (containing 10 mM HEPES) is 7.6 to 8.4.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The generation times in PSM or PYVM medium are 10 to 20 h.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Stimulation or inhibition of growth by various carbon sources differs for individual strains (Table 5).</s><s>Good growth occurs with 0.05% yeast extract or 0.025% yeast extract plus 0.025% peptone; nitrate does not serve as a sole nitrogen source.</s><s>Within 6 days, the strains of <i>P. americanum</i> remove 1 to 90% of the amino acids from PSM or PYVM culture broth (Table 6).</s></p><p class="description"><s>A vitamin mixture (24) or 1 μg of cyanocobalamin per liter is required for growth of strains IFAM G-1381<sup>T</sup> and IFAM BA-868 and stimulates the growth of strain IFAM BA-869.</s><s>The presence of 0.1% NaCl stimulates the growth of strain IFAM BA-868.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase is produced by strains IFAM G-1381<sup>T</sup> and IFAM BA-868, but not by strain IFAM BA-869.</s><s>All strains are positive for cytochrome oxidase and for reduction of nitrate to nitrite.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The strains of <i>P. americanum</i> are susceptible to several antibiotics (Table 7); only strain IFAM G-1381<sup>T</sup> is resistant to sulfanilamide.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The DNA base compositions of strains IFAM G-1381<sup>T</sup>, IFAM BA-868, and IFAM BA-869 are 64, 65, and 64 mol% G+C, (T<sub>m</sub>method) (12), respectively.</s><s>The DNA relatedness of the three strains is shown in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains are from freshwater habitats in North America (12); strain IFAM G-1381<sup>T</sup> was isolated from pond water in Sapsucker Woods, Ithaca, N.Y., by E.</s><s>Dale and strains IFAM BA-868 and IFAM BA-869 were isolated from a temporary puddle by J.</s><s>A.</s><s>Babinchak in Ann Arbor, Mich.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain IFAM G-1381 (= ATCC 43612).</s><s>Other strains include strains IFAM BA-868 (= ATCC 43613) and IFAM BA-869 (= ATCC 43615).</s></p></content></protolog>