<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2256_nm.9581" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9581" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9581" rank="species">Nocardia jiangxiensis</organism><reference id="rid.2256"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardia jiangxiensis sp. nov. and Nocardia miyunensis sp. nov., isolated from acidic soils</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1921</fpage><lpage>1925</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63644-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16166688</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Nocardia jiangxiensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Nocardia jiangxiensis</em> (jiang.xi.en′sis. N.L. fem. adj. <em>jiangxiensis</em> referring to Jiangxi Province, southern China, the source of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-positive, catalase-positive, partially acid–alcohol-fast, non-motile actinomycete that forms an extensively branched substrate mycelium that fragments into rod-shaped elements.</s><s>A pinkish white to orange substrate mycelium bears sparse to abundant, white to pink aerial hyphae on modified Sauton's agar.</s><s>A yellowish brown substrate mycelium carrying white aerial hyphae is formed on oatmeal agar at an initial pH of 5·5.</s><s>Diffusible pigments are not formed.</s><s>Does not degrade starch, Tween 20 or 80 or xanthine.</s><s>Acid is formed from d-arabinose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannose and d-xylose, but not from d-lactose, d-maltose, d-mannitol, <em>α</em>-l-rhamnose or sodium citrate.</s><s>d-Arabinose, d-cellobiose, <em>meso</em>-erythritol (weak), d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol (weak), d-lactose, d-maltose, d-melezitose, d-raffinose, d-ribose, d-sorbose, d-sucrose (weak), d-trehalose and d-xylose are used as sole carbon sources for energy and growth, but adonitol and sodium propionate are not.</s><s>Growth occurs at an initial pH between 3·5 and 9·5, and at 17–37 °C, but not at 10 or 45 °C.</s><s>Additional phenotypic properties are shown in Table 1.</s><s>Chemotaxonomic properties are typical of the genus <em>Nocardia</em>.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (12·4 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (24·8 %), C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> (12·3 %), C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (11·0 %) and 10-methyl C<sub>18 : 0</sub> (27·3 %).</s><s>The species description is based on a single strain, which therefore serves as the type strain.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 43401<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 4.1905<sup>T</sup>=JCM 12861<sup>T</sup>) was isolated from the rhizosphere of goose-grass (<em>Eleusine indica</em>) that was growing next to a copper mine in Wushan, Jiangxi Province, China.</s></p></content></protolog>