<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.671_nm.5270" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5270" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5270" rank="subspecies">Staphylococcus schleiferi schleiferi</organism><reference id="rid.671"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Freney</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brun</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bes</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Meugnier</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nervi</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fleurette</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Staphylococcus lugdunensis sp. nov. and Staphylococcus schleiferi sp. nov., two new species from human clinical specimens.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>168</fpage><lpage>172</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-2-168</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Staphylococcus schleiferi</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Staphylococcus schleiferi</i> (Latin genitive form of Schleifer. The name honors Karl Heinz Schleifer, German microbiologist, for his many contributions to the taxonomy of gram-positive organisms)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on 12 strains.</s><s>Cells are gram-positive cocci; 0.8 to 1.0 μm in diameter; nonmotile and nonsporeforming; occurring singly, in pairs, small clusters, or chains composed of three to seven cells.</s><s>Colonies on P agar are 3 to 5 mm in diameter after 4 days of incubation, nonpigmented, smooth and glossy, and slightly convex, with regular edges.</s><s>Good growth on 10% NaCl.</s><s>Weak growth on 15% NaCl after 4 days.</s><s>Homogeneous and heavy growth in brain heart broth at 30 to 45°C.</s><s>Weaker growth in 3 days at 20°C.</s><s>Good growth in both the aerobic and the anaerobic parts of thioglycolate medium.</s><s>In thioglycolate broth, the predominant acid is L-lactic acid.</s><s>Weak hemolysis on sheep blood agar after 2 days; no hemolysis on rabbit blood agar.</s><s>Catalase produced.</s><s>Oxidase test negative.</s><s>Coagulase test negative with both rabbit plasma and bovine plasma.</s><s>Staphylokinase not produced.</s><s>The heat-stable nuclease produced is not inhibited by anti-<i>S. aureus</i> deoxyribonuclease serum.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase test positive.</s><s>Ornithine not decarboxylated.</s><s>Acetoin produced from pyruvate.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase produced.</s><s>N-Acetylglucosaminidase test weakly positive.</s><s>Acid produced from D-glucose, D-mannose, and glycerol.</s><s>Acid not produced from maltose, lactose, sucrose, turanose, D-mannitol, D-raffinose, D-ribose, L-arabinose, D-cellobiose, D-xylose, xylitol, α-methyl-D-glucoside, and D-melibiose.</s><s>Esculin, f3-glucuronide, and L-arginine acrylamide not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Urea not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Enterotoxins A, B, and C, TSST-1 toxin, and exfoliatin toxin not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Susceptible to 25 μg of lysostaphin per ml.</s><s>Resistant to 400 μg of lysozyme per ml.</s><s>Resistant to the vibriostatic compound O/129 and to bacitracin.</s><s>Susceptible to 0.12 μg of novobiocin per ml.</s><s>Susceptibility to the following antibiotics is similar to that of <i>S. aureus</i> ATCC 29213 (minimal inhibitory concentrations given in parentheses): penicillin G (0.06 μg/ml), oxacillin (0.12 to 0.25 μg/ml), gentamicin (below 0.06 μg/ml), kanamycin (0.5 μg/ml), amikacin (0.25 to 0.5 μg/ml), chloramphenicol(2 μg/ml), tetracycline (0.12 to 0.25 μg/ml), erythromycin (below 0.06 μg/ml), clindamycin (below 0.06 μg/ml), rifampin (below 0.06 μg/ml), vancomycin (0.50 to 1 μg/ml), pefloxacin (1 μg/ml), fosfomycin (0.12 to 2 μg/ml), nitrofurantoin (2.5 to 5 μg/ml), and trimethoprim-sulfamethoxazole (1 to 4 μg/ml).</s><s>The peptidoglycan structure is of the L-Lys-Gly<sub>5-6</sub>-Ser<sub>0.2-0.3</sub>type.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cell wall teichoic acids contain glycerol, glucose, and glucosamine.</s><s>There is no β-ribitol teichoic acid or protein A.</s><s>The type strain is strain N850274 (= ATCC 43808).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>Strain N850274<sup>T</sup> was isolated from a catheter.</s><s>The type strain has all the characteristics given for the species.</s><s>In addition, it has the following properties: nitrate reduced; pyrrolidonylaminopeptide and 2-naphthyl-β-D-galactopyranoside hydrolyzed; clumping factor produced; acid weakly produced from fructose; no acid produced from trehalose.</s><s>Gelatin not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Not typable by the International Basic Set of <i>S. aureus</i> phages. <i>S. aureus</i> antigen a<sub>5</sub>/i<sub>1</sub>i<sub>2</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of DNA is 37 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>