<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2834_nm.7972" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7972" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7972" rank="species">Bacteroides oulorum</organism><reference id="rid.2834"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shah</surname><given-names>H.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Watabe</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mitsuoka</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacteroides oulorum sp. nov., a nonpigmented saccharolytic species from the oral cavity.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>193</fpage><lpage>197</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-35-2-193</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacteroides oulorum</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacteroides oulorum</i> (ou.lor.um. Gr. n. oula the gums; N.L. gen. pl. n. oulorum of the gums)</s></p><p class="description"><s>(i) Cellular characteristics.</s><s>Nonmotile, nonsporeforming, gram-negative rods approximately 0.5 μm wide by 1.0 to 1.5 μm long.</s><s>Gram-stains reveal short rods, which may occur singly, in pairs, or in chains of rods (24).</s></p><p class="description"><s>(ii) Colonies.</s><s>After 2 days of incubation on Eggerth-Gagnon agar, colonies are approximately 1.0 mm in diameter, circular, entire, convex, translucent, smooth, and shiny (24).</s><s>Similar colonial morphology occurs on blood agar plates, but the colonies are low, convex, and opaque.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(iii) Cultural characteristics.</s><s>Obligately anaerobic.</s><s>Cells grow well in either prereduced peptone-yeast extract-glucose or BM medium supplemented with hemin and menadione (23).</s><s>The terminal pH in glucose-containing broth media is 5.0; the terminal pH in media without glucose is pH 6.2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(iv) Biochemical and chemical characteristics.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose. fructose, glycogen, inulin, lactose, maltose, mannose, raffinose, starch, and sucrose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from arabinose, cellobiose, glycerol, mannitol, melezitose, rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, trehalose, xylan, and xylose.</s><s>Esculin is hydrolyzed.</s><s>Gelatin is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Indole negative.</s><s>Major end products of metabolism are acetate and succinate.</s><s>Malate dehydrogenase and glutamate dehydrogenase are present, whereas glucose-6- phosphate dehydrogenase and 6-phosphogluconate dehydrogenase are absent.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Sphingolipids are present.</s><s>Possesses both non-hydroxylated long-chain fatty acids (ca. 90%) and 3-hydroxy longchain fatty acids (ca. 10%).</s><s>The non-hydroxylated acids are primarily of the straight-chain saturated, iso- and anteisomethyl branched types, with 12-methyltetradecanoic acid constituting the major component.</s><s>The 3-hydroxy acids are of the straight-chain saturated and iso-methyl branched types, with 3-hydroxy-hexadecanoic and 3-hydroxy-15-methylhexadecanoic acids the predominant components.</s><s>The major respiratory quinones are menaquinones with 10 isoprene units (MK-10).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA ranges from 45 to 46 mol%, as determined by the melting temperature method.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(v) Source.</s><s>Isolated from gingival crevices.</s></p><p class="description"><s>(vi) Type strain.</s><s>The type strain is WPH 179 (= NCTC 11871).</s></p></content></protolog>