<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6161_nm.1231" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1231" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1231" rank="species">Rhizomonas suberifaciens</organism><reference id="rid.6161"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>van Bruggen</surname><given-names>A.H.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jochimsen</surname><given-names>K.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brown</surname><given-names>P.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rhizomonas suberifaciens gen. nov., sp. nov., the causal agent of corky root of lettuce.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>175</fpage><lpage>188</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-2-175</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhizomonas suberifaciens</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhizomonas suberifaciens</i> (su.be.ri.fa'ci.ens. L. gen. n. <i>suberis</i>, of cork, corky; L. part. adj. <i>faciens</i>, making, producing; M.L. part. adj. <i>suberifaciens</i>, corky making)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative, straight or slightly curved rods that are nonmotile or motile with one lateral, subpolar, or polar flagellum and measure 1.19 ± 0.23 by 0.46 ± 0.05 μm.</s><s>Filaments (up to 12 μm long) may occur.</s><s>Cell division takes place by binary fission.</s><s>Growth is better on diluted than on full-strength common bacteriological media.</s><s>Colonies on S-medium are nonpigmented, nonfluorescent, initially circular, and pulvinate or umbonate with entire margins, but later irregular and wrinkled with undulate margins.</s><s>All strains are obligate aerobes.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 28 to 32°C; strains do not grow at 37°C.</s><s>The oxidase reaction is positive, and the catalase reaction is weakly positive.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite and ammonia, but not to nitrogen gas.</s><s>Nitrogenase is not produced.</s><s>Ethanol is not converted to acetic acid.</s><s>Cells accumulate PHB granules, and arginine dihydrolase is not produced.</s><s>All strains produce acid from oxidative fermentation of glucose, maltose, salicin, and mannose.</s><s>Whole-cell fatty acid profiles consist mainly of 18:1, 16:1, and 16:O fatty acids.</s><s>The presence of a large amount of 2-OH-14:O fatty acid is characteristic; 10-CH<sub>3</sub>-18:1 and cyclo-19:0 fatty acids are usually found.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA ranges from 58.2 to 59.5 mol%.</s><s>Strains are pathogenic for several members of the Compositae and induce corkiness or swellings or both on the main roots.</s><s>Strain CA1 is the type strain and has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection and the National Collection of Plant Pathogenic Bacteria as strains ATCC 49355 and NCPPB 3629, respectively, together with strains FL1(= ATCC 49356 = NCPPB 3628), NY11 (= ATCC 49382 = NCPPB 3631), and W13 (= ATCC 49381 = NCPPB 3630).</s></p></content></protolog>