<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9691_nm.14835" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14835" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14835" rank="species">Paenibacillus cellulositrophicus</organism><reference id="rid.9691"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Akaracharanya</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lorliam</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanasupawat</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.-S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus cellulositrophicus sp. nov., a cellulolytic bacterium from Thai soil</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2680</fpage><lpage>2684</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.010298-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19625433</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus cellulositrophicus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus cellulositrophicus</em> [cel.lu.lo.si.tro′phi.cus. N.L. n. <em>cellulosum</em> cellulose; N.L. adj. <em>trophicus</em> (from Gr. adj. <em>trophikos</em>) nursing, tending; N.L. masc. adj. <em>cellulositrophicus</em> feeding on cellulose, growing on cellulose].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, spore-forming rods, 0.8–1.2×4–8 μm.</s><s>Motile by means of peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Central or subterminal ellipsoidal endospores are observed in swollen sporangia.</s><s>Colonies are white or white–cream, circular, convex and with an entire margin (0.9–2.3 mm diameter).</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 5–9 (optimally at pH 6–7), at 20–55 °C (optimally at 30–37 °C) and in 5 % (w/v) NaCl, but not at 10–15 °C or in 6 % NaCl.</s><s>Positive for catalase and oxidase activities, for hydrolysis of aesculin, l-arginine, gelatin and casein, for activities of DNase and urease and for citrate utilization, but negative for hydrolysis of starch, l-tyrosine and Tween 80, for nitrate reduction, for the MR–VP reaction and for production of indole and hydrogen sulphide and for the production of dihydroxyacetone from glycerol.</s><s>Acid production from adonitol, aesculin, amygdalin, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, arbutin, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, d-glucose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, d-lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, starch, trehalose, turanose, d-xylose, sucrose and methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside.</s><s>No acid is produced from d-arabitol, l-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, d-fucose, l-fucose, gluconate, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, inulin, d-lyxose, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, d-tagatose, xylitol or l-xylose.</s><s>MK-7 is the major isoprenoid quinone.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The diagnostic diamino acid in the cell-wall hydrolysates is <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, P2-1<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13135<sup>T</sup>=PCU 305<sup>T</sup>=TISTR 1888<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil sample.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 52.7 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>