<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7280_nm.7313" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7313" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7313" rank="species">Streptomyces turgidiscabies</organism><reference id="rid.7280"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Miyajima</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanaka</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Takeuchi</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kuninaga</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces turgidiscabies sp. nov.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>495</fpage><lpage>502</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-2-495</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9731290</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Streptomyces turgidiscabies</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Streptomyces turgidiscabies</i> (tur.gi.di.sca'bi.es. L. adj. <i>turgidus</i> swollen; L. fem. n. <i>scabies</i> scabbiness; N.L. fem. n. <i>turgidiscabies</i> a swollen scabbiness)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The species is placed in the genus <i>Streptomyces</i> as it has morphology typical of this genus and cell walls with the LL-diaminopimelic acid isomer.</s><s>Spores are 0.3-0.6 x 1.0-1.2 μm, smooth, grey, and are borne in mature flexuous chains containing eight or more spores.</s><s>Diffusible pigments and melanin are not produced.</s><s>All International Streptomyces Project sugars (L-arabinose, D-fructose, D-glucose, D-mannitol, iso-inositol, rhamnose, sucrose, D-xylose and raffinose) are used as carbon sources.</s><s>All strains that have been studied do not degrade xanthine or grow at 37°C and are susceptible to 20 μg streptomycin ml<sup>-1</sup>, 0.5 μg crystal violet ml<sup>-1</sup>, 100 μg potassium tellurite ml<sup>-1</sup> and 0.1 % phenol.</s><s>The G+C content of this species is 70.9-72-5 mol%. <i>S. turgidiscabies</i> differs from other potato scab pathogens in having grey, smooth, flexuous spore chains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is SY9113<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 700248<sup>T</sup>=IFO 16080<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>This strain was isolated from raised scab lesions on potato tubers in eastern Hokkaido, Japan, in 1991, and has been confirmed to be pathogenic.</s><s>It is positive for peptonization but not for coagulation of milk, is not susceptible to 25 μg oleandomycin ml<sup>-1</sup> or 10 IU penicillin G ml<sup>-1</sup>, and is not positive for utilization of sodium acetate or sodium propionate as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Specific characteristics are listed in Table 2 or are mentioned above.</s></p></content></protolog>