<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8358_nm.13321" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13321" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13321" rank="species">Exiguobacterium soli</organism><reference id="rid.8358"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chaturvedi</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prabhar</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Manorama</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pindi</surname><given-names>P.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bhadra</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Begum</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shivaji</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Exiguobacterium soli sp. nov., a psychrophilic bacterium from the McMurdo Dry Valleys, Antarctica.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2447</fpage><lpage>2453</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.2008/000067-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18842873</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Exiguobacterium soli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Exiguobacterium soli</em> sp. nov. (so′li. L. gen. n. <em>soli</em> of soil).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-positive, motile and rod-shaped (1.9 μm in length and 0.95 μm in width).</s><s>Stationary-phase cells are coccobacillary in shape (1.5 μm in length and 1.15 μm in diameter).</s><s>Colonies (2–3 mm) on nutrient agar are round, shiny, irregular, elevated and yellowish orange-coloured after 24 h at 22 °C.</s><s>No spores are observed.</s><s>Growth occurs between 2.5 and 30 °C and at pH 6–10.</s><s>The optimum temperature and pH for growth are 25 °C and 7.0.</s><s>NaCl is tolerated at 5.8 % and growth also occurs in the absence of salt.</s><s>Positive in tests for catalase, oxidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, phosphatase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, arginine decarboxylase, gelatinase, caseinase, malonate utilization, aesculin hydrolysis and starch hydrolysis and in the Voges–Proskauer test.</s><s>Negative for urease, lipase, DNase, tryptophan deamination, nitrate reduction to nitrite, citrate utilization, indole production, H<sub>2</sub>S production and in the methyl red test.</s><s>The following are utilized: d-glucose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-lactose, maltose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, raffinose, trehalose, d-ribose, melibiose, melezitose, cellobiose, sucrose, d-xylose, l-xylose, l-arabinose, d-arabinose, glycerol, d-sorbitol, dulcitol, starch, inulin, dextrin, <em>myo</em>-inositol, glycogen, sodium thioglycolate, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, amygdalin, arbutin, lactic acid, pyruvate, erythritol, <em>γ</em>-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, 5-ketogluconate, l-glycine, l-ornithine, l-alanine, l-leucine, l-isoleucine, l-lysine, l-arginine, l-glutamic acid, l-glutamine, l-asparagine, l-proline, l-histidine, l-creatinine.</s><s>The following are not utilized: l-fucose, l-sorbose, d-mannitol, d-adonitol, hydroxybutyric acid, dextran, sodium gluconate, sodium fumarate, sodium formate, sodium succinate, sodium propionate, sodium acetate, polyethylene glycol, potassium acetate, cellulose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl-<em>α</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, salicin, xylitol, citric acid, fumaric acid, l-malic acid, valeric acid, l-aspartic acid, l-cysteine, l-methionine, l-serine, l-threonine, l-tyrosine, l-tryptophan, l-valine and l-phenylalanine.</s><s>Acid is produced from cellobiose, d-fructose, d-glucose, d-mannose, maltose, d-ribose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, trehalose, l-xylose and inulin, but not from d-sorbitol, melibiose, d-lactose, l-arabinose or d-adonitol.</s><s>Resistant to the following antibiotics (μg): amoxicillin (30), colistin (10), doxycycline (25), norfloxacin (10), nitrofurantoin (300) and sulfamethoxazole (50).</s><s>Sensitive to the following antibiotics (μg): co-trimoxazole (25), clindamycin (25), amikacin (30), nalidixic acid (30), tobramycin (15), lomefloxacin (30), roxithromycin (30), ciprofloxacin (30), lincomycin (15), cefotaxime (30), cefazolin (30), kanamycin (30), novobiocin (30), chloramphenicol (30), ampicillin (25), tetracycline (30), streptomycin (25), erythromycin (15), bacitracin (10), gentamicin G (30), polymyxin B (50), oleandomycin (15), spectinomycin (100), rifampicin (25) and carbenicillin (100).</s><s>The respiratory quinones are MK-6, MK-7 and MK-8 and the cell-wall peptidoglycan is of the Lys–Gly type.</s><s>Phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylserine and phosphatidylinositol and an unidentified lipid are present.</s><s>The fatty acids present are iso-C<sub>12 : 0</sub> (2.0 %), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> (1.4 %), iso-C<sub>13 : 0</sub> (16.1 %), anteiso-C<sub>13 : 0</sub> (15.2 %), iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (2.3 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (1.3 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (17.1 %), anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (6.2 %), C<sub>15 : 1</sub><em>ω</em> 5<em>c</em> (2.2 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (4.1%) C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (3.6%), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em> 11<em>c</em> (0.7 %), anteiso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em> 9<em>c</em> (1.3 %), iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (10.6 %), iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em> 10<em>c</em> (2.3 %), anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (3.3 %), C<sub>18 : 0</sub> 10 methyl (1.1 %), C<sub>19 : 0</sub> (2.7 %), summed feature 1 (1.8 %), summed feature 3 (1.7 %), summed feature 4 (0.8 %) and summed feature 8 (2.2 %).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, DVS 3Y<sup>T</sup> (=MTCC 4816<sup>T</sup>=JCM 14376<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a moraine sample from the McMurdo Dry Valleys, Antarctica.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 48.5 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>