<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6852_nm.4754" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4754" rank="family">Entomoplasmataceae</organism><reference id="rid.6852"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tully</surname><given-names>J.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bové</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Laigret</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Whitcomb</surname><given-names>R.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Revised taxonomy of the class Mollicutes: proposed elevation of a monophyletic cluster of arthropod-associated mollicutes to ordinal rank (Entomoplasmatales ord. nov.), with provision for familial rank to separate species with nonhelical morphology (Entomoplasmataceae fam. nov.) from helical species (Spiroplasmataceae), and emended descriptions of the order Mycoplasmatales, family Mycoplasmataceae.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>378</fpage><lpage>385</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Entomoplasataceae</i> fam. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Entomoplasataceae</i> (En. to.mo. plas.ma. ta'ce.ae. M.L. neut. n. <i>Entomoplasma</i>, type genus of the family; -<i>aceae</i> ending to denote a family; M.L. fem. pl. n. <i>Entomoplasmataceae</i>, the <i>Entomoplasma</i> family)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are usually coccoidal or occur as short, branched or unbranched, pleomorphic, nonhelical filaments.</s><s>They are filterable through membranes with an average pore diameter of 220 to 450 nm; nonmotile; bounded by a single membrane, with no evidence of a cell wall; and facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Colonies on solid medium containing 0.8% Noble agar usually have a fried-egg appearance.</s><s>The organisms are chemoorganotrophic.</s><s>Acid is produced from glucose, with evidence of a phosphoenolpyruvate-dependent sugar transport system(s) in some members.</s><s>Arginine and urea are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Colonies of some species may hemadsorb guinea pig erythrocytes.</s><s>The organisms may or may not require serum or cholesterol for growth, with growth on serum-free broth medium occurring only in the presence of 0.04% Tween 80 (polyoxyethylene sorbitan).</s><s>The temperature range for growth varies from 10 to 37°C, with the optimum usually at 30°C.</s><s>The genome size ranges from 790 to 1,140 kbp, with the guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA varying from 27 to 30 mol%.</s><s>The organisms utilize the UGA codon as a tryptophan signal.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Two genera are accepted in this family: <i>Entomoplasma</i> gen. nov., the type genus, and <i>Mesoplasma</i> gen. nov.</s><s>Species of <i>Entomoplasma</i> require serum or cholesterol for growth.</s><s>Species of <i>Mesoplasma</i> cannot grow in serum-free broth medium alone but show sustained growth in serumfree medium containing 0.04% Tween 80 (polyoxyethylene sorbitan) or in serum-containing medium.</s></p></content></protolog>