<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9062_nm.4616" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4616" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4616" rank="subspecies">Mycoplasma mycoides mycoides</organism><reference id="rid.9062"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Manso-Silván</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vilei</surname><given-names>E.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sachse</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Djordjevic</surname><given-names>S.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thiaucourt</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frey</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycoplasma leachii sp. nov. as a new species designation for Mycoplasma sp. bovine group 7 of Leach, and reclassification of Mycoplasma mycoides subsp. mycoides LC as a serovar of Mycoplasma mycoides subsp. capri.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1353</fpage><lpage>1358</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.005546-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19502315</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Mycoplasma mycoides</em> subsp. <em>mycoides</em> (Borrel <em>et al.</em> 1910) Freundt 1955 (Approved Lists 1980)</s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>Initially designated <em>Asterococcus mycoides</em> (Borrel <em>et al.</em>, 1910), referring to its pleomorphic, mucous nature and to the production of mycelium-like filaments, the nomenclature of this taxon was modified to <em>Mycoplasma mycoides</em> when it acquired the legitimate genus name <em>Mycoplasma</em> (Edward &#x0026; Freundt, 1956), as listed on the Approved Lists of Bacterial Names that became effective in January 1980 (Skerman <em>et al.</em>, 1980).</s><s>This description, based on the original descriptions and on additional data, emphasizes the particularities related to the fact that this taxon no longer includes the Large Colony strains represented by strain Y-goat<sup>R</sup>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>A non-helical, pleomorphic organism measuring 125–175 nm in length (Edward, 1954).</s><s>Facultative anaerobe that displays a tendency to produce filamentous growth, but does not produce films or spots.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 37 °C; no growth is evident at 22 °C.</s><s>Its viability is extremely reduced after 12 h incubation at 45 °C (Cottew &#x0026; Yeats, 1978).</s><s>Grows relatively slowly and, after 2 days incubation, produces small colonies about 0.5 mm in diameter (Thigpen <em>et al.</em>, 1983), which show the characteristic fried-egg appearance on suitable solid medium such as that of Hayflick (1965).</s><s>When broth cultures are shaken, the sediment rises in characteristic ‘silky swirls’.</s><s>Digests casein and liquefies inspissated serum, albeit less vigorously than the other members of the <em>M. mycoides</em> cluster.</s><s>Produces haemolysis on horse blood agar and filtrates of 6 day cultures discolour horse erythrocytes.</s><s>Ferments glucose, does not metabolize arginine or urea and can be distinguished from other members of the <em>M. mycoides</em> cluster by its total inability to oxidize maltose and trehalose, coupled to its inability to oxidize mannose and glucosamine at concentrations &#x003C;50 μM (Abu-Groun <em>et al.</em>, 1994).</s><s>Shows serological cross-reactions with <em>M. mycoides</em> subsp. <em>capri</em> (Cottew &#x0026; Yeats, 1978; Thigpen <em>et al.</em>, 1983) and shares antigens with the newly designated taxon <em>M. leachii</em> (formerly MBG7).</s><s>According to <em>Bergey's Manual of Determinative Bacteriology</em> (Holt, 1994), the DNA G+C content is 26.1–27.1 mol%; the genome sequence from type strain PG1<sup>T</sup> showed a G+C content of 24.0 mol% (Westberg <em>et al.</em>, 2004). <em>Mycoplasma mycoides</em> subsp. <em>mycoides</em> is the aetiological agent of contagious bovine pleuropneumonia (CBPP).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, PG1<sup>T</sup> (=NCTC 10114<sup>T</sup> =CCUG 32753<sup>T</sup>), was deposited in 1931 by P.</s><s>Laidlaw as a representative of the CBPP agent.</s><s>The exact origin of the strain is not known and the cultures are no longer pathogenic.</s></p></content></protolog>