<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8661_nm.13612" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13612" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13612" rank="species">Sphingobacterium siyangense</organism><reference id="rid.8661"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>C.X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>S.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>X.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>K.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sphingobacterium siyangense sp. nov., isolated from farm soil.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1458</fpage><lpage>1462</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65696-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18523194</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sphingobacterium siyangense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sphingobacterium siyangense</em> (si.yang.en′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>siyangense</em> pertaining to Siyang in Jiangsu Province, China, the city where the strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile, non-spore-forming, strictly aerobic rods, 0.8–1.7 μm long and 0.7–0.9 μm wide.</s><s>After 2 days incubation on LB agar, colonies are 1.0–2.0 mm in diameter, slightly yellowish, convex, circular and smooth with entire margins.</s><s>Grows at 4–42 °C (optimum, 30–37 °C), pH 3.0–10.0 (optimum, pH 6.0–8.0) and 0–4 % NaCl (optimum, 0–2 %).</s><s>Growth occurs on nutrient agar and cetrimide agar, but not on Simmons' citrate agar or MacConkey agar.</s><s>Positive for catalase and oxidase.</s><s>In API 20E tests, positive for <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, arginine decarboxylase, urease and nitrate reduction.</s><s>Negative for ornithine decarboxylase, lysine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, indole and H<sub>2</sub>S production and Voges–Proskauer reaction.</s><s>Starch, DNA, aesculin and Tween 20 are hydrolysed, but casein, gelatin, carboxymethylcellulose, Tween 80 or chitin are not.</s><s>Acid is produced from trehalose and l-rhamnose, but not from d-glucose, cellobiose, d-galactose, sucrose, d-lactose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol or inositol.</s><s>Utilizes d-xylose, melibiose, turanose, maltose, d-fructose, d-glucose, d-lactose, sucrose, l-sorbose, trehalose, d-galactose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-ribose, d-mannose, melezitose, i-erythritol, adonitol, l-arabitol, xylitol, d-sorbitol, d-mannitol, salicin, inulin, dextrin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, gluconate, lysine, amygdalin and glycerol, but not inositol, acetate, malonate or tyrosine.</s><s>Resistant to streptomycin, kanamycin and polymyxin B, but sensitive to ceftazidime, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, tetracycline, ofloxacin, rifampicin, gentamicin, ampicillin and carbenicillin.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (32.9 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (10.9 %) and summed feature 3 (iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>; 24.1 %).</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 38.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SY1<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22131<sup>T</sup>=CGMCC 1.6855<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil sample from Jiangsu Province, PR China.</s></p></content></protolog>