<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6843_nm.8138" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8138" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8138" rank="species">Capnocytophaga granulosa</organism><reference id="rid.6843"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yamamoto</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kajiura</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hirai</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Watanabe</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Capnocytophaga haemolytica sp. nov. and Capnocytophaga granulosa sp. nov., from human dental plaque.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>324</fpage><lpage>329</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-2-324</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8186098</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Capnocytophaga granulosa</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Capnocytophaga granulosa</i> (gra.nu.lo'sa. L. adj. <i>granulosa</i>, granular)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are thin, gram-negative rods (5 to 8 by 0.3 to 0.4 μm).</s><s>Granular inclusions that are stained by basic fuchsin are observed at the ends and in the middle of Gram-stained cells.</s><s>These inclusions are clearly observed when the strains are grown anaerobically at 37°C in GAM broth for 5 to 7 days.</s><s>Flat, thin colonies with uneven edges are 1 to 2 mm in diameter after 5 to 7 days on TBBP agar.</s><s>No hemolysis occurs on TBBP agar or blood agar.</s><s>The colonial colors are gray to purple on TBBP and blood agar plates but yellow or orange on Trypticase soy agar.</s><s>Pellets of cells obtained by centrifugation after washing with distilled water are yellow or orange.</s><s>Cultures grow under microaerophilic conditions and can grow well on blood agar incubated at 37°C in the presence of 5% CO<sub>2</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Susceptible to actinomycin D.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-glucose, D-lactose, D-maltose, D-mannose, starch, and D-SUcrose.</s><s>Negative for oxidase activity, catalase activity, nitrate reduction, H<sub>2</sub>S production, and indole production.</s><s>No acid is produced from cellulose, D-mannitol, D-ribose, D-sorbitol, D-xylose, dextran, glycogen, and inulin.</s><s>Aminopeptidase positive with some of the substrates listed in Table 4.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major end products of glucose fermentation are acetate and succinate.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-6.</s><s>The dominant cellular fatty acids are i-15:O and 18:0 acids.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 41 to 42 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain B0611 (= JCM 8566) is the type strain of <i>C. granulosa</i>.</s><s>The characteristics of this strain are the same as those given above for the species.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of this strain is 41.7 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>