<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5250_nm.3638" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3638" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3638" rank="species">Pelobacter venetianus</organism><reference id="rid.5250"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schink</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stieb</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Fermentative degradation of polyethylene glycol by a strictly anaerobic, gram-negative, nonsporeforming bacterium, Pelobacter venetianus sp. nov.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>1905</fpage><lpage>1913</lpage><source id="228">Applied and Environmental Microbiology</source><abbrev>Appl Environ Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0099-2240</issn><essn>1098-5336</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">6881964</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pelobacter venetianus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pelobacter venetianus</i> (ve ne ti a'nus L. n. <i>venetianus</i> from Venice, the origin of the type strain and the place where it occurs in high numbers)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are rod shaped, 0.5 by 1.0 to 2.5 μm in size, and rounded at the ends.</s><s>They occur singly or in pairs, are motile in young cultures, do not form spores, and stain gram negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>P. venetianus</i> is a strictly anaerobic chemoorganotroph.</s><s>PEG, PEG-containing compounds, and acetoin were the only substrates it utilized.</s><s>The substrates were fermented to nearly equal amounts of acetate and ethanol.</s><s>1,2-Propanediol, 1,2-butanediol, and glycerol were also fermented to the corresponding acids and alcohols, but for growth, acetate was necessary as a source of carbon.</s><s>Sulfate, sulfur, thiosulfate, and nitrate were not reduced.</s><s>Growth required mineral media with a reductant.</s><s>Growth yields and rates of the type strain were higher on media containing at least 10 g of NaCl and 1.5 g of MgCl<sub>2</sub>⋄6H<sub>2</sub>O per liter.</s><s>No growth factors or vitamins were required.</s><s>Indole was not formed from tryptophan, and gelatin and urea were not hydrolyzed.</s><s>In coculture with a hydrogen-consuming methanogenic or homoacetogenic bacterium, growth on ethanol was achieved by oxidation of ethanol to acetate.</s><s>Selective enrichment with PEG as the sole substrate was accomplished.</s><s>The pH range was 5.5 to 8.0 (optimum, 7.0 to 7.5).</s><s>The growth temperature range was 10 to 40°C (optimum, 33°C).</s><s>No cytochromes were detectable.</s><s>The DNA base ratio was 52.2 ± 1.0 mol% guanine plus cytosine (determined by thermal denaturation).</s><s>Habitats include anaerobic mud of freshwater or marine origin.</s><s>The type strain is Gra PEG 1 (= DSM 2394) and is deposited in Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen, Gottingen, West Germany.</s></p></content></protolog>