<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.923_nm.11666" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11666" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4034" rank="species">Clostridium thermoautotrophicum</organism><reference id="rid.923"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wiegel</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Braun</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gottschalk</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium thermoautotrophicum species novum, a thermophile producing acetate from molecular hydrogen and carbon dioxide.</article-title><year>1981</year><volume>5</volume><fpage>255</fpage><lpage>260</lpage><source id="254">Current Microbiology</source><abbrev>Curr Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0343-8651</issn><essn>1432-0991</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF01571158</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of Clostridium thermoautotrophicum sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Clostridium thermoautotrophicum (ther.mo.au.to.tro.phi.cum. Gr. adj. <i>thermus</i> hot, Gr. adv. <i>autos</i> self, Gr. n. <i>trophus</i> food, <i>thermoautotrophicum</i> indicating that the organism grows at elevated temperatures and uses carbon dioxide as its principal carbon source for growth)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology.</s><s>Vegetative cells are rod shaped, measuring 3-6 μm by 0.8-1.0 μm.</s><s>The Gram-stain reaction of cells from the early logarithmic growth phase is positive, from later growth phases negative.</s><s>Ceils are slightly motile by 3-8 peritrichously inserted flagella (140-150 Å thick; 8-15 μm long).</s><s>The surface layer of the outer cell wall shows a tetragonal structure, and consists of subunits with about 112 Å in diameter.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Spores.</s><s>Round to slightly oval spores are formed at the polar cell region in oval sporangia (2-3 μm in diameter).</s><s>The spores were normally released during the stationary growth phase and they measure 1-2.5 μm in diameter.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell wall.</s><s>LL-Diaminopimelic acid type.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colony characteristics.</s><s>Surface colonies are tannish-white, circular convex, and smooth; colonies may turn brownish with time.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base composition.</s><s>The DNA of <i>C. thermoautotrophicum</i> contains 53-55 mol% guanine plus cytosine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Culture conditions.</s><s>Strict anaerobe; T<sub>min</sub>, 36°C; T<sub>opt</sub>, 55-58°C; T<sub>max</sub>, 69/70°C; pH range for growth 4.5-7.6, pH optimum around 5.7.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nutritional characteristics.</s><s>The organism converts 4 mol of molecular hydrogen and 2 mol of carbon dioxide to 1 mol of acetate.</s><s>Acetate is also the only main organic fermentation product during growth on glucose, fructose, galactose, methanol, glycerate, or formate; only some strains can utilize arabinose, xylose, mannose, maltose, D-lactose, or lactate.</s><s>The following compounds could not be used as carbon and energy source: D-ribose, D-fucose, D-mannose, sucrose, D-raffinose, starch, m-erythritol, xylitol, dulcitol, sorbitol, ethanol, ethyleneglycol, propanol, m-inositol, isopropanol, glycerol, malate, glutamate, pyruvate, succinate, citrate, tartrate, Casamino Acids, hippurate, nicotinic acid, and cellulose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat.</s><s>Widespread but in low numbers; present in mud and wet soils from Africa, Europe, North America, and Hawaii.</s><s>Not restricted to locations with elevated temperature.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain. <i>C thermoautotrophicum</i> JW 701/3 is designated as the type strain and is deposited in the German Collection of Microorganisms in Göttingen under the number DSM 1974.</s></p></content></protolog>