<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2272_nm.9646" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9646" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9646" rank="species">Chryseobacterium vrystaatense</organism><reference id="rid.2272"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>de Beer</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hugo</surname><given-names>C.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jooste</surname><given-names>P.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Willems</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vancanneyt</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Coenye</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Chryseobacterium vrystaatense sp. nov., isolated from raw chicken in a chicken-processing plant.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>2149</fpage><lpage>2153</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63746-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16166723</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Chryseobacterium vrystaatense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Chryseobacterium vrystaatense</em> (vry.staa.ten′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>vrystaatense</em> named after Vrystaat (Free State), the South African province where these bacteria were isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are shiny, orange–yellow and translucent with entire edges.</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative, catalase- and oxidase-positive and produce flexirubin-type pigments; they are non-motile and neither oxidative nor fermentative.</s><s>Colonies are seen after 24 h growth at 4, 15, 25 and 32 °C on nutrient agar, but no growth occurs at 37 °C or above.</s><s>Growth on MacConkey agar no. 3 (Oxoid CM115) is observed after 48 h at 15, 25 and 32 °C for all but one strain that grows only on MacConkey agar after 48 h at 32 °C.</s><s>All strains grow in nutrient broth containing 1 and 2 % NaCl (w/v); growth in 3 % NaCl broth is strain-dependent (14 strains, excluding the type strain, test positive for growth).</s><s>Although several strains initially show growth at different salt concentrations, only five show growth in 4 % NaCl broth after 5 days incubation (R-23493, R-23569, R-23575, R-23576 and R-23595).</s><s>Strains show strong DNase activity and also urease and lecithinase activity, but no starch or tyrosine hydrolysis.</s><s>Reactions on triple-sugar agar (Oxoid CM277) and 10 % lactose are alkaline.</s><s>Ability to produce H<sub>2</sub>S varies depending on incubation time on triple-sugar agar and SIM medium (Oxoid CM435).</s><s>Both media contain sodium thiosulfate, but SIM medium also contains ferrous ammonium sulfate and &#x003E;50 % of strains give a positive reaction.</s><s>All strains tested (<em>n</em>=22) show positive reactions in the Biolog system for Tweens 40 and 80, gentobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, d-mannose, d-trehalose, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid and l-asparagine.</s><s>At least 19 of the strains (85 %) react for glycyl l-glutamic acid, glycerol, l-glutamic acid, l-serine and l-aspartic acid.</s><s>Reactions in which more than 50 % of the strains give a positive result are for dextrin (<em>n</em>=16), d-mannitol (<em>n</em>=18), <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid (<em>n</em>=15), l-alanylglycine (<em>n</em>=12), l-threonine (<em>n</em>=16), inosine (<em>n</em>=13), uridine (<em>n</em>=15) and thymidine (<em>n</em>=12).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, LMG 22846<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 50970<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a raw chicken-portion sample obtained from a chicken-processing plant.</s><s>The other (35) isolates were obtained from raw-chicken samples, collected at different processing stages (portion, whole bird, automatic line, manual line and the spiral freezing process) on different occasions.</s><s>Three additional isolates have been deposited in the BCCM/LMG Bacteria Collection as LMG 22847, LMG 22848 and LMG 22954.</s></p></content></protolog>