<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3760_nm.11122" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11122" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11122" rank="species">Vagococcus elongatus</organism><reference id="rid.3760"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cotta</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Whitehead</surname><given-names>T.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vagococcus elongatus sp. nov., isolated from a swine-manure storage pit</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>751</fpage><lpage>754</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64730-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17392200</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Vagococcus elongatus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Vagococcus elongatus</em> (e.lon.ga′tus. L. masc. part. adj. <em>elongatus</em> elongated, pertaining to the pronounced elongation of the cells).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive cocci occurring singly or in short chains, with cells elongated in the direction of the chain, and some giving the appearance of short, fat rods.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic and catalase-negative.</s><s>Non-haemolytic and non-motile.</s><s>Lactic acid but no gas is produced from glucose metabolism.</s><s>No growth in broth containing 6.5 % NaCl.</s><s>No growth at 10 or 45 °C.</s><s>Using the API ID32S system, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase (weak reaction) and glycyl tryptophan arylamidase are detected.</s><s>Acid is not produced from <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, alkaline phosphatase, alanyl phenylalanine proline arylamidase, arginine dihydrolase, d-arabitol, l-arabinose, cyclodextrin, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, glycogen, lactose, maltose, mannitol, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, melezitose, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, pullulan, d-raffinose, d-ribose, sorbitol, sucrose, tagatose, trehalose or urease.</s><s>Using the API ZYM system, weak reactions are obtained for alkaline phosphatase, esterase C4 and esterase lipase C8.</s><s>No activity is detected for acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, trypsin or valine arylamidase.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer test is negative.</s><s>Aesculin is hydrolysed but hippurate and gelatin are not.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 44.5 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, PPC9<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 51432<sup>T</sup>=NRRL B-41357<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a swine-manure storage pit.</s><s>Habitat unknown.</s></p></content></protolog>