<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9926_nm.14894" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14894" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14894" rank="species">Kineosporia mesophila</organism><reference id="rid.9926"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>G.-Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>H.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Qin</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>W.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Kineosporia mesophila sp. nov., isolated from surface-sterilized stems of Tripterygium wilfordii</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>3150</fpage><lpage>3154</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.012021-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19643874</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Kineosporia mesophila</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Kineosporia mesophila</em> (me.so′phi.la. Gr. adj. <em>mesos</em> medium; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving; N.L. fem. adj. <em>mesophila</em> medium-temperature-loving, mesophilic).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Substrate mycelia are light orange to deep orange–yellow.</s><s>Does not produce any diffusible pigments on ISP 2, ISP 3, ISP 4, ISP 5 agars, potato agar, Czapek's agar or nutrient agar.</s><s>Single spores, spherical to oval or pyriform, are borne at the tips of substrate hyphae.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–32 °C and pH 6.0–8.0.</s><s>Tolerates 3 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Negative for production of H<sub>2</sub>S, nitrate reduction and milk coagulation and peptonization.</s><s>Urea, starch and Tweens 20, 40 and 80 are hydrolysed.</s><s>Adenine, cellulose, gelatin, hypoxanthine, l-tyrosine and xanthine are not decomposed.</s><s>Utilizes d-arabinose, d-fructose, glucose, d-xylose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, sodium oxalate, d-sorbitol and trisodium citrate as sole carbon sources, but not dulcitol, inositol, lactose, d-ribose or sodium acetate.</s><s>Acid is produced from l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-galactose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, sucrose, trehalose and turanose.</s><s>l-Alanine, l-asparagine, glycine, l-hydroxyproline, l-phenylalanine, l-serine and l-valine are used as sole nitrogen sources, but not l-arginine or l-lysine.</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan contains aspartic acid, glutamic acid, glycine, alanine and lysine.</s><s>Glucose, galactose, mannose and ribose are present in whole-cell hydrolysates.</s><s>Phospholipids are phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol, diphosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylinositol mannosides.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>Major fatty acids (&#x003E;10 %) are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub> <em>cis</em>-9 and TBSA.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM 65293<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AA 208061<sup>T</sup>=DSM 45271<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a surface-sterilized stem sample of <em>Tripterygium wilfordii</em> from Yunnan province, south-west China.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 70.3 mol%.1</s></p></content></protolog>