<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6587_nm.2564" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2564" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2564" rank="species">Pseudomonas asplenii</organism><reference id="rid.6587"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tvrzová</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Spröer</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sedlácek</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pácová</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sedo</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zdráhal</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steffen</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lang</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas moraviensis sp. nov. and Pseudomonas vranovensis sp. nov., soil bacteria isolated on nitroaromatic compounds, and emended description of Pseudomonas asplenii.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2657</fpage><lpage>2663</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63988-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17082407</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <em>Pseudomonas asplenii</em> (Ark and Tompkins 1946) Savulescu 1947</s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>Has the following properties in addition to those given previously (Ark &#x0026; Tompkins, 1946).</s><s>Oxidase-positive.</s><s>By API 20NE, indole and <em>β</em>-galactosidase are not produced, aesculin and gelatin are not hydrolysed and fermentation of d-glucose and assimilation of adipate are negative.</s><s>Caprate, malate and citrate are assimilated.</s><s>Assimilation (API 50 CH) is positive for glycerol, d-glucose, d-fructose and gluconate, and negative for erythritol, d-arabinose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-xyloside, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, d-cellobiose, d-maltose, d-lactose, d-melibiose, d-sucrose, inulin, d-melezitose, d-raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, d-turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, l-arabitol, 2-ketogluconate and 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized (Biolog system): methyl pyruvate, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, quinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, d-alanine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-proline, l-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid and urocanic acid.</s><s>Negative reactions (Biolog system) are observed with <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, adonitol, d-cellobiose, erythritol, l-fucose, gentiobiose, myo-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, d-galactonic acid lactone, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, sebacic acid, glucuronamide, glycyl l-aspartic acid, l-leucine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Other reactions determined by API 20NE, API 50 CH and Biolog systems are given in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is DSM 17133<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 23835<sup>T</sup>=CIP 106710<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>