<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3419_nm.3853" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3853" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3853" rank="species">Helicobacter salomonis</organism><reference id="rid.3419"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jalava</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kaartinen</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Utriainen</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Happonen</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hänninen</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Helicobacter salomonis sp. nov., a canine gastric Helicobacter sp. related to Helicobacter felis and Helicobacter bizzozeronii.</article-title><year>1997</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>975</fpage><lpage>982</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-4-975</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9336895</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Helicobacter salomonis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Helicobacter salomonis</i> (sa.lo.mo'nis, L. gen. n. <i>salomonis</i>, of Salomon; in honor of Hugo Salomon, a German scientist who was one of the first workers to describe three morphologically different spiral organisms in canine gastric mucosa)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells in in vitro cultures are loose spirals that are 0.8 to 1.2 μm wide by 5 to 7 μm long.</s><s>They do not have periplasmic fibrils.</s><s>In older cultures coccoids predominate.</s><s>The cells are gram negative and nonsporulating.</s><s>They are motile by means of tufts of 10 to 23 sheathed flagella at one or both ends of the cell; the movement is slower than that of <i>H. felis</i> or <i>H. bizzozeronii</i>.</s><s>Individual colonies are not formed, but cultures grow as spreading films on fresh moist agar media.</s><s>All strains are oxidase, catalase, and urease positive.</s><s>They reduce nitrate and TTC, and they are positive in indoxyl acetate, gamma-glutamyl transpeptidase, and alkaline phosphatase tests.</s><s>They are negative in hippurate hydrolysis, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, L-arginine arylamidase, and L-aspartate arylamidase tests.</s><s>Four of the five strains produce DNase.</s><s>They are resistant to nalidixic acid and are susceptible to cephalothin and cefoperazone.</s><s>One strain shows resistance to metronidazole.</s><s>They do not grow on media containing 1% ox bile, 1% glycine, or 1.5% NaCl.</s><s>They grow at 37°C, but not at 25 or 42°C.</s><s>All of the biochemical and tolerance characteristics are similar to the characteristics of <i>H. bizzozeronii</i>, except that one strain of <i>H. salomonis</i> is DNase negative and one strain is resistant to metronidazole.</s><s>The clinical significance of <i>H. salomonis</i> is unknown.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>Strain CCUG 37845 (= Inkinen) is the type strain of <i>H. salomonis</i>.</s><s>This strain conforms to the description given above.</s><s>It was isolated from a gastric biopsy of a healthy pet dog.</s><s>An additional strain, strain 06A, has been deposited in the Culture Collection of the University of Göteborg as strain CCUG 37848.</s></p></content></protolog>