<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8272_nm.14148" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14148" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14148" rank="species">Halomonas ilicicola</organism><reference id="rid.8272"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Arenas</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bañón</surname><given-names>P.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Copa-Patiño</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sánchez-Porro</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Soliveri</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Halomonas ilicicola sp. nov., a moderately halophilic bacterium isolated from a saltern.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>578</fpage><lpage>582</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.003509-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19244445</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Halomonas ilicicola</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Halomonas ilicicola</em> (i.li.ci′co.la. L. n. <em>ilici</em> the Roman name of Elche, the city close to the solar salterns where the type strain was isolated; L. suff. -<em>cola</em> inhabitant, dweller; N.L. n. <em>ilicicola</em> inhabitant of Ilici).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are short rods, 0.5–0.6×0.8–1.1 μm, occur singly or in pairs, are motile, do not form endospores and stain Gram-negative.</s><s>Colonies are circular, smooth, convex, pale orange, mucoid and 1.0–1.2 mm in diameter after 3 days incubation on MH medium at 37 °C.</s><s>In liquid medium, grows producing a uniform turbidity.</s><s>Exopolysaccharide is not produced.</s><s>Poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxyalkanoates are not accumulated.</s><s>Moderately halophilic, capable of growing in concentrations of between 2 and 17.5 % (w/v) salts.</s><s>No growth occurs in the absence of salt.</s><s>Optimal growth at 10 % (w/v) salts or NaCl.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 25–42 °C with optimal growth at 37 °C.</s><s>No growth detected at 15, 20 or 45 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 6.0−9.0 and is optimal at pH 6.5.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic.</s><s>Metabolism is respiratory, with oxygen, nitrate or nitrite as terminal electron acceptor.</s><s>Cells do not grow anaerobically in the presence of fumarate.</s><s>Catalase is produced but not oxidase.</s><s>d-Glucose is not fermented.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fucose, d-sorbitol, turanose and potassium 5-ketogluconate, but not from d-adonitol, l-arabinose, d-fructose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-lactose, maltose, d-mannose, melezitose, l-rhamnose, glycerol, d-mannitol, l-sorbose, trehalose or d-xylose.</s><s>Gelatin and aesculin are hydrolysed, but not starch, casein, Tween 80, DNA or tyrosine.</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite are reduced (with gas formation).</s><s>Grows on MacConkey and cetrimide agars supplemented with 10 % NaCl.</s><s>Methyl red test is positive.</s><s>Indole and H<sub>2</sub>S production are negative.</s><s>The Voges–Proskauer test and tests for activities of urease and lysine-, ornithine- and arginine decarboxylases, ONPG and phenylalanine deaminase are negative.</s><s>The following compounds can be used as sole carbon and energy sources: acetate, citrate, d-fructose, fumarate, d-galactose, gluconate, d-glucose, d-mannitol and propionate, but not aesculin, l-arabinose, cellobiose, ethanol, formate, lactose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, malonate, maltose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-ribose, starch, succinate, trehalose or d-xylose.</s><s>l-Alanine can be used as sole carbon, nitrogen and energy sources, but not l-cysteine, l-histidine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-serine or l-valine.</s><s>Cells are sensitive to (μg per disc) trimethoprim/sulfamethoxazole (1.25/23.75).</s><s>Intermediate resistance to (μg per disc): erythromycin (15), nalidixic acid (30) and rifampicin (5).</s><s>Resistant (μg per disc) to penicillin (10 U), vancomycin (30), chloramphenicol (30), streptomycin (10), bacitracin (10), cephalothin (30), novobiocin (30) neomycin (30), kanamycin (30) and tetracycline (30).</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (Table 2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SP8<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 7331<sup>T</sup>=CCM 7522<sup>T</sup>=DSM 19980<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a salty water sample from the solar salterns of Santa Pola (Alicante), located on the Mediterranean coast of Spain.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 66.9 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub> method).</s></p></content></protolog>