<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9219_nm.14472" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14472" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14472" rank="species">Clostridium sulfidigenes</organism><reference id="rid.9219"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sallam</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steinbüchel</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium sulfidigenes sp. nov., a mesophilic, proteolytic, thiosulfate- and sulfur-reducing bacterium isolated from pond sediment</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1661</fpage><lpage>1665</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.004986-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19542123</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Clostridium sulfidigenes</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Clostridium sulfidigenes</em> (sul.fi.di′ge.nes. N.L. n. <em>sulfidum</em> sulfide; N.L. neut. suff. -<em>genes</em> producing from Gr. v. <em>gennaio</em> to produce; N.L. neut. part. adj. <em>sulfidigenes</em> sulfide-producing).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rods, about 3–6 μm long and 0.5 μm in diameter, occurring as single cells or in pairs, and are motile until sporulation.</s><s>Subterminal to terminal spores are formed.</s><s>Gram staining is positive.</s><s>Colonies appearing after 48 h of incubation on peptone at 34 °C and after only 24 h on yeast extract are round with regular margins, translucent on peptone and yellowish brown on yeast extract.</s><s>Optimum growth temperature is 34 °C, with growth at 18–48 °C.</s><s>Optimum pH for growth is 6.6 and growth occurs at pH 5.5–9.0.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs in the absence of NaCl; however, concentrations up to 20 g NaCl l<sup>−1</sup> are tolerated.</s><s>The following substrates are used as carbon and energy sources: peptone, Casamino acids, gelatin, trypticase soy, l-citrulline, l-ornithine, l-arginine, l-alanine, l-leucine, l-isoleucine, l-methionine, l-threonine, l-serine, l-phenylalanine, l-valine, l-cysteine and pyruvate.</s><s>The following substrates are not used: l-proline, l-aspartate, l-lysine, l-histidine, l-glutamate, glycine, dl-tryptophan, l-tyrosine, lactose, glucose, galactose, mannose, arabinose, xylose, cellobiose, ribose, maltose, sucrose, fructose, lactate, acetate, succinate, ethanol and 1-propanol.</s><s>The main fermentation end products from Casamino acids, trypticase soy and gelatin are acetate, propionate, valerate and butyrate.</s><s>Peptone is converted mainly to acetate, succinate, propionate and valerate, whereas yeast extract is converted to acetate and ethanol.</s><s>The main fermentation end product detected from citrulline, ornithine, alanine, threonine, serine and cysteine is acetate; from arginine utilization, end-products are acetate and ethanol, and from methionine and phenylalanine, the end-product is mainly propionate.</s><s>Valine is converted to butyrate, leucine to valerate, and pyruvate to acetate and ethanol.</s><s>Uses thiosulfate and sulfur, but not sulfite, nitrate or nitrite as electron acceptors.</s><s>Thiosulfate improves the utilization of proteose peptone (Difco), Casamino acids, trypticase soy, l-arginine, l-ornithine and l-citrulline.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is SGB2<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 18982<sup>T</sup> =ATCC BAA-1538<sup>T</sup>), isolated from pond sediment in Münster, Germany.</s><s>Adverse effects on humans and animals by strain SGB2<sup>T</sup> are not known, but cannot be excluded.</s><s>Cautious handling and autoclaving of cultures before disposal is recommended.</s><s>Strain SGB2<sup>T</sup> has a DNA G+C content of 32.3 mol% (HPLC).</s></p></content></protolog>