<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9574_nm.14752" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14752" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14752" rank="subspecies">Pseudomonas brassicacearum neoaurantiaca</organism><reference id="rid.9574"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ivanova</surname><given-names>E.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bizet</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Clermont</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Motreff</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bouchier</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhukova</surname><given-names>N.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Crawford</surname><given-names>R.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kiprianova</surname><given-names>E.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudomonas brassicacearum subsp. neoaurantiaca subsp. nov., orange-pigmented bacteria isolated from soil and the rhizosphere of agricultural plants</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2476</fpage><lpage>2481</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.009654-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19622656</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudomonas brassicacearum</em> subsp. <em>neoaurantiaca</em> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudomonas brassicacearum</em> subsp. <em>neoaurantiaca</em> (ne.o.au.ran′ti.a′ca. Gr. adj. <em>neos</em> new; N.L. fem. adj. <em>aurantiaca</em> orange-coloured and also a bacterial specific epithet; N.L. fem. adj. <em>neoaurantiaca</em> new <em>aurantiaca</em>, referring to the phenotypic similarity to <em>Pseudomonas aurantiaca</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rod-shaped cells, single, 1.0–1.5 μm long and about 0.3–0.8 μm in diameter.</s><s>Gram-negative.</s><s>Motile, with three to five polar flagella.</s><s>Aerobic.</s><s>Chemorganotroph with respiratory metabolism.</s><s>Produces a water-soluble yellow–green fluorescent pigment, a water- and alcohol-soluble red–orange pigment and a complex of antimicrobial phloroglucinol derivates.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 4–37 °C, with optimum growth at 25 °C.</s><s>No growth at 40 °C.</s><s>The pH for growth is pH 6.0–10.0, with optimum growth at pH 7.0.</s><s>Does not accumulate poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate as an intracellular reserve product.</s><s>Positive for arginine dihydrolase; negative for lysine and ornithine decarboxylases.</s><s>Forms levan from sucrose.</s><s>Vigorous denitrifier.</s><s>Does not oxidize gluconate to 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>Liquefies gelatin and does not hydrolyse starch, agar, aesculin, chitin or DNA.</s><s>Lipase production (hydrolysis of Tween 80) is variable.</s><s>Only activities for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), trypsin, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase are detected in API ZYM tests.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as single sources of carbon and energy: d-glucose, d-xylose, l-arabinose, d-mannose, d-galactose, d-fructose, sucrose, trehalose, gluconate, acetate, propionate, butyrate, valerate, caproate, heptanoate, caprylate, pelargonate, malate, lactate, succinate, fumarate, glutarate, citrate, isocitrate, <em>α</em>-ketoglutarate, pyruvate, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, mannitol, sorbitol, inositol, glycerol, 2,3-butylene glycol, ethanol, n-propanol, n-butanol, isobutanol, benzoate, <em>p</em>-hydroxybenzoate, quinate, <em>α</em>-alanine, <em>β</em>-alanine, l-serine, l-leucine, l-isoleucine, l-valine, l-lysine, l-arginine, l-aspartate, l-glutamate, l-ornithine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyrate, l-histidine, l-proline, l-tyrosine, l-phenylalanine, betaine and sarcosine.</s><s>Strains isolated from oil-saturated soils utilize C<sub>6</sub>–C<sub>10</sub> hydrocarbons and produce phloroglucinol derivates when grown in synthetic medium in a C<sub>6</sub>–C<sub>10</sub> atmosphere with aeration (Smirnov &#x0026; Kiprianova, 1990).</s><s>d-Fucose, l-rhamnose, maltose, cellobiose, lactose, starch, inulin, salicin, oxalate, maleate, adipate, pimelate, <em>meso</em>-tartrate, glycolate, itaconate, dulcitol, adonitol, mandelate, <em>o</em>-hydroxybenzoate, <em>m</em>-hydroxybenzoate, phthalate, phenol, phenylacetate, glycine, citrulline, l- and d-tryptophan, anthranilate, <em>p-</em>aminobenzoate, creatine, hippurate, pantothenate, acetamide and nicotinate are not utilized.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 61.7–62.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CIP 109457<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC 49054<sup>T</sup> =IMV 387<sup>T</sup> =VKM B-1524<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Strains have been isolated from soils and the rhizosphere of plants in temperate areas.</s></p></content></protolog>