<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1583_nm.10852" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10852" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10852" rank="species">Massilia aurea</organism><reference id="rid.1583"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gallego</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sánchez-Porro</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>García</surname><given-names>M.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Massilia aurea sp. nov., isolated from drinking water.</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2449</fpage><lpage>2453</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64389-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17012578</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Massilia aurea</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Massilia aurea</em> (au′re.a. L. fem adj. <em>aurea</em> golden, referring to the yellowish pigment that the bacterium produces).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, straight rods 1.0×1.6–3.0 μm in size that occur singly or in pairs (on PCA medium at 28 °C after 48 h).</s><s>Cells are motile, non-spore-forming and strictly aerobic.</s><s>Colonies are circular, translucent, yellow-pigmented and 0.6–1.0 mm in diameter on PCA agar after 2 days incubation.</s><s>Good growth occurs on TSA, R2A and nutrient agar medium.</s><s>Does not grow on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Cells have a tendency to form pellicles on the surface of static liquid cultures.</s><s>Does not grow in the presence of 2 % NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4–30 °C (optimum temperature, 28 °C) and at pH 4.0–9.0 (optimum pH, 6.0–7.0).</s><s>Catalase-positive.</s><s>Weakly oxidase-positive.</s><s>Urease-negative.</s><s>Negative for indole production, hydrogen sulfide production and nitrate reduction, and in the methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests.</s><s>Glucose is not fermented.</s><s>Simmons' citrate test is positive.</s><s>Starch, gelatin, casein and DNA are hydrolysed but Tween 80 is not.</s><s>Acid is not produced oxidatively from d-galactose, d-mannose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-maltose, glycerol, d-mannitol, d-trehalose, d-xylose or lactose.</s><s>Alkaline and acid phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>α</em>-glucosidase are present.</s><s>Negative for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, lipase (C14), cysteine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Utilizes d-xylose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, aesculin, d-cellobiose, d-maltose, starch, glycogen, gentiobiose, adipic acid, malic acid and trisodium citrate as sole carbon and energy sources, but not glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, l-sorbose, dulcitol, inositol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, arbutin, salicin, d-lactose (bovine origin), d-melibiose, sucrose, d-trehalose, inulin, d-melezitose, d-raffinose, xylitol, d-turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate, potassium 5-ketogluconate, l-arabinose, capric acid or phenylacetic acid.</s><s>Resistant to the following antibiotics: penicillin (10 U per disc), bacitracin (10 U per disc) and cephalothin (30 μg per disc).</s><s>Sensitive to the following antibiotics (μg per disc): tetracycline (30), rifampicin (30), streptomycin (10), neomycin (10), erythromycin (15), kanamycin (30), vancomycin (30), nalidixic acid (30), novobiocin (30) and chloranphenicol (30).</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are C<sub>10 : 0</sub> (0.4 %), C<sub>10 : 0</sub> 3-OH (4.8 %), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> (4.6 %), C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 2-OH (1.9 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (0.6 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH (48.3 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (36.8 %) and C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (2.5 %).</s><s>The predominant ubiquinone is Q-8.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 66.0 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, AP13<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 7142<sup>T</sup>=CCM 7363<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18055<sup>T</sup>=JCM 13879<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from drinking water.</s></p></content></protolog>