<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4383_nm.1084" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1084" rank="genus">Methylarcula</organism><reference id="rid.4383"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Doronina</surname><given-names>N.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trotsenko</surname><given-names>Y.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tourova</surname><given-names>T.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Methylarcula marina gen. nov., sp. nov. and Methylarcula terricola sp. nov.: novel aerobic, moderately halophilic, facultatively methylotrophic bacteria from coastal saline environments.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>1849</fpage><lpage>1859</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11034496</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Methylarcula</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Methylarcula</i> (Me.thyl.ar.cu'la. M.L. n. <i>methyl</i> methyl group; L. fem. n. <i>arcula</i> small box; M.L. fem. n. <i>Methylarcula</i> methyl-using small box)</s></p><p class="description"><s>When grown in methylamine mineral salt medium, cells are Gram-negative, non-sporulating, colourless rods, usually 0.5-0.8 lm in length and 0.8-2.0 μm in diameter, which multiply by fission.</s><s>Colonies on methylamine agar are white and mucoid.</s><s>Aerobic and moderately halophilic and requiring NaCl for growth.</s><s>Accumulate ectoine intracellularly as the main osmoprotectant, and PHB granules.Donot require vitamins for growth.</s><s>Do not grow on peptone/yeast extract medium with or without NaCl.</s><s>Do not grow under methane or hydrogen.</s><s>Do not reduce nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>Utilize methylamine, sugars and some organic acids as carbon and energy sources.</s><s>Ammonium salts and methylamine are utilized as nitrogen sources.</s><s>Acids are produced from sugars oxidatively.</s><s>Do not form acetoin, indole, hydrogen sulfide and ammonia.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic and facultatively methylotrophic bacteria assimilating C<sub>1</sub> compounds via the isocitrate lyase-negative (icl<sup>−</sup>) serine pathway.</s><s>The major ubiquinone is Q-10.</s><s>Dominant phospholipids are phosphatidylethanolamine and phosphatidylcholine.</s><s>The prevailing cellular fatty acids are straight-chain unsaturated (C<sub>18:1</sub>), saturated (C<sub>18:0</sub>) and cyclopropane (C<sub>19:0</sub>) acids.</s><s>DNA G+C content ranges from 57 to 61 mol%.</s><s>The levels of DNA-DNA hybridization with members of the genera <i>Methylobacterium</i>, <i>Methylorhabdus</i>, <i>Aminobacter</i> and <i>Methylopila</i> are below 10%.</s><s>The genus <i>Methylarcula</i> belongs to the α-3 subclass of the <i>Proteobacteria</i>, as revealed by comparative sequence analysis of the 16S rDNA and is phylogenetically distinct from the other methylotrophic genera.</s><s>Type species is <i>Methylarcula marina</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>