<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.386_nm.5269" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5269" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5269" rank="subspecies">Staphylococcus saprophyticus bovis</organism><reference id="rid.386"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hájek</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Meugnier</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bes</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brun</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fiedler</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chmela</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lasne</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fleurette</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Freney</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Staphylococcus saprophyticus subsp. bovis subsp. nov., isolated from bovine nostrils.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>792</fpage><lpage>796</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-3-792</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8782691</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Staphylococcus saprophyticus</i> subsp. <i>bovis</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Staphylococcus saprophyticus</i> subsp. <i>bovis</i> (bo'vis. L. n. bos, a cow; L. gen. n. bovis, of a cow)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description of <i>Staphylococcus saprophyticus</i> subsp. <i>bovis</i> is based on a total of five strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Physiological and biochemical characteristics.</s><s>The organism has gram-positive spherical cells, 0.7 to 1.4 μm in diameter, that occur singly, in pairs, in short chains, and in irregular clumps.</s><s>The organism is nonmotile and non-spore forming.</s><s>Colonies are circular, entire, butyrous, slightly convex with gently raised centers and glistening surfaces, and grow to 4 mm in diameter after 3 days of cultivation.</s><s>Creamy to pale orange pigment is produced by four strains, and one strain is unpigmented.</s><s>Broth cultures form with uniform turbidity and delicate deposit.</s><s>Growth is very weak at 10°C, and there is no growth at 45°C.</s><s>Colonies formed on nutrient agar supplemented with NaCl at a concentration up to 10.0% and only weakly at a concentration up to 12.5%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The strains are facultative anaerobes.</s><s>The benzidine test for porphyrin is positive, and sodium hippurate is hydrolyzed.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced.</s><s>The organism is catalase and urease positive.</s><s>Acid is produced from fructose, glucose, glycerol, maltose, mannitol, ribose, trehalose, and N-acetylglycosamine under aerobic conditions and from glucose under anaerobic conditions.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The variable characteristics of <i>S. saprophyticus</i> subsp. <i>bovis</i> are listed in Table 1.</s></p><p class="description"><s>None of the strains studied produce coagulase, clumping factor, fibrinolysin, elastase, arginine arylamidase, arginine dihydrolase, ornithine and lysine decarboxylases, oxidase, acid phosphatase, heat-labile and heat-stable nucleases, hyaluronidase, hemolysins, and acid from adonitol, cellobiose, dulcitol, galactose, raffinose, rhamnose, and xylose.</s><s>Esculin and starch are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>All strains are negative for production of hydrogen sulfide, phenylalanine deaminase, and acid from mannitol under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>No growth is recorded on Simmons citrate agar and on nutrient agar in the presence of 15% NaCl.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Drug susceptibilities.</s><s>In disk diffusion tests, resistance to novobiocin, bacitracin, and vibriostatic compound O/129 is noted.</s><s>On the contrary, all of the strains are sensitive to lysostaphin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>As determined by MICs, all of the KV strains are susceptible to penicillin G (MIC [micrograms per milliliter], 0.06 to 0.1), ampicillin (MIC, 0.06 to 0.1), oxacillin (MIC, 0.2 to 0.5), azlocillin (MIC, 1.0 to 16.0), cephalothin (MIC, 0.2 to 0.5), streptomycin (MIC, 0.5 to 2.0), gentamicin (MIC, 0.06 to 0.1), kanamycin (MIC, 0.5) , tobramycin (MIC, 0.06), netilmicin (MIC, 0.03), neomycin (MIC, 0.06), minocycline (MIC, 0.06), chloramphenicol (MIC, 4.0), erythromycin (MIC, 0.06 to 0.5), lincomycin (MIC, 0.06 to 0.5), clindamycin (MIC, 0.06 to 0.1), pristinamycin (MIC, 0.25 to 1.0), rifampin (MIC, 0.1), teicoplanin (MIC, 0.5 to 2.0), vancomycin (MIC, 0.5 to l.O), ofloxacin (MIC, 0.21, and co-trimoxazole (MIC, 0.5 to 1.0).</s><s>From the disinfectants tested, efficacy was recorded for ethidium bromide (MIC, ≤10.0), acriflavine (MIC, ≤50.0), chlorbenzalconium (MIC, ≤2.6), chlorhexidine (MIC, ≤0.9), and hexamidine diisothionate (MIC, ≤10.0).</s><s>All strains are resistant to 1,000 μg of lysozyme per ml.</s><s>Some of the strains are resistant to tetracycline, cefotaxime, ceftriaxone, ceftazidime, pefloxacin, fusidic acid, or nitrofurantoin (Table 2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Phage typing.</s><s>None of the strains was susceptible to all 63 phages used at 1OOX routine test dilution.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Fatty acid profile.</s><s>The strains have a branched-chain anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub> fatty acid as their dominant component.</s><s>The presence of long-chain saturated unbranched fatty acids C<sub>18:0</sub> and C<sub>20:0</sub> has also been demonstrated as typical for staphylococci (24, 31).</s><s>In addition, evidently larger amounts of fatty acids iso-C<sub>15:0</sub> and particularly anteiso-C<sub>17:0</sub> were recorded.</s><s>The determination of fatty acid patterns yielded closely related results both in the KV strains and in E 39 (=CCM 883<sup>T</sup>), the <i>S. saprophyticus</i> type strain (Table 3).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell wall analysis.</s><s>The findings on the composition of peptidoglycans are given in Table 4.</s><s>In peptidoglycans of all estimated strains, a small amount of serine was present.</s><s>Except for the KV 19 strain, the glycineherine molar ratio reached approximately half the values for S. saprophyticus (30, 31).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Smaller amounts of serine coincide with the lysostaphin susceptibility observed in all strains.</s><s>The peptidoglycan type of the KV strains was determined as Lys-Gly<sub>3.4-4.0</sub>, Ser<sub>0.2-0.7</sub>.</s><s>The amount of NH<sub>3</sub> in the hydrolysates may indicate amidation on the α-carboxyl of glutamic acid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The data concerning the accessory carbohydrate polymers in the cell walls are summarized in Table 5.</s><s>Significant amounts of phosphorus in the prepared cell walls indicated the presence of teichoic acids.</s><s>The KV 12<sup>T</sup>, KV 20, KV 30, and KV 56 strains exhibited ribitol teichoic acids with partial substitution by N-acetylglucosamine.</s><s>In the case of the KV 56 strain, glucose may be a minor substituent of ribitol in addition to N-acetylglucosamine.</s><s>The teichoic acid of the KV 19 strain was found to be distinctly different.</s><s>Glycerol (Gro) is the polyol with typical behavior on hydrofluoric acid hydrolysis, allowing us to assume that chains consisting of [ -P-GlcNAc-P-Gro-] repeating units are present.</s><s>It could explain the rather large amount of phosphorus in this type of cell wall teichoic acid.</s><s>Glucose may function as a substituent.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Protein A has not been detected in the strains.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA-DNA hybridization.</s><s>The five KV strains form a genetically homogeneous group.</s><s>The DNA relatedness results obtained with labeled reference DNA from the KV 12<sup>T</sup> strain are given in Table 6.</s><s>The other KV strains are related at species levels of 94 to 99%, and the <i>S. saprophyticus</i> type strain, CCM 883, is related at a subspecies level of 71%.</s><s>The type strains of other staphylococcal species show relatedness at levels of no more than 32%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base composition.</s><s>The G + C contents of the DNA of all strains tested varied in a close range between 30.9 and 31.3 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>The type strain KV 12 (=CCM 4410<sup>T</sup>), isolated from the anterior nares of a cow, has the characteristics given for the species above and in Tables 1, 2, and 3.</s><s>The peptidoglycan structure is of the Lys-Gly<sub>3.8</sub>, Ser<sub>0.3</sub> type.</s><s>The G + C content of its DNA was found to be 31.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Distinguishing characteristics. <i>S. saprophyticus</i> subsp. <i>bovis</i> can be phenotypically distinguished from <i>S. saprophyticus</i> subsp. <i>saprophyticus</i> on the basis of smaller colony diameters, nitrate reduction, ability to produce pyrrolidonyl arylamidase but not acetylmethylcarbinol, and fermentation of galactose and ribose (Table 7).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The properties useful in the identification and separation of the new taxon <i>S. saprophyticus</i> subsp. <i>bovis</i> from the other novobiocin-resistant staphylococcal species and subspecies are listed in Table 8.</s><s>It can be recognized by the colony size, reduction of nitrates, production of urease and acid from ribose, and its inability to hydrolyze esculin and produce acid from cellobiose, raffinose, and xylose.</s></p></content></protolog>