<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4779_nm.3788" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3788" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3788" rank="species">Campylobacter butzleri</organism><reference id="rid.4779"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kiehlbauch</surname><given-names>J.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nicholson</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baker</surname><given-names>C.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patton</surname><given-names>C.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wachsmuth</surname><given-names>I.K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Campylobacter butzleri sp. nov. isolated from humans and animals with diarrheal illness.</article-title><year>1991</year><volume>29</volume><fpage>376</fpage><lpage>385</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2007646</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Campylobacter butzleri</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Campylobacter butzleri</i> (butz'ler.i., is named in honor of Jean-Paul Butzler, a Belgian clinician and microbiologist, in recognition of his many contributions to the field of Campylobacter. Butzler and colleagues were the first to describe a selective medium which allowed hospital-based laboratories to isolate and identify <i>C. jejuni</i> and <i>C. coli</i> organisms on a routine basis. More recently, they modified the selective medium and used less-selective techniques to isolate other campylobacter pathogens, such as C. fetus subsp. fetus, and "<i>C. upsaliensis</i>." Additionally, Butzler and colleagues have contributed to our current understanding of the disease process and the role of antimicrobial therapy in campylobacteriosis and has provided valuable information about the epidemiology of <i>C. jejuni</i> and <i>C. coli</i>. Butzler is currently the director of the World Health Organization Collaborating Centre for <i>C. jejuni</i>, a member of the International Subcommittees on <i>Campylobacter</i> taxonomy and serotyping, and actively involved with the organization of the biennial International Workshops on <i>Campylobacter</i> Infections.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative, nonsporeforming curved rods; some S-shaped forms are observed.</s><s>Aerotolerant; light growth under anaerobic conditions.</s><s>Darting motility; single, polar flagella at one or both ends.</s><s>Catalase negative or weakly positive; oxidase positive.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15, 25, 30, 36, and 40°C; no growth occurs at 5°C; variable, light growth at 42°C.</s><s>D-Glucose is not oxidized or fermented.</s><s>Growth occurs in medium containing 1% glycine; variable growth occurs in the presence of 1.5% (84%) and 3.5% (61%) NaCl.</s><s>Isolates reduce nitrate, but not nitrite or esculin, hydrolyze indoxyl acetate, but not urea or hippurate, and variably produce DNase (25 to 28%).</s><s>Growth in media containing 8% glucose and sodium succinate.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide not produced in triple sugar iron agar; variable production (16%) on lead acetate strips suspended over media containing cysteine.</s><s>Growth on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Variable (31%) red-pigmented growth on medium containing 0.04% TTC; no growth on medium containing sodium selenite All strains resistant to 2.5 μg of cadmium chloride, and most strains (72%) resistant to 20 μg of cadmium chloride.</s><s>Good growth on HIA and brucella media with and without blood.</s><s>Growth not enhanced by the use of chocolate agar.</s><s>Generally resistant to cephalothin and other cephalosporins, trimethoprim, and trimethoprim-sulfamethoxazole; intermediate susceptibility to nalidixic acid and erythromycin; susceptible to aminoglycosides, quinolones, polymyxin B, colistin, and rifampin (9).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains isolated most frequently from stools of human and nonhuman primates with diarrheal illness.</s><s>Additional strains isolated at necropsy from an ostrich with diarrheal illness and from aborted bovine and porcine fetuses.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The mean G+C content of six strains is 30 ± 1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain D2686 (ATCC 49616) is the type strain of <i>C. butzleri</i>.</s><s>This strain conforms to the species description given above.</s><s>Trace growth under anaerobic conditions and light growth at 42°C.</s><s>Weak production of catalase.</s><s>Growth in 1.5% NaCl, but not 3.5% NaCl.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide not produced in triple sugar iron agar, but a trace amount detected on lead acetate strips suspended over cysteine-containing medium.</s><s>Negative for DNase, as detected by both toluidine blue- and methyl green-containing media.</s><s>Growth does not occur in the presence of TTC-containing medium.</s><s>Resistant to a 30-μg cephalothin disk (no zone of inhibition) and a 20-μg disk of cadmium chloride (no zone of inhibition) and intermediately susceptible to a 30-μg nalidixic acid disk (10-mm zone of inhibition).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Antibiotic susceptibility as determined for the following antimicrobial agents by broth microdilution (26) (unless otherwise noted, antimicrobic concentrations are in micrograms per milliliter): resistant to ampicillin (&#x003E;32), ampicillinsulbactam (32.0/16.0), nalidixic acid (&#x003E;32), erythromycin (8.0), azithromycin (16.0), roxithromycin (16.0), chloramphenicol (&#x003E;32), cephalothin (&#x003E;32), cefuroxime (&#x003E;32), cefoperazone (&#x003E;32), cefotaxime (32.0), and clindamycin (&#x003E;8); susceptible to ciprofloxacin (-0.03), enoxacin (0.05), norfloxacin (0.5), ofloxacin (0.5), tetracycline (0.25), doxycycline (0.5), minocycline (0.25), gentamicin (0.25), amikacin (1.0), and trimethoprim-sulfamethoxazole (1/19 U).</s><s>No growth in polymyxin B (5 U), colistin (10 U), rifampin (10.0), or metronidazole (4.0); growth in novobiocin (15.0), trimethoprim (5.0, 10.0, and 50.0), vancomycin (10.0), cefazolin (15.0), cycloheximide (50.0), bacitracin (25 U), and amphotericin B (2.0).</s><s>Growth is not demonstrated on Campy-BAP agar, but does occur on Campy-CVA agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The mean G+C content of D2686 is 31 ± 2 mol%.</s><s>This strain was isolated in the United States from a male patient with diarrheal illness.</s></p></content></protolog>