<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9488_nm.14634" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14634" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14634" rank="species">Acidisoma sibiricum</organism><reference id="rid.9488"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Belova</surname><given-names>S.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pankratov</surname><given-names>T.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Detkova</surname><given-names>E.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kaparullina</surname><given-names>E.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dedysh</surname><given-names>S.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Acidisoma tundrae gen. nov., sp. nov. and Acidisoma sibiricum sp. nov., two acidophilic, psychrotolerant members of the Alphaproteobacteria from acidic northern wetlands</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2283</fpage><lpage>2290</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.009209-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19620354</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Acidisoma sibiricum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Acidisoma sibiricum</em> (si.bi′ri.cum. N.L. neut. adj. <em>sibiricum</em> from Siberia, the region of Russia from where the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is as for the genus but with the following additional traits.</s><s>Cells are 0.7–1.2 μm wide and 1.4–3.1 μm long.</s><s>Spirilloxanthin is present in small amounts.</s><s>Able to utilize the following carbon sources (0.05 %, w/v): sorbitol, arabinose, galactose, fructose, sorbose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, mannitol, dulcitol, glycerol, gluconate, pyruvate, galacturonic acid, yeast extract, Casamino acids, peptone, asparagine, xylose and glucose.</s><s>Utilization of lactose, trehalose, mannose, cellobiose and sucrose is variable.</s><s>Cannot utilize acetate, propionate, butyrate, capronate, formate, oxalate, citrate, benzoate, succinate, lactate, malate, ethanol, propanol, butanol, glucuronic acid, raffinose, maltose, fumarate, alanine, aspartate or leucine.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse pullulan, pectin, alginate, carboxymethylcellulose or chondroitin sulfate.</s><s>The ability to hydrolyse laminarin and fucoidan is variable.</s><s>The following enzyme activities are present: alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, esterase, esterase lipase, leucine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, phosphohydrolase and urease (API ZYM test).</s><s>Able to utilize the following nitrogen sources (0.05 %, w/v): ammonia, urea, Bacto yeast extract, glutamine, proline, histidine HCl, methionine and nitrate.</s><s>Utilization of asparagine is variable.</s><s>Contains phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol, an unknown aminolipid and an unknown polar lipid as major lipids.</s><s>Phosphatidylserine and several unknown polar lipids are present in minor amounts.</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin, lincomycin, novobiocin, streptomycin, chloramphenicol and neomycin, but susceptible to kanamycin and gentamicin.</s><s>Capable of growth at pH 3.7–7.6 (optimum, pH 5.0–6.5) and at 2–30 °C (optimum, 20–25 °C).</s><s>NaCl inhibits growth at concentrations above 2.5 % (w/v).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, TPB606<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 21000<sup>T</sup>=VKM B-2487<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the <em>Sphagnum</em> peat bog Bakchar in the Tomsk region of western Siberia.</s><s>TPB621, isolated from the same locality, is a second strain of the species.</s></p></content></protolog>