<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8193_nm.13402" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13402" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13402" rank="species">Marinobacter goseongensis</organism><reference id="rid.8193"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Roh</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Quan</surname><given-names>Z.X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nam</surname><given-names>Y.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chang</surname><given-names>H.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rhee</surname><given-names>S.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>H.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>C.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>J.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Marinobacter goseongensis sp. nov., from seawater.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2866</fpage><lpage>2870</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65522-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19060073</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Marinobacter goseongensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Marinobacter goseongensis</em> (go′se.on.gen′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>goseongensis</em> pertaining to the province Goseong, near the sampling site from which the bacterium was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped (0.5–0.8×1.6–2.0 μm), Gram-negative, non-motile, oxidase- and catalase-positive and non-spore-forming.</s><s>Cells are not heat resistant.</s><s>Colonies are cream-coloured, circular and approximately 0.5 mm in diameter after growth for 1 day on MA at 30 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–37 °C (optimum, 25–30 °C) and pH 5.3–9.3 (optimum, pH 7.5) and in 1–25 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum, 4–5 % NaCl).</s><s>Gelatin and starch are not hydrolysed.</s><s>According to Biolog GN plates, positive for Tween 40, Tween 80, pyruvic acid methyl ester, acetic acid, dl-lactic acid and l-glutamic acid; and negative for <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, d-cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, succinic acid monomethyl ester, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenyethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>According to API ZYM test strips, positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-B1-phosphohydrolase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase activities; and negative for lipase (C14), trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities.</s><s>Predominant fatty acids are C<sub>12 : 0</sub>, C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> (Table 2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, En6<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12515<sup>T</sup>=DSM 19471<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from seawater of the East Sea of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>