<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12560_nm.6673" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6673" rank="family">Pseudonocardiaceae</organism><reference id="rid.12560"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Labeda</surname><given-names>D.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chun</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhi</surname><given-names>X.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reassessment of the systematics of the suborder Pseudonocardineae: transfer of the genera within the family Actinosynnemataceae Labeda and Kroppenstedt 2000 emend. Zhi et al. 2009 into an emended family Pseudonocardiaceae Embley et al. 1989 emend. Zhi et al. 2009</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1259</fpage><lpage>1264</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.024984-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20601483</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the family <em>Pseudonocardiaceae</em> Embley <em>et al.</em> 1989 emend. Zhi <em>et al.</em> 2009</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudonocardiaceae</em> (Pseu.do.no.car′di.ac.e.ae. N.L. fem. n. <em>Pseudonocardia</em> the type genus of the family; L. suff. <em>-aceae</em> ending to denote a family; N.L. fem. pl. n. <em>Pseudonocardiaceae</em> the <em>Pseudonocardia</em> family).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The family contains the type genus <em>Pseudonocardia</em> Henssen 1957 (Approved Lists 1980) emend. Park <em>et al.</em> 2008, as well as the genera <em>Actinoalloteichus</em> Tamura <em>et al.</em> 2000, <em>Actinokineospora</em> Hasegawa 1988b emend. Labeda <em>et al.</em> 2010 (effective publication Hasegawa, 1988a), <em>Actinomycetospora</em> Jiang <em>et al.</em> 2008, <em>Actinophytocola</em> Indananda <em>et al.</em> 2010, <em>Actinosynnema</em> Hasegawa <em>et al.</em> 1978, <em>Alloactinosynnema</em> Yuan <em>et al.</em> 2010, <em>Allokutzneria</em> Labeda and Kroppenstedt 2008, <em>Amycolatopsis</em> Lechevalier <em>et al.</em> 1986 emend. Lee 2009, <em>Crossiella</em> Labeda 2001, <em>Goodfellowiella</em> Labeda <em>et al.</em> 2008 (previous illegitimate name <em>Goodfellowia</em> Labeda and Kroppenstedt 2006), <em>Haloechinothrix</em> Tang <em>et al.</em> 2010, <em>Kibdelosporangium</em> Shearer <em>et al.</em> 1986, <em>Kutzneria</em> Stackebrandt <em>et al.</em> 1994, <em>Lechevalieria</em> Labeda <em>et al.</em> 2001, <em>Lentzea</em> Yassin <em>et al.</em> 1995 emend. Labeda <em>et al.</em> 2001, <em>Prauserella</em> Kim and Goodfellow 1999 emend. Li <em>et al.</em> 2003, <em>Saccharomonospora</em> Nonomura and Ohara 1971 (Approved Lists 1980), <em>Saccharopolyspora</em> Lacey and Goodfellow 1975 (Approved Lists 1980) emend. Korn-Wendisch <em>et al.</em> 1989, <em>Saccharothrix</em> Labeda <em>et al.</em> 1984 emend. Labeda and Lechevalier 1989, <em>Sciscionella</em> Tian <em>et al.</em> 2009, <em>Streptoalloteichus</em> Tomita <em>et al.</em> 1987 emend. Tamura <em>et al.</em> 2008, <em>Thermocrispum</em> Korn-Wendisch <em>et al.</em> 1995, <em>Umezawaea</em> Labeda and Kroppenstedt 2007 and <em>Yuhushiella</em> Mao <em>et al.</em> 2011.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, mesophilic or thermophilic, catalase-positive actinomycetes.</s><s>Gram-positive.</s><s>Not acid-fast.</s><s>Morphologically heterogeneous; single or short chains of spores may be present on both aerial mycelium and substrate mycelium.</s><s>Vegetative mycelium branches, diameter approximately 0.5–0.7 µm; aerial mycelium is produced and fragments in some genera into single smooth-surfaced, rod-shaped elements or chains of such elements.</s><s>Some taxa may fail to produce aerial mycelium.</s><s>Marked fragmentation of hyphae occurs in some taxa, but is absent in others.</s><s>Other structures such as synnemata or dome-like bodies, sporangia or pseudosporangia may be produced in some genera.</s><s>Motile spores may be produced in some genera.</s><s>Most taxa are chemo-organotrophic, although some are autotrophic.</s><s>A few taxa are halophilic.</s><s>All genera contain <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid as the diamino acid in their peptidoglycan and all except <em>Haloechinothrix</em> contain galactose as one of many diagnostic whole-cell sugars.</s><s>Mycolic acids are not present in any of the genera.</s><s>Tetrahydrogenated menaquinones of nine isoprene units are characteristic components, although menaquinones containing eight isoprene units predominate in the genus <em>Pseudonocardia</em>.</s><s>The phospholipid profile generally includes phosphatidylethanolamine, sometimes containing hydroxylated fatty acids, as a major constituent, although representatives of one or more genera may also contain phosphatidylcholine.</s><s>Resistant to lysozyme.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA ranges from 66 to 74 mol%.</s><s>The pattern of 16S rRNA signatures consists of nucleotides at positions 127 : 234 (G–C), 564 (U), 672 : 734 (U–G), 831 : 855 (U–G), 832 : 854 (G–Y), 833 : 853 (U–G), 952 : 1229 (U–A) and 986 : 1219 (U–A).</s><s>Members of the family are found in a variety of environments, including soils, plant material, manure and clinical or veterinary samples.</s><s>The type genus is <em>Pseudonocardia</em> Henssen 1957 (Approved Lists 1980) emend. Park <em>et al.</em> 2008.</s></p></content></protolog>