<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1816_nm.11034" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11034" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11034" rank="species">Sphingobium aromaticiconvertens</organism><reference id="rid.1816"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wittich</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tiirola</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wieser</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Macedo</surname><given-names>A.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Abraham</surname><given-names>W.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Sphingobium aromaticiconvertens sp. nov., a xenobiotic-compound-degrading bacterium from polluted river sediment</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>306</fpage><lpage>310</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64433-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17267969</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Sphingobium aromaticiconvertens</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Sphingobium aromaticiconvertens</em> [a.ro.ma.ti′ci.con.ver′tens. L. adj. <em>aromaticus</em> aromatic; N.L. neut. n. <em>aromaticum</em> aromatic compound; L. part. adj. <em>convertens</em> converting; N.L. part. adj. <em>aromaticiconvertens</em> converting aromatic compounds (into other form)].</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is the same as that given for the genus with the following additional characteristics.</s><s>Colonies are light yellow on mineral salts medium and on LB medium.</s><s>Cells are short, irregular rods, 0.8–1.5 μm in length and 0.4–0.6 μm in diameter, forming rosettes in complex medium; on selective media, cells form branched thread-like/hypha-like aggregates.</s><s>A large capsule is formed during growth with dibenzofuran.</s><s>Gram-negative and oxidase-, <em>β</em>-galactosidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>d-Fructose, l-rhamnose, dl-lactate and l-aspartate are used as substrates for growth but not <em>n</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, <em>p</em>-arbutin, d-cellobiose, d-galactose, gluconate, d-glucose, d-mannose, d-maltose, d-melibiose, sucrose, salicin, d-trehalose, d-xylose, maltitol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, acetate, propionate, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, adipate, 4-aminobutyrate, azelate, citrate, fumarate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, l-malate, pyruvate, l-alanine, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate or phenylacetate.</s><s><em>p</em>-Nitrophenyl (pNP) <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, bis-pNP phosphate and l-alanine <em>p</em>-nitroanilide (pNA) are hydrolysed, but aesculin, pNP <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucuronide, pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP phenylphosphonate, pNP phosphorylcholine, 2-deoxythymidine-5′-pNP phosphate, l-glutamate-3-carboxy pna and l-proline pNA are not.</s><s>In the polar lipid profile, diphosphatidylglycerol, sphingoglycolipid and an unknown glycolipid are predominant.</s><s>Phosphatidylmonomethylethanolamine, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidyldimethylethanolamine, an unknown phospholipid and an unknown glycolipid are present in minor amounts.</s><s>Major fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub> (included within summed feature 7) and C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 2-OH and minor fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em> and C<sub>14 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Major cellular polyamine is spermidine (30.2 μmol g<sup>−1</sup> dry weight); minor amounts of spermine (2.7 μmol g<sup>−1</sup> dry weight) and traces of putrescine and cadaverine are present as well.</s><s>The quinone system is characterized by ubiquinone Q-10 only.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 60.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, RW16<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 12677<sup>T</sup>=CIP 109198<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from an enrichment culture on some monochlorinated dibenzofurans inoculated with aerobic sediment samples from the River Elbe, Germany.</s></p></content></protolog>