<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4188_nm.7553" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7553" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7553" rank="species">Nocardiopsis tropica</organism><reference id="rid.4188"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Evtushenko</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Taran</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Akimov</surname><given-names>V.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tiedje</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardiopsis tropica sp. nov., Nocardiopsis trehalosi sp. nov., nom. rev. and Nocardiopsis dassonvillei subsp. albirubida subsp. nov., comb. nov.</article-title><year>2000</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>73</fpage><lpage>81</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10826789</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Nocardiopsis tropica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Nocardiopsis tropica</i> (tro'pi.ca. M.L. adj. <i>tropica</i> referring to the tropical region where the type strain was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, oxidase- and catalase-positive nocardioform actinomycete.</s><s>Usually the aerial mycelium is white; however, it has a cream colour on Czapek's agar.</s><s>Substrate mycelium is colourless to olive±yellow or red-orange on the different media tested.</s><s>Soluble pigments are yellow-orange to yellow on oatmeal agar or glycerol-nitrate agar.</s><s>Melanin is not produced on peptone-yeast extract-iron agar (ISP 6).</s><s>Aerial hyphae are long and zig-zag shaped at the beginning of sporulation, fragmenting into elongated spore-like structures which subsequently subdivide into short rod-shaped spores of irregular size.</s><s>Spore surface is smooth.</s><s>Long branched substrate hyphae fragment into non-motile elements.</s><s>L-Arabinose, D-fructose, D-glucose, D-galactose, glycerol, melibiose, maltose, mannitol, D-mannose, L-rhamnose, sucrose and D-xylose are used as sole carbon sources for growth; adonitol, dulcitol, <i>i</i>-inositol, lactose, D-ribose and D-sorbose are not.</s><s>Acids are produced from L-arabinose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, glycerol, maltose, D-mannitol, melibiose, L-rhamnose and sucrose, but not from adonitol, dulcitol, <i>i</i>-inositol, lactose, D-ribose, sorbose or D-xylose.</s><s>An alkaline reaction is observed with citrate, formate, fumarate, lactate, malate, malonate, oxalate, propionate, pyruvate, sebacate, succinate and tartrate, but no alkaline reaction occurs with acetate, aconitate, benzoate or salicylate.</s><s>Xanthine, hypoxanthine, calcium oxalate crystals, urea, Tween 40, Tween 60, Tween 80 and Tween 85 are decomposed; casein and tyrosine are not.</s><s>Nitrates are not reduced to nitrites.</s><s>Growth occurs on media supplemented with 10% (w/v) NaCl, 1.5% (v/v) butanol, 2.5% (v/v) methanol and 3% (v/v) ethanol, but no growth occurs at 12% (w/v) NaCl and 50 mg lysozyme ml<sup>−1</sup>.</s><s>Growth occurs at 37 °C but not at 10 °C and 42 °C; optimum growth is at 28-30 °C.</s><s>The major menaquinones are MK-10(H<sub>6</sub>, H<sub>8</sub>).</s><s>Cell wall teichoic acid contains heterogeneous 1,5-poly(ribitol phosphate) chains with lateral glycerol phosphate oligomers.</s><s>The type strain is VKM Ac-1457<sup>T</sup>.</s><s>Isolated from soil in the rhizosphere of <i>Casuarina</i> sp. (Seychelles).</s></p></content></protolog>