<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2772_nm.9760" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9760" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9760" rank="species">Pontibacter actiniarum</organism><reference id="rid.2772"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nedashkovskaya</surname><given-names>O.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shevchenko</surname><given-names>L.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frolova</surname><given-names>G.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>H.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>K.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>H.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mikhailov</surname><given-names>V.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pontibacter actiniarum gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel member of the phylum 'Bacteroidetes', and proposal of Reichenbachiella gen. nov. as a replacement for the illegitimate prokaryotic generic name Reichenbachia Nedashkovskaya et al. 2003.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>2583</fpage><lpage>2588</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63819-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16280531</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pontibacter actiniarum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pontibacter actiniarum</em> (ac.ti.ni.a′rum. N.L. gen. pl. n. <em>actiniarum</em> of sea anemones or related animals).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells range from 0·3 to 0·4 μm in width and from 1·2 to 1·9 μm in length.</s><s>On marine agar, colonies are circular, 2–3 mm diameter, convex, shiny, pink and smooth.</s><s>Does not require Na<sup>+</sup> or sea water for growth.</s><s>Growth occurs at 6–43 °C; optimal temperature is 25–28 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 0–10 % NaCl.</s><s>No pigments of flexirubin type are formed.</s><s>Decomposes agar (weakly), gelatin, DNA and Tweens 20 and 40.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse casein, starch, Tween 80, cellulose (CM-cellulose or filter paper) or chitin.</s><s>Forms acid from aesculin and arbutin (API 50 CH gallery; bioMérieux).</s><s>Does not form acid from l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-lactose, d-maltose, d-melibiose, l-raffinose, l-rhamnose, l-sorbose, d-sucrose, dl-xylose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, glycerol, adonitol, dulcitol, inositol or mannitol.</s><s>Biolog GN2 tests show that the type strain utilizes dextrin, glycogen, methyl pyruvate, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, alaninamide, l-alanine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-proline, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, succinamic acid, l-alanyl-glycine, glycyl-l-aspartic acid and l-threonine.</s><s>Does not utilize <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, l-arabitol, cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-lactose, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melibiose, psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acids, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, glucuronamide, d-alanine, glycyl-l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Indole, H<sub>2</sub>S and acetoin (Voges–Proskauer reaction) production is negative.</s><s>According to the API ZYM gallery (bioMérieux), produces <em>β</em>-galactosidase, acid phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), leucine and valine arylamidases, trypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase but not esterase (C4), lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase or <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are C15 : 1 iso (28·8 %), C17 : 0 iso 3-OH (6·5 %), summed feature 3 (14·7 %; comprising C15 : 0 iso 2-OH and/or C16 : 1<em>ω</em>7) and summed feature 4 (31·3 %; consisting of C17 : 1 iso I and/or C17 : 1 anteiso B).</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin, benzylpenicillin, chloramphenicol, doxycycline, erythromycin, kanamycin, carbenicillin, lincomycin, oleandomycin and tetracycline.</s><s>Resistant to gentamicin, neomycin, polymixin B and streptomycin.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 48·7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KMM 6156<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 12367<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23027<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from unidentified actinians collected in Rudnaya Bay, Pacific Ocean.</s></p></content></protolog>