<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1734_nm.8466" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8466" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8466" rank="species">Anoxybacillus contaminans</organism><reference id="rid.1734"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>De Clerck</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rodríguez-Díaz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vanhoutte</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heyrman</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Anoxybacillus contaminans sp. nov. and Bacillus gelatini sp. nov., isolated from contaminated gelatin batches</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>941</fpage><lpage>946</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02960-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15143046</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Anoxybacillus contaminans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Anoxybacillus contaminans</em> (con.ta′mi.nans. L. part. adj. <em>contaminans</em> contaminating).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are curved or frankly curled, round-ended, Gram-variable (cells from the same colony stained either Gram-positive or Gram-negative), facultatively anaerobic, catalase-positive, oxidase-negative and feebly motile rods that occur singly, in pairs or in short chains.</s><s>Cell diameter is 0·7–1·0 μm; cell length is 4–10 μm.</s><s>Endospores are produced sparsely; they are oval in shape, lie subterminally or terminally and may swell sporangia slightly.</s><s>Colonies grown on TSA at 40 °C are circular with regular margins and raised centres and edges, opaque, glossy and cream-coloured.</s><s>Colony diameter ranges from 1 to 2 mm.</s><s>Maximum temperature for growth lies between 50 and 60 °C; optimum temperature is 50 °C.</s><s>Optimum pH for growth is 7·0; minimum pH for growth lies between 4·0 and 5·0 and maximum lies between 9·0 and 10·0.</s><s>Weak growth occurs in nutrient broth with 5 % NaCl added; no growth occurs at a salt concentration of 10 %.</s><s>Casein is not hydrolysed.</s><s>In the API 20E strip, gelatin is hydrolysed and nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>All strains are negative for <em>o</em>-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside hydrolysis, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase reactions, citrate utilization, hydrogen sulphide production, urease, tryptophan deaminase, indole production and the Voges–Proskauer reaction.</s><s>In the API 50 CH gallery using the CHB suspension medium, hydrolysis of aesculin is weak and small amounts of acid without gas are produced from the following carbohydrates: l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, glycogen, maltose, d-mannose, d-melezitose, methyl d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-raffinose, ribose, starch, sucrose, d-trehalose, d-turanose and d-xylose.</s><s>Production of acid is negative for adonitol, amygdalin, d-arabinose, d- and l-arabitol, arbutin, d-cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, d- and l-fucose, gentiobiose, gluconate, inulin, 2- and 5-keto-d-gluconate, lactose, d-lyxose, mannitol, d-melibiose, <em>meso</em>-inositol, methyl d-mannoside, methyl xyloside, rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, l-sorbose, d-tagatose, l-xylose and xylitol.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (respectively representing about 52, 11 and 12 % of total fatty acids).</s><s>The following fatty acids are present in smaller amounts: C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (respectively representing about 3, 7, 5 and 7 % of total fatty acids).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is LMG 21881<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 15866<sup>T</sup>); the DNA G+C content of this strain is 44·4 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>