<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9934_nm.14906" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14906" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14906" rank="species">Carnobacterium jeotgali</organism><reference id="rid.9934"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>M.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roh</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nam</surname><given-names>Y.-D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>J.-W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Carnobacterium jeotgali sp. nov., isolated from a Korean traditional fermented food</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>3168</fpage><lpage>3171</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.010116-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19643884</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Carnobacterium jeotgali</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Carnobacterium jeotgali</em> (je.ot.ga′li. N.L. gen. n. <em>jeotgali</em> of jeotgal, a traditional Korean fermented seafood).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, non-motile, facultatively anaerobic bacteria.</s><s>Cells are 3.5±0.7 μm long and 0.7–0.8 μm wide, and occur more frequently in chains than as single cells.</s><s>Cells lack flagella.</s><s>Colonies are about 1 mm in diameter, irregular in shape and pale yellow.</s><s>Colony surface is rough.</s><s>Grows at 4–37 °C (optimum 30 °C), at pH 5.5–9.0 (optimum pH 8.5) and in the presence of 0–5 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 2 % NaCl).</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-negative.</s><s>Assimilates erythritol, d-fructose, inositol, d-mannitol and aesculin, but not glycerol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xyloside, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, cellobiose, maltose, d-lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, gluconate or 2,5-ketogluconate.</s><s>In API 20NE and API ZYM tests for enzyme activities, negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, d-glucose fermentation, l-arginine dihydrolase and for hydrolysis of <em>β</em>-galactosidase, gelatin and urea, but positive for hydrolysis of aesculin.</s><s>Positive for acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, but negative for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids are C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> and C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, MS3<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13251<sup>T</sup>=JCM 15539<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from ‘toha jeotgal’, a traditional Korean fermented food.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA of the type strain is 43.9 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>