<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7082_nm.4355" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4355" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4355" rank="species">Syntrophobotulus glycolicus</organism><reference id="rid.7082"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Friedrich</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Springer</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ludwig</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schink</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic positions of Desulfofustis glycolicus gen. nov., sp. nov., and Syntrophobotulus glycolicus gen. nov., sp. nov., two new strict anaerobes growing with glycolic acid.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>1065</fpage><lpage>1069</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-4-1065</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8863436</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Syntrophobotulus glycolicus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Syntrophobotulus glycolicus</i> (gly.co'li.cus. M. L. n. <i>acidum glycolicum</i>, glycolic acid, <i>glycolicus</i>, referring to glycolic acid, the key substrate of this species)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Rod-shaped bacterium, slightly curved, 2.5 to 3.5 by 0.5 μm in size, occurring typically as single cells or in small aggregates.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Oval spores formed in ageing cultures at the cell ends.</s><s>Gram staining is negative, ultrastructural analysis shows gram-positive cell wall architecture.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strictly anaerobic bacteria, growing chemotrophically in pure culture by fermentative oxidation of glyoxylate.</s><s>Glycolate is oxidized in syntrophic coculture with, e.g., <i>Methanospirillum hungatei</i> or <i>Acetobacterium woodii</i> as a partner.</s><s>No other organic or inorganic substrates used.</s><s>Glycolic acid is converted to carbon dioxide and hydrogen in syntrophic culture; glyoxylic acid is fermented in pure culture to carbon dioxide, hydrogen, and glycolic acid.</s><s>Neither sulfate, sulfite, thiosulfate, elemental sulfur, nor nitrate reduced.</s><s>Cells contain menaquinone-7-10, with MK-9 as major fraction.</s><s>No cytochromes present.</s><s>pH range, 6.7 to 8.3; optimum pH, 7.3.</s><s>Temperature range, 15 to 37°C; optimum temperature, 28°C.</s><s>Growth optimal in freshwater medium.</s><s>Growth possible also in brackish-water medium with 110 mM NaCl-5 mM MgCl<sub>2</sub>; no growth in marine medium.</s><s>DNA base ratio, 46.7 ± 0.15 mol% G+C (determined by high-pressure liquid chromatography analysis).</s><s>Habitat, sewage sludge and anoxic freshwater sediments.</s><s>Type strain, FlGlyR (DSM 8271), deposited with the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen.</s></p></content></protolog>