<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3745_nm.10776" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10776" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10776" rank="species">Haloquadratum walsbyi</organism><reference id="rid.3745"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Burns</surname><given-names>D.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Janssen</surname><given-names>P.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Itoh</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kamekura</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jensen</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rodríguez-Valera</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bolhuis</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dyall-Smith</surname><given-names>M.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Haloquadratum walsbyi gen. nov., sp. nov., the square haloarchaeon of Walsby, isolated from saltern crystallizers in Australia and Spain.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>387</fpage><lpage>392</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64690-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17267984</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Haloquadratum walsbyi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Haloquadratum walsbyi</em> (wals′by.i. N.L. gen. masc. n. <em>walsbyi</em> of Walsby, named after A. E. Walsby, who first published observations on this organism).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are square (∼2×2 μm) and flat (0.2 μm thick) and can form large sheets.</s><s>Under suboptimal conditions, such as reduced salinity, they show flat, pleomorphic forms.</s><s>Colonies on agar medium are iridescent pink with an entire edge.</s><s>Strictly aerobic; only oxygen is used as the final electron acceptor.</s><s>Cannot utilize nitrate or DMSO as alternative electron acceptors.</s><s>Does not grow anaerobically on l-arginine.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 6.0–8.5, 25–45 °C and 14–36 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Halophilic; cells lyse immediately in distilled water and a minimum of ∼14 % (w/v) salts is required for growth.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs under neutrophilic to alkaliphilic conditions, above 18 % salinity.</s><s>Capable of growing in defined media, but is severely restricted in the substrates utilized.</s><s>Grows best on pyruvate as sole carbon source.</s><s>No growth enhancement occurs with acetate, alanine, arabinose, arginine, aspartate, benzoate, betaine, butanol, butyrate, cellobiose, citrate, ethanol, formate, fructose, fumarate, galactose, galacturonate, gluconuronate, glucose, glycerol, glycine, glycolate, lactate, lactose, leucine, lysine, malate, malonate, mannitol, mannose, methanol, propanol, propionate, ribose, serine, succinate, sucrose, tartrate, threonine, urea, valine or xylose at 10 mM or cellulose, chitin or starch at 0.1 % (w/v) as the sole carbon and energy source.</s><s>Acid is not produced from carbohydrate utilization.</s><s>Negative for <em>β</em>-galactosidase and indole production.</s><s>Sensitive to anisomycin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, novobiocin, rifampicin, simvastatin and tetracycline and resistant to ampicillin, bacitracin, cycloheximide, kanamycin, mycostatin, neomycin and streptomycin at 50 μg ml<sup>−1</sup>.</s><s>The polar lipids are C<sub>20</sub>C<sub>20</sub> derivatives of PG, PGP-Me and S-DGD-1.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the two known strains is 46.9 mol%.</s><s>Both strains were isolated from solar saltern crystallizer ponds.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is C23<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 12705<sup>T</sup>=DSM 16854<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Strain HBSQ001 (=JCM 12895=DSM 16790) is a reference strain.</s></p></content></protolog>