<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2659_nm.7518" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7518" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7518" rank="species">Planomonospora alba</organism><reference id="rid.2659"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Mertz</surname><given-names>F.P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Planomonospora alba sp. nov. and Planomonospora sphaerica sp. nov., two new species isolated from soil by baiting techniques.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>274</fpage><lpage>281</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Planomonospora alba</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Planomonospora alba</i> (al'ba. L. adj. <i>alba</i>, white, referring to the white aerial hyphae)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, nonmotile, not acid fast, gram positive, filamentous, and differentiated into substrate and aerial hyphae with a diameter of 1.0 μm.</s><s>There is no tendency to fragment.</s><s>The aerial hyphae are white, and the vegetative mycelium is grayish yellow.</s><s>No soluble pigment is produced.</s><s>Aerial hyphae produce sporangiophores bearing long parallel rows of large sporangia which resemble rows of bananas.</s><s>Each sporangium contains a single large cylindrical to obclavate spore which becomes motile after immersion in water for 30 to 60 min.</s><s>The average spore size is 4.4 by 1.5 μm (range, 3.5 to 5.4 by 1.4 to 1.6 μm).</s><s>Utilizes the carbohydrates D-glucose, <i>l</i>-arabinose, cellobiose, dextrin, <i>d</i>-fructose, D-galactose, glycerol, maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, L-rhamnose, starch, sucrose, trehalose, and D-xylose, but not adonitol, D-arabinose, cellulose, dulcitol, ethanol, erythritol, α-methyl-D-glucoside, glycogen, inositol, inulin, lactose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, D-ribose, salicin, D-sorbitol, and L-sorbose.</s><s>Sodium salts of the following organic acids are utilized as sole sources of carbon for energy and growth: acetate, butyrate, lactate, and pyruvate.</s><s>Benzoate, citrate, malate, mucate, oxalate, propionate, succinate, and tartrate are not utilized.</s><s>Hydrolyzes casein and DNA and decomposes L-tyrosine but not adenine, xanthine, calciummalate, esculin, hippurate, or hypoxanthine.</s><s>Produces urease, phosphatase, and gelatinase, survives exposure to 50°C for 8 h, grows at temperatures between 20 and 5O°C, is not able to reduce nitrate, tolerates NaCl only at a concentration of 2%, and is resistant to 2.0 μg of kasugamycin per ml.</s><s>Type III cell wall composition, type B whole-cell sugar pattern, and type PIV phospholipid pattern.</s><s>Mycolic acids are not present.</s><s>The major menaquinone detected is MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>); minor amounts of MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>) are also present.</s><s>Strain A82600<sup>T</sup> differs from other <i>Planomonospora</i> strains in fatty acid composition (Table 3) and in morphological, cultural, and physiological characteristics (Tables 1 and 2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>The type strain is A82600 (= NRRL 18924), which was isolated from soil collected in The Sudan.</s><s>The species description is based on a single strain and thus serves as the type strain description.</s></p></content></protolog>