<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.579_nm.4983" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4983" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4983" rank="species">Bacillus soli</organism><reference id="rid.579"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Heyrman</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vanparys</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Balcaen</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rodríguez-Díaz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Felske</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus novalis sp. nov., Bacillus vireti sp. nov., Bacillus soli sp. nov., Bacillus bataviensis sp. nov. and Bacillus drentensis sp. nov., from the Drentse A grasslands.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>47</fpage><lpage>57</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02723-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14742458</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus soli</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus soli</em> (so′li. L. gen. n. <em>soli</em> of soil).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive or Gram-variable, facultatively anaerobic, motile, round-ended rods (0·6–1·2 μm in diameter), sometimes curved, occurring as single cells, in pairs and in chains.</s><s>Endospores are ellipsoidal, lie paracentrally and may swell the sporangia (Fig. 3c).</s><s>On TSA, colonies are butyrous, cream-coloured, low and slightly umbonate, with entire margins and glossy or eggshell-textured surfaces.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is 30 °C and the maximum growth temperature is between 40 and 45 °C.</s><s>The minimum pH for growth lies between 4·0 and 5·0, the optimum is 7·0–8·0 and the maximum lies between 9·0 and 9·5.</s><s>Casein is hydrolysed.</s><s>In the API 20E strip, gelatin is hydrolysed and nitrate reduction is positive; reactions for ONPG hydrolysis, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, hydrogen sulfide production, urease, tryptophan deaminase, indole production and the Voges–Proskauer test are negative.</s><s>Hydrolysis of aesculin is positive in the API 50CH gallery.</s><s>Acid without gas is produced from the following carbohydrates in the API 50CH gallery, using CHB suspension medium: <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-fructose, d-glucose, glycogen, maltose (weak), d-mannose, ribose (weak), starch and d-trehalose (weak).</s><s>The following reactions are variable between strains and, when positive, are usually weak: galactose and sucrose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from the following carbohydrates: adonitol, amygdalin, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, arbutin, d-cellobiose, dulcitol, erythritol, d-fucose, l-fucose, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, glycerol, inulin, 2-keto-d-gluconate, 5-keto-d-gluconate, lactose, d-lyxose, d-mannitol, d-melezitose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl d-xyloside, raffinose, salicin, sorbitol, l-sorbose, d-tagatose, d-turanose, xylitol, d-xylose and l-xylose.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, respectively present at about 43 and 34 %.</s><s>The following fatty acids are present to at least 1 %: iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> alcohol, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>11<em>c</em>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>10<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>For the strains tested (Table 4), the G+C content is 40·1–40·4 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from soil (Drentse A agricultural research area, The Netherlands).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In the variable reactions listed above, the type strain, LMG 21838<sup>T</sup> (=R-16300<sup>T</sup>=IDA0086<sup>T</sup>=DSM 15604<sup>T</sup>), was positive for galactose (weak) and negative for sucrose.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 40·1 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>