<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2770_nm.843" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.843" rank="genus">Rhodovibrio</organism><reference id="rid.2770"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Petri</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Süling</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of species of the spiral-shaped phototrophic purple non-sulfur bacteria of the alpha-Proteobacteria: description of the new genera Phaeospirillum gen. nov., Rhodovibrio gen. nov., Rhodothalassium gen. nov. and Roseospira gen. nov. as well as transfer of Rhodospirillum fulvum to Phaeospirillum fulvum comb. nov., of Rhodospirillum molischianum to Phaeospirillum molischianum comb. nov., of Rhodospirillum salinarum to Rhodovibrio salexigens.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>793</fpage><lpage>798</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-3-793</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9734033</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhodovibrio</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhodovibrio</i> (Rho.do.vi'bri.o. Gr. n. <i>rhodon</i> the rose; M.L. masc. n. <i>Vibrio</i> a bacterial genus; M.L. masc. n. <i>Rhodovibrio</i> the rose <i>Vibrio</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The genus name <i>Rhodovibrio</i> was proposed by Molisch (1907) for bacteria (<i>Rhodovibrio parvus</i>) later recognized as belonging to <i>Rhodopseudomonas palustris</i>.</s><s>It is not included in the Approved Lists of Bacterial Names and therefore has no standing in nomenclature.</s><s>It is proposed to revive this name for description of bacteria with the following properties.</s><s>Cells are vibrioid- to spiral-shaped, 06-0.9 μm wide, motile by means of polar flagella, multiply by binary fission and are Gram-negative.</s><s>They belong to the α-<i>Proteobacteria</i> and have a G + C content between 65 and 69 mol%.</s><s>In tracytoplasmic photosynthetic membranes are present as vesicles, contain bacteriochlorophyll a and various carotenoids as photosynthetic pigments.</s><s>Contain ubiquinones and menaquinones Q-10 and MK-10 as major components.</s><s>Halophilic bacteria that require NaCl or sea salt for growth.</s><s>Have salt optima above sea water salinity and tolerate up to 20% total salts.</s><s>Growth occurs preferably photo-organotrophically under anoxic conditions in the light, but is also possible under microoxic to oxic conditions in the dark.</s><s>Complex nutrients are required.</s><s>Known species of the genus are <i>Rhodovibrio salinarum</i> and <i>Rhodovibrio sodomensis</i>.</s><s>The type species is <i>Rhodovibrio salinarum</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>