<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6505_nm.9495" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9495" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9495" rank="species">Nocardia elegans</organism><reference id="rid.6505"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yassin</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nocardia elegans sp. nov., a member of the Nocardia vaccinii clade isolated from sputum</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1505</fpage><lpage>1509</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63570-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16014473</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Nocardia elegans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Nocardia elegans</em> (e′le.gans. L. adj. <em>elegans</em> fastidious – with respect to utilization of nutrients).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The hyphae are Gram-positive and partially acid–alcohol-fast.</s><s>Vegetative hyphae are orange in colour, well developed with irregular branches penetrating the agar and bear white aerial hyphae.</s><s>At a late stage of growth the hyphae fragment into rod-shaped elements.</s><s>Grows at temperatures in the range 22–42 °C.</s><s>The organism possesses the salient chemotaxonomic characteristics of the genus <em>Nocardia</em>.</s><s>Its mycolic acids are cleaved, upon pyrolysis, releasing fatty acids C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub> and C<sub>18 : 0</sub> with C<sub>18 : 0</sub> as the major cleavage product.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin, testosterone and urea but not adenine, casein, elastin, gelatin, guanine, hypoxanthine, tyrosine or xanthine.</s><s>Assimilates acetate and glucose as carbon sources, but not adonitol, adipate, iso-amyl alcohol, arabinose, 2,3-butanediol, cellobiose, citrate, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, galactose, gluconate, <em>m</em>-hydroxybenzoate, <em>p</em>-hydroxybenzoate, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactate, lactose, maltose, mannitol, melezitose, 1,2-propanediol, raffinose, rhamnose, sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose or xylose.</s><s>Does not utilize acetamide, arginine, gelatin, ornithine, proline or serine as simultaneous carbon and nitrogen sources.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <em>Nocardia elegans</em> is strain IMMIB N-402<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 50200<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108553<sup>T</sup>).</s></p></content></protolog>