<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11580_nm.18615" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.18615" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.18615" rank="species">Saccharopolyspora gloriosae</organism><reference id="rid.11580"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Qin</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>H.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Klenk</surname><given-names>H.-P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>C.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Saccharopolyspora gloriosae sp. nov., an endophytic actinomycete isolated from the stem of Gloriosa superba L.</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1147</fpage><lpage>1151</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.015792-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19666795</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Saccharopolyspora gloriosae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Saccharopolyspora gloriosae</em> (glo.ri.o′sae. N.L. fem. gen. n. <em>gloriosae</em> of the plant genus <em>Gloriosa</em>, referring to the isolation of the type strain from a stem of <em>Gloriosa superba</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-stain-positive, non-acid–alcohol-fast, non-motile actinomycete that forms extensively branched substrate mycelium.</s><s>Smooth spores are arranged in curved and hooked chains on aerial mycelium.</s><s>Grows well on ISP 2, ISP 3 and ISP 5 media, moderately well on ISP 4, nutrient agar and Czapek's agar, but poorly on potato-glucose agar.</s><s>No diffusible pigment is produced.</s><s>Temperature range for growth is 10–32 °C, with optimum growth at 28 °C.</s><s>Grows at pH 6.0–8.0 and in the presence of 0–11 % NaCl (optimum growth at 0–5 % NaCl).</s><s>Utilizes a variety of organic compounds as sole carbon sources, including adonitol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, erythritol, aesculin, d-fructose, gentiobiose, d-glucose, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, maltose, mannitol, d-mannose, melezitose, l-rhamnose, starch, trehalose and d-xylose.</s><s>Utilizes l-adenine, d-arginine, l-asparagine, l-leucine, l-histidine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-serine and l-threonine as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>Degrades adenine, hypoxanthine, starch, tyrosine and xanthine, but not casein or chitin.</s><s>Negative for oxidase and reduction of nitrate.</s><s>The cell wall contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid as the diagnostic diamino acid.</s><s>Whole-cell hydrolysates contain arabinose, galactose and ribose.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids (&#x003E;10 %) are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and C<sub>17 : 1</sub> <em>cis</em>9.</s><s>The phospholipids comprise phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylmethylethanolamine, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol, phosphatidylinositol mannosides and several unknown phospholipids.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 71.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM 60513<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 19243<sup>T</sup> =CCTCC AA 207006<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a surface-sterilized stem of <em>Gloriosa superba</em> L. collected from the tropical rainforest of Xishuangbanna, Yunnan Province, south-west China.</s></p></content></protolog>