<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.607_nm.8496" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8496" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8496" rank="species">Bacillus fortis</organism><reference id="rid.607"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Scheldeman</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rodríguez-Díaz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goris</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pil</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Clerck</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Herman</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Heyndrickx</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus farraginis sp. nov., Bacillus fortis sp. nov. and Bacillus fordii sp. nov., isolated at dairy farms</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1355</fpage><lpage>1364</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63095-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15280314</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus fortis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus fortis</em> (for′tis. L. adj. <em>fortis</em> strong, referring to the fact that the strains were isolated after heat treatment for 30 min at 100 °C).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight, round-ended, motile, strictly aerobic, Gram-negative rods, occurring singly or in pairs.</s><s>Cell diameter is 0·6–0·8 μm and length 1·0–3·5 μm.</s><s>Spores are oval and occur centrally or paracentrally in slightly swollen sporangia.</s><s>Colonies grown on nutrient agar at 30 °C for 3 days are cream coloured, raised with entire margins and smooth, glossy surfaces.</s><s>Their maximum diameter is 1 mm.</s><s>Good growth occurs at 30 and 45 °C and weak growth occurs at 20 °C.</s><s>Growth does not occur at pH 9 or 5.</s><s>Growth is not inhibited by 7 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Hydrolysis of starch and casein is not observed within 7 days of incubation at 30 °C, and growth on casein agar is poor or negative.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase are positive.</s><s>All strains are unreactive in the API 20E and API 50CHB test kits.</s><s>In the Biotype100 kit using the Biotype 2 medium, strains use l-tryptophan and l-histidine as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Most strains (&#x003E;50 %) use the following substrates as sole carbon sources: 4-aminobutyrate, 5-aminovalerate, aesculin, ethanolamine, glutarate, hydroxyquinoline <em>β</em>-glucuronide, 2-oxoglutarate, dl-lactate, malonate, phenylacetate, l-proline, putrescine, d-ribose and l-tyrosine.</s><s>Some strains (&#x003C;50 %) use the following substrates: citrate, erythritol, d-gluconate, d-glucosamine, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, l-glutamate, dl-glycerate, histamine, <em>m</em>-hydroxybenzoate, 2- and 5-keto-d-gluconate, l- and d-malate, <em>α</em>-d-melibiose, protocatechuate, l-sorbose and l-tartrate.</s><s>Only the type strain uses d-glucuronate and no strain utilizes the following substrates as sole carbon sources: <em>trans</em>- and <em>cis</em>-aconitate, adonitol, d- and l-alanine, l-arabinose, d- and l-arabitol, l-aspartate, betaine, benzoate, caprate, caprylate, d-cellobiose, <em>m</em>-coumarate, dulcitol, <em>β</em>-d-fructose, <em>α</em>-l-fucose, fumarate, d-galactose, d-galacturonate, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, gentisate, glycerol, <em>p</em>-hydroxybenzoate, 3-hydroxybutyrate, <em>myo</em>-inositol, itaconate, <em>α</em>-lactose, lactulose, d-lyxose, maltitol, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melezitose, methyl <em>α</em>-galactopyranoside, methyl <em>β</em>-galactopyranoside, 3-methyl d-glucopyranose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, mucate, <em>N</em>-acetyl d-glucosamine, palatinose, 3-phenylpropionate, propionate, quinate, d-raffinose, <em>α</em>-l-rhamnose, d-saccharate, sucrose, l-serine, d-sorbitol, succinate, d-tagatose, d- and <em>meso</em>-tartrate, d-trehalose, tricarballylate, trigonelline, tryptamine, d-turanose, xylitol and d-xylose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is R-6514<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 22079<sup>T</sup>=DSM 16012<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Where results are variable, the type strain uses the following substrates: aesculin, d-gluconate, d-glucosamine, d-glucuronate, dl-glycerate, hydroxyquinoline-<em>β</em>-glucuronide, 2-oxoglutarate, 2- and 5-keto-d-gluconate, dl-lactate, malonate, phenylacetate, protocatechuate, l-tartrate and l-tyrosine.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids (&#x003E;5 % of total cellular fatty acids) are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 44·3 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>