<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2574_nm.11516" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11516" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11516" rank="species">Brachybacterium phenoliresistens</organism><reference id="rid.2574"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>K.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sheu</surname><given-names>S.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wei</surname><given-names>Y.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Brachybacterium phenoliresistens sp. nov., isolated from oil-contaminated coastal sand.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2674</fpage><lpage>2679</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65019-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17978239</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Brachybacterium phenoliresistens</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Brachybacterium phenoliresistens</em> (phe.nol.i.res.ist.ens. N.L. neut. n. <em>phenol</em> phenol; L. part. adj. <em>resistens</em> resisting; N.L. part. adj. <em>phenoliresistens</em> phenol resisting, referring to the organism's ability to resist phenol).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are small, coccoid to ovoid shaped, 0.8–1.3 μm in diameter.</s><s>Cells occur singly, in pairs or as agglomerates.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic, Gram-positive (Gram staining and KOH test), non-motile and non-spore-forming.</s><s>Colonies on marine 2216 agar are pale yellow, circular and convex in shape with entire edges.</s><s>Colonies are approximately 0.9–2.1 mm in diameter on marine 2216 agar after 48 h incubation at 28 °C.</s><s>No accumulation of poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate granules is observed.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are present.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs aerobically, while only moderate anaerobic growth is observed.</s><s>Good growth occurs at temperatures of 4–40 °C, 0.5–7.0 % NaCl and pH 5–10.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 28–35 °C, 2–3 % NaCl and pH 7.0.</s><s>Acid is produced from arabinose, fructose, mannose, raffinose, rhamnose, sucrose, xylose, cellobiose, galactose, glucose, lactose and trehalose, but not from ribose or sorbitol.</s><s>Positive for catalase, DNase, and hydrolysis of starch and Tween 20.</s><s>Weakly positive for hydrolysis of casein and Tween 40.</s><s>Negative for oxidase, nitrate reduction, nitrite reduction, lipase (corn oil) and hydrolysis of Tweens 60 and 80.</s><s>In the API Coryne system, positive for hydrolysis of pyrazinamidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and aesculin and acid production from d-glucose, d-xylose, d-mannitol, maltose, d-lactose and sucrose.</s><s>Negative for nitrate reduction, urease, gelatin hydrolysis and acid production from d-ribose and glycogen.</s><s>With the API 20E system, positive for ONPG test, acetoin production and acid production from glucose, mannitol, inositol, rhamnose, sucrose, amygdalin and arabinose, but negative for nitrate reduction, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, H<sub>2</sub>S production, urease, tryptophan deaminase, indole production, gelatinase and acid production from sorbitol and melibiose.</s><s>Positive enzyme reactions (API ZYM) for alkaline phosphatase, C4 esterase, C8 lipase, leucine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase, weak positive reactions for C14 lipase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, but negative reactions for trypsin and <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin.</s><s>The following carbon substrates (Biolog GP2) are oxidized: <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, arbutin, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melezitose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, palatinose, d-psicose, d-raffinose, salicin, d-sorbitol, stachyose, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, pyruvic acid methyl ester, glycerol, adenosine and 2′-deoxyadenosine.</s><s>Unable to oxidize <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, inulin, mannan, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-mannosamine, amygdalin, l-fucose, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, 3-methyl d-glucose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sedoheptulosan, d-tagatose, d-xylose, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, lactamide, d-lactic acid methyl ester, l-lactic acid, d-malic acid, l-malic acid, succinic acid monomethyl ester, propionic acid, pyruvic acid, succinamic acid, succinic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, inosine, thymidine, uridine, adenosine, uridine 5′-monophosphate, d-fructose 6-phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate, d-glucose 6-phosphate or dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin, gentamicin, nalidixic acid and tetracycline, but sensitive to chloramphenicol, erythromycin, kanamycin, novobiocin, penicillin G, rifampicin and streptomycin.</s><s>The diagnostic cell-wall diamino acid is <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid and the peptidoglycan type is variation A4<em>γ</em> containing amino acids <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid, alanine, glycine, aspartic acid and glutamic acid.</s><s>The polar lipid profile consists of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, three unknown glycolipids and one unknown phospholipid.</s><s>The predominant fatty acid is anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> with significant amounts of iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-7.</s><s>DNA G+C content is 70.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, phenol-A<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 23707<sup>T</sup>=BCRC 17589<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from oil-contaminated coastal sand, Pingtung County, Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>