<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8324_nm.13437" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13437" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13437" rank="species">Microbacterium kribbense</organism><reference id="rid.8324"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dastager</surname><given-names>S.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ju</surname><given-names>Y.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>C.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Microbacterium kribbense sp. nov., isolated from soil.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2536</fpage><lpage>2540</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.2008/001222-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18984689</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Microbacterium kribbense</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Microbacterium kribbense</em> (krib.ben′se. N.L. neut. adj. <em>kribbense</em> arbitrary adjective formed from the acronym of the Korea Research Institute of Bioscience and Biotechnology, KRIBB, where the taxonomic studies on the type strain were performed).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-positive, non-motile, catalase-negative and aerobic.</s><s>Colonies are pale to lemon yellow in colour.</s><s>Cells are irregular rods, 0.4–0.6×0.5–0.8 μm in size.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 7–11 and 20–37 °C; optimal growth occurs at pH 7.2–7.4 and 28 °C.</s><s>NaCl is tolerated at concentrations up to 3 %.</s><s>Arabinose, galactose, glucose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, sucrose and trehalose are assimilated, but ribose, fructose and xylose are not.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Aesculin, starch and Tween 80 are hydrolysed, but cellulose, gelatin and urea are not.</s><s>Esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase are detected with the API ZYM enzyme assay; alkaline phosphatase, lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase are negative.</s><s>The diagnostic diamino acid isomer of the peptidoglycan is l-lysine.</s><s>The acyl type of the peptidoglycan is <em>N</em>-glycolyl.</s><s>The predominant menaquinones are MK-11 and MK-12.</s><s>The main polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>Whole-cell hydrolysate contains ribose, galactose, glucose and xylose.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 71.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, MSL-04<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 19269<sup>T</sup> =DSM 19265<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil sample collected from Bigeum Island, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>