<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.21_nm.8258" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8258" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8258" rank="species">Flexibacter maritimus</organism><reference id="rid.21"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bernardet</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Deoxyribonucleic acid relatedness and phenotypic characterization of Flexibacter columnaris sp. nov., nom. rev., Flexibacter psychrophilus sp. nov., nom rev., and Flexibacter maritimus Wakabayashi, Hikida, and Masumura 1986.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>346</fpage><lpage>354</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-3-346</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Addendum to the description of <i>Flexibacter maritimus</i>.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>In addition to the original description (32), the characteristics given below may be useful in identification. <i>o</i>-Nitrophenyl-β-D-galactopyranoside is not hydrolyzed. Agar is not hydrolyzed. No acid is produced from carbohydrates in ammonium salt-sugar medium (API 50CH galleries). A brown color is produced on tyrosine agar. Lecithin (egg yolk), Tween 20, and Tween 80 are hydrolyzed. Weak, slow DNA hydrolysis. No inhibition zone is formed around the following types of disks (the concentration in each type of disk is indicated in parentheses): gentamicin (15 μg), neomycin (30 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), streptomycin (10 IU), polymyxin B (30 μg), actinomycin D (2.5 μg), and nalidixic acid (30 μg). Susceptible (inhibition zone, more than 9 mm) to vibriostatic compound 0/129, ampicillin (10 μg), cephalothin (30 μg), tetracycline (30 IU), chloramphenicol (30 μg), erythromycin (15 IU), novobiocin (30 IU), sulfonamides (200 μg), trimethoprim (5 μg), and nitrofurans (300 μg). The following substrates are hydrolyzed (API ZYM galleries): 2-naphthylphosphate (at pH 8.5 and 5.4), 2-naphthyl-butyrate, 2-naphthyl-caprylate, L-leucyl-2-naphthylamide, L-valyl-2-naphthylamide, L-cystyl-2-naphthylamide, N-benzoyl-DL-arginine-2-naphthylamide, N-glutaryl-phenylalanine-2-naphthylamide, and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphate. Does not hydrolyze the following substrates (API ZYM galleries): 2-naphthyl-myristate, 6-Br-2-naphthyl-α-D-galactopyranoside, and, 2-naphthyl-β-D-galactopyranoside, naphthol-AS-BI-β-D-glucuronide, 2-naphthyl-α-D-glucopyranoside, 6-Br-2-naphthyl-β-D-glucopyranoside, 1-naphthyl-N-acetyl-β-D-glucosaminide, 6-Br-2-naphthyl-α-D-mannopyranoside, and 2-naphthyl-α-L-fucopyranoside.</s></p></content></protolog>