<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3832_nm.6720" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6720" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6720" rank="species">Amycolatopsis methanolica</organism><reference id="rid.3832"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>de Boer</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dijkhuizen</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grobben</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goodfellow</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Parlett</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Whitehead</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Witt</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Amycolatopsis methanolica sp. nov., a facultatively methylotrophic actinomycete.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>194</fpage><lpage>204</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-2-194</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2223611</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Amycolatopsis methanolica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Amycolatopsis methanolica</i> (me.tha’noli.ca. M. L. n. <i>methanolicum</i>, methanol; M. L. fem. adj. <i>methanolica</i>, relating to methanol)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Yellow vegetative growth cames abundant white aerial hyphae.</s><s>Long chains of smooth, squarish spores (0.4 by 0.6 to 0.8 μm) in straight-to-flexuous chains formed on aerial hyphae when the organism is grown on Czapeck Dox agar.</s><s>The spores are covered by a wall 0.04 to 0.06 μm thick.</s><s>The chemical properties of the organism are described above, and many of the biochemical, degradative, enzymatic,enzymatic, nutritional, physiological, and tolerance features are given in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acid is formed from adonitol, L-arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, galactose, glucose, glycerol, mannose, rhamnose, ribose, salicin, sorbitol, trehalose, and xylose but not from dulcitol, erythritol, inositol, lactose, maltose, melibiose, raffinose, or sucrose.</s><s>The organism, which is sensitive to lysozyme, decarboxylates acetic, benzoic, fumaric, α-ketoglutaric, lactic, malic, propionic, pyruvic, and succinic acids but not citric, formic, oxalic, or gluconic acid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth occurs in mineral medium broth containing dimethylamine, trimethylamine, ethylamine, methanol, ethanol, 1-propanol, 1-butanol, 2,3-butanediol, acetone, betaine, choline, sarcosine, pectin, benzoic acid methylester, benzylamine, 3- and 4-hydroxybenzoates, 3,4-dihydroxybenzoate, phenylacetate, phenylacetaldehyde, phenyllactate, phenylpyruvate, 4-hydroxyphenylacetate, 4-hydroxyphenylpyruvate, D-phenylalanine, gentisate, and homogentisate as sole sources of carbon but not in methylamine, ethanolamine, propylamine, butylamine, methane, hexane, putrescine, benzene, toluene, or phenol; very sparse growth occurs in formaldehyde.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from a soil sample from New Guinea.</s><s>Type strain: <i>Amycolatopsis methanolica</i> NCIB 11946.</s></p></content></protolog>