<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5672_nm.1562" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1562" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1562" rank="species">Prosthecomicrobium hirschii</organism><reference id="rid.5672"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Staley</surname><given-names>J.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Prosthecomicrobium hirschii, a new species in a redefined genus.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>304</fpage><lpage>308</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-3-304</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Prosthecomicrobium hirschii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Prosthecomicrobium hirschii</i> (hirsch'i.i. N.L. gen. <i>hirschii</i> named in honor of Peter Hirsch, an indefatigable general microbiologist who has contributed greatly to our understanding of budding bacteria)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strains are unicellular, gram-negative bacteria having numerous prosthecae.</s><s>The prosthecae may be short (i.e., less than 1 μm long) or long (i.e., more than 2 μm long).</s><s>Cells are coccobacillary and measure about 0.8 to 1.2 by 1.0 to 2.0 μm.</s><s>Cells reproduce by budding from one pole of a mother cell.</s><s>Daughter buds may mature to form either large or short prosthecae or both, regardless of the appendage length of the mother cell.</s><s>Cells may be motile by single polar to subpolar flagella.</s><s>Gas vacuoles have not been detected.</s><s>Sugars and organic acids are used as carbon sources for growth.</s><s>In addition, methanol and ethanol can be used as carbon sources.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase positive.</s><s>Biotin, nicotinic acid, pantothenate, and thiamine are required for growth.</s><s>Strains are mesophilic and have been isolated from freshwater habitats.</s><s>Colonies are circular in form and umbonate in elevation, have entire margins, and are pink in color.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content ranges from 67.9 to 69.9 mol% (buoyant density method).</s><s>The type strain is strain 16 (ATCC 27832).</s></p></content></protolog>