<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2832_nm.7950" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7950" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7950" rank="species">Bacteroides forsythus</organism><reference id="rid.2832"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tanner</surname><given-names>A.C.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Listgarten</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ebersole</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Strzempko</surname><given-names>M.N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacteroides forsythus sp. nov., a slow-growing, fusiform Bacteroides sp. from the human oral cavity.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>213</fpage><lpage>221</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-36-2-213</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacteroides forsythus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacteroides forsythus</i> (for.sy'thus. N. L. n. <i>forsythus</i> referring to the Forsyth Dental Center, where the species was first isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram negative, fusiform with pointed ends (Fig. 4 and 5 ) , and 0.30 to 0.50 μm in diameter (mean 5 standard deviation, 0.40 ± 0.05 μm).</s><s>The cell length varies between 1 and 30 μm (average, 5 μm).</s><s>Filaments (Fig. 6), cells with central swellings that are up to 3 μm in diameter (Fig. 7), and spheres are frequently observed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are nonmotile and have no flagella.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell wall structure.</s><s>The outer membrane consists of an outer layer which is approximately 4 nm thick and is separated by a 2-nm electron-lucent space from an inner layer that is 1 nm thick (Fig. 8 and 9).</s><s>The inner membrane consists of two electron-dense layers, each approximately 2 nm wide, with a 2-nm intervening electron-lucent layer.</s><s>The inner and outer membranes are separated by a moderately electron-dense zone that is about 16 nm wide, which appears to lack a distinct peptidoglycan layer.</s><s>A regularly structured external layer which surrounds the outer membrane consists of subunits, which in some cross-sections resemble adjacent arches that are 10 nm wide and 10 nm high.</s><s>These subunits are separated from the outer membrane by a 12-nm electronlucent zone.</s><s>Electron-dense radial connections appear to extend from the subunits to the outer surface of the outer membrane.</s><s>Negative staining of tangential sections through the cell periphery indicates that the subunits in the outer most layer are packed in an orthogonal array (Fig. 10 and 11).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies.</s><s>Colonies on Trypticase soy blood agar plates after 7 to 10 days are pale pink, speckled, and 1 to 2 mm diameter on primary isolation and when they are growing well (Fig. 12).</s><s>Colonies of poorly growing cultures are &#x003C;0.5 mm in diameter.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultural characteristics.</s><s>These organisms are strict anaerobes and require CO<sub>2</sub> and H<sub>2</sub> in the atmosphere for growth on agar surfaces (preliminary experiments have revealed no growth on agar under 100% N<sub>2</sub>; 90% N<sub>2</sub>-10% CO<sub>2</sub>; or 90% N<sub>2</sub>-10% H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>To produce visible growth on agar plates, cultures require 4 to 6 days.</s><s>Complex media are required for growth.</s><s>Whole blood (e.g., 5% sheep blood) is required for optimal growth on agar.</s><s>Strains grow on Levinthal agar.</s><s>Growth on agar plates is stimulated by the presence of <i>F. nucleatum</i> (and strains of <i>Streptococcus sanguis</i>, <i>B. fragilis</i>, <i>Wolinella recta</i>, <i>Bacteroides intermedius</i>, and <i>Veillonella parvula</i> [unpublished data] in a satellite pattern.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Visible growth is produced in mycoplasma broth containing glucose (0.5%), sodium acetate (4 mg/ml), sodium sulfite (10 μg/ml), sodium succinate (100 μg/ml), L-cysteine (0.5 μg/ml), and hemin (3 mg/liter) (unpublished data; S.</s><s>S.</s><s>Socransky , personal communication).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultures also grow in Trypticase soy or mycoplasma broth supplemented with 8 to 12% gelatin and in biphasic cultures (10 ml of Trypticase soy agar in the solid phase and ≤5 ml of Trypticase soy or mycoplasma broth in the liquid phase), suggesting that agar or gelatin may be a detoxifying agent.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical characteristics: API ZYM and API An-Ident eactions.</s><s>Strains are positive in both API ZYM and API An-Ident tests for α-fucosidase, β-glucosidase, α-glucuronidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, and α-galactosidase activities.</s><s>In addition, the strains are positive in API ZYM tests for trypsin and β-galactosidase activities and in API An-Ident tests for α-arabinosidase, phosphatase, indoxylacetate, and arginine, alanine, histidine, and phenylalanine aminopeptidase activities (18).</s><s>The API ZYM and API An-Ident enzymatic substrate tests are the only biochemical tests in which <i>B. forsythus</i> consistently demonstrates clear positive reactions.</s><s>Strains do not react in the API 20A or API 20E test series.</s><s>There is no detectable pH decrease in media supplemented with carbohydrates.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Esculin is hydrolyzed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Serologic reactions.</s><s>The strains of <i>B. forsythus</i> isolated from seven different humans are members of a single serogroup and have no antigenic relationship to <i>F. nucleatum</i> FDC 364 or <i>Capnocytophaga sputigena</i> ATCC 33612<sup>T</sup>, which are morphologically similar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>PAGE of soluble cellular proteins. <i>B. forsythus</i> is characterized by two major protein bands at molecular weights of more than 205,000 (Fig. 1 and 2).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from human periodontal pockets.</s></p><p class="description"><s>G+C content, 46 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain FDC 338 (= ATCC 43037).</s></p></content></protolog>