<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8377_nm.13762" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13762" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13762" rank="species">Pseudogulbenkiania subflava</organism><reference id="rid.8377"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudogulbenkiania subflava gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from a cold spring.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2384</fpage><lpage>2388</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65755-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18842860</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudogulbenkiania subflava</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudogulbenkiania subflava</em> (sub.fla′va. L. fem. adj. <em>subflava</em> yellowish).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Accumulation of poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate is observed.</s><s>After 48 h growth on R2A agar at 25 °C, mean cell size is about 0.2–0.5 μm (width) by 1.0–1.6 μm (length).</s><s>Colonies are round, entire, convex and pale-yellow-pigmented.</s><s>Colonies are approximately 0.8–1.0 mm in diameter on R2A agar after 48 h incubation at 25 °C.</s><s>Grows at 15, 25, 30, 37 and 42 °C, in the presence of 0–1 % NaCl and at pH 6–8.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 25–35 °C, with 0 % NaCl and at pH 7–8.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 63.2 mol%.</s><s>Additional phenotypic properties are given in Table 2.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon sources in the Biolog GN2 test system: Tween 80, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, formic acid, d-gluconic acid, dl-lactic acid, quinic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, l-alanine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-proline, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid and urocanic acid.</s><s>Unable to oxidize <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tween 40, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, xylitol, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate, or d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Sensitive to tetracycline, kanamycin, rifampicin, gentamicin, penicillin G, chloramphenicol, nalidixic acid, novobiocin, streptomycin, ampicillin and sulfamethoxazole plus trimethoprim.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, BP-5<sup>T</sup> (=BCRC 17727<sup>T</sup> =LMG 24211<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a cold spring from northern Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>