<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2990_nm.3157" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3157" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3157" rank="species">Enterobacter gergoviae</organism><reference id="rid.2990"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brenner</surname><given-names>D.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Richard</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Steigerwalt</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Asbury</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mandel</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Enterobacter gergoviae sp. nov.: A new species of Enterobacteriaceae found in clinical specimens and the environment.</article-title><year>1980</year><volume>30</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>6</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-30-1-1</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Enterobacter gergoviae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Enterobacter gergoviae</i> (indicates that the type strain was isolated from samples taken during a urinary infection outbreak in Clermont-Ferrand University Hospital near Gergovie Highland in France. The suggested pronunciation is ger (rhymes with her) gó vee ē.)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical tests.</s><s>The biochemical reactions of 81 strains of <i>E. gergoviae</i> are presented in Table 2.</s><s>Thus far, test results have shown these organisms to be homogenous biochemically.</s><s>The only test in which 90% or more of the strains failed to give a similar (+ or -) reaction within 48 h was acid from lactose.</s><s>In this test, 58% of the strains were positive within 48 h, and an additional 40% gave delayed positive reactions (3 to 7 days).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>E. gergoviae</i> is a gram-negative, oxidase-negative, nitrate-positive, fermentative, rod-shaped organism that is peritrichous when motile.</s><s>As such, it conforms to the definition of <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The biochemical profile of <i>E. gergoviae</i> is most similar to those of Enterobacter species. <i>E. gergoviae</i> is perhaps most similar to <i>E. aerogenes</i>, but these two species can be separated by their reactions in tests for KCN, sorbitol, mucate, and urease (Table 3).</s><s>The tests of use in differentiating <i>E. gergoviae</i> from other species of <i>Enterobacter</i>, <i>Klebsiella pneumoniae</i>, and <i>Hafnia alvei</i> (<i>Enterobacter hafniae</i>) are shown in Table 3.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Antibiotic susceptibility.</s><s>Susceptibility of 25 strains to antibiotics was determined by the disk method of Bauer et al. (1).</s><s>All strains were resistant to penicillin (Table 4).</s><s>Most strains were susceptible to the other antibiotics tested.</s><s>Multiple resistance was found in six strains.</s><s>A strain isolated in France was resistant to penicillin, ampicillin, and cephalothin.</s><s>In addition to being resistant to penicillin, one strain isolated in the United States was resistant to cephalothin, and one was resistant to nalidixic acid.</s><s>Three strains isolated from an outbreak in France (8) were resistant to penicillin, nalidixic acid, and cephalothin.</s><s>Two of these were also resistant to sulfadiazine, kanamycin, and chloramphenicol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>G+C content and DNA hybridization.</s><s>Buoyant density ultracentrifugation in CsCl was used to determine the G+C content of DNA from <i>E. gergoviae</i> strains 76.01 (604-77) and 11/76 (608-77).</s><s>The buoyant density of both strains was 1.719 g/cm<sup>3</sup>, which corresponds to 60 mol% G+C.</s></p><p class="description"><s><sup>32</sup>PO<sub>4</sub>-labeled DNA from <i>E. gergoviae</i> strain 76.01 was used in DNA hybridization experiments.</s><s>DNAs from 10 strains of <i>E. gergoviae</i> were tested for relatedness with the labeled DNA (Table 5 ) .</s><s>In 60°C reactions, <i>E. gergoviae</i> strains were at least 75% related (75 to 97%).</s><s>The thermal stability of DNA duplexes formed in homologous <i>E. gergoviae</i> 76.01 reactions at 60°C was approximately 94°C.</s><s>The average thermal stability of heterologous <i>E. gergoviae</i> DNA duplexes was only 1°C lower than that of homologous duplexes.</s><s>Thus, almost no divergence has occurred in DNA sequences held in common between strains of <i>E. gergoviae</i>.</s><s>The 60°C incubation temperature is close to optimal for DNA reassociation.</s><s>When DNA is hydridized at 75°C, only closely related DNA sequences can reassociate.</s><s>On the basis of the very low percentage of divergence of related <i>E. gergoviae</i> DNA in 60°C reactions, one would predict that almost all of these duplexes would be stable at 75°C.</s><s>This is indeed the case (Table 5).</s><s>Thus, biochemical homogeneity in <i>E. gergoviae</i> is reflected by a high level of genetic relatedness in strains from France, Africa, and several states in the United States.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>E. gergoviae</i> is most similar biochemically to the genus <i>Enterobacter</i>.</s><s>DNA relatedness of <i>E. gergoviae</i> to members of <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> is highest with <i>E. gergoviae</i>, <i>E. cloacae</i>, two of the hybridization groups in <i>E. agglomerans</i>, and klebsiellae (35 to 40%). <i>E. gergoviae</i> is 7 to 15% related to <i>Hafnia</i>, <i>Yersinia</i>, and protei, and 20 to 30% related to other genera.</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>E. gergoviae</i> is distinct both biochemically and genetically from the presently described species of <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i>.</s><s>The G+C value of 60 mol% is compatible with findings for species of <i>Serratia</i>, <i>Klebsiella</i>, and <i>Enterobacter</i>. <i>E. gergoviae</i> is closest genetically to <i>Enterobacter</i> and <i>Klebsiella</i>.</s><s>Biochemically it is closest to <i>Enterobacter</i> on the basis of its motility and positive reaction for ornithine decarboxylase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The name <i>Enterobacter gergoviae</i> sp. nov. is proposed for this organism.</s><s>The specific epithet <i>gergoviae</i> indicates that the type strain was isolated from samples taken during a urinary infection outbreak in Clermont-Ferrand University Hospital near Gergovie Highland in France.</s><s>The suggested pronunciation is ger (rhymes with her) gó vee ē.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain CIP 76.01 (= ATCC 33028 = CDC 604-77) is the type strain of the species.</s><s>The clinical significance of <i>E. gergoviae</i> is not yet known.</s><s>Some 80 sporadic isolates have been identified in our laboratories since 1976, and the organism has been implicated in a nosocomial outbreak of urinary tract disease (8).</s><s>This already relatively large number of isolates will undoubtedly increase as laboratories become familiar with the characteristics of <i>E. gergoviae</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>