<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10577_nm.17826" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17826" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.17826" rank="species">Umboniibacter marinipuniceus</organism><reference id="rid.10577"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Romanenko</surname><given-names>L.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tanaka</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frolova</surname><given-names>G.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Umboniibacter marinipuniceus gen. nov., sp. nov., a marine gammaproteobacterium isolated from the mollusc Umbonium costatum from the Sea of Japan</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>603</fpage><lpage>609</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.010728-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19654350</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Umboniibacter marinipuniceus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Umboniibacter marinipuniceus</em> (ma.ri.ni.pu.ni′ce.us. L. masc. adj. <em>marinus</em> marine; L. masc. adj. <em>puniceus</em> purple, red; N.L. masc. adj. <em>marinipuniceus</em> marine and red).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the properties given in the genus description, the species is characterized as follows.</s><s>Cells are 0.4–0.6 μm in diameter and 1.5–2.5 μm long.</s><s>Non-motile.</s><s>Colonies on MA are faint pink–reddish pigmented, transparent, smooth and shiny with regular edges, 2–3 mm in diameter.</s><s>Abundant growth is observed on/in MA or MB supplemented with casein hydrolysate and media containing natural or artificial seawater supplemented with 0.5 % (w/v) peptone, tryptone or meat hydrolysate.</s><s>No growth on basal medium supplemented with 0.1 % glycerol, 0.1 % potassium acetate and 0.1 % potassium succinate or on basal medium when sodium salts are replaced by equimolar amounts of potassium salts.</s><s>Weak growth when d-glucose or a mixture of amino acids (l-alanine, l-asparagine, l-arginine, l-phenylalanine, l-lysine, l-leucine, l-valine and l-histidine) is added.</s><s>No growth on TSA, nutrient agar or R2A.</s><s>Requires NaCl for growth; growth occurs at 2–5 % NaCl (w/v) (optimum 2.5–3 %).</s><s>Weak growth in 2 and 5 % NaCl.</s><s>Grows well in/on peptone medium containing NaCl alone without addition of any of the components of sea salts (MgCl<sub>2</sub>, KCl, CaCl<sub>2</sub>, NaNO<sub>3</sub>, K<sub>2</sub>HPO<sub>4</sub>, KCl, NaSO<sub>4</sub>, NaHCO<sub>3</sub>, NaF or FeSO<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>Psychrotolerant; temperature range for growth is 5–33 °C with optimum growth at 25–28 °C.</s><s>Weak or no growth at 4 °C, slow growth at 5 °C and no growth above 33 °C.</s><s>Grows at pH 6.5–10.0, with optimum growth at pH 8.0–8.5.</s><s>Negative for H<sub>2</sub>S production.</s><s>Positive for hydrolysis of gelatin and Tweens 20, 40 and 80.</s><s>Casein is hydrolysed within 3–5 days.</s><s>Starch is hydrolysed weakly; clearance zones around bacterial spots on starch-containing agar are barely visible.</s><s>Does not degrade CM-cellulose, agar, chitin or DNA.</s><s>On l-tyrosine-containing medium, does not produce melanin-like pigments and/or clearance zones.</s><s>Strain-dependent weak acid production is observed from d-glucose and maltose; the type strain is positive for d-glucose and negative for maltose.</s><s>No acid formed from sucrose, lactose, d-galactose, d-mannose, cellobiose, d-xylose, l-arabinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol or d-mannitol.</s><s>In API 20NE tests, positive for gelatin hydrolysis and the PNPG test and negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose acidification, arginine dihydrolase, urease production, aesculin hydrolysis and assimilation of substrates that are included in the API 20NE strip.</s><s>Weak growth on d-glucose, maltose, sucrose, d-mannitol, citrate, l-alanine, l-asparagine, l-arginine, l-phenylalanine, l-valine and l-lysine in routine tests.</s><s>No growth on d-xylose, d-galactose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, lactose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-mannose, cellobiose, glycerol, acetate, glutamic acid or dl-methionine.</s><s>In API ZYM tests, positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and negative for lipase (C14), trypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Detailed fatty acid profiles are given in the text; major fatty acids are as given in the genus description.</s><s>The pigments are characterized by absorption peaks at 390 and 455 nm with a shoulder at 427 nm for strain KMM 3891<sup>T</sup> and an absorption peak at 407 nm only for strain KMM 3892.</s><s>Susceptible to (per disc) kanamycin (30 μg), nalidixic acid (30 μg), neomycin (30 μg), ofloxacin (5 μg), polymyxin (300 U), erythromycin (15 μg) and chloramphenicol (30 μg) and resistant to benzylpenicillin (10 U), carbenicillin (100 μg), oxacillin (10 μg), tetracycline (30 μg), cephazolin (30 μg) and cephalexin (30 μg).</s><s>Susceptibility to ampicillin (10 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), lincomycin (15 μg), oleandomycin (15 μg), rifampicin (5 μg) and streptomycin (30 μg) is strain-dependent: KMM 3891<sup>T</sup> is susceptible and KMM 3892 is resistant.</s><s>Strain KMM 3892 is susceptible to vancomycin (30 μg), whereas KMM 3891<sup>T</sup> is resistant.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, KMM 3891<sup>T</sup> (=NRIC 0753<sup>T</sup> =JCM 15738<sup>T</sup>), and reference strain KMM 3892 were isolated from the marine mollusc <em>Umbonium costatum</em> (Gastropoda, Trochidae), collected from the southern coast of the Sea of Japan, Russia.</s></p></content></protolog>