<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2747_nm.9862" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9862" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9862" rank="species">Stenothermobacter spongiae</organism><reference id="rid.2747"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lau</surname><given-names>S.C.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tsoi</surname><given-names>M.M.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Plakhotnikova</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dobretsov</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wong</surname><given-names>P.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pawlik</surname><given-names>J.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Qian</surname><given-names>P.Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Stenothermobacter spongiae gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel member of the family Flavobacteriaceae isolated from a marine sponge in the Bahamas, and emended description of Nonlabens tegetincola</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>181</fpage><lpage>185</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63908-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16403884</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Stenothermobacter spongiae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Stenothermobacter spongiae</em> (spon′gi.ae. L. gen. n. <em>spongiae</em> of a sponge, pertaining to the isolation source of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is as for the genus, with the following additions.</s><s>Cells are slowly motile by gliding.</s><s>Colonies on marine agar are orange in colour, circular, 2·0–4·0 mm in diameter and convex with smooth surfaces and entire margins.</s><s>No diffusible pigment.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are not produced.</s><s>Growth occurs at 20·0–36·0 °C (28·0–30·0 °C optimum), at pH 6·0–10·0 and at 2·0–6·0 % NaCl.</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, penicillin, streptomycin and tetracycline, but not to kanamycin.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 41·0 mol%.</s><s>The predominant fatty acids (&#x003E;5 %) are a15 : 0, i15 : 0, i15 : 0 3-OH, i17 : 0 3-OH, i17 : 1<em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> and summed feature 3 (comprising i15 : 0 2-OH and/or 16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>) (altogether representing 76·2 % of the total).</s><s>Produces acetoin, but not indole or H<sub>2</sub>S.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Hydrolyses gelatin, starch and Tweens 20, 40 and 80, but not agar, casein, carboxylmethylcellulose, chitin or DNA.</s><s>Positive for acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), trypsin and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase activities.</s><s>Negative for <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, arginine dihydrolase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase and urease activities.</s><s>Growth occurs on the following sole carbon sources in the API 20E, API 20NE and API 50 CH systems: d-arabinose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, d-mannitol, d-melibiose, d-sorbitol, starch and d-sucrose.</s><s>No acid is produced from these carbon sources.</s><s>The following carbon sources in the MicroLog 3 system are utilized: d-maltose, d-melibiose, d-raffinose, sucrose, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, propionic acid, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-ornithine and l-proline.</s><s>Refer to Supplementary Tables S2 and S3 for full lists of carbon sources included in the API and MicroLog 3 systems.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is UST030701-156<sup>T</sup> (=NRRL B-41138<sup>T</sup>=JCM 13191<sup>T</sup>), isolated from tissue of the marine sponge <em>Lissodendoryx isodictyalis</em> in the Bahamas.</s></p></content></protolog>