<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1353_nm.3115" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3115" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3115" rank="species">Budvicia aquatica</organism><reference id="rid.1353"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bouvet</surname><given-names>O.M.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Richard</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Aldora</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hauser</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gabrhelova</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Budvicia aquatica gen. nov. sp. nov.: a hydrogen sulphide-producing member of the Enterobacteriaceae.</article-title><year>1985</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>60</fpage><lpage>64</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-35-1-60</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Budvicia aquatica</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Budvicia aquatica</i> (a. qua' ti. ca. L. fem. adj. <i>aquatica</i> living in water)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative, nonsporeforming, non-encapsulated, straight rods with peritrichous flagella (when grown at 22°C).</s><s>Nonmotile strains occur.</s><s>The species conforms to the definition of the <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> (8).</s><s>All strains grow on nutrient agar, producing small colonies about 0.1 mm in diameter after 24 or 48 h at 37°C or about 0.5 mm in diameter after 24 h and 1.5 mm in diameter after 48 h at 30°C.</s><s>The colonies are translucent and have smooth, entire edges.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>All strains grow in 1 day at 4, 10, 30 or 37°C in tryptic soy broth and at 30°C in peptone-water containing 0 to 4% NaCl.</s><s>Growth in peptone-water containing 6% NaCl occurs in 2 days.</s><s>No growth at 42°C (in either tryptic soy broth or nutrient broth).</s><s>Growth occurs on MacConkey agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase produced.</s><s>Oxidase not produced.</s><s>Nitrates reduced to nitrites.</s><s>No growth occurs in KCN medium.</s><s>Tetrathionate reduced.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S produced in triple-sugar-iron agar or in glucose-lactose-iron agar.</s><s>Urea hydrolyzed in urea-indole medium and Christensen medium. <i>o</i>-Nitrophenyl-β-D-galactopyranoside hydrolyzed.</s><s>γ-Glutamyltransferase test positive; β-glucuronidase test negative.</s><s>Indole not produced in peptone-water or urea-indole medium.</s><s>Tryptophan and phenylalanine not deaminated.</s><s>Lysine, arginine, and ornithine not decarboxylated (Møller medium).</s><s>Tributyrin, Tween 80, starch, and DNA not hydrolyzed within 6 days.</s><s>Gelatin slowly hydrolyzed (film method, 2 to 5 days) or not hydrolyzed (tube method).</s><s>Glucose fermented with little or no production of gas.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer test negative (22, 30, or 37°C).</s><s>Methyl red test positive or negative.</s><s>Acid produced (in 2 days) in peptone-water from glucose, L-arabinose, galactose, galacturonate, xylose, and mucate.</s><s>Most strains produce acid from rhamnose.</s><s>Production of acid from D-mannitol is delayed (1 to 3 days in peptone-water at the IP) and may depend upon the method used (no acid was produced from D-mannitol in tests done at the IHE).</s><s>Acid not produced (in 2 days) from adonitol, cellobiose, dulcitol, inositol, maltose, mannose, glycerol, raffinose, salicin, sorbitol, sorbose, sucrose, trehalose, D-melezitose, and D-melibiose.</s><s>Acid produced (1 to 4 days) or not produced from lactose.</s><s>β-Xylosidase test positive or negative.</s><s>Esculin not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Gluconate test negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No growth on Simmons citrate or Trabulsi acetate.</s><s>Growth factor requirements are complex; nicotinic acid is absolutely required, and a combination of amino acids (including L-cysteine, threonine, aspartic acid, and glycine) is necessary to yield appreciable growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following compounds are used as sole carbon and energy sources (in a minimal medium supplemented with 31 growth factors): N-acetylglucosamine, L-arabinose, D-arabitol, L-aspartate, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, fumarate, galactose, galacturonate, gluconate, D-glucose, glucuronate, L-glutamate, DL-glycerate, glycerol, 2-ketogluconate, 5-ketogluconate, DL-lactate, L-malate, D-mannitol, mucate, 2-oxoglutarate, pyruvate, rhamnose, ribose, L-serine, succinate, D-tartrate,</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>meso</i>-tartrate, and D-xylose.</s><s>The following compounds are not used as sole carbon and energy sources: D-alanine, L-alanine, β-alanine, 2-aminobenzoate, DL-4-aminobutyrate, DL-5-aminovalerate, L-arabitol, benzoate, butyrate, caprate, caprylate, D-cellobiose, dulcitol, esculin, ethanolamine, L-fucose, β-gentiobiose, glucosamine, glutarate, heptanoate, histamine, L-histidine, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, DL-3-hydroxybutyrate, <i>myo</i>-inositol, itaconate, malonate, maltitol, maltose, D-mannose, D-melezitose, L-methionine, α-methyl-D-glucoside, 3-methyl-D-glucose, β-methyl-D-glucoside, α-methyl-D-mannoside, phenylacetate, putrescine, quinate, D-raffinose, salicin, sarcosine, sorbitol, L-sorbose, sucrose, D-tagatose, trehalose, trigonelline, tryptamine, D-tryptophan, L-tryptophan, and D-turanose.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 46 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated mostly from water (drinking or river water) and also from wild small mammals.</s><s>No strain has yet been identified as involved in a human, animal, or plant disease.</s><s>The type strain is strain 20186HG01 (= ATCC 25567).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of the type strain.</s><s>Strain 20186HG01<sup>T</sup> has all of the characteristics given above for the species.</s><s>In addition, this strain is motile and β-xylosidase positive, hydrolyzes gelatin (film method) in 3 days, produces a small amount of gas from glucose in peptone-water with a Durham tube, and produces acid from rhamnose (in 1 day), lactose (in 2 days), and D-mannitol (in 2 days).</s><s>The following substrates are utilized by strain 20186HG01T (API strips with carbon sources; minimal medium supplemented with 31 growth factors): D-fructose, lactose, D-lyxose, citrate, glycine, L-tyrosine, L-proline, and propionate.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized: adonitol, D-malate, <i>trans</i>-aconitate, betaine, L-tartrate, and acetate.</s></p></content></protolog>