<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9719_nm.14876" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14876" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14876" rank="species">Spirillum winogradskyi</organism><reference id="rid.9719"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Podkopaeva</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grabovich</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kuever</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lysenko</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tourova</surname><given-names>T.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kolganova</surname><given-names>T.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dubinina</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of Spirillum winogradskyi sp. nov., a novel microaerophilic species, an emended description of the genus Spirillum and Request for an Opinion regarding the status of the species Spirillum volutans Ehrenberg 1832</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2916</fpage><lpage>2920</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.009605-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19625415</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Spirillum winogradskyi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Spirillum winogradskyi</em> (wi.no.grad′sky.i. N.L. masc. gen. n. <em>winogradskyi</em> of Winogradsky, named after Sergey N. Winogradsky, a Russian microbiologist who made a great contribution to the study of chemolithoautotrophic micro-organisms).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Spiral cells, 1.7–2.1 μm in diameter, with one to three helices; helix diameter 6.1–10.3 μm.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of bipolar tufts of flagella.</s><s>Each tuft is covered with an individual sheath and looks like a thick polar flagellum under the phase-contrast microscope.</s><s>Accumulates hydroxyalkanoates and volutin and forms globules of elemental sulfur in the presence of sulfide or polysulfide.</s><s>Cells are facultatively microaerophilic, with optimal growth at an O<sub>2</sub> concentration of 2 %.</s><s>Activity of oxidase and very low activity of catalase are present.</s><s>Growth occurs within a pH range of 6.5–8.5, with an optimum at pH 7.5–7.8.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is at 28 °C.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic.</s><s>Utilizes the following organic acids as carbon and energy sources: 2-oxoglutarate, succinate, fumarate, malate, oxaloacetate, pyruvate and acetate.</s><s>Citrate, aconitate and isocitrate are utilized in the presence of yeast extract.</s><s>Does not utilize amino acids, sugars or alcohols.</s><s>Vitamins are required.</s><s>Uses ammonium salts, casein hydrolysate, yeast extract and peptone as nitrogen sources.</s><s>Does not hydrolyse casein or starch.</s><s>Does not use nitrate, fumarate, sulfate, thiosulfate or elemental sulfur as terminal electron acceptors.</s><s>Forms sulfide from cysteine.</s><s>Predominant cellular fatty acids are 16 : 0, 16 : 1 and 18 : 1.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 38.0 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, D-427<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 12756<sup>T</sup> =VKM B-2518<sup>T</sup>), was isolated in Russia from sediments of an aeration tank for the treatment of municipal wastewater containing sulfide.</s></p></content></protolog>