<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2032_nm.11096" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11096" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11096" rank="species">Tenacibaculum litopenaei</organism><reference id="rid.2032"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sheu</surname><given-names>S.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>K.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chang</surname><given-names>P.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Tenacibaculum litopenaei sp. nov., isolated from a shrimp mariculture pond.</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1148</fpage><lpage>1153</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64920-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17473274</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Tenacibaculum litopenaei</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Tenacibaculum litopenaei</em> (li.to.pen.ae′i. N.L. n. <em>Litopenaeus</em> the scientific name of a genus of penaeid shrimp; N.L. gen. n. <em>litopenaei</em> of <em>Litopenaeus</em>, referring to the isolation of the type strain from a shrimp belonging to the genus <em>Litopenaeus</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, Gram-negative, non-flagellated, non-spore-forming, straight rods, 0.3–0.5 μm in width and 2–10 μm in length and motile by gliding.</s><s>Degenerative spherical cells are occasionally observed in ageing broth cultures.</s><s>Poly-<em>β</em>-hydroxybutyrate granules are not accumulated.</s><s>Forms yellow-coloured, circular, convex colonies with spreading margins after 48 h of incubation at 28 °C on MA.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are absent.</s><s>Carotenoid pigments are produced with absorption peaks at 480, 454 and 425 nm.</s><s>Grows at 10–39 °C, in the presence of 2–10 % NaCl and at pH 5–10.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 28–37 °C, with 3 % NaCl and at pH 7.0–8.0.</s><s>Positive for gelatin hydrolysis and for oxidase, alkaline phosphatase, C4 esterase, C8 lipase, C14 lipase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities; negative for nitrate reduction, indole production, glucose fermentation, aesculin hydrolysis, catalase, urease, arginine dihydrolase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin and <em>β</em>-glucuronidase activities (API 20NE and API ZYM).</s><s>The following carbon sources are utilized (Biolog GN2): <em>α</em>-d-glucose, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, l-glutamic acid, hydroxy-l-proline, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine and uridine.</s><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized: <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, adonitol, arabinose, arabitol, cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acids, itaconic acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, d- and l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-histidine, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, thymidine, phenyl ethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin, gentamicin, kanamycin, penicillin G and streptomycin; sensitive to chloramphenicol, erythromycin, nalidixic acid, novobiocin, rifampicin and tetracycline.</s><s>The major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH), iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH and iso-C<sub>15 : 1</sub>.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 35.2 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, B-I<sup>T</sup> (=BCRC 17590<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23706<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a water sample collected from a shrimp (<em>Litopenaeus vannamei</em>) mariculture pond located in Pingtung County, southern Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>