<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12419_nm.21249" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21249" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21249" rank="species">Vibrio marisflavi</organism><reference id="rid.12419"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>X.-H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vibrio marisflavi sp. nov., isolated from seawater</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>568</fpage><lpage>573</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.022285-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20382785</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Vibrio marisflavi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Vibrio marisflavi</em> (ma.ris.fla′vi. L. n. <em>mare</em> -<em>is</em> the sea; L. adj. <em>flavus</em> -<em>a</em> -<em>um</em> yellow; N.L. gen. n. <em>marisflavi</em> of the Yellow Sea, isolated from the Yellow Sea Cold Water Mass).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-reaction-negative, slightly curved rods, 0.4–0.6×0.8–1 μm, facultatively anaerobic and motile by means of a polar flagellum.</s><s>Swarming motility and bioluminescence are not detected.</s><s>Colonies on MA media are light-yellow, 1–1.5 mm in diameter, smooth and circular.</s><s>Grows on TSA and forms yellow, translucent colonies on TCBS agar.</s><s>Accumulation of PHB inside the cells is observed.</s><s>Voges–Proskauer reaction is negative.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase activities are weakly positive.</s><s>Tests for gelatinase, caseinase, DNase, lipase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and <em>β</em>-galactosidase activities and hydrolysis of aesculin are positive but tests for amylase, urease, tryptophan deaminase and ornithine decarboxylase activities, citrate utilization and indole and hydrogen sulfide production are negative.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Growth occurs at 16–37 °C, but not at 4 or 40 °C, at pH 5–10 and in 1–6 % (w/v) NaCl, but not in the absence of NaCl.</s><s>In the API 50 CH system, acid is produced from d-glucose, sucrose, melibiose, amygdalin, glycerol, d-ribose, d-xylose, d-galactose, d-fructose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, arbutin, d-mannose, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, trehalose, gentiobiose and potassium gluconate but not from the other carbon sources on the test strips.</s><s>In the API ZYM system, positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-B1-phosphohydrolase but negative for lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities.</s><s>In MicroPlates (Biolog), the following substrates are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, maltose, d-mannose, melibiose, d-psicose, raffinose, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, methyl pyruvate, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, citric acid, d-gluconic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-serine, l-threonine, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, glycerol, <em>α</em>-dl-glycerol phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate; other substrates on the test strips are not utilized.</s><s>Resistant to (μg per disc unless stated otherwise) vancomycin (30), clindamycin (2), amikacin (30), gentamicin (10), kanamycin (30), neomycin (30), chloromycetin (30), minocycline (30), doxycycline (30), oxacillin sodium (1), ampicillin (10), cephalothin IV (30), cephalothin V (30) and Fortum (30), but sensitive to midecamycin (30), norfloxacin (10), ofloxacin (5), ciprofloxacin (5), polymyxin B (100 U), compound sulfamethoxazole (75), furazolidone (300), chloramphenicol (30), piperacillin (100) and cephalothin VI (30).</s><s>The predominant cellular fatty acids are summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH), C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em>, C<sub>18 : 0</sub>, C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, C<sub>12 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>12 : 0</sub>, summed feature 2 (C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 3-OH and/or iso-C<sub>16 : 1</sub> I), iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, WH134<sup>T</sup> (=CGMCC 1.8994<sup>T</sup> =LMG 25284<sup>T</sup> =DSM 23086<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from seawater samples collected near the Yellow Sea Cold Water Mass (3 ° 59.970′ N 12 ° 0.157′ E), China.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 42.5 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>