<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3634_nm.805" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.805" rank="genus">Prosthecochloris</organism><reference id="rid.3634"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phylogenetic taxonomy of the family Chlorobiaceae on the basis of 16S rRNA and fmo (Fenna-Matthews-Olson protein) gene sequences.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>941</fpage><lpage>951</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02403-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12892110</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of the genus <em>Prosthecochloris</em></s></p><p class="etymology" /><p class="description"><s>The genus <em>Prosthecochloris</em> comprises green sulfur bacteria with spherical to ovoid, vibrioid or rod-shaped cells that develop as single cells and may form non-branching prosthecae.</s><s>Some species and strains may contain gas vesicles.</s><s>The cell size ranges from 0·5 to 0·8 μm in width.</s><s>As photosynthetic pigments, either BChl <em>c</em> and <em>d</em> or BChl <em>e</em> is present.</s><s>The former are accompanied by carotenoids of the chlorobactene series, the latter by those of the isorenieratene series.</s><s>Salt is required for growth.</s><s>Vitamin B<sub>12</sub> is a growth factor.</s><s>The genus comprises those strains and species that belong phylogenetically to group 1 of the green sulfur bacteria, according to Alexander <em>et al.</em> (2002).</s><s>Photolithoautotrophic growth occurs under anoxic conditions in the light, with reduced sulfur compounds such as sulfide and elemental sulfur as electron donors.</s><s>During oxidation of sulfide, elemental sulfur is transiently deposited outside cells.</s><s>Final oxidation product is sulfate.</s><s>In the presence of sulfide and bicarbonate, simple organic substrates are photoassimilated.</s><s>Obligately phototrophic and strictly anaerobic.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 52·0–56·1 mol% (Bd).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <em>Prosthecochloris aestuarii</em> Gorlenko 1970, 148.</s></p></content></protolog>