<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9466_nm.14606" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14606" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14606" rank="species">Actinopolymorpha alba</organism><reference id="rid.9466"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cao</surname><given-names>Y.-R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>J.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>C.-L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinopolymorpha alba sp. nov., isolated from a rhizosphere soil</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2200</fpage><lpage>2203</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.010280-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19605725</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Actinopolymorpha alba</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Actinopolymorpha alba</em> (al′ba. L. fem. adj. <em>alba</em> white, referring to the white substrate mycelium).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Forms a milk–white substrate mycelium.</s><s>Sparse white aerial hyphae occur on ISP 2 medium.</s><s>No pigment is produced on any of the agars tested.</s><s>Good growth occurs on all agars tested at 28 °C except nutrient agar and ISP 4.</s><s>Cells show variable shapes.</s><s>Gram-positive, strictly aerobic.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Grows at 10–45 °C, pH 6.0–7.0 and in the presence of up to 7 % NaCl (w/v) on ISP 2 medium.</s><s>Positive for gelatin hydrolysis, but negative for nitrate reduction, milk coagulation and peptonization, starch hydrolysis and cellulose hydrolysis.</s><s>The type strain can use dextrin, fucose, maltose, mannose and ribose as sole carbon sources, but cannot utilize glycerol, l-rhamnose or d-xylose.</s><s>Other carbon source utilization data are given in Table 1.</s><s>Hydrolyses l-alanine, l-asparagine, l-proline, l-phenylalanine, l-tyrosine and l-valine, but not l-arginine, l-histidine, hypoxanthine, urea or xanthine.</s><s>Positive for the enzymes <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, esterase (C4), <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, leucine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, but negative for acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, cystine arylamidase, esterase lipase (C8), <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, lipase (C14), trypsin and valine arylamidase.</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan contains ll-diaminopimelic acid as the diagnostic diamino acid.</s><s>Glucose, rhamnose and ribose are present in the whole cell hydrolysate.</s><s>The polar lipids consist of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol mannosides and phosphatidylinositol.</s><s>The predominant menaquinones are MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>), MK-9(H<sub>8</sub>), MK-10(H<sub>6</sub>) and MK-10(H<sub>8</sub>).</s><s>Major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, 3-OH-iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and iso-H-C<sub>16 : 1</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YIM 48868<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AA 208030<sup>T</sup>=DSM 45243<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil sample collected in Yunnan Province, south-west China.</s><s>The DNA G<em>+</em>C content of the type strain is 66.6 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>