<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2592_nm.11540" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11540" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11540" rank="species">Arenimonas malthae</organism><reference id="rid.2592"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ho</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huber</surname><given-names>B.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>F.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>W.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rekha</surname><given-names>P.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Arenimonas malthae sp. nov., a gammaproteobacterium isolated from an oil-contaminated site</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2790</fpage><lpage>2793</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64975-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18048725</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Arenimonas malthae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Arenimonas malthae</em> (mal.tha′e. L. fem. n. <em>maltha</em> a kind of thick petroleum; L. gen. n. <em>malthae</em> of petroleum, because the type strain was isolated from an oil-contaminated site).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, aerobic, motile and rod-shaped.</s><s>Reproduction of cells is by division and not by budding.</s><s>Oxidase-, acetoin- and catalase-positive; shows an aerobic metabolism.</s><s>Good growth occurs after 48 h incubation on TSA and nutrient agar at 30 °C.</s><s>Colonies on complex standard media at 37 °C are transparent to brownish, circular, smooth and convex with entire edges.</s><s>No flexirubin-like pigments or fluorescence are formed.</s><s>Major polyamine is spermidine.</s><s>Ubiquinone Q-8 is the predominant respiratory quinone.</s><s>The polar lipid profile consists of the major compounds diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylethanolamine.</s><s>Moderate to minor amounts of phosphatidylmonomethylethanolamine, two unknown phospholipids, one unknown aminolipid and two unknown polar lipids and trace amounts of one unknown phospholipid and three unknown aminolipids are present.</s><s>The fatty acid profile of the type strain is as follows: (percentages in parentheses): C<sub>11 : 0</sub> iso (2.0), C<sub>11 : 0</sub> iso 3-OH (5.1), C<sub>13 : 0</sub> iso (0.3), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> iso (0.9), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (0.6), C<sub>15 : 1</sub> iso F (3.0), C<sub>15 : 0</sub> iso (43.0), C<sub>15 : 0</sub> anteiso (0.7), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> iso (6.5), summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or C<sub>15 : 0</sub> iso 2-OH) (1.7), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (1.4), iso C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> (25.8), C<sub>17 : 0</sub> iso (8.0) and C<sub>17 : 0</sub> anteiso (0.2).</s><s>The type strain utilizes fumarate, propionate, glutarate, pyruvate, l-alanine, l-aspartate, l-leucine, l-proline, l-serine and dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, utilizes l-phenylalanine weakly and is unable to utilize acetate, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, l-malate and mesaconate after 7 days of incubation.</s><s>The following carbon sources are oxidized (positive with the Biolog GN2 system): glycogen, pyruvic acid methyl ester, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-proline, l-serine, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid (weakly), succinamic acid (weakly), l-phenylalanine (weakly) and l-asparagine (weakly).</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized as carbon sources: dextrin, <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, Tween 40, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, adonitol, l-arabitol, d-cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, <em>cis-</em>aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, glucuronamide, d-alanine, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 6-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Aesculin is not hydrolysed.</s><s>Positive tests (API ZYM) are observed for arginine dihydrolase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase, esterase lipase, leucine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, with negative results for lipase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>The type strain is sensitive to gentamicin, erythromycin, tetracycline, minocycline, rifampicin, norfloxacin and levofloxacin, while it is resistant to penicillin, cotrimoxazole, plindamycin, vancomycin, teicoplanin, quinupristin-dalfopristin, coag(-)oxacillin and oxacillin.</s><s>The G+C content of the type strain is 70.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is CC-JY-1<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 53596<sup>T</sup> =CIP 109310<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a diesel-oil-contaminated soil sample.</s></p></content></protolog>