<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5012_nm.5876" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5876" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5876" rank="species">Arthrobacter sulfureus</organism><reference id="rid.5012"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Stackebrandt</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fowler</surname><given-names>V.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fiedler</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seiler</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic studies on Arthrobacter nicotianae and related taxa: description of Arthrobacter uratoxydans sp. nov. and Arthrobacter sulfureus sp. nov. and reclassification of Brevibacterium protophormiae as Arthrobacter protophormiae comb. nov.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>4</volume><fpage>470</fpage><lpage>486</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Arthrobacter sulfureus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Arthrobacter sulfureus</i> (sul.fu're.us L. adj. <i>sulfureus</i> of sulfur, meaning sulfur-colored)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description given below is taken from the orignal descriprion of '<i>Brevibacterium sulfureum</i>' (<i>lizuka</i> and <i>Komagata</i>, 1965) and supplemented with data on the menaquinone, fatty acid and polar lipid composition (<i>Collins</i> and <i>Kropppenstedt</i>, 1983), peptidoglycan (<i>Schleifer</i> and <i>Kandleler</i>, 1972), cell wall sugars (<i>Keddie</i> and <i>Cure</i>, 1976) and own data on the DNA G +C content and physiological studies.</s></p><p class="description"><s>In young cultures rod shaped cells, irregular, 0.4 to 0.6 by 1.2 to 1.6 μm, angular or slightly curved, occasionally club-shaped; snapping divisions are observed.</s><s>In old cultures rods become shorter, in some strains coccoid cells are dominating.</s><s>Gram-positive.</s><s>Motile with peritrichous flagella or non-motile.</s><s>Colonies large, circular, smooth, entire, raised, glistening, dull, yellow, opaque, butyrous; 1-3 mm in diameter.</s><s>In nutrient broth slightly turbid; in glutamate broth moderate growth, turbid.</s><s>In nutrient gelatine stab liquification.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrate reduced to nitrite; indol not produced; hydrolysis of starch and casein negative; acctyl-methyl carbinol not produced; catalase positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No acid or gas from glycerol, xylose, glucose, sucrose, lactose, dextrine and starch.</s><s>Utilization of a great variety of organic compounds: besides those listed in the footnote to Table 5, the following compounds are assimilate: 4-hydroxybenzoate, L-leucine, L-asparagine, L-arginine and L-histidine; 2 of three strains assimilate 5-aminovalerate, malonate, laevulinate, D-ribose, D-galactose, D-xylitole and 2,3-butylenglycol.</s><s>Cellulose nor attacked.</s><s>The peptide subunit consists of alanine, D-glutamic acid and lysine.</s><s>The interpeptide bridge consists of glutamic acid (Lys-Glu-type, variation A3α:, according to <i>Schleifer</i> and <i>Kandler</i>, 1972).</s><s>Cell walls contain galactose and traces of mannose (only one strain tested).</s><s>The long chain fatty acids (two strains tested) are primarily of the iso, anteiso, straight chain and unsaturated acid types, with the anteiso 12-methyl tetradecanoic acid (anteiso C<sub>15:0</sub>) dominating.</s><s>The major respiratory isoprenoid Quinones are unsaturated menaquinones either with 9 or with equal amounts of 9 and 10 isoprene units.</s><s>Polar lipids consists of phosphatidylglycerol and diphosphatidylglyccrol and of unidentified glycolipids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Optimal temperature for growth between 25 and 30°C-Optimal pH for growth between 7.0 and 8.0.</s><s>No growth at pH 5.0.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic.</s></p><p class="description"><s>G + C content of the DNA ranges from 64.5 to 66 mol%..</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habait: Soil.</s><s>The type strain was isolated from an oil brine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: <i>Arthrobacter sulfureus</i> ATCC 19098 (DSM 20167).</s></p></content></protolog>