<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10076_nm.15018" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.15018" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.15018" rank="species">Streptomyces artemisiae</organism><reference id="rid.10076"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>G.-Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Qin</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>H.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>W.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Streptomyces artemisiae sp. nov., isolated from surface-sterilized tissue of Artemisia annua L</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>27</fpage><lpage>32</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.011965-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19648351</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Streptomyces artemisiae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Streptomyces artemisiae</em> (ar.te.mi′si.ae. L. n. <em>artemisia</em> mugwort, and also a plant genus; L. gen. n. <em>artemisiae</em> of <em>Artemisia</em>, referring to isolation of the type strain from <em>Artemisia annua</em> L.).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-stain-positive actinomycete that forms an extensively branched substrate mycelium and an aerial mycelium that differentiates into spiral spore chains.</s><s>Spores are elliptical or short rods, and the spore surface is smooth.</s><s>Aerial mycelium is white to pink, substrate mycelium is white to pink and orange–brown.</s><s>Soluble pigments are produced on ISP 2 agar (pink) and on ISP 3 agar (red).</s><s>Additional cultural characteristics on various agar media are given in Table 1.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–45 °C and pH 5.0–9.0.</s><s>Optimal growth at 28 °C and pH 7.0–8.0.</s><s>Tolerates NaCl up to 5 %.</s><s>Catalase is produced.</s><s>Negative for Voges–Proskauer and methyl red tests, oxidase reaction, production of H<sub>2</sub>S, nitrate reduction and milk coagulation and peptonization.</s><s>Starch and Tweens 20, 40 and 80 are hydrolysed, but cellulose, gelatin and urea are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Utilizes dulcitol, d-galactose, glucose, glycerol, d-mannose, raffinose, l-rhamnose and d-sorbitol as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Erythritol, aesculin, inositol, maltose, sodium acetate and sucrose are not utilized.</s><s>l-Alanine, l-arginine, l-asparagine, glycine, hydroxy-l-proline, hypoxanthine, l-lysine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-tyrosine, l-valine and xanthine, but not adenine, can be used as sole nitrogen sources.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-arabinose, l-arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, d-fucose, lactose, mannitol, ribose, starch, trehalose and d-xylose.</s><s>The diagnostic amino acid in the peptidoglycan is ll-diaminopimelic acid, and glucose, galactose, ribose and mannose are present in whole-cell hydrolysates (cell wall type I).</s><s>Phospholipids are DPG, PG, PI, PE and GluNu, with trace amounts of PIM and four unknown phospholipids.</s><s>The quinone system is composed of the major compounds MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>) and MK-9(H<sub>8</sub>) and minor amounts of MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>).</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The G+C content of genomic DNA from the type strain is 72.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is YIM 63135<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AA 208059<sup>T</sup> =DSM 41953<sup>T</sup>), isolated from surface-sterilized tissue of <em>Artemisia annua</em> L. collected in Yunnan Province, south-west China.</s></p></content></protolog>