<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2757_nm.4461" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4461" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4461" rank="species">Zymophilus paucivorans</organism><reference id="rid.2757"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schleifer</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Leuteritz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weiss</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ludwig</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kirchhof</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Seidel-Rüfer</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic study of anaerobic, gram-negative, rod-shaped bacteria from breweries: emended description of Pectinatus cerevisiiphilus and description of Pectinatus frisingensis sp. nov., Selenomonas lacticifex sp. nov., Zymophilus raffinosivorans gen. nov., sp. nov., and Zymophilus paucivorans sp. nov.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>19</fpage><lpage>27</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-1-19</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1699594</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Zymophilus paucivorans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Zymophilus paucivorans</i> (pau.ci'vo.rans. L. adj. <i>paucus</i>, little; L. v. <i>vorare</i>, to eat. ; M.L. adj. <i>paucivorans</i>, utilizing relatively few carbohydrates)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description below is based on four strains that were isolated from pitching yeast.</s><s>These organisms are obligately anaerobic, motile, nonsporeforming, gram-negative rods.</s><s>The cells are curved or helically shaped and occur singly, in pairs, or in short chains.</s><s>They are 0.8 to 1.0 by 5 to 30 μm.</s><s>In two of the strains motility disappeared after several subcultivations.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on modified MRS agar medium are circular, smooth, slightly yellow, and 1 to 2 mm in diameter after 3 days at 30°C.</s><s>Glucose is fermented to acetic and propionic acids and trace amounts of lactic acid.</s><s>Phenotypic characteristics of the different group IIIa strains are shown in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cadaverine and rarely putrescine are found as characteristic components of the cell wall peptidoglycan.</s><s>The peptidoglycan type is directly cross-linked <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid, Lipid F is also found as a characteristic cellular compound.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 39 to 41 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is strain DSM 20756 (= AA1).</s><s>The phenotypic properties of the type strain are shown in Table 2.</s></p></content></protolog>