<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8404_nm.13137" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13137" rank="genus">Robinsoniella</organism><reference id="rid.8404"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cotta</surname><given-names>M.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Whitehead</surname><given-names>T.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Falsen</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lawson</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Robinsoniella peoriensis gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from a swine-manure storage pit and a human clinical source.</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>150</fpage><lpage>155</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65676-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19126740</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Robinsoniella</em> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Robinsoniella</em> (Ro.bin.so.ni.el′la. N.L. fem. dim. n. <em>Robinsoniella</em> in honour of Isadore M. Robinson, in recognition of his many contributions to swine microbiology).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, spore-forming, ovoid to short rods found as single cells or in pairs.</s><s>Anaerobic.</s><s>The cell-wall murein is based on <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid as the diagnostic diamino acid.</s><s>No respiratory quinones are detected.</s><s>Polar lipids include an aminophosphoglycolipid, an aminophospholipid, diphosphatidylglycerol, glycolipids, phospholipids, phosphatidylethanolamine and phosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The major long-chain cellular fatty acid profile consists of a complex mixture of straight-chain saturated, monounsaturated and iso-methyl-branched acids.</s><s>The major end products of metabolism include acetate and succinate, but no butyrate is detected.</s><s>Growth is observed with glucose in addition to a range of carbohydrates.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is approximately 49 mol%.</s><s>The type species of the genus is <em>Robinsoniella peoriensis</em>.</s><s>Comparative analysis of the 16S rRNA gene sequence shows that the genus <em>Robinsoniella</em> represents a separate line of descent within the family <em>Lachnospiraceae</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>