<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9216_nm.14469" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14469" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14469" rank="species">Jeotgalicoccus marinus</organism><reference id="rid.9216"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.-G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.-Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shi</surname><given-names>J.-X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>H.-D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Z.-X.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>X.-L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.-J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Jeotgalicoccus marinus sp. nov., a marine bacterium isolated from a sea urchin</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1625</fpage><lpage>1629</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.002451-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19542134</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Jeotgalicoccus marinus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Jeotgalicoccus marinus</em> (ma′ri.nus. L. masc. adj. <em>marinus</em> of the sea).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, non-motile, non-sporulating, catalase- and oxidase-positive, coccus-shaped, 0.7–1.1 μm in diameter and occur singly or in pairs, tetrads or clumps.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Flagella are not observed.</s><s>Colonies are creamy-white, circular, somewhat convex and non-translucent, have glistening surfaces and entire margins and are 2–3 mm in diameter after incubation at 28 °C for 3–5 days on MA5.</s><s>No diffusible pigments are produced.</s><s>Growth occurs at 10–45 °C (optimally at 25–30 °C) and pH 6.0–10.0 (optimally at pH 7.0–8.0).</s><s>Moderately halophilic, with growth at salinities of 0.5–25.0 % (w/v) total salts (optimally at 5.0–10.0 %).</s><s>Negative for hydrolysis of aesculin, casein, DNA, gelatin, hypoxanthine, starch, Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80, l-tyrosine and xanthine.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not produced.</s><s>The Voges–Proskauer test is positive, but the methyl red test is negative.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole sources of carbon and energy or sole sources of carbon, nitrogen and energy: l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-glucose, maltose, d-sorbitol, butyrate, citrate, gluconate, malate, succinate, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, l-glycine, l-serine and l-valine.</s><s>The following substances are not utilized as sole sources of carbon and energy or sole sources of carbon, nitrogen and energy: cellobiose, d-galactose, glycogen, d-lactose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose, d-xylose, adonitol, glycerol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, acetate, formate, fumarate, malonate, propionate, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-methionine and l-proline.</s><s>Produces acid from <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, glycerol, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, salicin, d-sorbitol and xylitol.</s><s>Positive for acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, trypsin and valine arylamidase.</s><s>Negative for alkaline phosphatase, cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, lysine decarboxylase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, ornithine decarboxylase, phenylalanine deaminase and urease.</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin (30 μg), carbenicillin (30 μg), gentamicin (30 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), lincomycin (2 μg), novobiocin (30 μg) and rifampicin (5 μg), but not to chloramphenicol (30 μg), nalidixic acid (20 μg), polymyxin B (30 μg), streptomycin (10 μg) or tetracycline (30 μg).</s><s>The major amino acid constituents of the cell wall are glycine, lysine and alanine.</s><s>Possesses menaquinones MK-7 (60.7 %) and MK-6 (39.3 %).</s><s>The polar lipids consist of diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol and an unidentified phospholipid.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 40.3 mol% (HPLC method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, JSM 076033<sup>T</sup> (=CCTCC AA 207028<sup>T</sup>=DSM 19772<sup>T</sup> =KCTC 13189<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a sea urchin (<em>Hemicentrotus pulcherrimus</em>) collected from Leizhou Bay, northern South China Sea, China.</s></p></content></protolog>