<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2545_nm.11485" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11485" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.11485" rank="species">Bacillus pocheonensis</organism><reference id="rid.2545"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ten</surname><given-names>L.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baek</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Im</surname><given-names>W.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Larina</surname><given-names>L.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>H.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus pocheonensis sp. nov., a moderately halotolerant, aerobic bacterium isolated from soil of a ginseng field</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2532</fpage><lpage>2537</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64491-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17978214</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus pocheonensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus pocheonensis</em> (po.che.on.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>pocheonensis</em> pertaining to Pocheon Province in South Korea, the source of the soil sample from which the type strain was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are strictly aerobic, rod-shaped, 0.7–1.3 μm in width and 3.5–6.5 μm in length and occur singly or in chains.</s><s>Growth occurs at 20–30 °C, the optimum temperature being 25 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 5.0–8.5, with an optimum between pH 6.5 and 7.0.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Growth occurs on nutrient agar, but not on TSA or MacConkey agar.</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin, but not starch, chitin, xylan, CM-cellulose, casein or DNA.</s><s>Negative for lipase activity.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized for growth: d-glucose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-mannose, l-xylose, d-xylose, l-arabinose, d-lyxose, d-cellobiose, maltose, d-melibiose, d-raffinose, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, acetate (weak growth), pyruvate, lactate, 3-hydroxybutylate (weak growth), valerate (weak growth), fumarate, benzoate (weak growth), salicin, malate, succinate (weak growth), sucrose, trehalose, inositol (weak growth), d-mannitol, glycerol, inulin, l-alanine (weak growth), l-arginine (weak growth), l-asparagine, l-aspartate, l-phenylalanine (weak growth), l-glutamine, l-histidine and l-proline.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized for growth: d-fucose, ethanol, l-rhamnose, l-sorbose, d-arabinose, d-ribose, citrate, formate, propionate, tartrate, gluconate, caprate, maleic acid, phenyl acetate, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, malonate, glutarate, itaconate, adipate, suberate, oxalate, d-lactose, d-adonitol, dulcitol, xylitol, d-sorbitol, amygdalin, methanol, glycogen, dextran, l-cysteine, glycine, l-isoleucine, l-leucine, l-glutamate, l-threonine, l-lysine, l-methionine, l-serine, l-tryptophan, l-tyrosine and l-valine.</s><s>In API 20E tests, the Voges–Proskauer reaction is weakly positive and the reactions for gelatin hydrolysis, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, urease, hydrogen sulphide production and indole production are all negative.</s><s>Acid is weakly produced from l-arabinose but is not produced from d-mannitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, l-rhamnose, sucrose, d-melibiose, d-glucose or amygdalin.</s><s>The major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 44.9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, Gsoil 420<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 13943<sup>T</sup>=DSM 18135<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from soil from a ginseng field in Pocheon Province, South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>