<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1236_nm.2017" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2017" rank="genus">Rhodocyclus</organism><reference id="rid.1236"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Imhoff</surname><given-names>J.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trüper</surname><given-names>H.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pfennig</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rearrangements of the species and genera of the phototrophic "purple nonsulfur bacteria."</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>340</fpage><lpage>343</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-3-340</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emendation of genus <i>Rhodocyclus</i> Pfennig 1978.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Type species: <i>Rhodocyclus purpureus</i> Pfennig 1978. Other species: <i>Rhodocyclus gelatinosus</i> (Molisch 1907) van Niel 1944 comb. nov. and <i>Rhodocyclus tenuis</i> Pfennig 1969 comb. nov. Formerly, <i>Rhodocyclus tenuis</i> has been included in the genus <i>Rhodospirillum</i> as <i>Rhodospirillum tenue</i>, and <i>Rhodocyclus gelatinosus</i> has been included in the genus <i>Rhodopseudomonas</i> as <i>Rhodopseudomonas gelatinosa</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are slender, curved, 0.3 to 0.7 μm in diameter, and motile by means of polar flagella or nonmotile.</s><s>Intracytoplasmic photosynthetic membranes are present in the form of small finger-like intrusions of the cytoplasmic membrane.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Although the species of this genus formerly have been included in three different genera, they show a remarkable degree of similarity to each other and significant differences compared with all other species of the purple nonsulfur bacteria. <i>Rhodocyclus</i> is the sole genus in this group that has only a few tubular intrusions of the cytoplasmic membrane as intracytoplasmic photosynthetic membranes, cytochrome c<sub>551</sub>, an S-sulfocysteine synthase, and Q-8 and MK-8 as major quinones.</s><s>All three species reduce sulfate via adenosine 5'-phosphosulfate.</s><s>According to DNA-rRNA hybridization studies and 16s rRNA analyses they form a group that is separate from all other purple nonsulfur bacteria.</s><s>The results of these analyses would allow establishment of different genera in a new family apart from the other purple nonsulfur bacteria.</s><s>However, the species now placed in the genus <i>Rhodocyclus</i> are surprisingly similar in a number of other properties.</s><s>It is obvious that these species have to be placed in a taxon separate from the other purple nonsulfur bacteria.</s><s>Because detailed determinative information is lacking to safely distinguish them on the generic level, we propose placing them in the genus <i>Rhodocyclus</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>