<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1332_nm.75" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.75" rank="genus">Acidianus</organism><reference id="rid.1332"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Segerer</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Neuner</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kristjansson</surname><given-names>J.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stetter</surname><given-names>K.O.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Acidianus infernus gen. nov., sp. nov., and Acidianus brierleyi comb. nov.: facultatively aerobic, extremely acidophilic thermophilic sulfur-metabolizing archaebacteria.</article-title><year>1986</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>559</fpage><lpage>564</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Acidianus</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Acidianus</i> (A.ci.d.ia'nus. L. masc. adj. <i>acidus</i> acid; L. masc. n. <i>Ianus</i> a mythical Roman figure with two faces looking in opposite directions; M. L. masc. n. <i>Acidianus</i> acidic bifaced [bacterium], reflecting the growth conditions and the metabolism of the organisms) cells are gram negative and are found almost exclusively singly; the cells have an irregular coccoid morphology (sometimes lobed or showing sharp bends and looking like tetrahedrons, pyramids, disks, or dishes)</s></p><p class="description"><s>They are nonmotile.</s><s>The cell width is between 0.5 and 2 μm, depending on the culture conditions.</s><s>Thin sections reveal a surrounding envelope about 25 nm wide covering the cell membrane.</s><s>The envelope is composed of subunits in a hexagonal array (45; U.</s><s>Sleytr, personal communication).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are facultative aerobes.</s><s>Lithotrophic growth occurs aerobically by means of S<sup>0</sup> oxidation or anaerobically by means of S<sup>0</sup> reduction with H<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>The cells are autotrophic and mixotrophic and may or may not grow heterotrophically on yeast extract without S<sup>0</sup> in the presence of O<sub>2</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The organisms are thermoacidophiles, thriving between pH 1 and 6 and between 45 and 96°C.</s><s>They grow in the presence of 0.1 to 4% NaCl.</s><s>Neither muramic acid nor <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid is present, indicating the absence of murein.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Elongation factor 2 is sensitive to adenosine diphosphate ribosylation by diphtheria toxin (21, 22; F.</s><s>Klink, personal communication).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells contain isopranyl ether lipids (26; T.</s><s>Langworthy, personal communication) calditol (9, 25; Langworthy, personal communication), and caldariellaquinone (10,25; M.</s><s>D.</s><s>Collins, personal communication).</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Acidianus</i> spp. are resistant to vancomycin, ampicillin, and kanamycin (150 μg/ml each).</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA-dependent ribonucleic acid polymerase shows incomplete immunological cross-reactions with antibody against DNA-dependent ribonucleic acid polymerase from <i>S. acidocaldarius</i> DSM 639<sup>T</sup>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The purified DNA has a G+C content of about 31 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Members of the genus <i>Acidianus</i> occur in acidic solfataras and in marine hydrothermal systems.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species is <i>Acidianus infernus</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>