<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5929_nm.10110" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10110" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10110" rank="species">Rubellimicrobium thermophilum</organism><reference id="rid.5929"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Denner</surname><given-names>E.B.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kolari</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoornstra</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tsitko</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Salkinoja-Salonen</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rubellimicrobium thermophilum gen. nov., sp. nov., a red-pigmented, moderately thermophilic bacterium isolated from coloured slime deposits in paper machines</article-title><year>2006</year><volume>56</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1355</fpage><lpage>1362</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63751-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16738114</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Rubellimicrobium thermophilum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Rubellimicrobium thermophilum</em> (ther.mo′phil.um. Gr. n. <em>therme</em> heat; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> friendly to, loving; N.L. neut. adj. <em>thermophilum</em> heat-loving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are 0.6–0.8×2.0–4.0 μm.</s><s>Motile by means of polar flagellation; number of flagella varies from one to three.</s><s>Moderately thermophilic; temperature optimum is between 45 and 52 °C (<em>T</em><sub>max</sub> 56 °C).</s><s>Slow growth at 28 and 37 °C.</s><s>No growth at room temperature or at 57 °C.</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar after 2 days incubation at 45 °C are translucent, circular, entire, convex, smooth and red-pigmented.</s><s>The pigment absorbance spectrum (acetone/methanol extract) is characterized by a major peak at 495 nm and two shoulders at 465 and 525 nm.</s><s>Growth does not occur under anaerobic conditions in the dark or in the light.</s><s>Bacteriochlorophyll <em>a</em> is not synthesized.</s><s>Urease-positive.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>The following compounds are assimilated: l-arabinose, <em>p</em>-arbutin, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gluconate, d-glucose, d-mannose, d-maltose, <em>α</em>-d-melibiose, d-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, salicin, d-trehalose, d-xylose, adonitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, maltitol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, acetate, 4-aminobutyrate, glutarate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, dl-lactate, l-malate, oxoglutarate, pyruvate, l-alanine, l-ornithine and l-proline.</s><s>Acid is not produced from d-glucose, lactose, sucrose, l-arabinose, l-rhamnose, maltose, d-xylose, cellobiose, d-mannitol, dulcitol, salicin, adonitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, sorbitol, raffinose, trehalose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, erythritol, melibiose, d-arabitol or d-mannose.</s><s>The following compounds are not assimilated: <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, putrescine, propionate, <em>cis</em>- and <em>trans</em>-aconitate, adipate, azelate, citrate, fumarate, itaconate, mesaconate, suberate, <em>β</em>-alanine, l-aspartate, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-tryptophan, 3- and 4-hydroxybenzoate and phenylacetate.</s><s>The following compounds are hydrolysed: <em>p</em>-nitrophenyl (pNP) <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside, bis-pNP phosphate, pNP phenylphosphonate and l-alanine <em>p</em>-nitroanilide (pNA).</s><s>Aesculin, pNP <em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside, pNP <em>β</em>-d-glucuronide, pNP phosphorylcholine, 2-deoxythymidine-5′-pNP phosphate, l-glutamate-<em>γ</em>-3-carboxy pNA, l-proline pNA, Tween 80, starch and casein are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, colistin sulphate, gentamicin, kanamycin, lincomycin, neomycin, nitrofurantoin, penicillin G, polymyxin B, streptomycin, tetracycline and vancomycin.</s><s>Chemotaxonomic characteristics are the same as those given in the genus description.</s><s>Polyamine patterns and fatty acid compositions of individual strains are summarized in Supplementary Tables S1 and S2.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 70 mol% (by HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain C-lvk-R2A-2<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 51817<sup>T</sup>=DSM 16684<sup>T</sup>=HAMBI 2421<sup>T</sup>), isolated from coloured deposits in a pulp dryer in Finland.</s></p></content></protolog>