<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8416_nm.13327" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13327" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13327" rank="species">Flavobacterium resistens</organism><reference id="rid.8416"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ryu</surname><given-names>S.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moon</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sung</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>C.O.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Flavobacterium resistens sp. nov., isolated from stream sediment.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2266</fpage><lpage>2270</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65720-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18842838</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Flavobacterium resistens</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Flavobacterium resistens</em> (re.sis′tens. L. part. adj. <em>resistens</em> resisting, based on the type strain being resistant to all antibiotics tested).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative rods, 0.4–0.6 μm wide and 1.6–3.2 μm long.</s><s>Motile by gliding; no flagella are observed.</s><s>Colonies on R2A agar are yellow, translucent, slightly raised, irregular and spreading with lobate margins.</s><s>Grows on R2A agar, LB agar, TSA and NA.</s><s>Growth occurs at 15–40 °C (optimum 20–30 °C), at pH 6.0–9.5 (optimum 7.0–8.0) and in the presence of 0–2.0 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 0–0.5 %).</s><s>Anaerobic growth is not observed after 20 days at 30 °C on R2A agar.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Casein, aesculin, starch and Tween 20 are hydrolysed, but Tween 80, urea, gelatin, tyrosine and CM-cellulose are not.</s><s>Flexirubin-type pigments are produced, but Congo red is not absorbed by colonies.</s><s>Acid is produced from raffinose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, l-arabinose, melibiose, d-fructose, d-mannose, d-glucose, d-mannitol, arbutin and salicin, but not from d-galactose.</s><s>Negative for glucose fermentation, indole production and arginine dihydrolase activity.</s><s>Positive for assimilation of maltose, but negative for assimilation of d-glucose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-mannose, l-arabinose, potassium gluconate, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid, trisodium citrate and phenylacetic acid (API 20NE).</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase activities are present, but trypsin, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase activities are absent; weak enzyme activities are observed for esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase (API ZYM).</s><s>Resistant to polymyxin B, gentamicin, kanamycin, oleandomycin, neomycin, ampicillin, streptomycin, penicillin G, lincomycin, chloramphenicol, tetracycline, carbenicillin and novobiocin.</s><s>Phosphatidylethanolamine is the major polar lipid.</s><s>The major (&#x003E;5 % of the total fatty acids) cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 3-OH, C<sub>15 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH, summed feature 3 (comprising C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH) and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH.</s><s>The major isoprenoid quinone is MK-6.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 35.4 mol% (HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, BD-b365<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 22078<sup>T</sup> =DSM 19382<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from Hakjang stream sediment in Busan, South Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>