<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7045_nm.4132" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4132" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4132" rank="species">Butyrivibrio hungatei</organism><reference id="rid.7045"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kopecný</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zorec</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mrázek</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kobayashi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Marinšek-Logar</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Butyrivibrio hungatei sp. nov. and Pseudobutyrivibrio xylanivorans sp. nov., butyrate-producing bacteria from the rumen.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>201</fpage><lpage>209</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02345-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12656174</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Butyrivibrio hungatei</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Butyrivibrio hungatei</em> (hun.ga′te.i.N.L. gen. n. <em>hungatei</em> named after Robert E. Hungate, an American microbiologist, who isolated similar strains in the 1960s).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, straight to slightly curved rods (0·3–0·5×1·5–2·5 μm) that do not form endospores.</s><s>Motile by means of a single polar or subpolar flagellum (Fig. 2).</s><s>Growth occurs anaerobically at 39 °C, but not at 25 °C.</s><s>Limited growth is observed at 45 °C.</s><s>No growth is observed in the presence of oxygen.</s><s>Arabinose, cellobiose, aesculin, glucose, lactose, maltose, mannose, raffinose, salicin, sucrose and xylose are utilized by the type strain.</s><s>Tryptophan, urea and gelatin are not utilized.</s><s>The following substrates do not support growth of the type strain: glycerol; mannitol; melezitose; sorbitol; rhamnose; trehalose.</s><s>Medium M10 with glucose (22 mM) is fermented to formate (12 mM), acetate (2·2 mM), butyrate (10·8 mM) and ethanol (3·4 mM).</s><s>No lactate or succinate production is observed.</s><s>No growth occurs in the absence of fermentable carbohydrates.</s><s>Does not show any significant fibrolytic or proteolytic activity, utilizing mainly oligo- and monosaccharides as growth substrates.</s><s>The type strain does not liquefy gelatin, produce hydrogen sulfide, reduce nitrate or hydrolyse urea and is catalase-negative.</s><s>α-Galactosidase, α-arabinosidase, phenylalanine arylamidase and leucine arylamidase are produced.</s><s>No amylase, xylanase, β-endoglucanase, laminarinase, pectin hydrolase, proteinase or DNase activities are detected.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acid components of strain JK 615<sup>T</sup> grown in DSM medium no. 330 without rumen fluid are saturated, branched-chain anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> (17·4 %) and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (14·5 %), and unsaturated straight-chain C<sub>16 : 1</sub> (13·2 %) fatty acids.</s><s>Also present are C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 2-OH (6·9 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 2-OH (4·3 %) and iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub> (3·4 %).</s><s>Branched-chain fatty acids represent the prevailing proportion of cellular fatty acids in this species.</s><s>Strains are common isolates in our set of anaerobic rumen bacteria.</s><s>In the rumen, they participate in the utilization of intermediates of fibre degradation.</s><s>Strains belonging to <em>Butyrivibrio hungatei</em> are listed in the footnote of Table 3.</s><s>The type strain is JK 615<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 14810<sup>T</sup> =ATCC BAA-456<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 44·8 mol% (as determined by the HPLC method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Electron micrograph of <em>Butyrivibrio hungatei</em> JK 615<sup>T</sup> cells showing the size and flagellar arrangement.</s><s>Bar, 1 μm.</s></p></content></protolog>