<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1498_nm.9310" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9310" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9310" rank="species">Guggenheimella bovis</organism><reference id="rid.1498"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wyss</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dewhirst</surname><given-names>F.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Paster</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Thurnheer</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Luginbühl</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Guggenheimella bovis gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated from lesions of bovine dermatitis digitalis</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>667</fpage><lpage>671</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63116-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15774641</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Guggenheimella bovis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Guggenheimella bovis</em> (bo′vis. L. gen. n. <em>bovis</em> of the cow, referring to the source of isolation).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells are 0·4×0·5–1·5 μm.</s><s>The type strain has murein type A4<em>β</em> l-orn–d-Asp and its DNA has a G+C content of 44·4 mol%.</s><s>Growth on OMIZ-Pat agar or on Columbia blood agar in GasPak jars yields shiny, white-opaque colonies, approx. 0·5 mm in diameter, within 7–10 days at 37 °C.</s><s>Liquid cultures in OMIZ-Pat become turbid within 3 days, with a marked change of the phenol red indicator to violet.</s><s>Cellular fatty acids are linear, non-hydroxylated saturated C16 and C18 as well as unsaturated C18.</s><s>End products are butyrate and minor amounts of isovalerate, isobutyrate, propionate and acetate.</s><s>Mesophilic; no growth at 25 or 45 °C.</s><s>The pH compatible with growth is 6·5–9·0, with an optimum between pH 7·5 and 8·0.</s><s>Enzymic activities detected by API ZYM are acid and alkaline phosphatases, C4 and C8 esterases, leucine arylamidase, chymotrypsin and naphthol phosphohydrolase.</s><s>Activities not detected by API ZYM test are trypsin, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidases, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-glucosidases, lipase C14, cystyl arylamidase, valine arylamidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>The following carbohydrates do not affect growth: d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-galactose, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucose, d-glucuronic acid, glycogen, d-lactose, d-maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, l-sorbose, starch, d-sucrose, d-trehalose, d-xylose and l-xylose.</s><s>Growth in OMIZ-Pat is resistant to fosfomycin (100 mg l<sup>−1</sup>), rifampicin (1 mg l<sup>−1</sup>), polymyxin (5 mg l<sup>−1</sup>) and nalidixic acid (30 mg l<sup>−1</sup>) alone or in combination.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is OMZ 913<sup>T</sup> (=CIP 108087<sup>T</sup>=DSM 15657<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Two independent strains were isolated from heifers with dermatitis digitalis in Switzerland; other habitats are not known.</s><s>The 16S rRNA gene sequence of the type strain has been deposited under accession number AY272039.</s></p></content></protolog>