<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12107_nm.20098" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.20098" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.20098" rank="species">Clostridium arbusti</organism><reference id="rid.12107"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>M.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>I.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>L.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Paek</surname><given-names>W.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chang</surname><given-names>Y.-H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clostridium arbusti sp. nov., an anaerobic
bacterium isolated from pear orchard soil</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2231</fpage><lpage>2235</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.013953-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19915114</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Clostridium arbusti</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Clostridium arbusti</em> (ar.bu′sti. L. gen. n. <em>arbusti</em> of an orchard, isolated from pear orchard soil).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells in RCM agar culture are Gram-staining-positive, straight to slightly curved rods, 1.0–1.3×3.5–4.5 μm, occurring singly or in pairs.</s><s>Motile cells are peritrichous.</s><s>Spores are oval, terminal and do not swell the cell.</s><s>Cell walls contain <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid; wall sugars are glucose, rhamnose and mannose.</s><s>Surface colonies on RCM agar plates are 1–1.5 mm in diameter, circular to irregular, low convex, translucent to semiopaque, white or ivory and shiny with a smooth or erose margin and an entire internal structure.</s><s>Cultures in PYG broth are turbid with a smooth sediment and have a pH of 5.0–5.2 after incubation for 5 days.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 37 °C.</s><s>Strains grow nearly as well at 35 °C, moderately well at 32 °C and poorly if at all at 40 °C.</s><s>Growth is stimulated by fermentable carbohydrate but inhibited by 3.0 % NaCl or a pH of 9.0.</s><s>Growth occurs in synthetic medium.</s><s>Abundant gas is detected in RCM and PYG deep agar cultures.</s><s>Negative API 20A reactions for oxidase, catalase and acid production from l-rhamnose, sucrose, trehalose, d-xylose, melezitose, salicin and d-sorbitol; positive reactions for acid production from d-glucose, sucrose, maltose, d-mannose and raffinose.</s><s>Positive Rapid ID 32A reactions for <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase and glutamic acid decarboxylase.</s><s>Positive API ZYM reactions for naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase; negative reactions for acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase, esterase lipase, lipase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Atmospheric N<sub>2</sub> is fixed; molybdenum is essential for biosynthesis and activity of the nitrogenase involved.</s><s>Cellular fatty acids include mainly the straight chain C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, monounsaturated C<sub>18 : 0</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> and summed feature 10 (containing C<sub>18 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>11<em>c</em>/9<em>t</em>/6<em>t</em>).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 31.1 mol%.</s><s>Products in PYG broth cultures include butyric and acetic acids; abundant CO<sub>2</sub> and H<sub>2</sub> are detected.</s><s>Ethanol is produced.</s><s>Pyruvate is converted principally to acetate, butyrate, CO<sub>2</sub> and H<sub>2</sub>; lactate is not utilized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is SL206<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 5449<sup>T</sup> =JCM 14858<sup>T</sup>), isolated from soil samples from a pear orchard in Daejeon, Republic of Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>