<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4805_nm.1677" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1677" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1677" rank="species">Ralstonia insidiosa</organism><reference id="rid.4805"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Coenye</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Goris</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vandamme</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>LiPuma</surname><given-names>J.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Classification of Ralstonia pickettii-like isolates from the environment and clinical samples as Ralstonia insidiosa sp. nov.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1075</fpage><lpage>1080</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12892129</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Ralstonia insidiosa</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Ralstonia insidiosa</em> (in.si.di.o′sa. L. fem. adj. <em>insidiosa</em> deceitful, dangerous, referring to the fact that these seemingly harmless environmental organisms can be isolated from, and possibly cause infection in, humans).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-sporulating, aerobic, non-fermentative, motile rods.</s><s>Growth occurs at 28, 32 and 37 °C and on BCSA.</s><s>Catalase, oxidase, lipase, phosphatase, proline aminopeptidase, pyrrolidonyl aminopeptidase and <em>γ</em>-l-glutamyl aminopeptidase activities are present.</s><s>No lysine decarboxylase, arginine dihydrolase, gelatinase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, tryptophan aminopeptidase or <em>N</em>-benzylarginine aminopeptidase activity is detected.</s><s>No indole production or production of acid from glucose, sucrose or lactose occurs.</s><s>Assimilates glucose, gluconate, caprate, adipate, malate and citrate but not arabinose, mannose, mannitol or maltose.</s><s>Reduces nitrate.</s><s>Characteristics that differentiate <em>R. insidiosa</em> from other <em>Ralstonia</em> species are summarized in Table 2.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 63·9–64·3 mol% G+C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, LMG 21421<sup>T</sup> (=CCUG 46789<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the sputum of a patient with acute lymphoblastic leukaemia in the USA in 2001.</s><s>In addition to the characteristics described for the species, the type strain shows no urease activity, does not assimilate <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and assimilates phenylacetate.</s></p></content></protolog>