<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12743_nm.22523" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22523" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22523" rank="species">Arthrobacter equi</organism><reference id="rid.12743"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yassin</surname><given-names>A.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Spröer</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Siering</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hupfer</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Arthrobacter equi sp. nov., isolated from veterinary clinical material</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2089</fpage><lpage>2094</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.026690-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20870884</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Arthrobacter equi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Arthrobacter equi</em> (e′qui. L. gen. n. <em>equi</em> of the horse).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive-staining, non-motile, non-spore-forming and have a rod–coccus cycle.</s><s>Cells are aerobic, catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Colonies are cream-coloured, convex and smooth with entire margins, reaching 1–2 mm in diameter on Columbia blood agar supplemented with 5 % sheep blood, BHI agar, DST agar and TSA after 2 days of incubation at 34 °C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 37 °C.</s><s>Tolerates 0–2 % NaCl.</s><s>Grows at pH 6.0–9.0, with optimum growth at pH 6.0; does not grow at pH 4.0–5.0.</s><s>Nitrate reduction is negative.</s><s>Acetoin is not produced.</s><s>Hydrolyses adenine, casein, DNA (2 days of incubation), gelatin, hippurate, hypoxanthine, starch (3 days of incubation), tyrosine and urea, but not aesculin, elastin, guanine, keratin, testosterone or xanthine.</s><s>Acetate, l-arabinose, 2,3-butanediol, cellobiose, citrate, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-gluconate, <em>p</em>-hydroxybenzoate, <em>myo</em>-inositol, l-lactate, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, melezitose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose and d-xylose are utilized as carbon sources, but adipate, adonitol, iso-amylalcohol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, <em>m</em>-hydroxybenzoate and 1,2-propanediol are not utilized as carbon sources.</s><s>l-Alanine, gelatin, l-proline and l-serine are utilized as simultaneous sources of carbon and nitrogen, but acetamide and ornithine are not utilized.</s><s>Acid is not produced from d-glucose, glycogen, lactose, d-mannitol, maltose, d-ribose, sucrose or d-xylose.</s><s>Activity is detected for β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, leucine arylamidase, pyrazinamidase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase.</s><s>No activity is detected for alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, α-chymotrypsin, esterase C4, ester lipase C8, α-galactosidase, β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-fucosidase, lipase C14, α-mannosidase, cystine arylamidase, pyrrolidonyl arylamidase, valine arylamidase, trypsin and urease.</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan type is A3α (Schleifer &#x0026; Kandler, 1972) with an l-Lys–l-Ser–l-Thr–l-Ala interpeptide bridge.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>The polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol, two unknown phospholipids and two unknown glycolipids.</s><s>The major fatty acids are ai-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and i-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is IMMIB L-1606<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 23395<sup>T</sup> = CCUG 59597<sup>T</sup>), isolated from a genital swab of a horse.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 67.0 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>