<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1318_nm.7710" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7710" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7710" rank="species">Bifidobacterium subtile</organism><reference id="rid.1318"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Biavati</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Scardovi</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>W.E.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Electrophoretic patterns of proteins in the genus Bifidobacterium and proposal of four new species.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>358</fpage><lpage>373</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bifidobacterium subtile</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bifidobacterium subtile</i> (sub'ti.le. L. adj. <i>subtilis</i> slender, referring to the slender cells)</s></p><p class="description"><s>This taxon previously was referred to as the <i>“subtile”</i> homology group of Scardovi and Trovatelli.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells of the type strain in peptone-yeast extract-glucose broth cultures are 0.8- by 2.1-μm to 4.5-μm, straight or bent rods that occur singly or in pairs.</s><s>Longer, branching, bifid, knobbed, and club-shaped forms in tangled masses are produced in semisolid thioglycolate medium.</s><s>Smaller coccoid and rod-shaped cells that occur in short chains are produced in broth media that do not contain fermentable carbohydrates.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on the surface of blood agar incubated anaerobically are punctiform to 1 mm in diameter, circular, entire, slightly raised, translucent, colorless, shiny, and smooth.</s><s>Similar (but smaller) colonies are produced on blood agar incubated in a candle jar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Dense turbidity with a granular or flocculent sediment and a final pH of 4.1 to 4.8 are produced in peptone-yeast extract broth containing fermentable carbohydrates.</s><s>Slight to moderate turbidity is produced in peptone-yeast extract broth containing carbohydrates that are not fermented.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Other characteristics of the type strain and other strains of this species are given in Tables 1, 2, and 5 , in Fig. 11 and 12, and by Scardovi and Trovatelli.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, ATCC 27537, was isolated from wastewater.</s></p></content></protolog>