<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1152_nm.508" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.508" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.508" rank="species">Deinococcus radiodurans</organism><reference id="rid.1152"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Brooks</surname><given-names>B.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Murray</surname><given-names>R.G.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nomenclature for "Micrococcus radiodurans" and other radiation resistant cocci: Deinococcaceae fam. nov. and Deinococcus gen. nov., including five species.</article-title><year>1981</year><volume>31</volume><fpage>353</fpage><lpage>360</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-31-3-353</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of the type strain of <i>Deinococcus radiodurans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>radiodurans</i> (M.L. adj. ra.di.o.du'rans. L.n. <i>radiatio radiation</i>; L. part. adj. <i>durans</i> enduring; <i>radiodurans</i> resisting radiation)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Spheres, 1.5 to 3 μm in diameter, occurring singly and in pairs and dividing in two planes to form tetrads or tablets of cells.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>The peptide subunit of the cell wall contains L-alanine, D-glutamic acid, and L-ornithine.</s><s>The interpeptide bridge contains glycine.</s><s>Teichoic acids are absent.</s><s>The cell wall consists of at least four layers and has a total thickness of 130 to 140 μm.</s><s>The peptidoglycan-containing layer is fenestrated.</s><s>The outermost layer consists of hexagonally packed protein subunits.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The predominant fatty acid component is palmitoleate.</s><s>No branched-chain fatty acids are present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies are red, smooth, and convex with a regular edge.</s><s>Multiple carotenoids are present.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Chemoorganotrophic; metabolism is strictly respiratory.</s><s>Acid production from some carbohydrates (glucose and fructose) is variable.</s><s>Fructose, glycerol, glucose, and mannose are utilized, but no acid is produced in standard broth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strictly aerobic.</s><s>Optimal growth temperature is 30°C.</s><s>All strains grow in the presence of 1% NaCl and most grow in 5% NaCl in media.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrates are not reduced to nitrites.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Resistant to 1.5 Mrad of gamma radiation and exposure to 1,800 ergs/cm<sub>2</sub> per s of ultraviolet radiation for 10 min.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Guanine-plus-cytosine (G+C) content of the deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA) is 67 mol% (by T<sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: ATCC (American Type Culture Collection) 13939 (=UWO [Collection in the Department of Microbiology and Immunology, University of Western Ontario] 288).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Variations in cell wall structure, reduction of nitrates, tolerance to sodium chloride, proportion of fatty acid components, and loss of pigmentation have been observed in strains included in <i>D. radiodurans</i>.</s><s>Some greater variations among strains assigned to <i>D. radiodurans</i> e.g., strains 1083, G+C = 70 mol%; see Table 2) will demand detailed study in the future in terms of relatedness and species assignment of the strains.</s></p></content></protolog>