<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.23_nm.3388" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3388" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3388" rank="species">Pasteurella mairii</organism><reference id="rid.23"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Sneath</surname><given-names>P.H.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stevens</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Actinobacillus rossii sp. nov., Actinobacillus seminis sp. nov., nom. rev., Pasteurella bettii sp. nov., Pasteurella lymphangitidis sp. nov., Pasteurella mairi sp. nov., and Pasteurella trehalosi sp. nov.</article-title><year>1990</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>148</fpage><lpage>153</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-40-2-148</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2223608</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pasteurella mairi</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pasteurella mairi</i> (mair'i. M.L. gen. n. <i>mairi</i>, of Mair, named after N. S. Mair, who isolated the organism)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Phenon 5 of Sneath and Stevens (46); <i>Pasteurella</i> sp. strain “Mair” of Kilian et al. (22).</s><s>Cells are small nonmotile bacilli and coccobacilli.</s><s>Gram reaction is negative.</s><s>Endospores are not formed.</s><s>Growth is aerobic and facultatively anaerobic, mesophilic.</s><s>Surface colonies grown aerobically on sheep blood agar are round, greyish, semitransparent, and about 3 mm in diameter after 48 h at 37°C; they usually have a narrow surrounding zone of hemolysis, occasionally with greening of the erythrocytes.</s><s>Notable for being sensitive to malachite green and 1% Teepol and for usually giving a positive ornithine decarboxylase reaction; growth on DNase agar (catalog no. CM321; Oxoid, Ltd., London, England) shows a characteristic orange fluorescence (46).</s><s>Other properties are shown in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>This organism has been isolated from abortion in sows and septic infections in piglets; it may occur in other animals (46).</s><s>It is phenotypically similar to <i>P. haemolytica</i> sensu stricto and <i>A. lignieresii</i> (46).</s><s>DNA-DNA pairing tests show values of 30 to 50% to some strains of <i>P. aerogenes</i> and <i>P. pneumotropica</i>, but values less than 25% to <i>P. multocida</i>, <i>Pasteurella volantium</i>, and <i>P. ureae</i> (28, 35).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 43.4 mol% (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i> method) (28).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain dCTC 10699 (= LPHL 5143170 = D1187 = A10 = 68) (28, 46).</s><s>In our hands this strain was negative for the tests marked d in Table 1, except for hemolysis and acid production from <i>m</i>-inositol.</s></p></content></protolog>