<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6797_nm.12205" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.12205" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5429" rank="subspecies">Lactobacillus sake carnosus</organism><reference id="rid.6797"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Torriani</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Van Reenen</surname><given-names>G.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Klein</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Reuter</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dellaglio</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dicks</surname><given-names>L.M.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lactobacillus curvatus subsp. curvatus subsp. nov. and Lactobacillus curvatus subsp. melibiosus subsp. nov. and Lactobacillus sake subsp. sake subsp. nov. and Lactobacillus sake subsp. carnosus subsp. nov., new subspecies of Lactobacillus curvatus Abo-Elnaga and Kandler 1965 and Lactobacillus sake Katagiri, Kitahara, and Fukami 1934 (Klein et al. 1996, emended descriptions), respectively.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>1158</fpage><lpage>1163</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-4-1158</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8863451</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Lactobacillus sake</i> subsp. <i>carnosus</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Lactobacillus sake</i> subsp. <i>carnosus</i> (car.no'sus. L. adj. <i>carnosus</i>, pertaining to meat)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rods with rounded ends (0.6 to 0.8 by 2 to 3 μm) and often are slightly curved or irregular, especially during the stationary growth phase; the cells occur in short chains or singly.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>No growth occurs at 45°C, but most strains grow at 42 and 4°C and some strains grow at 2°C.</s><s>Facultatively heterofermentative.</s><s>DL-Lactic acid is produced, and often there is an excess of the L-(+) isomer.</s><s>A few strains produce inactive lactic acid.</s><s>Acid is produced from fructose, galactose, gluconate, glucose, mannose, melibiose, ribose, salicin, sucrose, and trehalose.</s><s>Many strains do not produce acid from arabinose.</s><s>A few strains produce acid from cellobiose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from amygdalin, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, melezitose, raffinose, rhamnose, sorbitol, and xylose.</s><s>Ammonia is produced from arginine.</s><s>Most strains grow in the presence of 10% NaCl and produce acetoin from glucose.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA ranges from 42 to 44 mol%.</s><s>Originally isolated from fermented meat products.</s><s>Regularly found in vacuum-packaged meat, sauerkraut, and other fermented plant material.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain R 14b/a (= CCUG 31331).</s><s>The description of the type strain corresponds to the description of the subspecies, and the type strain produces acid from arabinose.</s></p></content></protolog>