<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12858_nm.22665" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22665" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22665" rank="species">Nitratireductor aquimarinus</organism><reference id="rid.12858"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Jang</surname><given-names>G.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hwang</surname><given-names>C.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>B.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nitratireductor aquimarinus sp. nov., isolated from a culture of the diatom Skeletonema costatum, and emended description of the genus Nitratireductor</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2676</fpage><lpage>2681</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.028373-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21169459</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Nitratireductor aquimarinus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Nitratireductor aquimarinus</em> (a.qui.ma.ri′nus. L. fem. n. <em>aqua</em> water; L. adj. <em>marinus</em>-, -<em>a</em>, -<em>um</em> marine, of the sea; N.L. masc. adj. <em>aquimarinus</em> pertaining to seawater).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped, approximately 0.4–0.7 µm wide and 1.3–2.0 µm long.</s><s>Cells are Gram-negative-staining, strictly aerobic and motile by means of a polar flagellum.</s><s>After 3 days on TSA and MA plates at 35 °C, colonies are smooth, circular, convex and creamy in colour.</s><s>Growth occurs at 20–40 °C (optimum 30–35 °C), at pH 6.5–9.0 (optimum pH 7.7–8.2) and in the presence of 1–7 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 3–4 % NaCl).</s><s>Positive for oxidase and catalase.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced.</s><s>According to API ZYM tests, positive for acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, cystine arylamidase (weak), esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8; weak for strain CL-SC22), leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, trypsin, valine arylamidase (weak) and <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase activities, but negative for α-chymotrypsin, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, lipase (C14) and α-mannosidase activities.</s><s>According to API 20NE tests, positive for nitrate reduction, β-galactosidase, urease, and assimilation of arabinose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, citrate, glucose and mannose, but negative for arginine dihydrolase, aesculin hydrolysis, gelatinase, glucose fermentation, indole production, and assimilation of adipate, caprate, gluconate, malate, maltose, mannitol and phenylacetate.</s><s>Cells are sensitive to (μg per disc) ampicillin (6), chloramphenicol (20), cephalexin (20), erythromycin (10), gentamicin (6), kanamycin (20), polymyxin B (25), streptomycin (6), tetracycline (20) and vancomycin (20), but resistant to nalidixic acid (20), mitomycin C (0.6) and penicillin G (6).</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and C<sub>19 : 0</sub>ω8<em>c</em> cyclo.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 56.7–57.1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, CL-SC21<sup>T</sup> ( = KCCM 90090<sup>T</sup> = JCM 17288<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a culture of the diatom <em>Skeletonema costatum</em>.</s><s>CL-SC22, isolated from the same source, is a second strain of the species.</s></p></content></protolog>