<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.657_nm.8768" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8768" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8768" rank="species">Parvibaculum lavamentivorans</organism><reference id="rid.657"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Schleheck</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rosselló-Mora</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cook</surname><given-names>A.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Parvibaculum lavamentivorans gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel heterotroph that initiates catabolism of linear alkylbenzenesulfonate.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1489</fpage><lpage>1497</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.03020-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15388700</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Parvibaculum lavamentivorans</em> gen. nov., sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Parvibaculum lavamentivorans</em> [Par.vi.ba′cu.lum. L. adj. <em>parvus</em> small; L. neut. n. <em>baculum</em> stick; N.L. neut. n. <em>Parvibaculum</em> small stick. la.va.men.ti.vo′rans. L. v. <em>lavo</em> to wash, L. neut. n. suffix -<em>mentum</em> agent of (specified) action; L. v. <em>voro</em> to consume; N.L. neut. part. adj. <em>lavamentivorans</em> consuming (chemicals) used for washing].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are aerobic, uniform, Gram-negative, short rods (0·8 μm in length and 0·2 μm in diameter).</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Mesophilic.</s><s>Motile when growing with acetate, octane or in complex medium.</s><s>Q<sub>11</sub> is the major respiratory quinone.</s><s>Straight-chain saturated and unsaturated, as well as ester- and (presumptively) amide-linked hydroxy-fatty acids are present in membrane fractions (see Table 2).</s><s>The major polar lipids are phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylcholine and two unidentified aminolipids.</s><s>16S rRNA gene sequence analysis indicates that this taxon is a member of the <em>α</em>-subclass of the <em>Proteobacteria</em>, with &#x003E;8 % sequence divergence with respect to any other species, within this subclass, whose name has been validly published.</s><s>The G+C content is 64 mol%.</s><s>Strain DS-1<sup>T</sup> grows with LAS and other surfactants via <em>ω</em>-oxygenation and <em>β</em>-oxidation of the alkyl chain to produce short-chain sulfophenylcarboxylates.</s><s>Growth in surfactant medium involves biofilm formation on solid support (polyester fleece, glass particles) and non-motile cells.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type species of the genus is <em>Parvibaculum lavamentivorans</em>.</s><s>Strain DS-1<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 13023<sup>T</sup>=NCIMB 13966<sup>T</sup>) is the type strain of <em>Parvibaculum lavamentivorans</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>