<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5830_nm.5446" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5446" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5446" rank="species">Lactobacillus zeae</organism><reference id="rid.5830"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dicks</surname><given-names>L.M.T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Du Plessis</surname><given-names>E.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dellaglio</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lauer</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Lactobacillus casei subsp. casei ATCC 393 and Lactobacillus rhamnosus ATCC 15820 as Lactobacillus zeae nom. rev., designation of ATCC 334 as the neotype of L. casei subsp. casei, and rejection of the name Lactobacillus paracasei</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>337</fpage><lpage>340</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-1-337</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8573516</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Lactobacillus zeae</i> sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Surface colonies on MRS agar are smooth, glistening, white, and 1 to 2 mm in diameter. Cells are rod shaped (ca. 0.5 to 0.6 by 1.2 to 2.4 μm) and occur singly or in chains, depending on the growth conditions. Gram positive. Nonmotile. Spores are not formed. Grows at 10 and 45°C. Facultatively heterofermentative. Produces mainly L-(+)-lactic acid and a minor amount of D-(-)- lactic acid. Acid is produced from amygdalin, cellobiose, fructose, galactose, gluconate, glucose, lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, melezitose, ribose, salicin, sucrose, tagatose, trehalose, and turanose. Acid is not produced from arabinose, dextrin, inositol, inulin, lactate, melibiose, raffinose, sorbitol (only strain ATCC 393<sup>T</sup>), sorbose, starch, and xylose. Strain ATCC 15820<sup>T</sup> ferments rhamnose, whereas strain ATCC 393<sup>T</sup> does not. Gas is produced from gluconate. Catalase, benzidine, urease, and indole tests are negative. Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite, and ammonia is not produced from arginine. Esculin is hydrolyzed. The L-(+)-lactic acid dehydrogenase polyacrylamide gel electrophoretic pattern is identical to the pattern obtained for <i>Lactobacillus casei</i> and <i>Lactobacillus rhamnosus</i>. The murein type is LYS-D-ASP. The G+C content of the DNA is 48 to 49 mol%. The type strain is strain ATCC 15820. Isolated from corn steep liquor.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Description of <i>Lactobacillus casei</i> neotype strain ATCC 334.</s><s>Neotype strain ATCC 334 of <i>Lactobacillus casei</i> has been described by Dellaglio et al. (4).</s></p></content></protolog>