<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.701_nm.3236" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3236" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3236" rank="species">Pantoea dispersa</organism><reference id="rid.701"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Gavini</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mergaert</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Beji</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mielcarek</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Izard</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Ley</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Transfer of Enterobacter agglomerans (Beijerinck 1888) Ewing and Fife 1972 to Pantoea gen. nov. as Pantoea agglomerans comb. nov. and description of Pantoea dispersa sp. nov.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>337</fpage><lpage>345</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-39-3-337</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Pantoea dispersa</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Pantoea dispersa</i> (dis. per' sa. L. v. <i>dispergere</i>, to spread, to scatter; L. fem. part. adj. dispersa, spread, scattered)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The species has all of' the characteristics of the genus, as well as the characteristics described below.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Culture conditions.</s><s>Strains grow at neither 4 nor 44°C, but grow well on nutrient agar at 30 and 41°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical characteristics.</s><s>The biochemical characteristics at 30°C (11) are shown in Tables 2 and 3.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nutritional characteristics, The following carbon sources are utilized at 30°C by 90 to 100% of the strains within 5 days: glycerol, <i>meso</i>erythritol, <i>meso</i>inositol, D-arabitol, D-mannitol, L-arabinose, D-ribose, D-xylose, D-galactose, D-glucose, D-fructose, D-mannose, L-rhamnose, amygdalin, D-cellobiose, D-maltose, sucrose, trehalose, gentiobiose, D-lyxose, D-gluconate, 2-keto-D-gluconate, 5-keto-D-gluconate, succinate, fumarate, DL-lactate, DL-glycerate, L-malate, L-tartrate, <i>meso</i>tartrate, cis-aconitate, citrate, Lhistidine, L-aspartate, L-glutamate, DL-4-aminobutyrate, and glucosamine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized at 30°C by 90 to 100% of the strains within 5 days: adonitol, dulcitol, sorbitol, <i>meso</i>xylitol, L-arabitol, L-xylose, L-sorbose, lactose, melibiose, D-melizitose, D-raffinose, D-tagatose, D-fucose, L-fucose, D-turanose, β-methyl-D-xyloside, α-methyl-D-mannoside, α-methyl-D-glucoside, inulin, starch , glycogen, propionate, butyrate, isobutyrate, <i>n</i>-valerate, isovalerate, <i>n</i>-caproate, heptanoate, caprylate, pelargonate, caprate, oxalate, malonate, maleate, glutarate, adipate, pimelate, suberate, azelate, sebacate, glycolate, DL-3-hy-droxybutyrate, D-tartrate, levulinate, citraconate, itaconate, mesaconate, phenylacetate, benzoate, <i>o</i>-hydroxybenzoate, <i>m</i>-hydroxybenzoate, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, D-mandelate, L-mandelate, phthalte, isophthalate, terephthalate, glycine, L-leucine, L-isoleucine, L-norleucine, L-valine, DL-norvaline, DL-2-aminobutyrate, L- threonine, L-methionine, L-phenylalanine, L-tyrosine, D-tryptophan, L-tryptophan, trigonelline, L-lysine, L-citrulline, L-arginine, DL-kynurenine, betaine, creatin, <i>p</i>-alanine, DL-3-aminobutyrate, DL-5-aminovalerate, DL-2-aminobenzoate, DL-3-minobenzoate, DL-4-aminobenzoate, urea, acetamide, sarcosine, butylamine , benzylamine, putrescine, spermine, histamine, and tryptamine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA base composition.</s><s>The guanine-plus-cytosine contents of four strains are 56.5 mol% (strain ATCC 14589<sup>T</sup>) (this paper), 58.6 mol% (strain Graham G146) (3,5 9.1 mol% (strain NCPPB 2285) (Mergaert, unpublished data), and 60.6 mol% (strain IPO 445) (9), as determined by the <i>T<sub>m</sub></i>, method.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat.</s><s>Isolated from plant surfaces, seeds, humans, and the environment.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>The type strain is strain ATCC 14589 (=LMG 2603), which was isolated from soil in Japan (18).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The biochemical characteristics of type strains <i>Pantoea agglomerans</i> ATCC 27155 and <i>Pantoea dispersa</i> ATCC 14589 are shown in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Differential characteristics for <i>Pantoea agglomerans</i>, <i>Pantoea dispersa</i>, and the species previously classified in or phenotypically related to the <i>Erwinia herbicola</i>- <i>Enterobacter agglomerans</i> complex are shown in Table 3.</s><s>Additional differential characteristics that differentiate <i>Pantoea agglomerans</i> and <i>Pantoea agglomerans</i> are utilization of <i>meso</i>erythritol, amygdalin, and gentiobiose as carbon sources within 5 days at 30°C (absent in the former species and present in the latter species).</s></p></content></protolog>