<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5828_nm.4560" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4560" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4560" rank="species">Thermoanaerobacter wiegelii</organism><reference id="rid.5828"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cook</surname><given-names>G.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rainey</surname><given-names>F.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Morgan</surname><given-names>H.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characterization of a new obligately anaerobic thermophile, Thermoanaerobacter wiegelii sp. nov.</article-title><year>1996</year><volume>46</volume><fpage>123</fpage><lpage>127</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-46-1-123</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8573487</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Thermoanaerobacter wiegelii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Thermoanaerobacter wiegelii</i> (wie.gel'i.i. M.L. gen. n. <i>wiegelii</i>, of Wiegel, in recognition of Juergen Wiegel's contributions to our knowledge of thermophilic anaerobes)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphology.</s><s>Colonies are 0.5 to 2.0 mm in diameter, smooth, nonpigmented, and uniformly round.</s><s>Gram-negative rods are 0.4 to 0.6 μm wide by 4 to 10 μm long.</s><s>Cells occur singly, in pairs, or (less frequently) in chains.</s><s>Cells grown in rich TYEG medium do not sporulate.</s><s>When the organism is grown in a minimal medium (5), the cells are long and filamentous and spores are formed.</s><s>The spores are round and terminal, distend the cells, and are brightly refractile as determined by phase-contrast microscopy.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cellular characteristics.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 35.6 ± 1.2 mol% (as determined by the HPLC method).</s><s>An inner cell wall layer and an outer cell wall layer are present (a monolayer ceIl wall coated by an inner layer and an outer layer having a globular structure).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth characteristics.</s><s>Obligately anaerobic.</s><s>The optimum temperature is 65 to 68°C; the maximum temperature at which growth occurs is 76 to 78°C.</s><s>Growth at 38°C is poor; no growth occurs at 28°C.</s><s>Growth occurs at pH 5.5 to 7.2; optimum growth occurs at pH 6.8.</s><s>The doubling time in glucose-containing medium is 72 min.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Metabolic characteristics.</s><s>Chemoorganotroph.</s><s>Utilizes various mono-, di-, and polysaccharides, including glucose, xylose, maltose, lactose, cellobiose, raffinose, glucosamine, galactose, fructose, mannose, sucrose, glycerol, soluble starch, pectin, and chitin.</s><s>Sorbitol, mannitol, and trehalose are also fermented, but ethanol, DL-lactate, sodium citrate, sodium succinate, transaconitate, malonate, glutamate, glutamine, sodium pyruvate, 2-deoxyglucose, α-methyl-glucoside, L-arabinose, dulcitol, <i>m</i>-inositol, ribose, α-L-fucose, α-L-rhamnose, and L-sorbose are not fermented.</s><s>The products of metabolism during growth on glucose are ethanol, lactate, acetate, CO<sub>2</sub>, and H<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>Propionate is formed during growth on xylose or cellobiose in pH-controlled (pH 7) batch cultures.</s><s>Growth on glucose is inhibited by oxygen, cephalosporin C, erythromycin, bacitracin, tetracycline, polymyxin B, and various metabolic inhibitors.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat.</s><s>The habitat is neutral to alkaline freshwater (56 to 69°C) in a geothermally heated water source in Government Gardens, Rotorua, New Zealand.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain. <i>Thermoanaerobacter wiegelii</i> Rt8.B1<sup>T</sup> was isolated from a freshwater runoff pool from a geothermally heated water source in Rotorua, New Zealand, and has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen as strain DSM 10319.</s><s>Strain Rt8.B1<sup>T</sup> is the only strain that has been isolated so far.</s></p><p class="description"><s>We propose that on the basis of its morphological characteristics, DNA G+C content, relatively narrow pH range for growth (pH 5.5 to 7.2), antibiotic susceptibility, ability to ferment some sugar alcohols, growth in the absence of yeast extract, formation of propionate when it is grown on xylose or cellobiose, and levels of 16s rRNA sequence homology, strain Rt8.B1<sup>T</sup> should be included in the genus <i>Thermoanaerobacter</i> as a new species, <i>Thermoanaerobacter wiegelii</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>