<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1485_nm.6149" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6149" rank="genus">Rathayibacter</organism><reference id="rid.1485"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zgurskaya</surname><given-names>H.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Evtushenko</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Akimov</surname><given-names>V.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kalakoutskii</surname><given-names>L.V.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rathayibacter gen. nov., including the species Rathayibacter rathayi comb. nov., Rathayibacter tritici comb. nov., Rathayibacter iranicus comb. nov., and six strains from annual grasses.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>143</fpage><lpage>149</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rathayibacter</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rathayibacter</i> (Ra. thay'. i. bac. ter. M.L. gen. n. <i>rathayi</i>, of Rathay, referring to E. Rathay, the Australian plant pathologist who first isolated members of the genus; L. masc. n. <i>bacter</i>, rod; N. L. n. <i>Rathayibacter</i>, rod isolated by Rathay)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Irregular, pleomorphic, short rods (width, 0.4 to 0.8 μm; length, 0.5 to 1.8 μm).</s><s>V-forms and sometimes short cell chains are formed; a clear rod-coccus cycle is not observed.</s><s>Nonmotile.</s><s>Nonsporulating.</s><s>Gram positive and not acid fast.</s><s>Obligately aerobic.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic, having an oxidative type of catabolism.</s><s>Catalase positive.</s><s>Nutritionally exacting.</s><s>Mesophilic; optimal growth occurs at temperatures between 24 and 28°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cell wall peptidoglycan contains alanine, glutamic acid, glycine, and DAB (1:1:1:2).</s><s>Cell wall sugars include glucose, mannose, and rhamnose.</s><s>Xylose and galactose also occur in the cell walls of some strains.</s><s>Menaquinones are of the MK-10 type.</s><s>Mycolic acids are absent.</s><s>Among the fatty acids, branching saturated fatty acids of the anteiso type (anteiso-15:O and anteiso-17:O) predominate.</s><s>Diagnostic phospholipids are represented by phosphatidylglycerol, diphosphatidylglycerol, and unknown glycosyldiacylglycerols; several strains contain lyso-phosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The G+C contents of DNAs range from 63 to 72 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Most strains utilize cellobiose, fructose, galactose, glucose, glycerol, maltose, mannose, melezitose, methyl-α-D-arabinopyranoside, raffinose, salicin, sucrose, and trehalose as sole carbon sources but do not utilize adonitol, dextrin, dulcitol, erythritol, inositol, lyxose, mannitol, melibiose, L-rhamnose, tagatose, or sorbitol.</s><s>No acids are formed from dulcitol, inositol, lactose, mannitol, melibiose, L-rhamnose, or sorbitol.</s><s>Acid production from other sugars is variable.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acetate, formate, fumarate, gluconate, glutarate, α-ketoglutarate, lactate, malate, propionate, succinate, and valerate are utilized.</s><s>Phenylalanine and methionine are assimilated, but most amino acids are not used as sole sources of nitrogen.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Casein, elastin, guanine, hypoxanthine, testosterone, Tween 60, Tween 65, Tween 80, starch, urea, and xanthine are not hydrolyzed or decomposed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Hydrolysis of hippurate is negative.</s><s>Methyl red reduction and Voges-Proskauer tests are variable.</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures between 16 and 35°C, but not at 10 or 37°C.</s><s>Susceptible to 7% NaCl and 0.02% potassium tellurite but tolerates 0.01% potassium tellurite.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Some strains produce bacteriocins.</s><s>Most strains contain plasmids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated mainly from cereal crops and annual cereal grasses.</s><s>The type species of the genus is <i>Rathayibacter rathayi</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>