<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8713_nm.13518" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13518" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13518" rank="species">Paenibacillus woosongensis</organism><reference id="rid.8713"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paenibacillus woosongensis sp. nov., a xylanolytic bacterium isolated from forest soil.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>612</fpage><lpage>616</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65350-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18319465</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus woosongensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus woosongensis</em> (woo.song.en′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>woosongensis</em> of Woosong, the Korean name for the university in Korea at which the organism was isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are xylanolytic, Gram-variable, motile, aerobic or facultatively anaerobic, endospore-forming (ellipsoidal, terminal) rods measuring 0.5–0.7×2.5–5.0 μm.</s><s>Colonies on TSA medium are circular with slightly irregular edges, low convex, light beige to greyish, translucent, glossy and usually 1–2 mm in diameter within 48 h at 37 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 28–47 °C (optimum, 37 °C) and from pH 6.0 to 10.6 (optimum, pH 7.5).</s><s>Grows at salinities of 0–3 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum, 3 % NaCl).</s><s>No growth occurs in the presence of &#x003E;5 % NaCl.</s><s>Oxidase-negative and catalase-positive.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Aesculin, casein and starch are hydrolysed; tyrosine, Tween 80, gelatin and urea are not hydrolysed.</s><s>l-Arabinose, CM-cellulose, d-fructose, galactose, gluconate, glucose, d-ribose, starch, xylan and d-xylose are utilized; 5-keto-d-gluconate, d-arabinose, rhamnose and xylitol are utilized weakly as sole carbon and energy sources. 2-Keto-d-gluconate, citrate, glycerol, sorbitol, sorbose and succinate are not utilized as sole carbon and energy sources.</s><s>Acid is produced from amygdalin, arabinose, arbutin, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, gluconate, d-glucose, glycogen, inulin, d-lactose, d-lyxose, maltose, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, raffinose, d-ribose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose, turanose and d-xylose; acid is produced weakly from xylitol.</s><s>Acid is not produced from 2-keto-d-gluconate, 5-keto-d-gluconate, d-adonitol, arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, fucose, gluconate, glycerol, inositol, melezitose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, d-sorbitol, l-sorbose, d-tagatose or l-xylose.</s><s>Xylanase, cellulase, amylase, <em>β</em>-mannanase, <em>β</em>-mannosidase, <em>β</em>-xylosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and <em>β</em>-glucosidase are produced.</s><s>The cell-wall peptidoglycan contains <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-7.</s><s>The major fatty acid is anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 51.7 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, YB-45<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 3953<sup>T</sup>=DSM 16971<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from forest soil at Daejeon in Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>