<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6852_nm.4614" type="emendation" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4614" rank="family">Mycoplasmataceae</organism><reference id="rid.6852"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tully</surname><given-names>J.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bové</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Laigret</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Whitcomb</surname><given-names>R.F.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Revised taxonomy of the class Mollicutes: proposed elevation of a monophyletic cluster of arthropod-associated mollicutes to ordinal rank (Entomoplasmatales ord. nov.), with provision for familial rank to separate species with nonhelical morphology (Entomoplasmataceae fam. nov.) from helical species (Spiroplasmataceae), and emended descriptions of the order Mycoplasmatales, family Mycoplasmataceae.</article-title><year>1993</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>378</fpage><lpage>385</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Emended description of <i>Mycoplasmataceae</i> (Freundt 1955) Razin and Freundt 1984.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Cells are nonhelical, varying from pleomorphic coccoidal forms 300 to 850 nm in diameter to short or long, branched or unbranched filaments 200 to 300 nm in width to 1,500 nm in length. Some have specialized terminal structures that mediate attachment to eukaryotic cells. Cells lack a cell wall and are bounded by a single plasma membrane. They are usually nonmotile, but some demonstrate gliding motility. The organisms are facultatively anaerobic, with some species showing growth only under more rigorous anaerobic (but not oxygen-free) environments. They possess a truncated flavin-terminated electron transport chain devoid of quinones and cytochromes. Fermentative species frequently have a phosphoenolpyruvate-dependent sugar-phosphotransferase enzyme system(s). Colonies are small (1 mm in diameter) to very small, varying in morphology from uniformly granular types to those with a fried-egg appearance. The organisms are chemoorganotrophs, using either sugars, arginine, or urea as a major energy source. Some species exhibit neither glucose fermentation nor arginine hydrolysis. The cells require cholesterol or a related sterol for growth. Temperature range for growth is 30 to 43"C, with the optimum usually at 37°C. Organisms are parasites and pathogens of a wide range of vertebrate hosts. The G+C content (in moles percent) of the DNA ranges from 23 to 40, and the genome size varies from 600 to 1,350 kbp. All species examined utilize UGA as a tryptophan codon. The type species is <i>Mycoplasma mycoides</i> (Borrel, Dujardin-Beaumetz, Jeantet, and Jouan 1910) Freundt 1955, 73.</s></p></content></protolog>