<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3436_nm.3449" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3449" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3449" rank="species">Mannheimia varigena</organism><reference id="rid.3436"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Angen</surname><given-names>Ø.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mutters</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Caugant</surname><given-names>D.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Olsen</surname><given-names>J.E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bisgaard</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Taxonomic relationships of the [Pasteurella] haemolytica complex as evaluated by DNA-DNA hybridizations and 16S rRNA sequencing with proposal of Mannheimia haemolytica gen. nov., comb. nov., Mannheimia granulomatis comb. nov., Mannheimia glucosida sp. nov., Mannheimia ruminalis sp. nov. and Mannheimia varigena sp. nov.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>67</fpage><lpage>86</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-1-67</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10028248</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mannheimia varigena</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mannheimia varigena</i> (va.ri'ge.na. L. adj. <i>varia</i> varied; L. adj.-forming element -<i>gena</i> orginating from; L. adj. <i>varigena</i> of different origin, referring to the isolation of strains of this species both from ruminants and from pigs)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile, small rods or coccobacilli.</s><s>Colonies are smooth and greyish on blood agar and are 1-2 mm in diameter after 24 h incubation.</s><s>Most strains are haemolytic on bovine blood agar.</s><s>All strains ferment L-arabinose and Dxylose but not D-sorbitol.</s><s>Most strains do not ferment glucosides, those fermenting glucosides also ferment D-melibiose.</s><s>Most strains are ornithine decarboxylasepositive (biovar 1) and correspond to [<i>P</i>.] <i>haemolytica</i> biogroup 6, Bisgaard taxon 36 and Bisgaard taxon 15 biovar 1.</s><s>Ornithine decarboxylase-negative strains (biovar 2) were isolated from pigs and correspond to Bisgaard taxon 15 biovar 2.</s><s>Strains of <i>M. varigena</i> have been isolated from pneumonia, mastitis and septicaemia in cattle as well as from the oral cavity, rumen and intestines (Angen et al., 1997a).</s><s>Isolates from pigs have been associated with septicaemia, enteritis or pneumonia and have also been isolated from the upper respiratory tract (Bisgaard, 1984; McLaughlin <i>et al</i>., 1991; Angen <i>et al</i>., 1997b).</s><s>The type strain is 177<sup>T</sup> (= CCUG 38462<sup>T</sup>), isolated from bovine pneumonia in Western Germany, previously classified as [<i>P</i>.] <i>haemolytica</i> biogroup 6 (Bisgaard &#x0026; Mutters, 1986).</s><s>This strain is indole-negative, ONPG and ONPF-positive, NPG-negative, ferments maltose and <i>meso</i>-inositol, but not dextrin.</s><s>The G + C content of the DNA of the type strain in 41.7 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>