<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12919_nm.22744" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22744" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22744" rank="species">Pedobacter rhizosphaerae</organism><reference id="rid.12919"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kwon</surname><given-names>S.-W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Son</surname><given-names>J.-A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>Y.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>I.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bok</surname><given-names>J.-I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Weon</surname><given-names>H.-Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pedobacter rhizosphaerae sp. nov. and Pedobacter soli sp. nov., isolated from rhizosphere soil of Chinese cabbage (Brassica campestris)</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2874</fpage><lpage>2879</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.026781-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21257686</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pedobacter rhizosphaerae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pedobacter rhizosphaerae</em> [rhi.zo.sphae′rae. Gr. fem. n. <em>rhiza</em> root; L. fem. n. <em>sphaera</em> -<em>ae</em> (from Gr. fem. n. <em>sphaira</em> -<em>as</em>) ball, any globe, sphere; N.L. gen. fem. n. <em>rhizosphaerae</em> of the rhizosphere].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are strictly aerobic, Gram-stain-negative, non-motile, non-spore-forming rods, 0.7–0.8 µm in diameter and 1.4–2.2 µm long after 2 days at 28 °C on TSA.</s><s>Colonies are 0.4–1.0 mm in diameter, smooth, circular, convex and pink after 2 days at 28 °C on TSA.</s><s>Grows on LB agar, NA, R2A agar and TSA, but not on MacConkey agar.</s><s>Catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Growth occurs at 2–37 °C, at pH 5.5–8.0 and with NaCl concentrations of 0–1.5 %.</s><s>Hydrolyses casein, gelatin, starch, tyrosine and Tween 80, but not chitin, CM-cellulose, heparin, hypoxanthine, urea or xanthine.</s><s>Positive (in API ZYM strips) for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase, but negative for lipase (C14), α-chymotrypsin and β-glucuronidase activities.</s><s>Assimilates d- and l-arabinose, d-xylose, galactose, glucose, fructose, mannose, rhamnose, sorbitol, methyl α-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, gentiobiose, turanose and gluconate, but not glycerol, erythritol, ribose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl β-d-xyloside, sorbose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, methyl α-d-mannoside, inulin, melezitose, xylitol, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d- or l-fucose, d- or l-arabitol or 2- or 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>The predominant menaquinone is MK-7.</s><s>The major fatty acids are iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and summed feature 3 (iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH and/or C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 37.8 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 01-96<sup>T</sup> ( = KACC 14938<sup>T</sup>  = NBRC 107690<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the rhizosphere of Chinese cabbage (<em>Brassica campestris</em> L.).</s></p></content></protolog>