<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8830_nm.13736" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13736" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13736" rank="species">Limibacter armeniacum</organism><reference id="rid.8830"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Matsuo</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kasai</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Limibacter armeniacum gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel representative of the family 'Flammeovirgaceae' isolated from marine sediment.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>982</fpage><lpage>986</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65595-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18398206</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Limibacter armeniacum</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Limibacter armeniacum</em> [ar.me′ni.a.cum. L. neut. n. <em>armeniacum</em> (nominative in apposition) an apricot, a rod called the apricot, intended to mean apricot-coloured].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Main characteristics are the same as those given for the genus.</s><s>In addition, cells are long rods, 0.3–0.5 μm wide and 15–40 μm long.</s><s>Colonies grown on 1/10-strength MA are circular, convex and apricot- to pale-orange-pigmented.</s><s>The temperature range for growth is 17–37 °C; optimal growth occurs at 27–30 °C and no growth occurs at 4 or 45 °C.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 7–9, with an optimum around neutral pH.</s><s>NaCl is required for growth and can be tolerated up to 6.5 % (w/v).</s><s>Seawater is not required for growth.</s><s>Gelatin is hydrolysed but agar and starch are not.</s><s>Positive for <em>o</em>-nitrophenyl <em>β</em>-d-galactosidase (ONPG) and production of tryptophan deaminase.</s><s>Negative for the Voges–Proskauer reaction, citrate utilization and production of arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, hydrogen sulfide and indole.</s><s>Acid is produced from galactose, glucose, aesculin ferric citrate, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose and 5-ketogluconate, but not from d- or l-arabinose, ribose, d- or l-xylose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, fructose, mannose, rhamnose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melezitose, inulin, raffinose, gentiobiose, d- or l-fucose, glycerol, erythritol, adonitol, sorbose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, starch, glycogen, xylitol, d- or l-arabitol, gluconate or 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase tests are positive, but esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C4), cystine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase tests are negative.</s><s>Cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, maltose, d-lactose, d-mannose and trehalose are oxidized, but d-fructose, l-fucose, d-glucose, d-mannitol, melibiose, d-sorbitol, acetic acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, inosine, glucose 1-phosphate, Tween 40, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, adonitol, d-arabitol, i-erythritol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactulose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, furanose, xylitol, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acids, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, d- and l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d- and l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate are not oxidized.</s><s>Major fatty acid components (&#x003E;1.0 %) include C<sub>13 : 1</sub> at 12–13 (1.6 %), C<sub>14 : 0</sub> (1.1 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (28.1 %), C<sub>15 : 0</sub> (1.7 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> alcohol (2.3 %), iso-C<sub>16 : 1</sub> H (2.2 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> N alcohol (3.2 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (23.2 %), C<sub>16 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>5<em>c</em> (9.9 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> (3.5 %), iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 3-OH (3.7 %), iso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>9<em>c</em> (1.6 %), C<sub>17 : 1</sub><em>ω</em>6<em>c</em> (1.0 %), C<sub>16 : 0</sub> 3-OH (4.9 %) and iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> 3-OH (4.5 %).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is YM11-185<sup>T</sup> (=MBIC08286<sup>T</sup> =KCTC 22132<sup>T</sup>), which was isolated from sediment samples collected from the shore of Carp Island, Republic of Palau.</s></p></content></protolog>