<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.9249_nm.14518" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.14518" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.14518" rank="species">Spirochaeta dissipatitropha</organism><reference id="rid.9249"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Pikuta</surname><given-names>E.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoover</surname><given-names>R.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bej</surname><given-names>A.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Marsic</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Whitman</surname><given-names>W.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Krader</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Spirochaeta dissipatitropha sp. nov., an alkaliphilic, obligately anaerobic bacterium, and emended description of the genus Spirochaeta Ehrenberg 1835</article-title><year>2009</year><volume>59</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1798</fpage><lpage>1804</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.016733-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19578151</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Spirochaeta dissipatitropha</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Spirochaeta dissipatitropha</em> [dis.si.pa.ti.tro′pha. L. part. adj. <em>dissipatus</em> dissipated, dispersed; N.L. fem. adj. <em>tropha</em> (from Gr. adj. <em>trophikos</em>) nursing, tending; N.L. fem. adj. <em>dissipatitropha</em> tending to dissipated products, pertaining to the ability to utilize dissipated products after primary anaerobes].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are motile and helical, with sizes of 0.23×8.0–18.0 μm.</s><s>Cells stain Gram-negative and have regular, unstable primary coils.</s><s>Spheroplasts are formed at the end of the growth period.</s><s>Alkaliphilic; cannot grow at pH 7.0.</s><s>pH range for growth is 7.8–10.5, with optimum growth at pH 10.0.</s><s>Growth is obligately dependent upon carbonate and sodium ions.</s><s>Requires NaCl for growth: no growth occurs at ≤0.5 or ≥3 % (w/v) NaCl; optimum growth was observed at 2 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Mesophilic; the temperature range for growth is 13–41 °C, with an optimum at 35 °C.</s><s>Cells can be stored frozen in liquid medium.</s><s>Strictly anaerobic, catalase-negative, chemo-organoheterotrophic and dissipotrophic with fermentative metabolism.</s><s>d-Glucose, d-fructose, d-maltose, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-trehalose, d-ribose, l-ribose, starch, sucrose, d-mannitol, propionate, citrate, peptone, yeast extract, Casamino acids, l-arginine, l-isoleucine, l-methionine, l-threonine, l-histidine, l-alanine, l-aspartic acid, l-tryptophan and l-valine are used as substrates for growth.</s><s>No growth occurs with the following substrates: acetate, lactate, pyruvate, butyrate, formate, methanol, ethanol, glycerin, betaine, chitin, pectin, l-glucose, l-fucose, l-mannose, d-mannose, lactose, glycine, l-serine, l-cysteine, l-cystine, l-phenylalanine, l-tyrosine, l-lysine, <em>trans</em>-4-hydroxy l-proline, l-glutamic acid, l-glutamine, l-asparagine, l-leucine, l-proline and trimethylamine.</s><s>Growth on microcrystallic cellulose and filter paper occurs only on the first transfer.</s><s>Major end products of glucose fermentation are CO<sub>2</sub> and acetate; hydrogen and ethanol are minor trace products.</s><s>Resistant to kanamycin and rifampicin, but sensitive to ampicillin, gentamicin, tetracycline and chloramphenicol.</s><s>For the type strain, the genomic DNA G+C content is 43.8 mol% (by HPLC), the <em>T</em><sub>m</sub> of the genomic DNA is 71 °C and the genome size is 6×10 <sup>8</sup> Da.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, ASpC2<sup>T</sup> (=ATCC BAA-1083<sup>T</sup>=JCM 12856<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from anaerobic mud sediments of the alkaline, hypersaline remnant of Owens Lake in east–central California, USA.</s></p></content></protolog>