<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12728_nm.22498" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22498" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22498" rank="species">Glaciimonas immobilis</organism><reference id="rid.12728"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>D.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Redzic</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schinner</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Margesin</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Glaciimonas immobilis gen. nov., sp. nov., a member of the family Oxalobacteraceae isolated from alpine glacier cryoconite</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2186</fpage><lpage>2190</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.028001-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20935085</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Glaciimonas immobilis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Glaciimonas immobilis</em> (im.mo′bi.lis. L. fem. adj. <em>immobilis</em> motionless).</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the characteristics listed above for the genus, the following properties are observed.</s><s>Cells are 0.9–1.0×1.1–1.5 µm in size after 7 days at 20 °C on R<sub>2</sub>A agar plates.</s><s>Flagella or pili are absent.</s><s>Colonies on R<sub>2</sub>A agar are white, round, convex and smooth with entire margins; slime is produced.</s><s>Good growth occurs in liquid R<sub>2</sub>A medium and on R<sub>2</sub>A agar plates at 1–20 °C; growth at 25 °C is absent on agar plates and weak in liquid culture.</s><s>Growth is weak on nutrient agar plates and almost absent on tryptic soy agar plates at 20 °C.</s><s>On R<sub>2</sub>A agar plates, grows in the presence of 0–1 % (w/v) NaCl and at pH 6–8.</s><s>Negative for indole and H<sub>2</sub>S production, hydrolysis of urease, aesculin, gelatin, milk proteins (skimmed milk) and starch.</s><s>Negative for arginine dihydrolase, lysine dihydrolase and ornithine dihydrolase.</s><s>In the API ZYM system, positive for acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, esterase (C4) and esterase lipase (C8) activities.</s><s>Valine arylamidase activity is weak.</s><s>Negative for lipase (C14), trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase activities.</s><s>In the API 20NE system, positive for assimilation of d-glucose, l-arabinose and potassium gluconate.</s><s>d-Mannose, d-mannitol, maltose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, trisodium citrate, capric acid, adipic acid, malic acid and phenylacetic acid are not assimilated.</s><s>Negative for acid production from d-glucose, d-mannitol, sucrose, inositol, d-sorbitol, l-rhamnose, d-melibiose, amygdalin and l-arabinose.</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin (10 µg), fusidinic acid (10 µg) and erythromycin (15 µg); sensitive to streptomycin (10 µg), chloramphenicol (30 µg), tetracycline (30 µg), kanamycin (30 µg), gentamicin (10 µg), amikacin (30 µg), rifampicin (30 µg) and nalidixic acid (30 µg).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is Cr9-30<sup>T</sup> ( = DSM 23240<sup>T</sup> = LMG 25547<sup>T</sup>), isolated from alpine glacier cryoconite collected from the Tiefenbachferner glacier in the Oetztaler Alps, Tyrol, Austria.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of strain Cr9-30<sup>T</sup> is 51.0 mol%.</s><s>Strain Cr9-12 ( = DSM 22814), isolated from the same source, is a second strain of the species.</s></p></content></protolog>