<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6678_nm.6151" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6151" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6151" rank="species">Rathayibacter caricis</organism><reference id="rid.6678"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Dorofeeva</surname><given-names>L.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Evtushenko</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Krausova</surname><given-names>V.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Karpov</surname><given-names>A.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Subbotin</surname><given-names>S.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tiedje</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Rathayibacter caricis sp. nov. and Rathayibacter festucae sp. nov., isolated from the phyllosphere of Carex sp. and the leaf gall induced by the nematode Anguina graminis on Festuca rubra L., respectively</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>52</volume><fpage>1917</fpage><lpage>1923</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12508848</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rathayibacter caricis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rathayibacter caricis</i> (ca.ri.cis. M.L. n. <i>Carex</i> sedge; M.L. gen. n. <i>caricis</i> of <i>Carex</i>, generic name of the plant where the type strain of this species was found)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on corynebacterium agar are circular, yellow and convex.</s><s>Cells are non-spore-forming, non-motile, irregular rods.</s><s>A life cycle may be observed.</s><s>Obligately aerobic, catalase-positive.</s><s>Oxidase test with tetramethyl-<i>p</i>-phenylenediamine is negative or weakly positive, depending on growth phase.</s><s>Optimum growth temperature is 24-26°C; no growth observed at 7 or 37°C.</s><s>D-Glucose, D-galactose, adonitol, L-arabinose, cellobiose, dulcitol, D-fructose, mesoinositol, inulin, D-lactose, maltose, mannose, mannitol, melibiose, melizitose, raffinose, L-rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, trehalose, turanose and D-xylose are utilized as carbon sources for growth on salt medium supplemented with 0.1% (w/v) yeast extract and 0.1% (w/v) casitone.</s><s>Dextran, fucose, lyxose, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, ribose and sorbose are not utilized.</s><s>Asparagine, glycine, leucine, methionine, proline and tyrosine are used as nitrogen sources for growth.</s><s>Alkaline reaction is positive with fumarate, malate, maleinate and succinate, but negative with acetate, citrate, glutamate, formate, lactate, oxalate, palmetinate, propionate, stearate and tartrate.</s><s>Tween 40 is hydrolysed, but Tween 60, Tween 80, starch, aesculin, hypoxanthine and xanthine are not.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced (weakly).</s><s>Methyl red and Voges-Proskauer tests are positive.</s><s>Weak growth with 5% (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin (10 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>), gentamicin (10 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>) and rubomicin (10 μg ml<sup>-1</sup>).</s><s>Susceptible to karbonicillin, levomicetin, metacycline, rifampicin and streptomycin in the same concentrations and 0.03% (w/v) potassium tellurite and 0.03% (w/v) tellurium acetate.</s><s>DNA G+C content is approximately 68 mol%.</s><s>Cellwall sugars consist of predominantly rhamnose and mannose; minor sugars are fucose, glucose and xylose.</s><s>Other chemotaxonomic characteristics are as given previously (Zgurskaya et al., 1993; Sasaki et al., 1998).</s><s>The type strain of the species, VKM Ac-1799<sup>T</sup> (=UCM Ac-618<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from phyllosphere of <i>Carex</i> sp. (Central Chernozem Nature Park, Belgorod Region, Russia).</s></p></content></protolog>