<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1775_nm.11120" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.11120" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7874" rank="species">Treponema socranskii</organism><reference id="rid.1775"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Smibert</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ranney</surname><given-names>R.R.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Treponema socranskii sp. nov., Treponema socranskii subsp. socranskii subsp. nov. Treponema socranskii subsp. buccale subsp. nov., and Treponema socranskii subsp. paredis subsp. nov. isolated from human periodontia</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>457</fpage><lpage>462</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-4-457</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Treponema socranskii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Treponema socranskii</i> (so.cranśki.i. N.L. gen. n. <i>socranskii</i> named for Sigmund S. Socransky, Forsyth Dental Center)</s></p><p class="description"><s><i>Treponema socranskii</i> (homology groups A1, A2, and K) is an obligately anaerobic motile helically coiled treponeme (Fig. 1).</s><s>Electron photomicrographs of cultures in the logarithmic phase of growth show that there is one periplasmic flagellum originating from each end of the cell.</s><s>The periplasmic flagella overlap in the center region of the cell, giving a “1-2-1” relationship.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The cells are 6 to 15 μm long and 0.16 to 0.18 μm wide.</s><s>They have tapered ends with a slight bend or “hook” at one or both ends of the cell.</s><s>The cells form coccoid bodies in the late stationary growth phase.</s><s>Cells in broth cultures have both rotational and translational movement.</s><s>Serpentine movement of cells can be seen by dark-field microscopy of cultures grown in a semisolid medium.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies.</s><s>Colonies usually appear in OTI agar in 7 to 10 days.</s><s>The colonies grow into the agar, are white and translucent, and often have slightly denser centers.</s><s>The edges of the colonies may be entire or irregular.</s><s>The colonies spread and become larger after extended incubation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cultural and growth characteristics. <i>T . socranskii</i> grows only in media containing a fermentable carbohydrate and either rumen fluid (20 to 30%) or a mixture of short-chain fatty acids (3, 16).</s><s>Serum is not required.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature is 37°C.</s><s>There is only slight growth at 25 or 42°C.</s><s>Broth cultures become turbid with a slightly granular sediment in 3 to 4 days.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Biochemical reactions and fermentation products.</s><s>The phenotypic characteristics of representative strains of <i>T . socranskii</i> are shown in Table 3.</s><s>The majority of the strains ferment glucose, with a final pH ranging from 5.1 to 5.9.</s><s>A few strains belonging to <i>T. socranskii</i> subsp. <i>buccale</i> do not produce a pH below 6.0 when they are grown in glucose-containing broth.</s><s>These cultures have a pH range of 6.2 to 6.7.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Inulin, lactose, melizitose, melibiose, cellobiose, salicin, D-sorbitol, glycerol, amygdalin, adonitol, dulcitol, i-erythritol, inositol, and D-mannitol are not fermented, as indicated by only a slight change in the pH of the medium.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide is produced in SIM medium (BBL) supplemented with rumen fluid by all but 1 of 32 strains tested.</s></p><p class="description"><s>None of the strains studied produces catalase, peroxidase, indole, or acetylmethylcarbinol.</s><s>Esculin is not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Hydrogen gas is not detected by gas chromatography of samples taken from the atmosphere above the broth medium in rubber-stoppered tubes.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major acid fermentation products of all strains grown in PY-glucose-rumen fluid broth are acetic, lactic, and succinic acids.</s><s>Trace amounts of formic acid occasionally can be found.</s><s>The strains produce an average of 8 mM lactic acid (range, 3 to 16 mM), 6.5 mM acetic acid (range, 2.6 to 10.4 mM), and 3 mM succinic acid (range, 1 to 6.5 mM).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Habitat. <i>T. socranskii</i> is associated with human gingival crevices and gingival sulci of patients with periodontal disease and experimental gingivitis and in people with healthy gingivae.</s><s>It is the most frequently isolated treponeme and is usually the most numerous organism among the cultivable treponemes in either supragingival or subgingival samples. <i>T . socranskii</i> subsp. <i>socranskii</i> and <i>T . socranskii</i> subsp. <i>buccale</i> are more common in these sites than <i>T. socranskii</i> subsp. <i>paredis</i>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>G+C content.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 50.5 ± 2 mol% (thermal denaturation method) for selected strains and 52 mol% (thermal denaturation method) for the type strain.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain.</s><s>The type strain is strain ATCC 35536 (= VPI DR56BRIII6), which was isolated from a subgingival sample</s></p><p class="description"><s>from a patient with severe periodontal disease.</s></p></content></protolog>