<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12864_nm.22674" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22674" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.22674" rank="species">Enterobacter mori</organism><reference id="rid.12864"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lou</surname><given-names>M.-M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Xie</surname><given-names>G.-L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>G.-F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Su</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Duan</surname><given-names>Y.-P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Enterobacter mori sp. nov., associated with bacterial wilt on Morus alba</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2769</fpage><lpage>2774</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.028613-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21216919</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Enterobacter mori</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Enterobacter mori</em> (mo′ri. L. gen. n. <em>mori</em> of a mulberry tree, of <em>Morus</em>, the generic name of the white mulberry, <em>Morus alba</em> L., from which the first strains were isolated).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-negative, motile, short rods, 0.3–1.0 µm wide and 0.8–2.0 µm long, with peritrichous flagella, appearing singly or in pairs.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>Growth occurs at 20–30 °C with an optimum at 28 °C.</s><s>Grows at pH 4–10, with optimal growth at pH 7.</s><s>Colonies are cream in colour on YDC agar and dark pink with translucent margins on TZC agar.</s><s>In API 20E tests, positive for catalase, oxidase, ornithine decarboxylase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, aesculin hydrolysis, Voges–Proskauer reaction and gelatin liquefaction; negative for methyl red test and indole production.</s><s>Using Biolog GN2 microplates, positive for utilization of citrate, dextrin, glycogen, melibiose, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-arabitol, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, α-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, methyl β-d-glucoside, d-psicose, raffinose, α-l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, methyl pyruvate, citric acid, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid-γ-lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucuronic acid, α-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, dl-lactic acid, mucate, malonic acid, d-saccharic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, glucuronamide, d- and l-alanine, putrescine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, d- and l-serine, l-threonine, inosine, uridine, thymidine, glycerol, dl-α-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Using Biolog GN2 microplates, the following compounds are not utilized as sole sources of carbon: cyclodextrin, adonitol, <em>meso</em>-erythritol, α-hydroxybutyric acid, itaconic acid, α-ketovaleric acid, sebacic acid, succinamic acid, <em>cis</em>-4-hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-pyroglutamic acid, dl-carnitine, γ-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, phenylethylamine, 2-aminoethanol and 2,3-butanediol.</s><s>The genomic DNA G+C content of the type strain is 55.1±0.5 mol%.</s><s>The major fatty acids are summed feature 2 (iso-C<sub>16 : 1</sub> I and/or C<sub>14 : 0</sub> 3-OH), C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, summed feature 3 (C<sub>16 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em> and/or iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> 2-OH), C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>, C<sub>17 : 0</sub> cyclo and C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>According to 16S rRNA and <em>rpoB</em> gene sequence analyses, the closest phylogenetic relatives are <em>E. asburiae</em>, <em>E. amnigenus</em>, <em>E. cancerogenus</em>, <em>E. cloacae</em> subsp. <em>cloacae</em>, <em>E. cloacae</em> subsp. <em>dissolvens</em> and <em>E. nimipressuralis</em>.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, R18-2<sup>T</sup> ( = CGMCC 1.10322<sup>T</sup>  = LMG 25706<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a white mulberry (<em>Morus alba</em> L.) sampled from Tonglu, Hangzhou, Zhejiang province, China, as a phytobacterium.</s></p></content></protolog>