<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12669_nm.22404" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.22404" rank="genus">Pseudoteredinibacter</organism><reference id="rid.12669"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>M.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sheu</surname><given-names>S.-Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.-C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>C.A.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>J.-T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.-M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Pseudoteredinibacter isoporae gen. nov., sp. nov., a marine bacterium isolated from the reef-building coral Isopora palifera</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1887</fpage><lpage>1893</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.024190-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20833889</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Pseudoteredinibacter isoporae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Pseudoteredinibacter isoporae</em> (N.L. n. <em>Isopora</em> the scientific name of a genus of coral; N.L. gen. n. <em>isoporae</em> of <em>Isopora</em>, referring to the isolation of the type strain from a coral belonging to the genus <em>Isopora</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those described for the genus.</s><s>Cells are motile by a single polar flagellum.</s><s>After 48 h growth on MA at 30 °C, mean cell size is 0.3–0.4×0.7–1.2 µm.</s><s>Colonies are round, entire, convex, colourless and semi-translucent, approximately 0.8–1.0 mm in diameter on MA after 48 h incubation at 30 °C.</s><s>Grows at 10–45 °C (optimum, 30–35 °C), at pH 7.0–8.0 (optimum, pH 7.5) and with 2.0–4.0 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum, 2.5–3.0 %).</s><s>Eumelanin production is not observed.</s><s>No accumulation of poly-β-hydroxybutyrate granules.</s><s>Positive for oxidase, catalase, DNase, lipase (corn oil) and hydrolysis of starch, gelatin, aesculin, lecithin and Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80.</s><s>Negative for hydrolysis of agar, alginate, chitin, CM-cellulose and casein.</s><s>In API 20NE tests, negative for glucose acidification, arginine dihydrolase and urease and assimilation of glucose, mannose, malate, arabinose, mannitol, gluconate, caprate, adipate, citrate and phenylacetate; positive for nitrate and nitrite reduction, indole production, β-glucosidase, protease and assimilation of <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine and maltose.</s><s>In the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, C4 esterase, C8 esterase lipase, C14 lipase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase activities are present, and α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase activities are absent.</s><s>The following compounds are oxidized in the Biolog GN2 MicroPlate: Tweens 40 and 80, d-arabitol, cellobiose, α-d-glucose, d-mannose, acetic acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, γ-hydroxybutyric acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, d- and l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid, d- and l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, γ-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-α-glycerol phosphate, α-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>All other substrates in the GN2 microplate are not oxidized.</s><s>Utilizes the following compounds as carbon and energy sources: cellobiose, aesculin, d-glucose, d-mannose, acetate, propionate, succinate, glycerol, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-asparagine, l-aspartate, l-glycine, l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-lysine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine, l-threonine, l-valine and urea.</s><s>The following compounds are not used as carbon and energy sources: amygdalin, l-arabinose, d-fructose, d-galactose, lactose, maltotriose, maltose, d-ribose, d-salicin, trehalose, xylose, sucrose, citrate, gluconate, lactate, malate, malonate, pyruvate, adonitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, l-cysteine, l-isoleucine, l-methionine and l-tryptophan.</s><s>The type strain is sensitive to discs containing rifampicin (5 µg), kanamycin (30 µg), nalidixic acid (360 µg), chloramphenicol (30 µg), gentamicin (10 µg), novobiocin (30 µg), tetracycline (30 µg), streptomycin (10 µg) and penicillin (10 U) but is resistant to ampicillin (10 µg).</s><s>Minor polar lipids include phosphatidylserine, diphosphatidylglycerol and four unknown phospholipids.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, SW-11<sup>T</sup> ( = BCRC 17935<sup>T</sup>  = LMG 25246<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the coral <em>Isopora palifera</em>.</s></p></content></protolog>