<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5341_nm.1119" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1119" rank="genus">Rhodovulum</organism><reference id="rid.5341"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Hiraishi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ueda</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Intrageneric structure of the genus Rhodobacter: transfer of Rhodobacter sulfidophilus and related marine species to the genus Rhodovulum gen. nov.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>15</fpage><lpage>23</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-1-15</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Rhodovulum</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Rhodovulum</i> (Rho.do'vu.lum. Gr. n. <i>rhodos</i>, rose; L. dim. n. <i>ovulum</i>, small egg; M. L. neut.n. <i>Rhodovulum</i>, small red egg)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The characteristics described below are based on information obtained from Imhoff et al. (23-25) and this study.</s><s>Cells are ovoid to rod shaped, 0.5 to 0.9 μm wide, and 0.9 to 2.0 μm long.</s><s>Motile by means of a single polar flagellum or nonmotile.</s><s>Cells divide by binary fission.</s><s>Gram negative.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic phototrophs which grow under anaerobic conditions in the light or under aerobic conditions in the dark.</s><s>Phototrophically grown cells form vesicular intracytoplasmic membranes together with bacteriochlorophyll a (esterified with phytol) and carotenoids of the spheroidene series.</s><s>The color of phototrophic cultures is yellow-green to yellow-brown, while aerobic cultures are pink to red.</s><s>Mesophilic and halophilic.</s><s>Sodium chloride at a concentration of 0.5 to 7.5% is required for optimal growth.</s><s>Photoorganotrophy with various organic compounds is the preferred mode of growth.</s><s>Good carbon sources are pyruvate, lactate, lower fatty acids, intermediates of the citric acid cycle, and some sugars.</s><s>Growth on formate also occurs.</s><s>Photoautotrophic or photoheterotrophic growth occurs in the presence of sulfide or thiosulfate as the electron donor.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of high sulfide concentrations (2 mM or more).</s><s>The final oxidation product of sulfide is sulfate.</s><s>Ubiquinone 10 is the major quinone.</s><s>The major fatty acid is C<sub>18:1</sub>.</s><s>Membrane lipids contain sulfolipids but not phosphatidylcholine.</s><s>The G+C content of the genomic DNA ranges from 62 to 69 mol%.</s><s>The phylogenetic position is the alpha subclass (α-3) of the <i>Proteobacteria</i>.</s><s>Natural habitats are marine and hypersaline environments.</s><s>The type species is <i>Rhodovulum sulfidophilum</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>