<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8204_nm.13200" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13200" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13200" rank="species">Agrococcus versicolor</organism><reference id="rid.8204"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Behrendt</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ulrich</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Agrococcus versicolor sp. nov., an actinobacterium associated with the phyllosphere of potato plants.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>2833</fpage><lpage>2838</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.2008/001610-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19060068</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Agrococcus versicolor</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Agrococcus versicolor</em> (ver.si′co.lor. L. adj. <em>versicolor</em> colour changing).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are asporogenous, non-motile, short to ovoid rods (0.5–0.6×0.8–1.2 μm) and occur singly or in pairs, sometimes forming small irregular clusters.</s><s>Gram-positive and strictly aerobic.</s><s>Colonies on nutrient agar are dark pink to red in colour and are smooth with regular margins.</s><s>Young, solitary, growing colonies are yellow, turning dark pink with age.</s><s>The optimal growth temperature is 21 °C; no growth at 4 or 37 °C.</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite are not reduced.</s><s>Growth occurs at 1 and 2 % NaCl but not at higher concentrations.</s><s>Catalase activity is present, but oxidase, urease, l-phenylalanine deaminase, lysine and ornithine decarboxylase, arginine dihydrolase and tryptophan deaminase activities are absent.</s><s><em>β</em>-Galactosidase activity is weak.</s><s>Gelatin, casein and aesculin are hydrolysed, but starch and tyrosine are not.</s><s>Hydrogen sulphide is not produced.</s><s>Indole production from l-tryptophan and the reaction in the Voges–Proskauer test are negative.</s><s>The following are utilized on Biolog microplates GP2: dextrin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, palatinose, d-psicose, d-ribose, sucrose, d-tagatose, turanose, d-xylose, propionic acid and glycerol.</s><s>Maltotriose, trehalose, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, l-alaninamide and adenosine are utilized with prolonged incubation.</s><s>The following are not utilized: <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, glycogen, inulin, mannan, Tweens 40 and 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-mannosamine, amygdalin, d-arabitol, arbutin, d-galactose, l-fucose, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, raffinose, l-rhamnose, salicin, sedoheptulosan, d-sorbitol, stachyose, xylitol, acetic acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, lactamide, d-lactic acid methyl ester, l-lactic acid, d- and l-malic acid, monomethyl succinate, succinamic acid, succinic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl l-glutamic acid, d- and l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, 2′-deoxyadenosine, inosine, thymidine, uridine, adenosine 5′-monophosphate, thymidine 5′-monophosphate, uridine 5′-monophosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate, d-glucose 6-phosphate and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>Oxidative acid production with API 50 CH is positive for ribose and l-arabinose but weak for d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, sucrose and turanose.</s><s>Acid production is negative for glycerol, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-xylose, d-adonitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, l-sorbose, l-rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, d-lactose (bovine origin), melibiose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, xylitol, gentiobiose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d- and l-fucose, d- and l-arabitol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate and potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Strain-specific reactions are shown for d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-cellobiose and maltose.</s><s>The diagnostic cell-wall diamino acid is DAB; alanine, glycine, threonine, aspartic acid and glutamic acid are also present.</s><s>The major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 1</sub> and minor fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>, C<sub>14 : 0</sub>, iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>14 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The major menaquinones are MK-10 and MK-11.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, K 114/01<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 19812<sup>T</sup> =LMG 24386<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from the phyllosphere of potato plants in Dahnsdorf, Germany.</s></p></content></protolog>