<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1820_nm.4121" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4121" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4121" rank="species">Lachnospira pectinoschiza</organism><reference id="rid.1820"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cornick</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jensen</surname><given-names>N.S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stahl</surname><given-names>D.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hartman</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Allison</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Lachnospira pectinoschiza sp. nov., an anaerobic pectinophile from the pig intestine.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>87</fpage><lpage>93</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-1-87</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8123565</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Lachnospira pectinoschiza</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Lachnospira pectinoschiza</i> (pec'ti.no.schiz.a. M.L. n. <i>pectinum</i>, pectin; Gr. adj. <i>schizon</i>, splitting; M.L. fern. <i>pectinoschiza</i>, pectin splitting [40])</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells grown in medium PF broth are rod shaped, 0.36 to 0.56 μm wide, and 2.4 to 3.1 μm long and are arranged singly, in pairs, or in chains containing three to six cells.</s><s>Cells peritrichous and motile by means of 6 to 18 flagella per cell.</s><s>Gram positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Colonies on medium PF agar are opaque, circular with wavy edges, umbonate, and 3 to 5 mm in diameter.</s><s>Growth in medium containing PGA is rapid, with a doubling time of aproximately 55 min.</s><s>Final cell yields are 2 x 10<sup>9</sup> to 3.5 x 10<sup>9</sup> CFU/ml.</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures ranging from 30 to 45°C.</s><s>No growth occurs at 25 or 50°C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Obligate anaerobes.</s><s>Growth requires a fermentable carbohydrate such as pectin, PGA, gluconic acid, lactose, or cellobiose.</s><s>Fructose is used after a lag period of 2 to 6 days.</s><s>The following compounds do not support growth: L-arabinose, D-galactose, D-glucose, D-glucuronate, glycogen, inositol, inulin, D-maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, salicin, D-sorbitol, soluble starch, sucrose, trehalose, D-xylose, amino acids, arabinogalactan, carboxymethyl cellulose, cellulose, gum arabic, pig gastric mucin, and xylan.</s><s>Catalase is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Esculin and gelatin are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Growth occurs in medium PF broth supplemented with 20% bile.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The major end products of PGA fermentation are formate and acetate; minor amounts of ethanol and CO<sub>2</sub> are also formed.</s><s>Methanol is formed when pectin is fermented.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Pectin is depolymerized by extracellular pectin methylesterase and a Ca<sup>2+</sup>-dependent exopectate lyase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content is 42 mol%, as determined by thermal denaturation.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from cecal and colonic contents of pigs.</s><s>The type strain, strain 150-1, has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 49827.</s></p></content></protolog>