<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2720_nm.7597" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7597" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7597" rank="species">Actinomadura kijaniata</organism><reference id="rid.2720"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Horan</surname><given-names>A.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Brodsky</surname><given-names>B.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>A novel antibiotic producing Actinomadura, Actinomadura kijaniata sp. nov.</article-title><year>1982</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>195</fpage><lpage>200</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-32-2-195</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinomadura kijaniata</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinomadura kijaniata</i> (The specific epithet is derived from kijani, the Swahili word for green)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Morphological observations.</s><s>On both YD agar and water agar, abundant aerial mycelia which fragment into long chains of eliptical spores (10 or more) approximately 1 .O to 1.5 μm in diameter by 1.5 to 2.0 μm long (Fig. 1) are formed.</s><s>Electron microscopic observation indicated that the spores are smooth walled.</s><s>Aerial mycelia occur as long, open spirals.</s><s>Motile spores do not occur.</s><s>The vegetative mycelia form abundant branches and also appear to fragment into chains of spores.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Whole-cell analysis.</s><s>Hydrolyzed whole cells contain the <i>meso</i> isomer of diaminopimelic acid, along with a trace of the L-isomer.</s><s>Madurose is the characteristic sugar component.</s><s>A type PI phospholipid pattern, characteristic of <i>Actinomadura</i>, was found.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth characteristics.</s><s>Table 2 shows the macroscopic appearance of strain SCC 1256 on various descriptive media.</s><s>This strain grows well on most organic media.</s><s>The vegetative mycelium colors range from tan to dark green; shades of green are characteristic.</s><s>Abundant white aerial mycelia are formed on ISP no. 7 agar and starch agar.</s><s>Gray, brown, and green diffusible pigments are formed on several media.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Carbohydrate utilization and physiological properties.</s><s>Table 3 shows the carbohydrate utilization and physiological properties of strain SCC 1256.</s><s>The positive properties include utilization of adonitol, D-arabinose, L-arabinose, fructose, L-fucose, galactose, glucose, glycerol, inositol, maltose, mannose, rhamnose, ribose, sucrose, trehalose, and D-xylose; methyl-β-D-glucopyranoside is utilized and a distinctive green diffusible pigment is formed.</s><s>Strain SCC 1256 is capable of hydrolyzing all of the compounds tested; however, the hydrolyses of starch and adenine are weak.</s><s>Urea and allantoin are degraded, growth occurs at 45"C, the strain survives at 50°C for 8 h, growth occurs in the presence of most of the antibiotics tested, and lactamase is formed.</s><s>Strain SCC 1256 is unable to utilize dulcitol, erythritol, α-methyl-D-glucoside, inulin, lactose, mannitol, melibiose, melizitose, or raffinose, to grow in the presence of rosaramicin, and to form hydrogen sulfide and melanin.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Identity of strain SCC 1256.</s><s>The presence of <i>meso</i>-diaminopimelic acid and madurose as characteristic whole-cell components, a type PI phospholipid pattern, and the formation of aerial mycelia with long spore chains identify this strain as a member of the genus <i>Actinomudura</i> Lechevalier and Lechevalier (13).</s><s>Table 4 compares the whole-cell data and differentiating morphological and physiological (6) characteristics of the strains listed in Table 1 with the data obtained for SCC 1256.</s><s>Of the strains used in this study and the species of <i>Actinomudura</i> described in the literature, none shares with SCC 1256 the combination of deep green vegetative mycelia, white to green aerial mycelia, long spore chains with smooth spores, the ability to hydrolyze xanthine, the ability to utilize methyl-β-D-glucoside, and the ability to produce kijanimiciq.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Our data suggest that strain SCC 1256 represents a new, distinct antibiotic-producing species of <i>Actinomudura</i>, for which the name <i>Actinomudura kijaniata</i> is proposed.</s><s>The specific epithet is derjved from kijani, the Swahili word for green.</s><s>The type strain is SCC 1256 (= ATCC 31588).</s><s>Since at present there has been only one strain identified as belonging to this species, (the type strain), the description presented above applies to both the species and the type strain.</s></p></content></protolog>