<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.837_nm.1903" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1903" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1903" rank="species">Methylobacillus flagellatus</organism><reference id="rid.837"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Govorukhina</surname><given-names>N.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kletsova</surname><given-names>L.V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tsygankov</surname><given-names>Yu.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Trotsenko</surname><given-names>Yu.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Netrusov</surname><given-names>A.I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characteristics of a new obligate methylotroph.</article-title><year>1987</year><volume>56</volume><fpage>849</fpage><lpage>854</lpage><source id="130">Mikrobiologiia</source><issn>0026-3656</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Methylobacillus flagellatus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Methylobacillus flagellatus</i> (Fla.gel.la.tum: from Latin flagellum; <i>flagelatum</i> from Latin for attached flagellum, flagellated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are mobile gram-negative bacilli (1.4-1.8) x (0.5-0.6) μm in size, reproduce by division, do not form spores or capsules.</s><s>Colonies on agarized medium with methanol are round, translucent, with milky color, and surface is smooth, the profile convex. the edge even, structure is finely granular, consistency is viscous.</s><s>It is an obligate methylotroph: it utilizes only methanol and methylamine as the source of carbon and energy.</s><s>It consumes methylamine, ammonia salts, dimethylamine, nitrates, and peptone as the source of nitrogen.</s><s>It grows in a temperature range of 10-25°C and a pH of 5.8-8.4.</s><s>Optimal values are 42°C for temperature and 7.2-7.3 for pH.</s><s>Generation time is 2h.</s><s>It does not require vitamins.</s><s>It does not form acids or gases from glucose.</s><s>It does not peptonize milk.</s><s>The arginine test is negative.</s><s>Tests for urease, catalase, and oxidase are positive.</s><s>It hydrolyzes starch but not cellulose, gelatin, or Tween-80.</s><s>It reduces nitrates to nitrites.</s><s>It employs the BMP pathway of assimilation of formaldehyde (Entner-Doudoroff variant).</s><s>It assimilates ammonia by reduction amination of α-ketoglutarate by glutamate dehydrogenase.</s><s>Predominant acids in the fatty acid composition of cells are C<sub>16:0</sub> and C<sub>16:1</sub>.</s><s>The ratio of cis-vaccenic to palmitoleic is 0.32.</s><s>Content of DNA GC is 55.5 mole %.</s><s>Level of DNA-DNA to <i>M. glycogenes</i> ATCC 29475 is 18%, more than 30% for <i>P. thiaminophague</i> ATCC 21371, and <i>P. insueta</i> ATCC 21276.</s><s>The type species of <i>M. flagellatum</i> KT was isolated from sewage and is stored in the collection of the Institute of Biochemistry and Physiology of Microorganisms, Academy of Sciences of the USSR.</s></p></content></protolog>