<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7245_nm.1707" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1707" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1707" rank="species">Herbaspirillum frisingense</organism><reference id="rid.7245"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kirchhof</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Eckert</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stoffels</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Baldani</surname><given-names>J.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Reis</surname><given-names>V.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hartmann</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Herbaspirillum frisingense sp. nov., a new nitrogen-fixing bacterial species that occurs in C4-fibre plants.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>157</fpage><lpage>168</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11211253</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Herbaspirillum frisingense</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Herbaspirillum frisingense</i> (fri.sin.gen'se. L. gen. n. <i>frisingense</i> of Frisinga, now known as Freising, a town in Germany where the <i>Spartina pectinata</i> and <i>Miscanthus</i> spp. plants were grown from which the organisms were first isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Characteristics useful for the identification of the genus <i>Herbaspirillum</i> as well as differentiating the new species <i>Herbaspirillum frisingense</i> sp. nov. are summarized in Table 2.</s><s>Cells are slightly curved, spiral rods and motile.</s><s>The cells have mostly two, occasionally one or three unipolar flagella and are able to swarm on soft nutrient agar.</s><s>The cells are 0.5-0.7 μm in diameter and 1.4-1.8 μm long.</s><s>The strains are able to fix atmospheric nitrogen and grow well with N<sub>2</sub> as sole nitrogen source under microaerobic conditions.</s><s>The optimum growth temperature in the presence of nitrogen is between 30 and 37 °C.</s><s>The pH optimum is between 6.0 and 7.0.</s><s>Catalase, oxidase and urease activities are positive and gelatin is not hydrolysed.</s><s>NO<sub>3</sub><sup>-</sup> is reduced to NO<sub>2</sub><sup>-</sup> but not to N<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>The metabolism is of typical respiratory nature, a broad spectrum of sugars and alcohols are oxidized.</s><s>Di- and trisaccharides are not metabolized.</s><s>Organic acids are preferably utilized as carbon sources.</s><s>Fatty acid oxidation is positive.</s><s>Amino acids are also utilized.</s><s>Microaerophilic growth was observed with L-arabinose, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, D-fructose, D-glucose, malate, mannitol and L-tartrate and does not occur with <i>meso</i>-erythritol, <i>meso</i>-inositol and L-rhamnose.</s><s>16S rDNA sequence similarity within the species is 98.8-99.4%.</s><s>The G+­C content of the DNA is 63±2 mol%.</s><s>The type strain is GSF30<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 13128<sup>T</sup>); DNA G+­C content is 64 mol%.</s><s>The organisms are associated with roots, stems and leaves of the C4-gramineous plants <i>Spartina pectinata</i>, <i>Miscanthus sinensis</i>, <i>Miscanthus sacchariflorus</i> and <i>Pennisetum purpureum</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>