<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5228_nm.2787" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2787" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2787" rank="species">Psychrobacter faecalis</organism><reference id="rid.5228"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Albrecht</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Buczolits</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Busse</surname><given-names>H.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Psychrobacter faecalis sp. nov., a new species from a bioaerosol originating from pigeon faeces.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>25</volume><fpage>31</fpage><lpage>36</lpage><source id="121">Systematic and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>Syst Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0723-2020</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1078/0723-2020-00099</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12086186</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Psychrobacter faecalis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Psychrobacter faecalis</i> (fae.ca´lis, L. n. <i>faex</i> faecis, dregs; M.L. adj. <i>faecalis</i>, faecal)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight rods, 0.8 to 1.2 μm by 1 to 2 μm.</s><s>Cells occur singly, they are nonmotile, Gram-negative, oxidase positive, catalase positive; with an oxidative, chemoheterotrophic metabolism.</s><s>Ubiquinone Q-8 is the major quinone type, beside low amounts of ubiquinone Q-9 and Q-7; spermidine is the major polyamine.</s><s>The polar lipid profile is characterized by the presence of phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol, and diphosphatidylglycerol.</s><s>The fatty acids 18:1 <i>ω</i>9<i>c</i>, 17:1 <i>ω</i>8<i>c</i> and summed feature 3 (16:1 <i>ω</i>7<i>c</i> and iso 15:0 2OH), in addition to the hydroxylated fatty acid 12:0 3OH are produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>On nutrient Agar, colonies are circular, opaque slightly raised, and beige with entire margins.</s><s>The type strain Iso-46<sup>T</sup> grew well at 4 to 36 °C on different complex media, like R2A-Agar, Nutrient Agar, no growth was found at 45, and 55 °C on Nutrient Agar.</s><s>No growth occurred on Salmonellα-Shigella Agar.</s></p><p class="description"><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is not produced.</s><s>Indole production, growth on Simmons citrate, urease, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase were all negative.</s><s>No acid production from the following sugars could be detected: glucose, lactose, sucrose, D-mannitol, dulcitol, salicin, adonitol, inositol, sorbitol, L-arabinose, raffinose, L-rhamnose, maltose, D-xylose, trehalose, cellobiose, methyl-D-glucoside, erythritol, melibiose, D-arabitol, and D-mannose.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Utilization of N-acetyl-D-galactosamine, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, L-arabinose (weak), D-glucose (weak), acetate, propionate (weak), <i>cis</i>-aconitate, 4-aminobutyrate, citrate, fumarate, glutarate, DL-3-hydroxybutyrate, DL-lactate, L-malate, 2-oxoglutarate, pyruvate, L-alanine, L-aspartate, L-leucine, and L-ornithine (weak) was positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole sources of carbon: L-arbutine, cellobiose, D-galactose, gluconate, D-maltose, D-mannose, α-D-melibiose, L-rhamnose, D-ribose, sucrose, salicine, D-trehalose, D-xylose, adonitol, <i>i</i>-inositol, D-sorbitol, glycerol, D-fructose, D-mannitol, maltitol, putrescine, <i>trans</i>-aconitate, mesaconate, adipate, azelate, itaconate, suberate, β-alanine, L-phenylalanine, L-serine, L-proline, L-histidine, L-tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, and phenylacetate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The chromogenic substrates <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-α-Dglucopyranoside, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-galactopyranoside (pNPG), ONPG, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-glucuronide, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl- β-D-glucopyranoside, <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-β-D-xylopyranoside, 2–deoxythymidine-5'-<i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-phosphate, L-glutamate-γ-3–carboxy-<i>p</i>-nitroanilide, L-proline-<i>p</i>-nitroanilide, and <i>p</i>-nitrophenyl-phosphoryl-choline were not hydrolysed.</s><s>Only hydrolysis of L-alanine-<i>p</i>-nitroanilide and bis-pNP-phosphate was positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain Iso-46<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 14664<sup>T</sup>=CIP 107288<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Strain Iso-46<sup>T</sup> has been isolated from a bioaerosol originating from pigeon faeces on MacConkey Agar.</s><s>The 16S rRNA gene sequence is deposited at the EMBL data bank under the accession number AJ421528.</s></p></content></protolog>