<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.571_nm.1821" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1821" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.1821" rank="species">Ottowia thiooxydans</organism><reference id="rid.571"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Spring</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jäckel</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wagner</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Ottowia thiooxydans gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel facultatively anaerobic, N2O-producing bacterium isolated from activated sludge, and transfer of Aquaspirillum gracile to Hylemonella gracilis gen. nov., comb. nov.</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>99</fpage><lpage>106</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02727-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14742465</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Ottowia thiooxydans</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Ottowia thiooxydans</em> (thi.o.ox′y.dans. Gr. n. <em>thion</em> sulfur; N.L. v. <em>oxydo</em> to make acid, oxidize; N.L. part. adj. <em>thiooxydans</em> oxidizing sulfur).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are straight to slightly curved rods with pointed ends, 0·8 μm wide and 2–6 μm long, occurring singly, in pairs or short chains.</s><s>Colonies are small (diameter approx. 1 mm), circular, smooth, slightly raised and translucent with a cream to yellow pigmentation.</s><s>Temperature and pH ranges for growth are 2–29 °C and pH 5·6–9·8.</s><s>Optimal conditions for growth are pH 6·8–7·8 and 25–27 °C.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic growth with nitrate and nitrite.</s><s>Produces N<sub>2</sub>O as sole end product of nitrate respiration.</s><s>Substrates assimilated under aerobic conditions (0·1 % w/v): acetate, aconitate, fumarate, glutarate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, dl-lactate, l-malate, propionate, pyruvate, suberate, l-aspartate, l-leucine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline and phenylacetate.</s><s>Carbon sources not assimilated under aerobic conditions (0·1 % w/v): <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gluconate, d-glucose, d-mannose, d-maltose, <em>α</em>-d-melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, salicin, d-trehalose, d-xylose, adonitol, i-inositol, maltitol, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, adipate, 4-aminobutyrate, azelate, citrate, itaconate, mesaconate, oxoglutarate, l-alanine, l-histidine, l-ornithine, l-serine, l-tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate and putrescine.</s><s>Negative for aesculin hydrolysis (<em>β</em>-glucosidase).</s><s>Thiosulfate can be utilized as cosubstrate for aerobic chemolithoheterotrophic growth and is oxidized to sulfate.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 59 mol% (<em>T</em><sub>m</sub>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, K11<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 14619<sup>T</sup>=JCM 11629<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from activated sludge of a high-load basin of a municipal wastewater-treatment plant.</s></p></content></protolog>