<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12545_nm.21406" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21406" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21406" rank="species">Desertibacter roseus</organism><reference id="rid.12545"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Dai</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Cai</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Rahman</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fang</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Desertibacter roseus gen. nov., sp. nov., a gamma radiation-resistant bacterium in the family Rhodospirillaceae, isolated from desert sand</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1109</fpage><lpage>1113</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.021246-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20543156</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Desertibacter roseus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Desertibacter roseus</em> (ro′se.us. L. masc. adj. <em>roseus</em> rose-coloured, pink).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Colonies are pink, circular and convex with regular margins.</s><s>Cells contain PHB.</s><s>Growth occurs at 12–42 °C (optimum 37–40 °C), at pH 7–10 (optimum pH 8) and at NaCl concentrations of up to 1.5 % (optimum 0.5 % NaCl).</s><s>Hydrolyses aesculin and gelatin but not casein, tyrosine or starch.</s><s>In API ZYM tests, positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, β-galactosidase (weakly) and α-glucosidase (weakly) and negative for lipase (C14), trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, β-glucosidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase.</s><s>In API 20NE tests, shows positive reactions for nitrate reduction, aesculin hydrolysis, gelatin hydrolysis, urease and β-galactosidase and negative reactions for arginine dihydrolase, indole production and glucose fermentation.</s><s>Does not assimilate d-glucose, l-arabinose, maltose, d-mannose, d-mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, adipic acid, capric acid, malic acid, potassium gluconate, trisodium citrate or phenylacetic acid.</s><s>In API 20E tests, shows positive reactions for β-galactosidase, Voges–Proskauer reaction, urease and gelatin hydrolysis, but negative reactions for arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, citrate utilization, H<sub>2</sub>S production, tryptophan deaminase, indole production and oxidation of glucose, mannitol, inositol, sorbitol, rhamnose, sucrose, melibiose, amygdalin and arabinose.</s><s>Susceptible to (per disc) erythromycin (15 µg), vancomycin (30 µg), streptomycin (10 µg), acheomycin (30 µg) and penicillin (10 IU).</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 71.4 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, 2622<sup>T</sup> ( = CCTCC AB 208152<sup>T</sup>  = KCTC 22436<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from sand from the Taklimakan desert in Xinjiang, China.</s></p></content></protolog>