<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7248_nm.5063" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5063" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4958" rank="species">Virgibacillus pantothenticus</organism><reference id="rid.7248"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Heyndrickx</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lebbe</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Forsyth</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Virgibacillus: a new genus to accommodate Bacillus pantothenticus (Proom and Knight 1950). Emended description of Virgibacillus pantothenticus.</article-title><year>1998</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>99</fpage><lpage>106</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-48-1-99</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Virgibacillus</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Virgibacillus</i> (Vir.gi.ba.cil'lus. L. n. <i>virga</i> a green twig, transf., a branch in a family tree; L. dim. n. <i>bacillus</i> from <i>Bacillus</i>, a genus of aerobic endospore-forming bacteria; <i>Virgibacillus</i> a branch of the genus <i>Bacillus</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are motile, Gram-positive rods (0.5-0.7 by 2-5 μm) which often form chains.</s><s>They bear spherical to ellipsoidal endospores which lie in terminal, sometimes subterminal, positions in swollen sporangia.</s><s>After 2 d on Trypticase Soy agar colonies are small (0-5-2 mm in diameter), circular and slightly irregular, smooth, glossy or sometimes matt, flat, butyrous, creamy to yellowish white and almost opaque.</s><s>Members of the genus are facultatively anaerobic and catalase positive.</s><s>They have a nutritional requirement for pantothenic acid, thiamin, biotin and amino acids.</s><s>In the API 20E strip and in conventional tests the Voges-Proskauer reaction is negative, indole is not produced, nitrate reduction to nitrite is variable.</s><s>Hydrolysis of casein and of aesculin positive, hydrolysis of gelatin usually positive, and hydrogen sulphide is usually not produced (but a few strains give weak positive reactions in the API 20E strip).</s><s>A few strains also give positive reactions for arginine dihydrolase, citrate utilization and ONPG in the API 20E strip.</s><s>Growth is stimulated by 4% NaCl and not inhibited by 10% NaCl.</s><s>Growth may occur between 15 and 50°C, with an optimum of about 37°C.</s><s>Acid without gas is produced from the following carbohydrates in the API 5OCHB gallery: N-acetylglucosamine, arbutin, D-fructose, galactose, D-glucose, maltose, D-mannose, ribose, salicin, D-tagatose, trehalose; acid production from the following carbohydrates is variable: amygdalin, D-arabinose, cellobiose, L-fucose, β-gentiobiose, gluconate, glycerol, glycogen, inositol, lactose, methyl α-D-glucoside, methyl α-D-mannoside, rhamnose, sorbitol, starch, sucrose and D-turanose.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15:0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub>.</s><s>The major quinone is menaquinone 7 (27).</s><s>Murein of the type strain of the type species has been reported as <i>meso</i>-DAP direct type (3).</s><s>The G+C content has been reported (7) as 36.9 (T<sub>m</sub>) while we found 38.3 mol% to be the mean of two determinations for the type strain of the only species, <i>Virgibacillus pantothenticus</i>.</s></p></content></protolog>