<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2216_nm.3426" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3426" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3426" rank="species">Haemophilus felis</organism><reference id="rid.2216"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Inzana</surname><given-names>T.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shell</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Møller</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kilian</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Isolation and characterization of a newly identified Haemophilus species from cats: "Haemophilus felis."</article-title><year>1992</year><volume>30</volume><fpage>2108</fpage><lpage>2112</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1500518</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Haemophilus felis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s>Chronic bronchitis in cats can be triggered by many causes, such as immotile cilia syndrome, bronchiectasis, feline asthma, and viral or parasitic infection. The resulting inflammation may cause mucosal hyperemia and edema, proliferation of bronchial glands and goblet cells, and increased secretions. In the case of the cat described in this report, chronic accumulation of mucous in the respiratory tract (similar to human cystic fibrosis) was apparently the predisposing condition causing obstructive pulmonary disease. Secondary bacterial colonization and infection can exacerbate the clinical signs and prevent normal recovery by inducing inflammation. The isolate from this cat was obtained from the specimen in pure culture. An <i>Haemophilus</i> species from cats has not previously been recognized as a pathogen, and therefore, the isolate described here probably colonized the respiratory tract of an already compromised animal. The isolate was initially identified as <i>H. paraphrophilus</i>, but <i>H. paraphrophilus</i> is a commensal organism of the mouths and throats of healthy humans (4) and has not previously been recovered from cats or any other animal species. Because the organism was strongly catalase positive, oxidase negative, and biochemically more similar to <i>H. parasuis</i>, extensive biochemical and DNA testing was done.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Besides catalase, other predominant features that distinguished the isolate from the cat from <i>H. paraphrophilus</i> was a delayed hemolytic reaction on sheep blood agar in the presence of Staphylococcus species; the lack of gas from glucose (although <i>H. paraphrophilus</i> strains were variable for gas production); failure to ferment melibiose, trehalose, and ribose; and fermentation of mannitol.</s><s>In addition, the acid produced by the isolate from the cat in fermentation tests was relatively weak, reducing the pH of the medium (e.g., mannitol) from 7.6 to only 6.5, which is similar to the degree of acidification produced by <i>H. parasuis</i> (7).</s><s>In contrast, the acid produced by H. paraphrophilus carbohydrate fermentation reduces the pH of the medium to 5.4 or less (7).</s><s>The isolate differed from H. parasuis in colony morphology, CO<sub>2</sub> requirement, α-fucosidase activity, and mannitol and ribose fermentation.</s><s>However, some isolates tentatively identified as <i>H. parasuis</i> from pigs have demonstrated improved growth in the presence of CO<sub>2</sub> (7).</s><s>The isolate was substantially different from taxon D in many of the biochemicals.</s><s>The G+C content of 38% for the isolate from the cat was similar to the G+C content of 37% for our reference strain of <i>H. parasuis</i> and the mean 38.7% G+C content reported for the <i>Haemophilus</i> type species <i>H. influenzae</i> (7, 14).</s><s>The G+C content of 40% for our reference strain of <i>H. paraphrophilus</i> was very similar to the average G+C content of 41.9% for five <i>H. paraphrophilus</i> strains reported previously (7).</s></p><p class="description"><s>DNA reassociation data between the isolate from the cat and five other <i>Haemophilus</i> species confirmed that the isolate is a distinct species.</s><s>However, DNA reassociation was greatest between the isolate from the cat and <i>H. paraphrophilus</i>, supporting the similarity in colonial morphology, supplemental CO<sub>2</sub> requirement, and some biochemical tests.</s><s>The next closest association was with <i>H. parasuis</i>, which also shared some biochemical similarities with the isolate from the cat.</s><s>Therefore, the isolate was tentatively assigned to the genus <i>Haemophilus</i> as "<i>H. felis</i>." Differentiation of "<i>H. felis</i>" from other <i>Haemophilus</i> species is most easily determined by host specificity, colony morphology, catalase and oxidase activities, and mannitol</s></p><p class="description"><s>and ribose fermentations.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Culture samples from the nasopharynxes of 28 apparently normal cats resulted in the isolation of bacteria that required NAD and that were morphologically identical to the original isolate from six cats.</s><s>For nine isolates that survived, all biochemical tests were identical to those for the original isolate from the cat except for weak raffinose fermentation by two isolates and weak salicin fermentation by one isolate, as determined by pH measurement.</s><s>Therefore, "<i>H. felis</i>" or "<i>H. felis</i>"-like organisms may be relatively common inhabitants of the feline upper respiratory tract, but it has only now been identified because of its isolation in pure culture from a cat with chronic respiratory disease.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Antibiotic susceptibility testing indicated that resistance to ampicillin can occur, but the organism would be susceptible to most cephalosporins, chloramphenicol, imipenem, tetracycline, and trimethoprim-sulfamethoxazole.</s></p></content></protolog>