<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6691_nm.8441" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8441" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6085" rank="species">Agromyces hippuratus</organism><reference id="rid.6691"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ortiz-Martinez</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gonzalez</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Evtushenko</surname><given-names>L.I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jurado</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Laiz</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Groth</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Saiz-Jimenez</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Reclassification of Agromyces fucosus subsp. hippuratus as Agromyces hippuratus sp. nov., comb. nov. and emended description of Agromyces fucosus</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1553</fpage><lpage>1556</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02856-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15388709</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Agromyces hippuratus</em> sp. nov., comb. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Agromyces hippuratus</em> (hip.pu.ra′tus. N.L. n. <em>hippuratum</em> hippurate; N.L. masc. adj. <em>hippuratus</em> pertaining to hippurate, relating to the ability to decompose hippurate).</s></p><p class="nomenclature"><s>Basonym: <em>Agromyces fucosus</em> subsp. <em>hippuratus</em> Zgurskaya <em>et al.</em> 1992.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The description is based on phenotypical data of Zgurskaya <em>et al.</em> (1992), Gnilozub <em>et al.</em> (1994), Malysheva (1994), Groth <em>et al.</em> (1996), Suzuki <em>et al.</em> (1996), Altenburger <em>et al.</em> (1997) and Dorofeeva <em>et al.</em> (2003).</s><s>Colonies on nutrient media are opaque, entire, convex and usually penetrate into the agar media.</s><s>Produces a yellow carotenoid pigment.</s><s>Branching hyphae (width, 0·2–0·6 mm) break into diphtheroid and rod-like, irregular, non-motile fragments.</s><s>Aerobic, catalase- and oxidase-positive.</s><s>Mesophilic; optimum growth is at 26–30 °C.</s><s>Strains are able to grow at 7 °C; weak or no growth occurs at 37 °C.</s><s>d-Arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, maltose, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, l-rhamnose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose and d-xylose are used for growth as sole carbon sources in a salt medium supplemented with 0·1 % (w/v) yeast extract (Zgurskaya <em>et al.</em>, 1992).</s><s>Adonitol, dulcitol, <em>meso</em>-inositol, lyxose, d-mannitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-arabinopyranoside and l-sorbose are not used as sole carbon sources in the same medium.</s><s>Acids are produced from d-arabinose, glycerol and l-rhamnose; no acid production from cellobiose, inulin, lactose, maltose, raffinose, d-ribose, salicin or trehalose.</s><s>Acid production from l-arabinose and sucrose is variable.</s><s>Fumarate, hippurate, malate and pyruvate are utilized.</s><s>No alkaline reactions with ascorbate, citrate, gluconate, oxalate, propionate, salicylate, succinate and tartrate are observed; some strains show positive reaction with <em>trans</em>-aconitate.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite and tyrosinase is produced.</s><s>Aesculin, hypoxanthine and starch are hydrolysed.</s><s>Adenine, elastin, guanine, pectin, testosterone, urea and xanthine are not decomposed or hydrolysed.</s><s>Casein is usually not hydrolysed.</s><s>Indole test is negative.</s><s>No growth occurs on media supplemented with 5 % NaCl, 0·01 % sodium azide or 0·0175 % potassium tellurite.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-12 with a minor amount of MK-13.</s><s>Polyamine content is low; putrescine and spermidine are predominant compounds (data for the type strain only).</s><s>Cell wall sugars are rhamnose, galactose and trace mannose.</s><s>Cell wall contains 1,5-poly(ribitol phosphate) teichoic acid.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA is about 71 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from soil.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is VKM Ac-1352<sup>T</sup> (=JCM 9087<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>The GenBank/EMBL/DDBJ accession number for the 16S rRNA gene sequence of this strain is D45061.</s></p></content></protolog>