<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12549_nm.21410" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.21410" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.21410" rank="species">Ruegeria faecimaris</organism><reference id="rid.12549"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>K.-H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>Y.-T.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>T.-K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yoon J.-H.</surname><given-names /></person-name></authors><article-title>Ruegeria faecimaris sp. nov., isolated from a tidal flat sediment</article-title><year>2011</year><volume>61</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1182</fpage><lpage>1188</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.025999-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20562248</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Ruegeria faecimaris</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Ruegeria faecimaris</em> (fae.ci.ma′ris. L. n. <em>faex faecis</em> sediment; L. gen. n. <em>maris</em> of the sea; N.L. gen. n. <em>faecimaris</em> of the sediment of the sea).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells stain Gram-negative, are non-motile and rod-shaped.</s><s>Cells are 0.3–0.6×1.0–8.0 µm; a few cells longer than 10.0 µm may occur.</s><s>Colonies on MA are circular, glistening, convex, smooth, greyish yellow in colour and 0.5–2.0 mm in diameter after incubation for 5 days at 30 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at 4 and 37 °C, but not at 40 °C.</s><s>Optimal pH for growth is between 7.0 and 8.0; growth occurs at pH 5.0, but not at pH 4.5.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 7.0 % (w/v) NaCl, but not in the absence of NaCl or in the presence of more than 8.0 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Hypoxanthine, l-tyrosine and Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80 are hydrolysed and aesculin is weakly hydrolysed, but casein, gelatin, starch, urea and xanthine are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-mannose, acetate, citrate, l-malate, pyruvate and succinate are utilized as carbon and energy sources, but l-arabinose, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, d-xylose, benzoate, formate, salicin, l-glutamate are not utilized.</s><s>Acid is produced from d-galactose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose and sucrose, but not from l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, d-sorbitol, trehalose or d-xylose.</s><s>Susceptible to ampicillin, carbenicillin, cephalothin, chloramphenicol, gentamicin, kanamycin, neomycin, penicillin G, polymyxin B and streptomycin, but not to lincomycin, novobiocin, oleandomycin or tetracycline.</s><s>In assays with the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase and acid phosphatase are present and esterase (C4) is weakly present, but esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase are absent.</s><s>The predominant ubiquinone is Q-10.</s><s>The major fatty acid (&#x003E;10 % of total fatty acids) is C<sub>18 : 1</sub>ω7<em>c</em>.</s><s>The major polar lipids are phosphatidylcholine, phosphatidylglycerol, an unidentified aminolipid and two unidentified lipids.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 57.9 mol% (determined by HPLC).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, HD-28<sup>T</sup> ( = KCTC 23044<sup>T</sup> = CCUG 58878<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a tidal flat of Hwang-do, Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>