<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3444_nm.5068" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5068" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5068" rank="species">Virgibacillus proomii</organism><reference id="rid.3444"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Heyndrickx</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lebbe</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kersters</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Hoste</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Wachter</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>De Vos</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Forsyth</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Proposal of Virgibacillus proomii sp. nov. and emended description of Virgibacillus pantothenticus (Proom and Knight 1950) Heyndrickx et al. 1998.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>1083</fpage><lpage>1090</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-49-3-1083</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10425765</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Virgibacillus proomii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Virgibacillus proomii</i> (proom.i.i. M.L. adj. <i>proomii</i> of Proom, referring to Harold Proom, the person who, with B. C. J. G. Knight, first isolated a member of this species and who described Bacillus pantothenticus)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are motile, Gram-positive, usually long, rods (0.5-0.7 by 2-8 μm) which sometimes, especially in cells form filaments), creamy-grey and almost opaque with an eggshell or matt appearance;the appearance under x 10 magnification is reminiscent of white soapflakes in a greyish matrix.</s><s>After 4 d colonies smell of ammonia and are 5-10 mm in diameter with lobed and/or fimbriate margins.</s><s>Organisms are facultatively anaerobic and catalase-positive, and they may have a nutritional requirement for pantothenic acid, thiamin, biotin and amino acids.</s><s>The Voges-Proskauer reaction is negative.</s><s>Hydrogen sulphide is not produced, but a few strains may give positive reactions for arginine older cultures, form chains and/or filaments.</s><s>They bear spherical to ellipsoidal endospores which lie in dihydrolase and citrate utilization in the API 20E strip.</s><s>Indole is not produced.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Hydrolysis of aesculin and of casein positive; hydrolysis of gelatin usually positive.</s><s>Growth may occur between 15 and 50°C, with an optimum of about 37°C.</s><s>Acid without gas is produced from the following carbohydrates : N-acetylglucosamine, arbutin, D-fructose, galactose, D-glucose, inositol, maltose, D-mannose, ribose, salicin, D-tagatose and trehalose.</s><s>Acid production from the following carbohydrates is variable : amygdalin, cellobiose and gluconate (these three usually negative), glycogen, methyl α-D-glucoside, rhamnose, starch and sucrose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from the following carbohydrates: adonitol, D- or L-arabinose, D- or L-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, D- or L-fucose, β-gentiobiose, glycerol, inulin, 2-keto-D-gluconate, 5-keto-D-gluconate, lactose, D-lyxose, mannitol, D-melibiose, D-melezitose, methyl α-D-mannoside, methylxyloside, D-raffinose, sorbitol, L-sorbose, D-turanose, xylitol or D- or L-xylose.</s><s>The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C<sub>15:0</sub>, and anteiso-C<sub>15:0</sub> present in about equal amounts.</s><s>iso-C<sub>15:0</sub> is always present at a level of more than 0.5% of the total fatty acids.</s><s>The G+C content is 37 mol% for the type strain, LMG 12370<sup>T</sup>, and 36.8 mol% for strain LMG 17368; the 16s rRNA sequence of the type strain is deposited at EMBL under accession number AJO 12667.</s><s>In the variable characters listed above, the type strain is weak for hydrolysis of gelatin; and acid without gas is produced from methyl α-D-glucoside, starch and sucrose, but not from amygdalin, cellobiose, gluconate, glycogen and rhamnose.</s></p></content></protolog>