<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1423_nm.9326" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.9326" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.9326" rank="species">Nonomuraea kuesteri</organism><reference id="rid.1423"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kämpfer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kroppenstedt</surname><given-names>R.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grün-Wollny</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Nonomuraea kuesteri sp. nov.</article-title><year>2005</year><volume>55</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>847</fpage><lpage>851</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.63380-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15774673</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Nonomuraea kuesteri</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Nonomuraea kuesteri</em> (kue′ster.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>kuesteri</em> of Küster, in honour of Eberhard Küster, a German microbiologist, in recognition of his numerous contributions to the taxonomy of actinomycetes).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Forms an extensive branched substrate mycelium.</s><s>Only traces of aerial mycelium are visible on oatmeal agar.</s><s>Spore chains are spiral; sporangia are not detected.</s><s>Gram-positive and oxidase-positive; shows oxidative metabolism.</s><s>Good growth occurs after 3 days incubation on oatmeal agar and nutrient agar (Oxoid) at 25–30 °C.</s><s>dl-Diaminopimelic acid is the diagnostic amino acid in the peptidoglycan.</s><s>The main menaquinones of the type strain are MK-9(H<sub>4</sub>) (71 %), MK-9(H<sub>6</sub>) (15 %), MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>) (6 %) and MK-9 (2 %); MK-8(H<sub>4</sub>) (6 %) is also present.</s><s>The polar lipids include diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol, phosphatidylethanolamine, methyl-phosphatidylethanolamine and the diagnostic phospholipid <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine.</s><s>The fatty acids comprise mainly iso- and 10-heptadecanoic-branched fatty acids.</s><s>Smaller amounts of unsaturated and 2-hydroxy fatty acids are also detected.</s><s>Results of carbon-source utilization and degradation tests (including differentiating characteristics) are shown in Table 1.</s><s>The type strain does not produce acids from the following sugars: glucose, lactose, sucrose, d-mannitol, dulcitol, salicin, adonitol, inositol, sorbitol, l-arabinose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, maltose, d-xylose, trehalose, cellobiose, methyl d-glucoside, erythritol, melibiose and arabitol.</s><s>The following carbon sources are utilized (after 7 days incubation): <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-mannose, d-melibiose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, d-trehalose, d-xylose, adonitol, d-mannitol, fumarate (weak), dl-lactate, malate, 2-oxoglutarate, l-aspartate (weak) and l-proline.</s><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized: <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>p</em>-arbutin, d-gluconate, d-maltose, d-ribose, salicin, inositol, maltitol, sorbitol, putrescine, acetate, propionate, <em>cis</em>-aconitate, <em>trans</em>-aconitate, adipate, 4-aminobutyrate, azelate, citrate, glutarate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, itaconate, mesaconate, pyruvate, suberate, l-alanine, <em>β</em>-alanine, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-tryptophan, dl-3-hydroxybenzoate, dl-4-hydroxybenzotae and l-phenylacetate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, GW 14-1925<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 44753<sup>T</sup>=NRRL B-24325<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a soil sample.</s></p></content></protolog>