<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.67_nm.3317" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.3317" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.3317" rank="species">Serratia entomophila</organism><reference id="rid.67"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jackson</surname><given-names>T.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ageron</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Noonan</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Serratia entomophila sp. nov. associated with amber disease in the New Zealand grass grub Costelytra zealandica.</article-title><year>1988</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>6</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-38-1-1</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Serratia entomophila</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Serratia entomophila</i> (en.to.mo'phi.la. Gr. noun <i>entomon</i>, insect; Gr. vb. <i>phylein</i>, love; L. fem. adj. <i>entomophila</i>, insect loving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative , nonsporeforming, nonencapsulated , straight rods with peritrichous flagella.</s><s>The species conforms to the definition of the family <i>Enterobacteriaceae</i> (4) and produces the enterobacterial common antigen.</s></p><p class="description"><s>All strains grow on nutrient agar, producing colonies of about 2.5 to 3 mm in diameter after 24 h at 30 or 37°C.</s><s>The colonies are whitish and opaque and have smooth, entire edges.</s><s>Facultatively anaerobic.</s><s>All strains grow well in 1 day at 10, 20, 30, and 37°C and weakly at 4°C (in 4 days) or 41°C (in 1 day) in tryptic soy broth.</s><s>However, 37°C is not optimal for biochemical characterization, and incubation at 30°C is preferred.</s><s>No growth occurs at or above 42°C.</s><s>Growth occurs on caprylate-thallous agar at 30°C in 2 to 6 days.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase produced.</s><s>Oxidase not produced.</s><s>Nitrates reduced to nitrites.</s><s>Tetrathionate not reduced.</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S not produced in glucose-lactose-iron agar or triple sugar iron agar.</s><s>Urea not hydrolyzed in urea-indole medium. <i>o</i>-Nitrophenyl-β-D-galactopyranoside hydrolyzed.</s><s>γ-Glutamyltransferase test positive; β-glucuronidase and β-xylosidase tests negative.</s><s>Indole not produced in peptone water or urea-indole medium.</s><s>Tryptophan and phenylalanine not deaminated.</s><s>Lysine, arginine, and ornithine not decarboxylated (Mgller medium).</s><s>Tributyrin and chitin hydrolyzed by most strains; DNA, gelatin, Tween 20, Tween 40, Tween 60, and Tween 80 hydrolyzed.</s><s>Starch not hydrolyzed in 4 days.</s><s>Glucose fermented without gas production.</s><s>Voges-Proskauer test positive.</s><s>Methyl red usually negative.</s><s>Acid produced from adonitol (2 to 4 days), D-cellobiose (3 to 4 days), galacturonate (1 to 4 days), glycerol (1 to 4 days), <i>myo</i>-inositol (1 to 4 days), maltose (1 day), D-mannitol (1 day), D-mannose (1 day), salicin (1 day), sucrose (1 day), and trehalose (1 day).</s><s>Acid production from D-arabitol and D-xylose defines biotypes.</s><s>No acid produced from L-arabinose, dulcitol, lactose, melibiose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-sorbitol, and L-sorbose.</s><s>Esculin hydrolyzed, Gluconate test positive.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth on Simmons citrate.</s><s>No growth factor required.</s><s>Malonate test negative.</s><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources by all strains (in 1 to 4 days): N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, <i>cis</i>-aconitate, <i>trans</i>-aconitate, adonitol, D-alanine, L-alanine, L-aspartate, D-cellobiose, citrate, β-D-fructose, α-L-fucose, fumarate, D-galactose, D-galacturonate, β-gentiobiose, D-gluconate, D-glucosamine , D-glucose , D-glucuronate, L-glutamate, DL-glycerate, glycerol, L-histidine, <i>myo</i>-inositol, itaconate, 2-keto-D-gluconate, 5-keto-D-gluconate, DL-lactate, L-malate, maltose, maltotriose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, β-methyl-D-glucoside, L-proline, putrescine, D-ribose, salicin, L-serine, succinate, sucrose, and D-trehalose.</s><s>Utilization of D-arabitol, L-arabitol, and D-xylose define two biotypes.</s><s>Most strains utilize benzoate, caprate, phenylacetate, propionate, quinate, and L-tyrosine.</s><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: β-alanine, DL-Yamin<i>o</i>-n-valerate, L-arabinose, betaine, <i>o</i>-coumarate, 2-deoxy- D-glucose, 2,3-dihydroxybenzoate, 2,4-dihydroxybenzoate, 3,5-dihydroxybenzoate, dulcitol, <i>meso</i>-erythritol, ethanolamine, ferulate, gentisate, glycine, heptanoate, histamine, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate, DL-β-hydroxybutyrate, lactose, lactulose, malonate, maltitol, D-melezitose, D-melibiose, L-methionine, methyl-α-galactoside, methyl-β-galactoside, 3-O-methylglucose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, methyl-α-D-mannoside, α-methyl-D-xyloside, mucate, palatinose, 3-phenylpropionate, protocatechuate, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, saccharate, sarcosine, D-sorbitol, L-sorbose, D-tagatose, D-tartrate, L-tartrate,<i> meso</i>-tartrate, tricarballylate, trigonelline, tryptamine, D-tryptophan, D-turanose, and vanilate.</s><s>Most strains failed to utilize glutarate, D-malate, and xylitol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The G+C content of the DNA is 58 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Isolated from larvae of <i>C. zealandica</i> (grass grub) with amber disease, and from the environment.</s><s>No strain has been identified as being involved in a human, animal (other than insect), or plant disease.</s><s>The type strain is strain A1<sup>T</sup> (ATCC 43705<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>Strain A1<sup>T</sup> has all the characteristics given above for the species.</s><s>In addition, this strain failed to utilize benzoate, caprate, aketoglutarate, phenylacetate, or propionate as the sole source of carbon and energy.</s><s>Experimentally (per os) pathogenic for <i>C. zealandica</i> larvae.</s></p></content></protolog>