<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.11572_nm.18608" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.18608" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.18608" rank="species">Agromyces atrinae</organism><reference id="rid.11572"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>E.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>M.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>M.-J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Roh</surname><given-names>S.W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chang</surname><given-names>H.-W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Shin</surname><given-names>K.-S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>J.-W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Agromyces atrinae sp. nov., isolated from fermented seafood</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1056</fpage><lpage>1059</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.012294-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19666805</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Agromyces atrinae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Agromyces atrinae</em> [a.tri′na.e. N.L. n. <em>Atrina</em> zoological name for a genus of bivalve mollusc; N.L. gen. n. <em>atrinae</em> of <em>Atrina</em>, referring to the isolation of the type strain from a fermented food prepared from <em>Atrina pectinata</em> (comb pen shell)].</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-staining-positive, aerobic, non-motile and straight or curved rods (1.0–2.0×0.5–1.0 μm) after incubation for 2 days on MA medium at 30 °C.</s><s>Colonies on MA are circular, smooth, convex and yellow.</s><s>Growth occurs in the presence of 0–4 % NaCl, at 10–37 °C and at pH 6–10.</s><s>No growth is detected in an anaerobic chamber on MA.</s><s>Optimal conditions are 30 °C, pH 6–7 and 2 % NaCl on MA or in MB.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Reduces nitrate to nitrite.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: dextrin, glycogen, Tweens 40 and 80, arbutin, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-gluconic acid, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>α</em>-lactose, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-psicose, d-ribose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose, d-xylose, acetic acid, pyruvic acid methyl ester, pyruvic acid, glycerol, adenosine, inosine, thymidine, uridine, thymidine 5′-monophosphate and uridine 5′-monophosphate.</s><s>The following substrates are not utilized: <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, inulin, mannan, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-d-mannosamine, amygdalin, d- and l-arabinose, l-fucose, d-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, lactulose, melezitose, melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, 3-methyl d-glucose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, palatinose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, sedoheptulosan, d-sorbitol, stachyose, d-tagatose, turanose, xylitol, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>-and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acids, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, lactamide, d-lactic acid methyl ester, l-lactic acid, d- and l-malic acid, succinic acid monomethyl ester, propionic acid, succinamic acid, succinic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl-l-glutamic acid, l-alaninamide, d- and l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, putrescine, 2,3-butanediol, 2′-deoxyadenosine, adenosine 5′-monophosphate, d-fructose 6-phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate, d-glucose 6-phosphate and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>With the API ZYM system, positive for leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-galactosidases and <em>α</em>- and <em>β</em>-glucosidases; weakly positive for esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8) and acid phosphatase; negative for alkaline phosphatase, lipase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>The major cell-wall sugars are galactose, mannose and rhamnose.</s><s>The peptidoglycan amino acids are 2,4-diaminobutyric acid, alanine, glutamic acid and glycine.</s><s>The predominant menaquinones are MK-12 and MK-11; minor components are MK-10 and MK-13.</s><s>Major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>, anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub> and iso-C<sub>16 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 69.0 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, P27<sup>T</sup> (=KCTC 19593<sup>T</sup> =JCM 15913<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a traditional fermented seafood in Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>