<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1363_nm.6115" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6115" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6115" rank="subspecies">Clavibacter xyli cynodontis</organism><reference id="rid.1363"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Davis</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gillaspie</surname><given-names>A.G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Vidaver</surname><given-names>A.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Harris</surname><given-names>R.W.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Clavibacter: a new genus containing some phytopathogenic coryneform bacteria, including Clavibacter xyli subsp. xyli sp. nov., subsp. nov. and Clavibacter xyli subsp. cynodontis subsp. nov., pathogens that cause ratoon stunting disease of sugarcane and bermudagrass stunting disease.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>107</fpage><lpage>117</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-2-107</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Clavibacter xyli</i> subsp. <i>cynodontis</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Clavibacter xyli</i> subsp. <i>cynodontis</i> (cy.no.don'tis. N.L. n. <i>Cynodon</i> genus of Bermudagrass; N.L. gen. n. <i>cynodontis</i> of Bermudagrass)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-positive, non-acid-fast, non-endospore-forming , pleomorphic rods that are nonmotile and measure approximately 0.2 by 5.0 μm.</s><s>Colonies on SC agar are circular with entire margins (diameter, 0.4 to 1.0 mm), convex, glistening, and butryous.</s><s>All strains are obligate aerobes.</s><s>Optimal growth occurs at 26 to 30°C; strains do not grow at 36°C.</s><s>All strains produce a yellow pigment which intensifies with the age of the culture.</s><s>All strains produce acid from oxidative fermentation of dextrin, glucose, glycerol, mannitol, mannose, maltose, starch, and trehalose; acid is not produced from adonitol, arabinose, arbutin, cellobiose, dulcitol, esculin, ethanol, fructose, galactose, geraniol, i-inositol, inulin, lactose, melibiose, melezitose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, β-methyl-D-glucoside , propanol, propylene glycol, raffinose, ribose, rhamnose, salicin, sorbitol, sucrose, or xylose.</s><s>Gas is not produced from glucose metabolism.</s><s>Starch is hydrolyzed, but casein, corn oil, esculin, gelatin, Tween 20, Tween 80, tyrosine, and urea are not decomposed.</s><s>KCN is tolerated at a concentration of 0.0075% in RSD broth.</s><s>Nitrate and nitrite are not reduced.</s><s>Catalase and acetoin are produced, but H<sub>2</sub>S, indole, ammonium from peptone, and oxidase are not produced.</s><s>Citrate and malate are utilized, but acetamide, anthranilate, benzoate, citroacontate, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, β-hydroxybutyrate, formate, galacturonate, gluconate, glucuronate, glycolate, lactate, levulinate, maleic acid, malonate, oxalate, propionate, saccharate, succinate, <i>m</i>-tartrate, and tryptamine are not utilized.</s></p><p class="description"><s>This taxon is distinguished from other coryneform bacteria on the basis of the G+C content (66 mol%) of its DNA, the presence of diaminobutyric acid in its peptidoglycan, and its distinct pattern of protein bands in polyacrylamide gels.</s><s>It is distinguished from the other subspecies of <i>Clavibacter xyli</i> sp. nov. by its yellow pigmentation, colony size, ability to utilize citrate and malate, ability to hydrolyze starch, distinct protein bands in polyacrylamide gels, and ability to induce Bermudagrass stunting disease in Bermudagrass [<i>Cynodon dactylon</i> (L.) Pers].</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain TB1A (= ATCC 33973).</s><s>The subspecies description given above is based on six strains, which are virtually indistinguishable; thus, the subspecies description is also the type strain description.</s></p></content></protolog>