<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5742_nm.4586" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4586" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4586" rank="species">Halothermothrix orenii</organism><reference id="rid.5742"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Cayol</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ollivier</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>B.K.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Prensier</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Guezennec</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garcia</surname><given-names>J.L.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Isolation and characterization of Halothermothrix orenii gen. nov., sp. nov., a halophilic, thermophilic, fermentative, strictly anaerobic bacterium.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>534</fpage><lpage>540</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-3-534</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7520742</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Halothermothrix orenii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Halothemzothrix orenii</i> (O.ren'i.i M.L. gen. n. <i>orenii</i>, of Oren, name in honor of Aharon Oren, who made important contributions to the knowledge of halophilic anaerobic bacteria)</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to the characteristics given in the description above, <i>H. orenii</i> has the characteristics described below.</s><s>Colonies are yellow, flat, and circular with 0.5- to 1-mm diameters.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophic and strictly anaerobic.</s><s>Oxidizes carbohydrates including arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, galactose, glucose, melibiose, mannose, starch, ribose, and xylose but not lactose, maltose, rhamnose, sucrose, sorbose, cellulose, formate, acetate, butyrate, propionate, fumarate, lactate, malate, succinate, adonitol, dulcitol, glycerol, mannitol, Casamino Acids, bio-Typcase, or trimethylamine.</s><s>The end products of fermentation are acetate, ethanol, H<sub>2</sub>, and CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>NaCl and yeast extract are required for growth.</s><s>The optimum NaCl concentration for growth is about lo%, with upper and lower limits of 20 and 4%, respectively.</s><s>The pH range for growth is 5.5 to 8.2; the optimum pH is 6.5 to 7.0.</s><s>Grows between 45 and 68°C, with no growth occurring at 70°C.</s><s>The optimum temperature for growth is 60°C.</s><s>Isolated from sediments of a Tunisian salted lake (Chott El Guettar) from a depth of 40 to 60 cm but not from any other depth (up to 1.2 m).</s><s>The type strain is strain H168, deposited in the Oregon Collection of Methanogens (OCM 544).</s></p></content></protolog>