<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4628_nm.4965" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4965" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4965" rank="species">Bacillus pseudofirmus</organism><reference id="rid.4628"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Nielsen</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Fritze</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Priest</surname><given-names>F.G.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Phenetic diversity of alkaliphilic Bacillus strains: proposal for nine new species.</article-title><year>1995</year><volume>141</volume><fpage>1745</fpage><lpage>1761</lpage><source id="144">Microbiology</source><issn>0026-2617</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Bacillus pseudofirmus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Bacillus pseudofirmus</i> (pseu.do.fir.mus, Gr. adj. <i>pseudes</i> false; specific epithet firmus. ML adj. <i>pseudofirmus</i> the false firmus; referring to physiological similarities to <i>B. firmus</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>This description is taken from this study for strains of DNA hybridization group 1.</s><s>Colonies are yellow and round with irregular margins.</s><s>Cells are rod-shaped (0.6-0.8 x 3.0-6.0 μm), producing spores which are oval (0.5-0.7 X 0.5-1.2 μm) and located centrally to subterminally without swelling the sporangium.</s><s>The strains in this species are characterized by hydrolysis of Tween 40 and 60, gelatin, casein and starch.</s><s>Hippurate, MUG, pullulan (with the exception of PN-3, PN-10 and PN-72) and Tween 20 are not hydrolysed, nitrate is not reduced but all strains deaminate phenylalanine.</s><s>The strains are strictly alkaliphilic: for most of the strains no growth is obtained at pH 7.0 and the optimum is around pH 9.0.</s><s>The strains show growth from 10 to 45°C.</s><s>Growth is detected in the presence of up to 16 % NaCl, with most strains tolerating 17 % NaCl.</s><s>The carbohydrate utilization profile shows growth on ribose or D-xylose, but no growth on L-arabinose, galactose, rhamnose, sorbitol, lactose, melibiose, melizitose, D-raffinose or D-tagatose.</s><s>The chromosomal DNA composition is between 39·0 and 40.8 mol % G +C.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Source: soil and animal manure.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain of this species is PN-3 (= DSM 8715 = NCIMB 10283).</s></p></content></protolog>