<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4866_nm.6250" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6250" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6250" rank="species">Corynebacterium nigricans</organism><reference id="rid.4866"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Shukla</surname><given-names>S.K.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Bernard</surname><given-names>K.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Harney</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Frank</surname><given-names>D.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Reed</surname><given-names>K.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Corynebacterium nigricans sp. nov.: proposed name for a black-pigmented Corynebacterium species recovered from the human female urogenital tract</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>4353</fpage><lpage>4358</lpage><source id="183">Journal of Clinical Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Clin Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0095-1137</issn><essn>1098-660X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1128/JCM.41.9.4353-4358.2003</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12958268</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Corynebacterium nigricans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Corynebacterium nigricans</i> ((ni'gri-kanz) is derived from the word “niger” (L. fr. niger, black))</s></p><p class="description"><s>This description is based on the biochemical and genetic characteristics of five strains characterized so far.</s><s>The name  The bacterial cells are gram positive, catalase positive, coccobacillary to rod-shaped, nonmotile, nonsporulated, and 1.25 to 2.5 micron in size.</s><s>Colonies are small, dry, nonhemolytic, and granular.</s><s>They are pitted, with a strong adhesion to agar.</s><s>The colonies grow up to 2 to 3 mm in size after 48 h.</s><s>The colonies produce black pigmentation on heme-containing sheep blood agar, colistin-naladixic acid agar, chocolate agar, and non-heme-containing brain heart infusion agar after 24 to 48 h of incubation.</s><s>In a laboratory, these could be the criteria to distinguish this coryneform from other coryneforms.</s><s>The pigment is not water soluble.</s><s>Colonies also turn black on trypticase soy agar after 4 to 5 days.</s><s>The organism grows well in ambient air or in air saturated with 5% CO<sub>2</sub>.</s><s>The <i>C. nigricans</i> strain fermented glucose, maltose, and sucrose.</s><s>Ribose and glycogen reactions were variable.</s><s>The fermentation of glycogen, ribose, and sucrose was weak at 24 h of incubation.</s><s>The tests for nitrate reduction, urea, casein, starch, xanthine, and esculin hydrolysis are negative.</s><s>The <i>C. nigricans</i> strains produce variable reactions for pyrazinamidase and alkaline phosphatase as well.</s><s>For example, CN-2 is negative for pyrazinamidase and weakly positive for alkaline phosphatase.</s><s>Interestingly, CN 3415 is negative for alkaline phosphatase and positive for pyrazinamidase (Table 1).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Strain CN-1 is CAMP negative.</s><s>Its major CFAs are hexadecanoic acid and cis-9 octadecanoic acid, and its minor CFAs are tetradecanoic acid, octadecanoic acid, cis-9 hexadecanoic acid, cis-9,12 octadecadienoic acid, and octadecanoic acid.</s><s>Finally, phylogenetic analysis based on 16S rRNA sequence data indicates that all the proposed <i>C. nigricans</i> strains form a closely related group of organisms that exhibit greater than 99% pairwise sequence identity.</s><s>The <i>C. nigricans</i> type strain CN-1 has been deposited into the ATCC as accession ATCC 700795.</s></p></content></protolog>