<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6808_nm.5035" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5035" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5035" rank="species">Gracilibacillus halotolerans</organism><reference id="rid.6808"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Wainø</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tindall</surname><given-names>B.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ingvorsen</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Gracilibacillus gen. nov., with description of Gracilibacillus halotolerans gen. nov., sp. nov.; transfer of Bacillus dipsosauri to Gracilibacillus dipsosauri comb. nov., and Bacillus salexigens to the genus Salibacillus gen. nov., as Salibacillus salexigens comb. nov.</article-title><year>1999</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>821</fpage><lpage>831</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-47-3-747</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10319508</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Gracilibacillus halotolerans</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Gracilibacillus halotolerans</i> (ha.lo'to.le.rans. Gr. n. <i>hals</i> salt; L. adj. <i>tolerans</i> tolerating; M.L. adj. <i>halotolerans</i> salt-tolerating)</s></p><p class="description"><s>In addition to those characteristics given above for the genus, the following features are characteristic for <i>G. halotolerans</i>.</s><s>Cells are rod-shaped, 0.4-0.6 by 2-5 μm and motile by peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Endospores are ellipsoid.</s><s>Colonies are creamy white.</s><s>Obligately aerobic and extremely halotolerant.</s><s>Grows at 0-20% (w/v) NaCl, with optimal growth at 0% NaCl.</s><s>Growth occurs at temperatures of 6-50 °C (optimum 47 °C).</s><s>The pH range for growth is 5-10 (optimum about pH 7.5).</s><s>H<sub>2</sub>S is produced.</s><s>Tween 80 and urea are hydrolysed.</s><s>Produces alkaline phosphatase.</s><s>Does not produce phenylalanine deaminase, chitinase or lecithinase.</s><s>Cells are resistant to gentamicin, kanamycin, nalidixic acid, neomycin and tetracycline, but susceptible to bacitracin, carbenicillin, erythromycin, novobiocin, penicillin and rifampicin.</s><s>The following compounds (0-2%, w/v) are utilized as growth substrates in Tris-medium (10% NaCl): amylose, DL-arabinose, D-cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, glycogen, inulin, lactose, maltose, D-mannose, D-melibiose, D-melizitose, raffinose, L-rhamnose, starch, D-trehalose, D-xylose, glycerol, L-ascorbic acid, D-galacturonic acid, D-gluconic acid, D-glucuronic acid, L-malate, oxoglutaric acid, N-acetylglucosamine, trimethylamine and Tween 80.</s><s>No growth occurs on fucose, butanol, ethanol, methanol, pentanol, propanol, Dsorbitol, acetate, adipic acid, anisic acid, benzoate, butyrate, caproic acid, caprylate, citrate, formate, fumarate, glutaric acid, glycolate, glyoxylate, lactate, nicotinate, picolinic acid, propionate, pyruvate, succinate, valerate, L-alanine, L-arginine, L-aspartate, betaine, L-cysteine, L-glutamate, L-lysine, L-methionine, L-ornithine, L-phenylalanine, L-proline, L-serine, L-threonine, tryptophan, acetamide, benzamide, sulfanilamide, ethanolamine, methylamine, coconut oil, oil of cedar wood, acetone, cellulose or crab shell chitin.</s><s>Does not ferment glucose or xylose.</s><s>The G + C content is 38 mol %.</s><s>The polar lipids are phosphatidyl glycerol, diphosphatidyl glycerol and two phospholipids of unknown structure.</s><s>The type strain, strain NN<sup>T</sup>, isolated from the Great Salt Lake, Utah, USA, has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen (Braunschweig, Germany) as strain DSM 11805<sup>T</sup>.</s></p></content></protolog>