<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.10789_nm.17896" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.17896" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.17896" rank="species">Kistimonas asteriae</organism><reference id="rid.10789"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>E.J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kwon</surname><given-names>H.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sohn</surname><given-names>Y.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>H.O.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Kistimonas asteriae gen. nov., sp. nov., a gammaproteobacterium isolated from Asterias amurensis</article-title><year>2010</year><volume>60</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>938</fpage><lpage>943</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.014282-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19661507</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Kistimonas asteriae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Kistimonas asteriae</em> (as.te′ri.ae. N.L. gen. n. <em>asteriae</em> of <em>Asterias amurensis</em>, a starfish).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-stain-negative, aerobic, motile and rod-shaped.</s><s>Light-yellow-pigmented colonies are formed on A1+C medium, nutrient agar, marine agar and TSA medium.</s><s>Grows between 15 and 30 °C, with an optimal temperature of 25 °C.</s><s>Does not grow at 4, 10, 37 or 42 °C.</s><s>No growth observed in A1+C medium prepared with deionized water without NaCl.</s><s>No colonies detected when medium contains 11–15 % NaCl.</s><s>Growth is reduced by NaCl at concentrations higher than 9 % (w/v).</s><s>Grows at pH 5–10 but not at pH 4.</s><s>Can utilize the following carbon sources in the API 50CH test: glycerol, ribose, galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, inositol, mannitol, methyl-<em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, <em>β</em>-gentiobiose, turanose, d-tagatose, l-arabitol and potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Can also use gelatin and xylan as a carbon source, but not casein or alginate.</s><s>Shows <em>β</em>-galactosidase activity as determined by a nitrophenyl-<em>β</em>-d-galactopyranoside reaction in API 20E and API 20NE tests (Table 1).</s><s>Does not produce H<sub>2</sub>S, indole or acetoin.</s><s>Positive for the oxidation of glucose, mannitol, sucrose and melibiose, and the assimilation of glucose, mannitol, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, maltose, gluconate and malate in API 20E and API 20NE tests.</s><s>Shows cytochrome oxidase activity.</s><s>API ZYM tests using naphthyl-substrates indicate positive results for the activities of alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4) and esterase lipase (C8).</s><s>However, test results are negative for lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain KMD 001<sup>T</sup> (KCCM 90076<sup>T</sup> =JCM 15607<sup>T</sup>) was isolated from the skin of <em>Asterias amurensis</em> collected at the Im-Won port in Samcheok, East Sea in Korea.</s></p></content></protolog>