<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.7058_nm.5148" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5148" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5148" rank="species">Paenibacillus nematophilus</organism><reference id="rid.7058"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Enright</surname><given-names>M.R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>McInerney</surname><given-names>J.O.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Griffin</surname><given-names>C.T.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Characterization of endospore-forming bacteria associated with entomopathogenic nematodes, Heterorhabditis spp., and description of Paenibacillus nematophilus sp. nov.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>435</fpage><lpage>441</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02344-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12710609</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Paenibacillus nematophilus</em> sp. nov</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Paenibacillus nematophilus</em> (ne.ma.to′phi.lus. N.L. n. <em>nematoda</em> nematode; Gr. adj. <em>philos</em> loving or having affinity for; N.L. adj. <em>nematophilus</em> nematode-loving).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are rod-shaped, motile, 3·5–7·0 μm long and 0·5–1·0 μm wide.</s><s>Cells stain Gram-negative (Gram-variable in older cultures).</s><s>Oval-shaped endospores are produced in swollen, spindle-shaped sporangia and lie in a central/paracentral position.</s><s>Endospore is retained within the sporangium.</s><s>Endospores measure on average 1·7×1·2 μm, while sporangia are 6·5–10·6 μm long.</s><s>Relatively slow-growing on nutrient agar, with colonies measuring 0·5–4·0 mm in diameter.</s><s>Colonies are thin, non-pigmented, regular, smooth and slightly umbonate with an undulate edge.</s><s>Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative.</s><s>Under anaerobic conditions, growth is weak and germination of endospores is poor compared with aerobic conditions.</s><s>Grows in 2 % but not 3 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Grows optimally at 30 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs at between 10 and 37 °C.</s><s>No growth at 5 or 40 °C.</s><s>Growth at pH 6–11; no growth at pH 5·6.</s><s>As determined with API 20E strips, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase and urease are not produced.</s><s>Citrate is not utilized.</s><s>Hydrogen sulfide, indole and NO<sub>2</sub> are not produced.</s><s>Gelatin is not hydrolysed.</s><s>The Voges–Proskauer reaction is positive.</s><s>Starch is hydrolysed.</s><s>Casein and Tween 80 are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Isolates are negative for egg yolk lecithinase activity.</s><s>No colour change in litmus milk.</s><s>In API 50CHB galleries, when API CHB suspension medium is used, aesculin is hydrolysed and acid but no gas is produced from d-glucose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, starch, glycogen and gentiobiose.</s><s>Acid is produced at a slower rate from 5-keto-d-gluconate.</s><s>Utilization of d-mannose is variable (type strain is positive).</s><s>Glycerol, ribose, erythritol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-xylose, l-xylose, adonitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-xyloside, galactose, fructose, sorbose, rhamnose, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, lactose, melibiose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, xylitol, d-turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, gluconate and 2-ketogluconate can not be utilized as sole carbon sources.</s><s>The major fatty acids are anteiso-C<sub>15</sub> and C<sub>16 : 0</sub> and the G+C content is approximately 44 mol% as determined by HPLC.</s><s>The type strain, strain NEM1a<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 13559<sup>T</sup>=NCIMB 13845<sup>T</sup>), and strain NEM1b were found associated with the entomopathogenic nematode <em>H. megidis</em> EU17 isolated from Estonia.</s></p></content></protolog>