<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4541_nm.2979" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2979" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2979" rank="species">Vibrio lentus</organism><reference id="rid.4541"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Macián</surname><given-names>M.C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ludwig</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Aznar</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Grimont</surname><given-names>P.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schleifer</surname><given-names>K.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Garay</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Pujalte</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Vibrio lentus sp. nov., isolated from Mediterranean oysters.</article-title><year>2001</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>1449</fpage><lpage>1456</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11491345</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Vibrio lentus</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Vibrio lentus</i> (len'tus. L. adj. <i>lentus</i> slow)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative rods, facultatively anaerobic, motile by a polar flagellum.</s><s>Colonies are regular in shape and unpigmented.</s><s>Swarming has not been detected.</s><s>Glucose metabolism is fermentative without gas production.</s><s>Tests for catalase, oxidase and nitrate reduction to nitrite are positive.</s><s>Resistant to the vibriostatic agent O129 (150 μg per disc).</s><s>No growth occurs without the addition of NaCl to the culture medium.</s><s>Growth occurs between 4 and 30 °C.</s><s>Not luminescent.</s><s>All strains are positive for Thornley's ADH test.</s><s>Indole is positive in most strains.</s><s>All strains hydrolyse starch, gelatin and Tween 80.</s><s>Acid is produced from D-glucose, D-galactose, D-trehalose, D-mannose, maltose, cellobiose, D-mannitol and melibiose; none of the strains produce acid from L-arabinose, D-xylose, L-rhamnose, D-raffinose, sucrose, D-galacturonate, methyl α-D-glucopyranoside, erythritol, adonitol, D-sorbitol, <i>m</i>-inositol or salicin.</s><s>Strains that do not require growth factors use D-galactose, D-mannose, maltose, cellobiose, N-acetyl D-glucosamine, glycerol, D-mannitol, pyruvate, fumarate, DL-lactate, glycine, L-serine, L-threonine, L-glutamate, L-alanine, aspartate and glutamine as sole carbon sources.</s><s>Most of the strains that do not require growth factors also use D-glucose, D-fructose, D-trehalose, citrate, transaconitate, α-ketoglutarate, succinate, DL-malate, L-citrulline and L-histidine as sole carbon sources.</s><s>None of the strains utilizes the following substrates as sole carbon and energy sources: L-arabinose, D-xylose, L-rhamnose, sucrose, lactose, D-melibiose, D-raffinose, salicin, amygdalin, D-galacturonate, glucosamine, D-sorbitol, <i>m</i>-inositol, DL-glycerate, D-saccharate, methanol, propionate, DL-β-hydroxybutyrate, <i>p</i>-hydroxybenzoate, L-leucine, L-arginine, L-tyrosine, γ-aminobutyrate, L-ornithine, L-lysine, sarcosine and putrescine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain 4OM4<sup>T</sup> (=CECT 5110<sup>T</sup>=DSM 13757<sup>T</sup>).</s><s>In addition to the characteristics given in the species description, the type strain is indole-positive.</s><s>It hydrolyses casein and DNA, but not alginate.</s><s>It does not produce acid from D-mannitol or melibiose.</s><s>It utilizes D-fructose, D-galactose, D-mannose, maltose, N-acetyl D-glucosamine, glycerol, D-mannitol, pyruvate, citrate, <i>trans</i>-aconitate, α-ketoglutarate, succinate, fumarate, DL-malate, DL-lactate, glycine, L-serine, L-threonine, L-glutamate, L-alanine, L-citrulline, aspartate, glutamine and L-histidine as sole carbon sources.</s><s>In addition to the negative traits given above for all 12 strains, the type strain is negative for utilization of D-ribose, D-glucose, D-trehalose, D-gluconate, D-glucuronate and acetate.</s><s>The mean G+­C content is 44.0 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from oysters from the Mediterranean coast of Valencia (Spain).</s></p></content></protolog>