<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.12_nm.1965" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.1965" rank="genus">Iodobacter</organism><reference id="rid.12"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Logan</surname><given-names>N.A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Numerical taxonomy of violet-pigmented, Gram-negative bacteria and description of Iodobacter fluviatile gen. nov., comb. nov.</article-title><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>450</fpage><lpage>456</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Iodobacter</i> gen. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Iodobacter</i> (from Gr. adj. <i>ioeides</i> violet-colored; M. L. masc. n. <i>bacter</i>, the equivalent of Gr. neut. n. <i>bacterion</i>, a small rod; M.L. masc, n. <i>Iodobacter</i>, a violet-colored, small rod)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, straight, round-ended rods 0.7 by 3.0 to 3.5 μm, occurring singly, in pairs, sometimes in chains, and occasionally as long filaments.</s><s>Motile with a single polar flagellum and one or more lateral flagella.</s><s>Grow on ordinary peptone media.</s><s>On low-nutrient media such as 1/4NA, colonies usually differ from those of <i>Chromobacterium</i> and <i>Janthinobacterium</i> species by being very thin, with rough surfaces and irregular edges, and spreading to 1 cm or more in diameter; they are of butyrous consistency and are easily emulsified in water.</s><s>Occasional strains may spread only poorly and may produce slightly gelatinous colonies.</s><s>All strains produce nonspreading colonies on rich media.</s><s>Most strains produce the violet pigment violacein, and this shows most intensely in the centers of spreading colonies.</s><s>Growth in 1/4NB is moderate after 24 h at 25°C, with uniform turbidity aid a violet ring at the surface but no pellicle; strains forming long filaments may appear to gel in broths.</s><s>Chemoorganotrophs; facultative anaerobes which attack carbohydrates fermentatively without gas production.</s><s>Grow at 4 to about 30°C, with optimum growth around 25°C. <i>Iodobacter</i> species differ from <i>Chromobacterium</i> species by inability to grow at 37°C and from <i>Janthinobacterium</i> species by anaerobic growth and fermentative attack of carbohydrates.</s><s>Other characters useful for separating these genera are shown in Table 1.</s></p></content></protolog>