<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1980_nm.10672" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.10672" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.10672" rank="species">Comamonas odontotermitis</organism><reference id="rid.1980"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sheu</surname><given-names>S.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>K.Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arun</surname><given-names>A.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Young</surname><given-names>C.C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Comamonas odontotermitis sp. nov., isolated from the gut of the termite Odontotermes formosanus</article-title><year>2007</year><volume>57</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>887</fpage><lpage>891</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.64551-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17392226</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Comamonas odontotermitis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Comamonas odontotermitis</em> (o.don′to.ter′mi.tis. N.L. n. <em>Odontotermes</em> the scientific name of a genus of termite; N.L. gen. n. <em>odontotermitis</em> of a termite of the genus <em>Odontotermes</em>, referring to the isolation of the type strain from the termite <em>O. formosanus</em>).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Aerobic, Gram-negative, non-spore-forming, motile and rod-shaped.</s><s>After 24 h growth on nutrient agar at 25 °C, the mean cell size is 0.5–1.0 μm width and 2.0–2.5 μm length.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at 28–35 °C, 0–1 % NaCl and pH 7.0.</s><s>In API 20NE tests, shows positive reactions for oxidase (weak), catalase (weak), nitrate reduction and assimilation of gluconate, malate, citrate and phenylacetate and negative reactions for indole production, hydrolysis of aesculin and gelatin, glucose fermentation, arginine dihydrolase, urease, <em>β</em>-galactosidase and assimilation of glucose, arabinose, mannose, maltose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, caprate and adipate.</s><s>In API 20E tests, positive for acetoin production and negative for the ONPG test, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, H<sub>2</sub>S production, tryptophan deaminase, indole production, gelatinase and acid production from glucose, mannitol, inositol, sorbitol, rhamnose, sucrose, melibiose, amygdalin and arabinose.</s><s>In API ZYM tests, shows positive enzyme reactions for alkaline phosphatase, C4 esterase, C8 lipase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and negative reactions for C14 lipase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucuronidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>The following compounds are oxidized in the Biolog GN2 microtitre test system: glycogen, Tweens 40 and 80, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, formic acid, <em>α</em>-, <em>β</em>- and <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acids, <em>α</em>-ketobutyric acid, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid, <em>α</em>-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactate, propionic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, d- and l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, l-pyroglutamic acid and l-threonine.</s><s>Cannot oxidize <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, dextrin, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-galactosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, d-cellobiose, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, <em>myo</em>-inositol, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, <em>cis</em>-aconitic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, <em>p</em>-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, malonic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, l-histidine, d- or l-serine, dl-carnitine, <em>γ</em>-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate, <em>α</em>-d-glucose 1-phosphate or d-glucose 6-phosphate.</s><s>Resistant to ampicillin, penicillin G and rifampicin and sensitive to chloramphenicol, gentamicin, kanamycin, nalidixic acid, novobiocin, streptomycin and tetracycline.</s><s>The major fatty acids are 16 : 0 (33.6 %), 18 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> (16.2 %) and summed feature 3 (16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> and/or 15 : 0 iso 2-OH; 33.9 %).</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 61.6 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain Dant 3-8<sup>T</sup> (=BCRC 17576<sup>T</sup>=LMG 23579<sup>T</sup>) was isolated from the gut of the termite <em>O. formosanus</em> (Shiraki) from southern Taiwan.</s></p></content></protolog>