<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3852_nm.8215" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8215" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8215" rank="species">Algoriphagus ratkowskyi</organism><reference id="rid.3852"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Bowman</surname><given-names>J.P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mancuso Nichols</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Gibson</surname><given-names>J.A.E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Algoriphagus ratkowskyi gen. nov., sp. nov., Brumimicrobium glaciale gen. nov., sp. nov., Cryomorpha ignava gen. nov., sp. nov. and Crocinitomix catalasitica gen. nov., sp. nov., novel flavobacteria isolated from various polar habitats.</article-title><year>2003</year><volume>53</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1343</fpage><lpage>1355</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02553-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">13130017</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Algoriphagus ratkowskyi</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Algoriphagus ratkowskyi</em> (rat.kow′sky.i. N.L. gen. n. <em>ratkowskyi</em> of Ratkowsky, in honour of David A. Ratkowsky, who made significant contributions to growth-modelling of bacteria, including psychrophilic bacteria).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Exhibits the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.</s><s>Cells appear as small coccobacilli (0·3–0·4×0·3–0·9 μm).</s><s>Serpentine filamentous cells (10–20×0·4 μm) may also occur.</s><s>Strains grow at −2 to 25 °C, with a temperature optimum of 16–19 °C.</s><s>Can tolerate up to 1 M NaCl (growth range 0·1–1·0 M NaCl).</s><s>Catalase-negative and cytochrome-<em>c</em> oxidase-positive.</s><s>Can hydrolyse casein.</s><s>Some strains can also hydrolyse starch and chitin.</s><s>Produces alkaline phosphatase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>α</em>-fucosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, arginine arylamidase and glutamyl glycine arylamidase.</s><s>Some strains form <em>β</em>-glucuronidase weakly.</s><s>Acid is produced oxidatively from d-glucose, dl-arabinose, d-mannose, d-galactose, d-fructose, l-rhamnose, d-xylose, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, lactose, cellobiose, trehalose, maltose, sucrose, melibiose and raffinose, but not from sugar alcohols.</s><s>The following substrates are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: l-rhamnose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-mannose, d-xylose, cellobiose, lactose, d-maltose, d-melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, salicin, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, d-sorbitol, <em>m</em>-inositol, d-mannitol, <em>β</em>-glycerophosphate, d-gluconate, propionate, isobutyrate, malonate, succinate, pimelate, azelate, l-proline, 2-aminobutyrate and l-serine.</s><s>Best growth occurs on maltose and sucrose as sole carbon sources.</s><s>l-Ornithine, glycogen, <em>n</em>-butyrate, glutarate, aconitate, l-malate, fumarate and hydroxy-l-proline are used by some but not all strains.</s><s>The following carbon sources are not utilized: dl-arabinose, l-fucose, 2-ketogluconate, adonitol, d-arabitol, dulcitol, i-erythritol, glycerol, methanol, itaconate, formate, acetate, <em>n</em>-valerate, suberate, 3-dl-hydroxybutyrate, citrate, oxaloacetate, benzoate, dl-lactate, dl-tartrate, pyruvate, methylamine, isovalerate, heptanoate, caproate, nonanoate, adipate, 2-oxoglutarate, l-alanine, l-aspartate, l-asparagine, l-phenylalanine, l-glutamate, l-histidine, l-threonine, l-tyrosine, l-leucine, putrescine and urate.</s><s>Produces salmon-pink colonies that are smooth, circular, convex, with an entire edge and a butyrous consistency when grown on marine 2216 agar (at 10 °C).</s><s>Other characteristics are listed in Table 2.</s><s>The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 35–36 mol% (thermal denaturation procedure).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, IC025<sup>T</sup> (=ACAM 646<sup>T</sup>=LMG 21435<sup>T</sup> =CIP 107452<sup>T</sup>), and other strains were isolated from cold marine and marine-derived habitats including sea ice and algal mats of saline lakes.</s></p></content></protolog>