<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.3495_nm.5052" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5052" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5052" rank="species">Paraliobacillus ryukyuensis</organism><reference id="rid.3495"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Ishikawa</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ishizaki</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamamoto</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Yamasato</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Paraliobacillus ryukyuensis gen. nov., sp. nov., a new Gram-positive, slightly halophilic, extremely halotolerant, facultative anaerobe isolated from a decomposing marine alga.</article-title><year>2002</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>269</fpage><lpage>279</lpage><source id="120">The Journal of General and Applied Microbiology</source><abbrev>J Gen Appl Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0022-1260</issn><essn>1349-8037</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2323/jgam.48.269</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12501437</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Paraliobacillus ryukyuensis</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Paraliobacillus ryukyuensis</i> (ryu.kyu.en'sis. M.L. adj. <i>ryukyuensis</i> from the Ryukyu Islands, Japan, where the type strain was isolated)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The species has all of the characteristics that define the genus.</s><s>In addition, it has the characteristics described below.</s><s>Colonies on 2.5% NaCl GYPF (glucose-yeast extract-peptone-fish extract) agar are round, convex, entire, yellow and transparent, with diameters of 1.2–1.5 mm after 3 days at 30°C.</s><s>Deep colonies are creamy white, opaque and lenticular, with diameters of 0.5–1.5 mm.</s><s>Cells are 0.4–0.5 x 2.3–4.5 mm occurring singly, in pairs or in chains.</s><s>Spores are formed on agar media at 37°C, measuring 0.9–1.0 x 0.9–1.4 mm.</s><s>The optimum NaCl concentration for growth is 0.75–3.0% (w/v) with a range of 0–22.0% (w/v).</s><s>The optimum pH for growth is 7.0–8.5 with a range of 5.5–9.5.</s><s>Growth is observed at 10–47.5°C with an optimum temperature of 37–40°C.</s><s>Negative for nitrate reduction, gelatin liquefaction and production of ammonia from L-arginine.</s><s>Starch is hydrolyzed.</s><s>The following carbohydrates and related compounds are utilized: D-glucose, D-fructose, D-mannose, L-arabinose, D-xylose, D-ribose, maltose, sucrose, lactose, D-cellobiose, D-trehalose, D-raffinose, D-melezitose, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, adonitol (weak), dulcitol (weak), glycerol, <i>myo</i>-inositol, starch, inulin, D-salicine, amethyl D-glucoside, and sodium gluconate.</s><s>D-Galactose, melibiose, D-rhamnose, D-arabinose, ethanol, formate, acetate, lactate, pyruvate, succinate, malate, fumarate, oxaloacetate, 2-oxoglutarate, and citrate are not utilized.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of strain O15-7<sup>T</sup> is 35.6 mol%.</s><s>Isolated from a decomposing alga collected at a foreshore in Okinawa, Japan.</s><s>The type strain is strain O15-7<sup>T</sup> which has been deposited at the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen GmbH (DSMZ), Braunschweig, Germany, the IAM Culture Collection (IAM), the Institute of Molecular and Cellular Biosciences, The University of Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan, the NITE Biological Resource Center (NBRC), National Institute of Technology and Evaluation, Kisarazu, Japan, and the Nodai Culture Collection Center (NRIC), Tokyo University of Agriculture, Tokyo, Japan, under the accession numbers of DSM 15140<sup>T</sup>, IAM 15001<sup>T</sup>, NBRC 10001<sup>T</sup>, and NRIC 0520<sup>T</sup>, respectively.</s></p></content></protolog>