<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.2636_nm.4704" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.4704" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.4704" rank="species">Mycoplasma mustelae</organism><reference id="rid.2636"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Salih</surname><given-names>M.M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Friis</surname><given-names>N.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Arseculeratne</surname><given-names>S.N.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Freundt</surname><given-names>E.A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Christiansen</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Mycoplasma mustelae, a new species from mink.</article-title><year>1983</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>476</fpage><lpage>479</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-33-3-476</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycoplasma mustelae</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycoplasma mustelae</i> (L. n. <i>Mustela</i> weasel, generic name of the mink <i>Mustela vison</i>; L. gen. n. <i>mustelae</i> of <i>Mustela</i>)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The three isolates from minks showed the same biochemical and serological characteristics, indicating that they belong to the same species.</s><s>Their lack of a cell wall, their cellular morphology, their filterability through a membrane filter with a pore diameter of 300 nm, their typical colonial morphology, and their failure to revert to a bacterial form indicate that these organisms belong to the class <i>Mollicutes</i> and the order <i>Mycoplasmatales</i>.</s><s>Their susceptibilities to digitonin and sodium polyanethol sulfonate, their requirement for cholesterol for growth, their lack of spiral morphology, and their inability to hydrolyze urea place these mink strains in the family <i>Mycoplasmataceae</i> and the genus <i>Mycoplasma</i>.</s><s>Strain MX9<sup>T</sup> is serologically different from all other currently accepted <i>Mycoplasma</i> species and serogroups, as demonstrated by immunofluorescence, growth inhibition, and growth precipitation tests.</s><s>The slight oneway cross-reaction with <i>M. mycoides</i> subsp. <i>mycoides</i> in the growth inhibition test may be considered nonspecific, as it was not observed in the immunofluorescence and growth precipitation tests.</s><s>From the inorphological, biological, and serological results, we concluded that the three isolates from minks represent a new species of the genus <i>Mycoplasma</i>.</s><s>We propose the name <i>Mycoplasma mustelae</i> sp. nov. for this species.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <i>M. mustelae</i> is strain MX9.</s><s>It has been deposited in the Food and Agriculture Organization/World Health Organization Collaborating Centre for Animal Mycoplasmas, Institute of Medical Microbiology, University of Aarhus, Aarhus, Denmark, as strain AMRC-C 1486, in the American Type Culture Collection, Rockville, Md., as strain ATCC 35214, and in the National Collection of Type Cultures, London, England, as strain NCTC 10193.</s></p></content></protolog>