<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.340_nm.6315" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.6315" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.6315" rank="species">Mycobacterium agri</organism><reference id="rid.340"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Tsukamura</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Numerical analysis of rapidly growing, nonphotochromogenic mycobacteria, including Mycobacterium agri, Tsukamura 1972 Tsukamura sp. nov. nom. rev</article-title><year>1981</year><volume>31</volume><fpage>247</fpage><lpage>258</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-31-3-247</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Mycobacterium agri</i> (Tsukamura 1972) sp. nov., nom. rev.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Mycobacterium agri</i> (ag'ri. Gr. n. <i>agrus</i> field; M. L. gen. n. <i>agri</i> of a field)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The original isolate of this species was obtained from alkali-treated soil inoculated on egg media incubated at 42°C.</s><s>As shown in the present study, this taxon can readily be differentiated from all previously described species of rapidly growing, nonphotochromogenic mycobacteria.</s><s>Furthermore, it is clearly different from all other mycobacteria, including the rapidly growing, scotochromogenic mycobacteria (39).</s><s>Consequently, the name is herein revived for the same organism with which it was originally associated (30).</s><s>The characters of this species are listed in Table 2.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The characters of the type strain 90012 (= ATCC 27406) are as follows.</s><s>Acid-fast rods which often grow into long threads.</s><s>Rough, nonpigmented colonies are produced in the dark and after exposure to light.</s><s>Growth occurs after 3 days on egg media and at 28,37, and 45°C; there is no growth at 52°C.</s><s>Resistant to each of the following in egg media (Ogawa egg medium or Lowenstein-Jensen medium): 5% NaCl, <i>p</i>-nitrobenzoic acid (0.5 mg/ml); thiophene-2-carboxylic acid hydrazide (1 μg/ml).</s><s>Niacin is not produced.</s><s>Catalase positive (semiquantitative method).</s><s>Tween not hydrolyzed after 10 days (slightly hydrolyzed after 14 days).</s><s>β-Galactosidase is usually produced.</s><s>Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Susceptible to NH<sub>2</sub>OH⋄HCl (0.25 mg/ ml) in egg media; tolerant to 0.2% picric acid in Sauton agar; tolerant to 0.1% sodium nitrite in Sauton agar.</s><s>Arylsulfatase negative after 3 days but positive after 14 days.</s><s>Produces α- and β-esterases but not acid phosphatase.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Amidase pattern: acetamidase, urease, nicotinamidase, pyrazinamidase, and allantoinase are produced; benzamidase, isonicotinamidase, salicylamidase, and succinamidase are not produced.</s><s>Glutamate and glucosamine are utilized as simultaneous nitrogen and carbon sources; serine, acetamide, benzamide, monoethanolamine, and trimethylene diamine are not so utilized.</s><s>Glucose, mannose, xylose, inositol, fructose, acetate, succinate, malate, pyruvate, fumarate, ethanol, <i>n</i>-propanol, and propylene glycol are utilized as carbon sources in the presence of ammoniacal nitrogen; galactose, arabinose, rhamnose, trehalose, mannitol, sorbitol, sucrose, citrate, benzoate, malonate, <i>n</i>-butanol, isobutanol, 1,3-, 1,4-, and 2,3-butylene glycols are not thus utilized.</s><s>Nitrite is not utilized as a sole source of nitrogen in the presence of glycerol as a carbon source.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Source: Soil.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Type strain: 90012; a culture of this strain has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection, Rockville, Md., as ATCC 27406.</s></p></content></protolog>