<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.4697_nm.2537" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.2537" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.2537" rank="species">Deleya halophila</organism><reference id="rid.4697"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Quesada</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ventosa</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ruiz-Berraquero</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Ramos-Cormenzana</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Deleya halophila, a new species of moderately halophilic bacteria.</article-title><year>1984</year><volume>34</volume><fpage>287</fpage><lpage>292</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-34-3-287</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Deleya halophila</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Deleya halophila</i> (hal.o.phi'la. Gr. n. <i>halos</i> salt; Gr. adj, <i>philus</i> loving; M.L. adj. <i>halophila</i> salt loving)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are gram-negative, nonsporeforming rods 0.5 to 0.7 by 1.5 to 2.0 μm.</s><s>Cells are motile by means of one to eight peritrichous flagella.</s><s>Strict aerobes.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Circular, low convex, smooth, opaque, and cream-pigmented colonies develop on 7.5% (wt/vol) marine salts solid medium after 4 days at 32°C.</s><s>No pigments.</s><s>Broth cultures are uniformly turbid.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The optimal marine salts concentration for growth is 7.5% (wt/vol) at 32°C.</s><s>Able to grow at marine salts concentrations between 2 and 30% (wt/vol).</s><s>No growth in the absence of sodium chloride.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth at 15 to 45°C (optimal growth at 30 to 37°C) and between pH 5 and 10 (optimal growth at pH 7).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Catalase and oxidase are produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Acids are produced from D-glucose and D-galactose.</s><s>Acids are not produced from L-arabinose, lactose, glycerol, <i>meso</i>-inositol, or D-mannitol.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Esculin is hydrolyzed; gelatin, casein, starch, Tween 80, and blood are not hydrolyzed.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Nitrates reduced to nitrites; no reduction of nitrite.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Indole, acetylmethylcarbinol, phenylalanine deaminase, and deoxyribonuclease are not produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Phosphatase and hydrogen sulfide are produced.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Methyl red test is negative.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: L-arabinose, D-cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, maltose, D-mannose, salicin, sucrose, D-trehalose, D-xylose, DL-glycerol, acetate, citrate, fumarate, D-gluconate, DL-lactate, DL-malate, pyruvate, and succinate.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon, nitrogen, and energy sources: L-alanine, L-arginine, L-aspartic acid, L-glutamic acid, and L-serine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following compounds are not utilized as sole carbon, nitrogen, and energy sources: <i>meso</i>-inositol, D-tartrate, L-histidine, and L-valine.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Susceptible to cephalothin, chloramphenicol, polymyxin B, and rifampin A.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Not susceptible to bacitracin, lincomycin, neomycin, and tetracycline.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Source: isolated from saline soils near Alicante in southeast Spain.</s></p><p class="description"><s>G+C content of the DNA: 66.7 mol% (thermal denaturation midpoint estimation).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain is strain FS-7; a culture of this strain has been deposited with the Czechoslovak Collection of Microorganisms, Brno, Czechoslovakia, as strain CCM 3662.</s><s>The description of the type strain is the same as that given above for the species, with exception of those characteristics shown in Table 1.</s></p></content></protolog>