<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8383_nm.13214" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13214" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13214" rank="species">Anoxybacillus bogrovensis</organism><reference id="rid.8383"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Atanassova</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Derekova</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Mandeva</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sjøholm</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Kambourova</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Anoxybacillus bogrovensis sp. nov., a novel thermophilic bacterium isolated from a hot spring in Dolni Bogrov, Bulgaria</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2359</fpage><lpage>2362</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65745-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18842856</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Anoxybacillus bogrovensis</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Anoxybacillus bogrovensis</em> (bo.gro.ven′sis. N.L. masc. adj. <em>bogrovensis</em>, pertaining to Bogrov region, referring to the place of isolation of the type strain).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive, rod-shaped, single or in long chains, facultatively anaerobic, non-motile and 1.4–4.0×0.3–0.6 μm.</s><s>Endospores are ellipsoidal, and located terminally in non-swollen sporangia.</s><s>After cultivation for 24 h on PY agar, colonies are pale white–yellowish in colour, with an irregular edge, high conical surface and viscous consistency.</s><s>Moderately thermophilic (temperature range for growth is 40–69 °C, with optimum growth at 65 °C) and alkalitolerant (pH range for growth is 6.0–10.0, with an optimum at pH 8.0).</s><s>Doubling time is 28 min.</s><s>Catalase-positive and grows at NaCl concentrations up to 1.5 %, with optimum growth at 0.5 %.</s><s>Chemo-organotrophic, and is able to ferment a wide spectrum of carbon sources: d-glucose, fructose, sucrose, maltose, cellobiose, l-rhamnose, l-arabinose, melibiose, amygdalin, mannitol, salicin, glycogen and starch.</s><s>The Voges–Proskauer reaction is negative.</s><s>Starch and gelatin are hydrolysed, but casein is not.</s><s>Acetoin, H<sub>2</sub>S and indole are not formed, phenylalanine and urea are not decomposed, and nitrates are not reduced.</s><s>Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and tryptophan deaminase tests are negative; <em>β</em>-galactosidase is positive.</s><s>Cells mainly contain iso-branched saturated fatty acids (content of about 80 % of the total fatty acids).</s><s>The major fatty acid is iso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>, followed by iso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub> and anteiso-C<sub>17 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 44.1 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, BT 13<sup>T</sup> (=DSM 17956<sup>T</sup>=NBIMCC 8427<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a hot spring near Dolni Bogrov village, Sofia region, Bulgaria.</s></p></content></protolog>