<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.6439_nm.5796" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.5796" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.5796" rank="subspecies">Actinomyces neuii anitratus</organism><reference id="rid.6439"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Funke</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Stubbs</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>von Graevenitz</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>M.D.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Assignment of human-derived CDC group 1 coryneform bacteria and CDC group 1-like coryneform bacteria to the genus Actinomyces as Actinomyces neuii subsp. neuii sp. nov., subsp. nov., and Actinomyces neuii subsp. anitratus subsp. nov.</article-title><year>1994</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>167</fpage><lpage>171</lpage><source id="116">International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Bacteriol</abbrev><issn>0020-7713</issn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/00207713-44-1-167</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8123558</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Actinomyces neuii</i> subsp. <i>anitratus</i> subsp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Actinomyces neuii</i> subsp. <i>anitratus</i> (a.ni.tra'.tus. Gr. pref. <i>a</i>, not; L.n. <i>nitratus</i>, nitrate; M.L. adj. <i>anitratus</i>, not reducing nitrate)</s></p><p class="description"><s>The following description of morphological and physiological features is based on nine strains (reference 7 and unpublished data).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The morphological characteristics of <i>A. neuii</i> subsp. <i>anitratus</i> are similar to those of <i>A. neuii</i> subsp. <i>neuii</i>, except that <i>A. neuii</i> subsp. <i>anitratus</i> is nonhemolytic.</s><s>Cells are catalase positive.</s><s>Acid is produced from adonitol, D-arabitol, erythritol, D-fructose, D-galactose, 5-ketogluconate7 D-glucose, α-methyl-D-glucoside, glycerol, inositol, lactose, D-lyxose, maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, D-ribose, sucrose, trehalose, and D-xylose.</s><s>Some strains produce acid from N-acetylglucosamine, L-arabitol, cellobiose, dulcitol, D-fucose, L-fucose, gentiobiose, gluconate, glycogen, salicin, and D-tagatose.</s><s>Acid is not produced from D-arabinose, L-arabinose, 2-ketogluconate, inulin, α-methyl-D-mannoside, L-rhamnose, D-glucitol, L-sorbose, xylitol, and L-xylose.</s><s>Leucine arylamidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, α-mannosidase, and pyrazinamidase are positive.</s><s>Alkaline phosphatase activity can be observed in some strains.</s><s>Valine arylamidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, β-glucuronidase, and β-glucosidase are negative.</s><s>Esculin, urea, and gelatin are not hydrolyzed.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.</s><s>Straight-chain saturated fatty acids are mainly palmitic and stearic acids.</s><s>Oleic acid is the predominant unsaturated fatty acid.</s><s>The DNA base composition is 55 to 58 mol% G+C (midpoint temperature).</s><s>The strains are isolated mainly from abscesses in association with mixed anaerobic flora as well as from human blood cultures.</s><s>The type strain is strain 50/90 and has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung für Mikroorganismen under no. DSM 8577.</s><s>Strain 50/90<sup>T</sup> has the characteristics described for the species, except that, in the variable carbohydrate fermentation tests, only N-acetylglucosamine, gluconate, and salicin are positive.</s><s>The G+C content of its DNA is 55 mol%.</s></p></content></protolog>