<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.1704_nm.8480" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.8480" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.8480" rank="species">Arthrobacter nitroguajacolicus</organism><reference id="rid.1704"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Kotoučková</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Schumann</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Durnová</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Spröer</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Sedláček</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Neca</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Zdráhal</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Němec</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Arthrobacter nitroguajacolicus sp. nov., a novel 4-nitroguaiacol-degrading actinobacterium</article-title><year>2004</year><volume>54</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>773</fpage><lpage>777</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.02923-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15143023</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Arthrobacter nitroguajacolicus</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Arthrobacter nitroguajacolicus</em> (ni.tro.gu.a.ja.co′li.cus. N.L. masc. adj. <em>nitroguajacolicus</em> pertaining to the chemical nitroguaiacol, whose name is based on N.L. <em>guaiacum</em> – from Spanish <em>guayaco</em>, a tropical American tree and the resin derived thereof).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are Gram-positive irregular rods, club-shaped with typical V-forms, motile and non-acid-fast.</s><s>They display a rod–coccus life cycle.</s><s>Cocci are 0·7–1 μm in diameter; rods are 0·6–1·0 μm wide and 1·0–4 μm long.</s><s>Spores are not formed.</s><s>Colonies are yellow, circular, convex and opaque.</s><s>Growth occurs with a suitable carbon source in mineral salts medium; no additional growth factors are required.</s><s>Obligately aerobic.</s><s>Growth at 4–37 °C, with optimum at 25–30 °C.</s><s>Growth occurs in the pH range 6·0–8·0 and in the presence of up to 6 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Catalase and oxidase positive.</s><s>Nitrate not reduced.</s><s>Methyl red test, urease and haemolysis negative.</s><s>Gelatin, starch, casein, aesculin, ONPG and tyrosine are hydrolysed.</s><s>Tween 80, DNA and lecithin are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Elastase is produced.</s><s>Pyrrolidonyl arylamidase and arginine dihydrolase are not produced.</s><s>Production of alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase is variable between strains: the type strain shows positive reactions.</s><s>Simmon's citrate is utilized, but not gluconate.</s><s>Acid is not produced from ribose, mannitol, sorbitol, lactose, trehalose, raffinose, sucrose, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, cyclodextrin, glycogen, pullulan, maltose, melibiose, melezitose, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucopyranoside or tagatose.</s><s>In the Biolog test system, the following compounds are utilized for respiration: dextrin, glycogen, arbutin, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, <em>α</em>-d-glucose, maltose, maltotriose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, palatinose, d-psicose, d-raffinose, d-ribose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, turanose, acetic acid, <em>α</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, <em>β</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, p-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, l-malic acid, methyl pyruvate, propionic acid, pyruvic acid, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl-glycine, l-asparagine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl-l-glutamic acid, l-pyroglutamic acid, l-serine, putrescine and glycerol.</s><s>Utilization of gentiobiose, <em>α</em>-ketoglutaric acid and <em>β</em>-ketoglutaric acid is strain dependent: the type strain is positive.</s><s>A negative reaction is seen with <em>α</em>-cyclodextrin, <em>β</em>-cyclodextrin, inulin, mannan, Tween 40, Tween 80, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-glucosamine, <em>N</em>-acetyl-d-mannosamine, amygdalin, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, l-fucose, d-galacturonic acid, <em>α</em>-d-lactose, lactulose, d-melezitose, d-melibiose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-galactoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-galactoside, 3-methylglucose, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>β</em>-d-glucoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannoside, l-rhamnose, salicin, sedoheptulosan, d-tagatose, d-trehalose, xylitol, d-xylose, <em>γ</em>-hydroxybutyric acid, lactamide, d-lactic acid methyl ester, d-malic acid, monomethyl succinate, succinamic acid, succinic acid, <em>N</em>-acetyl glutamic acid, 2,3-butanediol, adenosine, 2-deoxyadenosine, inosine, thymidine, uridine, adenosine 5′-monophosphate, thymidine 5′-monophosphate, uridine 5′-monophosphate, fructose 6-phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate, glucose 6-phosphate and dl-<em>α</em>-glycerol phosphate.</s><s>The cell wall diamino acid is lysine.</s><s>The peptidoglycan type is A3<em>α</em>, with an Ala–Thr–Ala interpeptide bridge.</s><s>The major menaquinone is MK-9(H<sub>2</sub>).</s><s>The cellular fatty acid pattern is dominated by anteiso-C<sub>15 : 0</sub>.</s><s>The G+C content is 61·9 mol%.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain of <em>Arthrobacter nitroguajacolicus</em> is G2-1<sup>T</sup> (=CCM 4924<sup>T</sup>=DSM 15232<sup>T</sup>), isolated from forest soil.</s></p></content></protolog>