<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<protolog id="rid.8587_nm.13237" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.13237" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.13237" rank="species">Bacillus isabeliae</organism><reference id="rid.8587"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Albuquerque</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Tiago</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Taborda</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Nobre</surname><given-names>M.F.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Veríssimo</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>da Costa</surname><given-names>M.S.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Bacillus isabeliae sp. nov., a halophilic bacterium isolated from a sea salt evaporation pond.</article-title><year>2008</year><volume>58</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>226</fpage><lpage>230</lpage><source id="117">International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology</source><abbrev>Int J Syst Evol Microbiol</abbrev><issn>1466-5026</issn><essn>1466-5034</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1099/ijs.0.65217-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18175713</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <em>Bacillus isabeliae</em> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><em>Bacillus isabeliae</em> (i.sa.be.li′ae. N.L. gen. fem. n. <em>isabeliae</em> of Isabel, in honour of Portuguese microbiologist Isabel Spencer-Martins).</s></p><p class="description"><s>Cells are curved rods that are 0.5–1.0 μm in width and 2.8–5.7 μm in length.</s><s>Gram stain is positive.</s><s>Cells are non-motile and form rarely observed endospores in subterminal swollen sporangia.</s><s>Colonies on Degryse 162 medium containing 5 % (w/v) NaCl are orange.</s><s>Strictly aerobic and heterotrophic.</s><s>Oxidase- and catalase-positive.</s><s>Optimum growth temperature is approximately 35–37 °C; growth does not occur at 15 or 45 °C.</s><s>Optimum pH is between 7.5 and 8.0; growth does not occur at pH 6.0 or pH 9.0.</s><s>Optimum growth occurs at NaCl concentrations between 4 and 6 % (w/v); no growth occurs in medium without NaCl or in medium containing 16 % (w/v) NaCl.</s><s>Cell-wall peptidoglycan is of the A1<em>γ</em> type with <em>meso</em>-diaminopimelic acid as the diagnostic diamino acid.</s><s>The major respiratory quinone is MK-7.</s><s>Predominant fatty acids are iso-15 : 0, 16 : 0, anteiso-15 : 0 and iso-16 : 0; smaller amounts of iso-13 : 0, iso-14 : 0, 14 : 0, 15 : 0, 16 : 1<em>ω</em>7<em>c</em> alcohol, 16 : 1<em>ω</em>11<em>c</em>, summed feature 3, iso-17 : 0 and anteiso-17 : 0 are also present.</s><s>The major polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylethanolamine, phosphatidylglycerol and an unknown aminoglycophospholipid.</s><s>Yeast extract or growth factors are required for growth.</s><s>Nitrate is not reduced.</s><s>Aesculin, arbutin, starch and xylan are hydrolysed, but gelatin, casein, elastin, hippurate and Tweens 20 to 80 are not hydrolysed.</s><s>Positive for DNase, esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase and <em>α</em>-chymotrypsin.</s><s>Negative for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>β</em>-glucosidase, <em>β</em>-galactosidase, <em>α</em>-galactosidase, <em>N</em>-acetyl-<em>β</em>-glucosaminidase, <em>α</em>-mannosidase and <em>α</em>-fucosidase.</s><s>Glucose, fructose, xylose, sucrose, maltose, trehalose, cellobiose, succinate, <em>α</em>-ketoglutarate, lactate, malate, pyruvate, citrate, acetate and proline are assimilated.</s><s>Mannose, galactose, sorbose, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, ribose, lactose, melezitose, melibiose, l-rhamnose, raffinose, fucose, ribitol, xylitol, sorbitol, erythritol, arabitol, mannitol, <em>myo</em>-inositol, glycerol, aspartate, glutamate, alanine, asparagine, cysteine, phenylalanine, glycine, histidine, isoleucine, lysine, methionine, glutamine, arginine, serine, threonine, valine and ornithine are not assimilated.</s><s>Acid is produced from ribose, xylose, fructose, sorbose, cellobiose, sucrose, trehalose, melezitose, glycogen, gentiobiose, turanose, tagatose and potassium 5-ketogluconate.</s><s>Acid is not produced from glycerol, erythritol, arabinose, l-xylose, ribitol, methyl <em>β</em>-d-xylopyranoside, galactose, glucose, mannose, rhamnose, galactitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, methyl <em>α</em>-d-mannopyranoside, methyl <em>α</em>-d-glucopyranoside, <em>N</em>-acetylglucosamine, amygdalin, arbutin, salicin, maltose, lactose, melibiose, inulin, raffinose, starch, xylitol, lyxose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, gluconate or 2-ketogluconate.</s><s>The DNA G+C content is 37.9 mol% (HPLC method).</s></p><p class="description"><s>The type strain, strain CVS-8<sup>T</sup> (=LMG 22838<sup>T</sup>=CIP 108578<sup>T</sup>), was isolated from a sea salt evaporation pond on the Island of Sal in the Cape Verde Archipelago.</s></p></content></protolog>