<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<protolog id="rid.5307_nm.7861" type="description" xmlns="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://namesforlife.com/ns/protolog file:/C:/NamesforLife/workspace/namesforlife-schema/protolog.xsd"><organism doi="10.1601/nm.7861" exemplar-doi="10.1601/ex.7861" rank="species">Treponema bryantii</organism><reference id="rid.5307"><citation citation-type="journal"><authors><person-name><surname>Stanton</surname><given-names>T.B.</given-names></person-name><person-name><surname>Canale-Parola</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></person-name></authors><article-title>Treponema bryantii sp. nov., a rumen spirochete that interacts with cellulolytic bacteria</article-title><year>1980</year><volume>127</volume><fpage>145</fpage><lpage>156</lpage><source id="118">Archives of Microbiology</source><abbrev>Arch Microbiol</abbrev><issn>0302-8933</issn><essn>1432-072X</essn><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7425785</pub-id></citation></reference><content><p class="title"><s>Description of <i>Treponema bryantii</i> sp. nov.</s></p><p class="etymology"><s><i>Treponema bryantii</i> (bry.ań.ti.i, M.L. gen. of Bryant; named for Professor M. P. Bryant, who described rumen spirochetes in the early 1950's)</s></p><p class="description"><s>Helical cells measuring 0.3 x 3-8 μm and usually exhibiting irregular coiling.</s><s>One periplasmic fibril is inserted in the protoplasmic cylinder near each end of the cell.</s><s>The two fibrils overlap in the central region of the cell.</s><s>An outer sheath surrounds both the periplasmic fibrils and the protoplasmic cylinder.</s></p><p class="description"><s>No translational motility at 22°C.</s><s>At 37°C the cells perform translational motion while apparently rotating about their longitudinal cell axis.</s></p><p class="description"><s>The spirochete grows (1.9x10<sup>9</sup> cells/ml, final yield) in rumen fluid-glucose-sodium bicarbonate-salts medium under anaerobic conditions (in CO<sub>2</sub> atmosphere).</s><s>No growth occurs aerobically.</s><s>Subsurface colonies in 0.7% Noble agar medium are spherical and white, resembling cotton balls in appearance.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Growth occurs in media in which rumen fluid is replaced with volatile fatty acids and vitamins.</s><s>The spirochete grows in a chemically defined medium.</s><s>Exogenously supplied isobutyrate, α-2-methylbutyrate, pyridoxal, folic acid, DL-acanamlde, biotin, and thiamine are required for growth.</s><s>Riboflavin stimulates growth.</s><s>A carbohydrate and substrate amounts of carbon dioxide are required for growth.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Ferments L-arabinose, D-xylose, D-glucose, D-galactose, D-mannose, cellobiose, lactose, and sucrose.</s><s>Does not ferment L-rhamnose, D-fructose, L-sorbose, D-ribose, maltose, raffinose, soluble starch, cellulose, pectin, inulin, dextran, amino acids, L-arabitol, D-mannitol, glycerol, ribitol, xylitol, sorbitol, potassium gluconate, sodium succinate, sodium acetate, sodium formate, potassium fumarate, Tween 80.</s><s>Grows in media containing cellulose as energy source when cocultured with cellulolytic bacteria (e.g., <i>Bacteroides succinogenes</i> or <i>Ruminococcus albus</i>).</s><s>When cocultured with cellulolytic bacteria, <i>T. bryantii</i> uses, as fermentable substrates, soluble sugars released from cellulose by the cellulolytic bacteria.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Products of growing cells (μmol per 100μmol glucose and 84μmol of CO<sub>2</sub> utilized): acetate, 110; formate, 119; succinate, 53.</s><s>Approximately 15% of the glucose carbon consumed by growing cells is assimilated in cell material.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Gram-negative, catalase-negative, chemoorganotrophic, obligate anaerobe.</s><s>Optimum growth temperature, 39°C.</s><s>No growth at 22°C or 45°C.</s><s>GC content of the DNA is 36±1% (<i>T<sub>m</sub></i>).</s><s>Indigenous to the bovine rumen.</s></p><p class="description"><s>Reference strain: RUS-1; deposited with the American Type Culture Collection under the number ATCC 33254 and the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen, DSM Accession No.: 1788.</s></p></content></protolog>